<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:28:40Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-10" from="2017-07-10" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1008.5165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1008.5165</id><created>2010-08-30</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baladi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benedicks</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maume-Deschamps</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Correcting the proof of Theorem 3.2 and Corollary 5.2 in Almost sure
  rates of mixing for i.i.d. unimodal maps by V. Baladi, M. Benedicks, V.
  Maume-Deschamps, Ann. E.N.S. (2002)</title><categories>math.DS nlin.CD</categories><comments>Corrigendum for Cor 5.2 concatenated with Corrigendum for Theorem 3.2</comments><msc-class>37E05, 28D05, 37A25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2010, Weixiao Shen pointed out to us that the proof of Theorem 3.2 of our
2002 paper in Ann ENS was flawed, and he kindly provided an argument to fix
this proof. (We do not make claims on the lower bounds for the stationary
density anymore.) In 2017, Wael Bahsoun, Christopher Bose, and Marks Ruziboev
pointed out to us that the proof of Corollary 5.2 in the same paper is flawed.
We explain how to recover Corollary 5.2 up to replacing the set $M'_q$ on p. 93
by a slightly smaller set (this does not affect the rest of the paper).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.5073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.5073</id><created>2013-06-21</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nalbach</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schechter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry reduction for tunneling defects due to strong couplings to
  phonons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures; minor modification, final version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 063030 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tunneling two-level systems are ubiquitous in amorphous solids, and form a
major source of noise in systems such as nano-mechanical oscillators, single
electron transistors, and superconducting qubits. Occurance of defect tunneling
despite their coupling to phonons is viewed as a hallmark of weak defect-phonon
coupling. This is since strong coupling to phonons results in significant
phonon dressing and suppresses tunneling in two-level tunneling defects
effectively. Here we determine the dynamics of a crystalline tunnelling defect
strongly coupled to phonons incorporating the full 3D geometry in our
description. We find that inversion symmetric tunnelling is not dressed by
phonons whereas other tunnelling pathways are dressed by phonons and, thus, are
suppressed by strong defect-phonon coupling. We provide the linear acoustic and
dielectric response functions for a crystalline tunnelling defect for strong
defect-phonon coupling. This allows direct experimental determination of the
defect-phonon coupling. The singling out of inversion-symmetric tunneling
states in single tunneling defects is complementary to their dominance of the
low energy excitations in strongly disordered solids as a result of
inter-defect interactions for large defect concentrations. This suggests that
inversion symmetric two-level systems play a unique role in the low energy
properties of disordered solids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.5206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.5206</id><created>2013-06-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Eugenio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haggard</keyname><forenames>Hal M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovelli</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>The boundary is mixed</title><categories>gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravition (2017) 49: 100</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2263-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Oeckl's boundary formalism incorporates quantum statistical
mechanics naturally, and we formulate general-covariant quantum statistical
mechanics in this language. We illustrate the formalism by showing how it
accounts for the Unruh effect. We observe that the distinction between pure and
mixed states weakens in the general covariant context, and surmise that local
gravitational processes are indivisibly statistical with no possible quantal
versus probabilistic distinction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.1175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.1175</id><created>2013-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Guccione</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adlong</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnsson</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hope</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchler</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering-Free Optical Levitation of a Cavity Mirror</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 111 (18), 183001 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.111.183001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the feasibility of levitating a small mirror using only
radiation pressure. In our scheme, the mirror is supported by a tripod where
each leg of the tripod is a Fabry-Perot cavity. The macroscopic state of the
mirror is coherently coupled to the supporting cavity modes allowing coherent
interrogation and manipulation of the mirror motion. The proposed scheme is an
extreme example of the optical spring, where a mechanical oscillator is
isolated from the environment and its mechanical frequency and macroscopic
state can be manipulated solely through optical fields. We model the stability
of the system and find a three-dimensional lattice of trapping points where
cavity resonances allow for build up of optical field sufficient to support the
weight of the mirror. Our scheme offers a unique platform for studying quantum
and classical optomechanics and can potentially be used for precision
gravitational field sensing and quantum state generation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7276</id><created>2014-11-26</created><updated>2014-11-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vassilicos</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laval</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foucaut</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanislas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The streamwise turbulence intensity in the intermediate layer of
  turbulent pipe flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, Volume 774, pp. 324-341 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.241</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spectral model of Perry, Henbest &amp; Chong (1986) predicts that the
integral length-scale varies very slowly with distance to the wall in the
intermediate layer. The only way for the integral length scale's variation to
be more realistic while keeping with the Townsend-Perry attached eddy spectrum
is to add a new wavenumber range to the model at wavenumbers smaller than that
spectrum. This necessary addition can also account for the high Reynolds number
outer peak of the turbulent kinetic energy in the intermediate layer. An
analytic expression is obtained for this outer peak in agreement with extremely
high Reynolds number data by Hultmark, Vallikivi, Bailey &amp; Smits (2012, 2013).
The finding of Dallas, Vassilicos &amp; Hewitt (2009) that it is the eddy turnover
time and not the mean flow gradient which scales with distance to the wall and
skin friction velocity in the intermediate layer implies, when combined with
Townsend's (1976) production-dissipation balance, that the mean flow gradient
has an outer peak at the same location as the turbulent kinetic energy. This is
seen in the data of Hultmark, Vallikivi, Bailey &amp; Smits (2012, 2013). The same
approach also predicts that the mean flow gradient has a logarithmic decay at
distances to the wall larger than the position of the outer peak, a qualitative
prediction which the aforementioned data also support.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.03445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.03445</id><created>2015-01-14</created><updated>2015-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barraquand</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corwin</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>The $q$-Hahn asymmetric exclusion process</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>40 pages,11 figures. v3: Presentation improved in Introduction and
  Section 4. to appear in Ann. Appl. Probab</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Appl. Probab. Volume 26, Number 4, 2304-2356 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/15-AAP1148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce new integrable exclusion and zero-range processes on the
one-dimensional lattice that generalize the $q$-Hahn TASEP and the $q$-Hahn
Boson (zero-range) process introduced in [Pov13] and further studied in
[Cor14], by allowing jumps in both directions. Owing to a Markov duality, we
prove moment formulas for the locations of particles in the exclusion process.
This leads to a Fredholm determinant formula that characterizes the
distribution of the location of any particle. We show that the model-dependent
constants that arise in the limit theorems predicted by the KPZ scaling theory
are recovered by a steepest descent analysis of the Fredholm determinant. For
some choice of the parameters, our model specializes to the
multi-particle-asymmetric diffusion model introduced in [SW98]. In that case,
we make a precise asymptotic analysis that confirms KPZ universality
predictions. Surprisingly, we also prove that in the partially asymmetric case,
the location of the first particle also enjoys cube-root fluctuations which
follow Tracy-Widom GUE statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04117</id><created>2015-03-13</created><updated>2015-12-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barraquand</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corwin</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Random-walk in Beta-distributed random environment</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>54 pages, 9 figures. v3: extended revised version. To appear in
  Probab. Theory Related Fields</comments><journal-ref>Probability Theory and Related Fields, Volume 167, Issue 3, pp
  1057-1116 (April 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00440-016-0699-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an exactly-solvable model of random walk in random environment
that we call the Beta RWRE. This is a random walk in $\mathbb{Z}$ which
performs nearest neighbour jumps with transition probabilities drawn according
to the Beta distribution. We also describe a related directed polymer model,
which is a limit of the $q$-Hahn interacting particle system. Using a Fredholm
determinant representation for the quenched probability distribution function
of the walker's position, we are able to prove second order cube-root scale
corrections to the large deviation principle satisfied by the walker's
position, with convergence to the Tracy-Widom distribution. We also show that
this limit theorem can be interpreted in terms of the maximum of strongly
correlated random variables: the positions of independent walkers in the same
environment. The zero-temperature counterpart of the Beta RWRE can be studied
in a parallel way. We also prove a Tracy-Widom limit theorem for this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02511</id><created>2015-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Van Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Linh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laval</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chainais</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>A Bayesian fusion model for space-time reconstruction of finely resolved
  velocities in turbulent flows from low resolution measurements</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2015/10/P10008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of turbulent flows calls for measurements with high resolution both
in space and in time. We propose a new approach to reconstruct
High-Temporal-High-Spatial resolution velocity fields by combining two sources
of information that are well-resolved either in space or in time, the
Low-Temporal-High-Spatial (LTHS) and the High-Temporal-Low-Spatial (HTLS)
resolution measurements. In the framework of co-conception between sensing and
data post-processing, this work extensively investigates a Bayesian
reconstruction approach using a simulated database. A Bayesian fusion model is
developed to solve the inverse problem of data reconstruction. The model uses a
Maximum A Posteriori estimate, which yields the most probable field knowing the
measurements. The DNS of a wall-bounded turbulent flow at moderate Reynolds
number is used to validate and assess the performances of the present approach.
Low resolution measurements are subsampled in time and space from the fully
resolved data. Reconstructed velocities are compared to the reference DNS to
estimate the reconstruction errors. The model is compared to other conventional
methods such as Linear Stochastic Estimation and cubic spline interpolation.
Results show the superior accuracy of the proposed method in all
configurations. Further investigations of model performances on various range
of scales demonstrate its robustness. Numerical experiments also permit to
estimate the expected maximum information level corresponding to limitations of
experimental instruments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00790</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2015-12-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Anshuman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemilentsau</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fung</keyname><forenames>Kin Hung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Nicholas X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Low</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral plasmon in gapped Dirac systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 041413(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.041413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the electromagnetic response and surface electromagnetic modes in a
generic gapped Dirac material under pumping with circularly polarized light.
The valley imbalance due to pumping leads to a net Berry curvature, giving rise
to a finite transverse conductivity. We discuss the appearance of nonreciprocal
chiral edge modes, their hybridization and waveguiding in a nanoribbon
geometry, and giant polarization rotation in nanoribbon arrays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05958</id><created>2015-10-20</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kopeliovich</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames><affiliation>Moscow, INR &amp; Moscow, MIPT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Potashnikova</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames><affiliation>Santa Maria U., Valparaiso</affiliation></author></authors><title>Simple estimates of the masses of pentaquarks with hidden beauty or
  strangeness</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages; Prepared for Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D93 (2016) no.7, 074012</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.074012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The masses of cryptoexotic pentaquarks with hidden beauty are estimated
phenomenologically using the results by the LHCb collaboration which discovered
recently the cryptoexotic pentaquarks with hidden charm. The expected masses of
the hidden beauty pentaquarks are about $10.8$ GeV and $10.7$ GeV in the limit
of some kind of heavy quark symmetry. The states with hidden strangeness
considered in similar way have masses about $2.37$ Gev and $2.30$ GeV, by
several hundreds of MeV higher than states discussed previously in connection
with the relatively light positive strangeness pentaquark $\theta^+$. Empirical
data on spectra of pentaquarks can be used to get information about quarkonia
interaction with nucleons. The results obtained for the case of heavy flavors
are in fair agreement with model of isospin (pion) exchange between flavored
baryons and anti-flavored vector mesons, proposed by Karliner and Rosner, and
in qualitative agreement with the bound state version of the chiral soliton
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08968</id><created>2015-12-25</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhedong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of long-lived coherence and excitation dynamics in
  pigment-protein complexes</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 37629 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep37629</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the mechanism for the long-lived quantum coherence by considering
the discrete phonon modes: these vibrational modes effectively weaken the
exciton-environment interaction, due to the new composite (polaron) formed by
excitons and vibrons. This subsequently demonstrates the role of vibrational
coherence which greatly contributes to long-lived feature of the excitonic
coherence that has been observed in femtosecond experiments. The estimation of
the timescale of coherence elongated by vibrational modes is given in an
analytical manner. To test the validity of our theory, we study the
pigment-protein complex in detail by exploring the energy transfer and
coherence dynamics. The ground-state vibrational coherence generated by
incoherent radiations is shown to be long-survived and is demonstrated to be
significant in promoting the excitation energy transfer. This is attributed to
the nonequilibriumness of the system caused by the detailed-balance-breaking,
which funnels the downhill migration of excitons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03233</id><created>2016-02-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Guccione</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slatyer</keyname><forenames>Harry J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9; R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchler</keyname><forenames>Ben C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>Ping Koy</forenames></author></authors><title>Squeezing quadrature rotation in the acoustic band via optomechanics</title><categories>physics.optics gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics B 49 (6), 065401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/6/065401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the use of optomechanically-generated squeezing to obtain a
sensitivity enhancement for interferometers in the gravitational-wave band. The
intrinsic dispersion characteristics of optomechanical squeezing around the
mechanical frequency are able to produce squeezing at different quadratures
over the spectrum, a feature required by gravitational-wave interferometers to
beat the standard quantum limit over an extended frequency range. Under
realistic assumptions we show that the amount of available squeezing and the
intrinsic quadrature rotation may provide, compared to similar amounts of
fixed-quadrature squeezing, a detection advantage. A significant challenge for
this scheme, however, is the amount of excess noise that is generated in the
unsqueezed quadrature at frequencies near the mechanical resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00530</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bulawa</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal Hypersurfaces in Spacetimes with Translational Symmetry</title><categories>gr-qc math.DG</categories><msc-class>53Z05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider four-dimensional vacuum spacetimes which admit a nonvanishing
spacelike Killing field. The quotient with respect to the Killing action is a
three-dimensional quotient spacetime $(M,g)$. We establish several results
regarding maximal hypersurfaces (spacelike hypersurfaces of zero mean
curvature) in such quotient spacetimes. First, we show that a complete
noncompact maximal hypersurface must either be a cylinder $S^1 \times
\mathbb{R}$ with flat metric or else conformal to the Euclidean plane
$\mathbb{R}^2$. Second, we establish positivity of mass for certain maximal
hypersurfaces, referring to a analogue of ADM mass adapted for the quotient
setting. Finally, while lapse functions corresponding to the maximal
hypersurface gauge are necessarily bounded in the four-dimensional
asymptotically Euclidean setting, we show that nontrivial quotient spacetimes
admit the maximal hypersurface gauge only with unbounded lapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08117</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaina</keyname><forenames>Nad&#xe8;ge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Causier</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourlier</keyname><forenames>Yoan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthelot</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lerosey</keyname><forenames>Geoffroy</forenames></author></authors><title>Slow waves in locally resonant metamaterials line defect waveguides</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the past decades, many efforts have been devoted to the temporal
manipulation of waves, especially focusing on slowing down their propagation.
In electromagnetism, from microwave to optics, as well as in acoustics or for
elastic waves, slow wave propagation indeed largely benefits both applied and
fundamental physics. It is for instance essential in analog signal computing
through the design of components such as delay lines and buffers, and it is one
of the prerequisite for increased wave/matter interactions. Despite the
interest of a broad community, researches have mostly been conducted in optics
along with the development of wavelength scaled structured composite media,
that appear promising candidates for compact slow light components. Yet their
minimum structural scale prevents them from being transposed to lower
frequencies where wavelengths range from sub-millimeter to meters. In this
article, we propose to overcome this limitation thanks to the deep
sub-wavelength scale of locally resonant metamaterials. In our approach,
implemented here in the microwave regime, we show that introducing coupled
resonant defects in such composite media allows the creation of deep
sub-wavelength waveguides. We experimentally demonstrate that waves, while
propagating in such waveguides, exhibit largely reduced group velocities. We
qualitatively explain the mechanism underlying this slow wave propagation and
first experimentally demonstrate, then numerically verify, how it can be taken
advantage of to tune the velocity, achieving group indices ng as high as 227
over relatively large bandwidths. We conclude by highlighting the three
beneficial consequences of our line defect slow wave waveguides in locally
resonant metamaterials: the deep sub-wavelength scale, the very large group
indices and the fact that slow wave propagation does not occur at the expense
of drastic bandwidth reductions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00310</id><created>2016-05-01</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lipowski</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipowska</keyname><forenames>Dorota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Antonio L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Agreement dynamics on directed random graphs</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, J. Stat. Mech. (in press)</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 063408</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa727a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine some agreement-dynamics models that are placed on directed random
graphs. In such systems a fraction of sites $\exp(-z)$, where $z$ is the
average degree, becomes permanently fixed or flickering. In the Voter model,
which has no surface tension, such zealots or flickers freely spread their
opinions and that makes the system disordered. For models with a surface
tension, like the Ising model or the Naming Game model, their role is limited
and such systems are ordered at large~$z$. However, when $z$ decreases, the
density of zealots or flickers increases, and below a certain threshold ($z\sim
1.9-2.0$) the system becomes disordered. On undirected random graphs agreement
dynamics is much different and ordering appears as soon the graph is above the
percolation threshold at $z=1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02953</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delord</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolas</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Lucien</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe9;tet</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron spin resonance from NV centers in diamonds levitating in an ion
  trap</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 figures, 8 pages</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 033031 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa659c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report observations of the Electron Spin Resonance (ESR) of Nitrogen
Vacancy (NV) centers in diamonds that are levitating in an ion trap. Using a
needle Paul trap operating under ambient conditions, we demonstrate efficient
microwave driving of the electronic spin and show that the spin properties of
deposited diamond particles measured by the ESR are retained in the Paul trap.
We also exploit the ESR signal to monitor the rotation of levitating
monocrystals, a first step towards spin-controlled mechanical systems in
scattering-free traps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08120</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Slatyer</keyname><forenames>Harry J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guccione</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Young-Wook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchler</keyname><forenames>Ben C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>Ping Koy</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of optical spring potentials in optomechanical systems</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 (12), 125401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/12/125401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to tailor the potential experienced by a moveable end
mirror in a cavity optomechanical system by specifying the spectral properties
of the input field. We show that by engineering the power spectral density of
the cavity input field a desired force function can be approximated, with the
accuracy of the approximation limited only by the linewidth of the cavity. The
very general technique presented here could have applications in many kinds of
optomechanical systems, particularly those used for sensing and metrology. We
demonstrate the method by applying it to improve the sensitivity of a
particular gravity measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01203</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2016-09-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Prithwish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pariari</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Prabhat</forenames></author></authors><title>Prominent metallic surface conduction and the singular magnetic response
  of topological Dirac fermion in three-dimensional topological insulator
  Bi$_{1.5}$Sb$_{0.5}$Te$_{1.7}$Se$_{1.3}$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 4883 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-05164-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report semiconductor to metal-like crossover in temperature dependence of
resistivity ($\rho$) due to the switching of charge transport from bulk to
surface channel in three-dimensional topological insulator
Bi$_{1.5}$Sb$_{0.5}$Te$_{1.7}$Se$_{1.3}$. Unlike earlier studies, a much
sharper drop in $\rho$($T$) is observed below the crossover temperature due to
the dominant surface conduction. Remarkably, the resistivity of the conducting
surface channel follows a rarely observable $T^2$ dependence at low temperature
as predicted theoretically for a two-dimensional Fermi liquid system. The field
dependence of magnetization shows a cusp-like paramagnetic peak in the
susceptibility ($\chi$) at zero field over the diamagnetic background. The peak
is found to be robust against temperature and decays linearly with field from
its zero-field value. This unique behavior of $\chi$ is associated with the
spin-momentum locked topological surface state of
Bi$_{1.5}$Sb$_{0.5}$Te$_{1.7}$Se$_{1.3}$. The reconstruction of surface state
with time is clearly reflected through the reduction of peak height with the
age of the sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06028</id><created>2016-08-21</created><updated>2016-12-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gangat</keyname><forenames>Adil A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>I</keyname><forenames>Te</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kao</keyname><forenames>Ying-Jer</forenames></author></authors><title>Steady States of Infinite-Size Dissipative Quantum Chains via Imaginary
  Time Evolution</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>5+3 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 010501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.010501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Directly in the thermodynamic limit, we show how to combine imaginary and
real time evolution of tensor networks to efficiently and accurately find the
nonequilibrium steady states (NESS) of one-dimensional dissipative quantum
lattices governed by the Lindblad master equation. The imaginary time evolution
first bypasses any highly correlated portions of the real-time evolution
trajectory by directly converging to the weakly correlated subspace of the
NESS, after which real time evolution completes the convergence to the NESS
with high accuracy. We demonstrate the power of the method with the dissipative
transverse field quantum Ising chain. We show that a crossover of an order
parameter shown to be smooth in previous finite-size studies remains smooth in
the thermodynamic limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00742</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kagan</keyname><forenames>Grigory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baalrud</keyname><forenames>Scott D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daligault</keyname><forenames>Jerome</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of coupling on thermal forces and dynamic friction in plasmas
  with multiple ion species</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Revised version accepted for publication in Physics of Plasmas.
  Copyright American Institute of Physics 2017</comments><report-no>Los Alamos National Lab LA-UR-16-26693</report-no><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas 24, 072705 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4986086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently proposed effective potential theory [Phys. Rev. Lett. 110,
235001 (2013)] is used to investigate the influence of coupling on
inter-ion-species diffusion and momentum exchange in multi-component plasmas.
Thermo-diffusion and the thermal force are found to diminish rapidly as strong
coupling onsets. For the same coupling parameters, the dynamic friction
coefficient is found to tend to unity. These results provide an impetus for
addressing the role of coupling on diffusive processes in inertial confinement
fusion experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03687</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03687</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coladangelo</keyname><forenames>Andrea W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parallel self-testing of (tilted) EPR pairs via copies of (tilted) CHSH</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>35 pages. Added references, corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information and Computation, Vol.17, No.9&amp;10 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Device-independent self-testing allows a verifier to certify that potentially
malicious parties hold on to a specific quantum state, based only on the
observed correlations. Parallel self-testing has recently been explored, aiming
to self-test many copies (i.e. a tensor product) of the target state
concurrently. In this work, we show that $n$ EPR pairs can be self-tested in
parallel through $n$ copies of the well known CHSH game. We generalise this
result further to a parallel self-test of $n$ tilted EPR pairs with arbitrary
angles, and finally we show how our results and calculations can also be
applied to obtain a parallel self-test of $2n$ EPR pairs via $n$ copies of the
Mermin-Peres magic square game.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00766</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Aidan I</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rutenberg</keyname><forenames>Andrew D</forenames></author></authors><title>A model of autophagy size selectivity by receptor clustering on
  peroxisomes</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.SC</categories><comments>25 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Selective autophagy must not only select the correct type of organelle, but
also must discriminate between individual organelles of the same kind so that
some but not all of the organelles are removed. We propose that physical
clustering of autophagy receptor proteins on the organelle surface can provide
an appropriate all-or-none signal for organelle degradation. We explore this
proposal using a computational model restricted to peroxisomes and the
relatively well characterized pexophagy receptor proteins NBR1 and p62. We find
that larger peroxisomes nucleate NBR1 clusters first and lose them last through
competitive coarsening. This results in significant size-selectivity that
favors large peroxisomes, and can explain the increased catalase signal that
results from siRNA inhibition of p62. Excess ubiquitin, resulting from damaged
organelles, suppresses size-selectivity but not cluster formation. Our proposed
selectivity mechanism thus allows all damaged organelles to be degraded, while
otherwise selecting only a portion of organelles for degradation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01236</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Rui-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>Fingerprints of bosonic symmetry protected topological state in a
  quantum point contact</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 216803 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.216803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the transport through a quantum point contact for
bosonic helical liquid that exists at the edge of a bilayer graphene under a
strong magnetic field. We identify &quot;smoking gun&quot; transport signatures to
distinguish bosonic symmetry protected topological (BSPT) state from fermionic
two-channel quantum spin Hall (QSH) state in this system. In particular, a
novel charge insulator/spin conductor phase is found for BSPT state, while
either charge insulator/spin insulator or charge conductor/spin conductor phase
is expected for the two-channel QSH state. Consequently, a simple transport
measurement will reveal the fingerprint of bosonic topological physics in
bilayer graphene systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04548</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Low</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaves</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldwell</keyname><forenames>Joshua D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Anshuman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Nicholas X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avouris</keyname><forenames>Phaedon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Tony F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guinea</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Moreno</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koppens</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Polaritons in layered 2D materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nature Materials 16, 182--194 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4792</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, enhanced light-matter interactions through a plethora of
dipole-type polaritonic excitations have been observed in two-dimensional (2D)
layered materials. In graphene, electrically tunable and highly confined
plasmon-polaritons were predicted and observed, opening up opportunities for
optoelectronics, bio-sensing and other mid-infrared applications. In hexagonal
boron nitride (hBN), low-loss infrared-active phonon-polaritons exhibit
hyperbolic behavior for some frequencies, allowing for ray-like propagation
exhibiting high quality factors and hyperlensing effects. In transition metal
dichalcogenides (TMDs), reduced screening in the 2D limit leads to optically
prominent excitons with large binding energy, with these polaritonic modes
having been recently observed with scanning near field optical microscopy
(SNOM). Here, we review recent progress in state-of-the-art experiments, survey
the vast library of polaritonic modes in 2D materials, their optical spectral
properties, figures-of-merit and application space. Taken together, the
emerging field of 2D material polaritonics and their hybrids provide enticing
avenues for manipulating light-matter interactions across the visible, infrared
to terahertz spectral ranges, with new optical control beyond what can be
achieved using traditional bulk materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06122</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2016-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Henkel</keyname><forenames>Malte</forenames></author></authors><title>From dynamical scaling to local scale-invariance: a tutorial</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>1+ 23 pages, 2 figures, final form</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Special Topics 226, 605-625 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60336-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical scaling arises naturally in various many-body systems far from
equilibrium. After a short historical overview, the elements of possible
extensions of dynamical scaling to a local scale-invariance will be introduced.
Schr\&quot;odinger-invariance, the most simple example of local scale-invariance,
will be introduced as a dynamical symmetry in the Edwards-Wilkinson
universality class of interface growth. The Lie algebra construction, its
representations and the Bargman superselection rules will be combined with
non-equilibrium Janssen-de Dominicis field-theory to produce explicit
predictions for responses and correlators, which can be compared to the results
of explicit model studies.
  At the next level, the study of non-stationary states requires to go over,
from Schr\&quot;odinger-invariance, to ageing-invariance. The ageing algebra admits
new representations, which acts as dynamical symmetries on more general
equations, and imply that each non-equilibrium scaling operator is
characterised by two distinct, independent scaling dimensions. Tests of
ageing-invariance are described, in the Glauber-Ising and spherical models of a
phase-ordering ferromagnet and the Arcetri model of interface growth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09214</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Bl&#xe1;zquez-Salcedo</keyname><forenames>Jose Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>Valeria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gualtieri</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanti</keyname><forenames>Panagiota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoo</keyname><forenames>Fech Scen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleihaus</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunz</keyname><forenames>Jutta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macedo</keyname><forenames>Caio F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mojica</keyname><forenames>Sindy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radu</keyname><forenames>Eugen</forenames></author></authors><title>Black holes in Einstein-Gau\ss -Bonnet-dilaton theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc.IAU, 12 (S324), 265-272 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1743921316012965</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generalizations of the Schwarzschild and Kerr black holes are discussed in an
astrophysically viable generalized theory of gravity, which includes higher
curvature corrections in the form of the Gauss-Bonnet term, coupled to a
dilaton. The angular momentum of these black holes can slightly exceed the Kerr
bound. The location and the orbital frequency of particles in their innermost
stable circular orbits can deviate significantly from the respective Kerr
values. Study of the quasinormal modes of the static black holes gives strong
evidence that they are mode stable against polar and axial perturbations.
Future gravitational wave observations should improve the current bound on the
Gauss-Bonnet coupling constant, based on observations of the low-mass x-ray
binary A 0620-00.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09364</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Elayavalli</keyname><forenames>Raghav Kunnawalkam</forenames></author></authors><title>Jet structure modifications in heavy-ion collisions with JEWEL</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings for a talk given at Hot Quarks 2016 conference</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 832 (2017) no.1, 012004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/832/1/012004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Key features of jet-medium interactions in heavy-ion collisions are
modifications to the jet structure. Recent results from experiments at the LHC
and RHIC have motivated several theoretical calculations and monte carlo models
towards predicting these observables simultaneously. In this report, the recoil
picture in \textsc{Jewel} is summarized and two independent procedures through
which background subtraction can be performed in \textsc{Jewel} are introduced.
Information of the medium recoil in \textsc{Jewel} significantly improves its
description of several jet shape measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09556</id><created>2016-10-29</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonreciprocal State Conversion between Microwave and Optical Photons</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013808 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013808</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optomechanical quantum interfaces can be utilized to connect systems with
distinctively different frequencies in hybrid quantum networks. Here we present
a scheme of nonreciprocal quantum state conversion between microwave and
optical photons via an optomechanical interface. By introducing an auxiliary
cavity and manipulating the phase differences between the linearized
optomechanical couplings, uni-directional state transmission can be achieved.
The interface can function as an isolator, a circulator, and a two-way switch
that routes the input states to a selected output channel. We show that under a
generalized impedance matching condition, the state conversion can reach high
fidelity and is robust against the thermal fluctuations in the mechanical mode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02134</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2017-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sprau</keyname><forenames>Peter O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostin</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreisel</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hmer</keyname><forenames>Anna E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taufour</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canfield</keyname><forenames>Paul C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Shantanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschfeld</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Brian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>J. C. S&#xe9;amus</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of Orbital-Selective Cooper Pairing in FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>for movie S1, see
  http://www.physik.uni-leipzig.de/~kreisel/oscp/S1.mp4, for movie S2, see
  http://www.physik.uni-leipzig.de/~kreisel/oscp/S2.mp4 and for movie S3, see
  http://www.physik.uni-leipzig.de/~kreisel/oscp/S3.mp4</comments><report-no>NBI CMT 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Science 357, 75 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aal1575</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconductor FeSe is of intense interest thanks to its unusual
non-magnetic nematic state and potential for high temperature
superconductivity. But its Cooper pairing mechanism has not been determined.
Here we use Bogoliubov quasiparticle interference imaging to determine the
Fermi surface geometry of the bands surrounding the $\Gamma = (0,0)$ and
$X=(\pi / a_{Fe}, 0)$ points of FeSe, and to measure the corresponding
superconducting energy gaps. We show that both gaps are extremely anisotropic
but nodeless, and exhibit gap maxima oriented orthogonally in momentum space.
Moreover, by implementing a novel technique we demonstrate that these gaps have
opposite sign with respect to each other. This complex gap configuration
reveals the existence of orbital-selective Cooper pairing which, in FeSe, is
based preferentially on electrons from the $d_{yz}$ orbitals of the iron atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02710</id><created>2016-11-08</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>Deovrat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Prateek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babul</keyname><forenames>Arif</forenames></author></authors><title>AGN jet-driven stochastic cold accretion in cluster cores</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures, 1 table; accepted in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1698</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several arguments suggest that stochastic condensation of cold gas and its
accretion onto the central supermassive black hole (SMBH) is essential for
active galactic nuclei (AGN) feedback to work in the most massive galaxies that
lie at the centres of galaxy clusters. Our 3-D hydrodynamic AGN jet-ICM
(intracluster medium) simulations, looking at the detailed angular momentum
distribution of cold gas and its time variability for the first time, show that
the angular momentum of the cold gas crossing $\lesssim 1$ kpc is essentially
isotropic. With almost equal mass in clockwise and counter-clockwise
orientations, we expect a cancellation of angular momentum on roughly the
dynamical time. This means that a compact accretion flow with a short viscous
time ought to form, through which enough accretion power can be channeled into
jet mechanical energy sufficiently quickly to prevent a cooling flow. The
inherent stochasticity, expected in feedback cycles driven by cold gas
condensation, gives rise to a large variation in the cold gas mass at the
centres of galaxy clusters, for similar cluster and SMBH masses, in agreement
with the observations. Such correlations are expected to be much tighter for
the smoother hot/Bondi accretion. The weak correlation between cavity power and
Bondi power obtained from our simulations also match observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02986</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Rieger</keyname><forenames>Frank M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gamma-Rays from Non-Blazar AGN</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Invited review paper for the 6th Symposium on High Energy Gamma-Ray
  Astronomy, to appear in AIP Conference Proc., 11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conference Proceedings 1792 (2017), 020008</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4968893</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-blazar Active Galactic Nuclei (AGN) have emerged as a new gamma-ray
emitting source class on the extragalactic sky and started to deepen our
understanding of the physical processes and the nature of AGN in general. The
detection of Narrow Line Seyfert 1 galaxies in the Fermi-LAT energy regime, for
example, offers important information for our understanding of jet formation
and radio-loudness. Radio galaxies, on the other hand, have become particularly
interesting at high (HE) and very high (VHE) gamma-ray energies. With their
jets not directly pointing towards us (i.e. misaligned), they offer a unique
tool to probe into the nature of the fundamental (and often hidden) physical
processes in AGN. This review highlights and discusses some of the
observational and theoretical progress achieved in the gamma-ray regime during
recent years, including the evidence for unexpected spectral hardening in
Centaurus A and extreme short-term variability as seen in IC 310 and M87.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04459</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Dhrubaditya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberoi</keyname><forenames>Divya</forenames></author></authors><title>On the energisation of charged particles by fast magnetic reconnection</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1291</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the role of turbulence in magnetic reconnection, within the
framework of magneto-hydrodynamics, using three-dimensional direct numerical
simulations. For small turbulent intensity we find that the reconnection rate
obeys Sweet-Parker scaling. For large enough turbulent intensity reconnection
rate departs significantly from Sweet-Parker behaviour, becomes almost a
constant as a function of the Lundquist number. We further study energisation
of test-particles in the same setup. We find that the speed of the energised
particles obeys a Maxwellian distribution, whose variance also obeys
Sweet-Parker scaling for small turbulent intensity but depends weakly on the
Lundquist number for large turbulent intensity. Furthermore, the variance is
found to increase with the strength of the reconnecting magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04604</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rosenfeld</keyname><forenames>Wenjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burchardt</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garthoff</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redeker</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortegel</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rau</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinfurter</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author></authors><title>Event-Ready Bell Test Using Entangled Atoms Simultaneously Closing
  Detection and Locality Loopholes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 10 figures, supplemental material included</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 010402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.010402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An experimental test of Bell's inequality allows ruling out any
local-realistic description of nature by measuring correlations between distant
systems. While such tests are conceptually simple, there are strict
requirements concerning the detection efficiency of the involved measurements,
as well as the enforcement of spacelike separation between the measurement
events. Only very recently could both loopholes be closed simultaneously. Here
we present a statistically significant, event-ready Bell test based on
combining heralded entanglement of atoms separated by $398\,\mathrm{m}$ with
fast and efficient measurements of the atomic spin states closing essential
loopholes. We obtain a violation with $S=2.221\pm0.033$ (compared to the
maximal value of 2 achievable with models based on local hidden variables)
which allows us to refute the hypothesis of local-realism with a significance
level $P&lt;2.57\cdot10^{-9}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06912</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alves</keyname><forenames>Rog&#xe9;rio Gomes</forenames></author></authors><title>On Kirkwood-Salsburg solutions at criticality</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the Kirkwood-Salsburg equations of equilibrium
classical continuous systems. We prove a Laurent expansion for the resolvent,
at an eigenvalue of largest modulus of the Kirkwood-Salsburg operator, which is
shown to have a pole of order 1. Then we prove that all correlation functions
have an asymptotic limit as the activity parameter tends to a smallest zero of
the partition function. As corollary, we show that any smallest zero of the
partition function is simple. The main consequence is that in case of positive
or hardcore potentials we find the spectral radius of the Kirkwood-Salsburg
operator and the convergence radius of the solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08053</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stephen</keyname><forenames>David T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dong-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>Abhishodh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Tzu-Chieh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raussendorf</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational Power of Symmetry-Protected Topological Phases</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>V2: published version. Also see companion paper by R. Raussendorf et.
  al., submitted in parallel (arXiv:1609.07549, DOI:
  10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012302)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 010504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.010504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider ground states of quantum spin chains with symmetry-protected
topological (SPT) order as resources for measurement-based quantum computation
(MBQC). We show that, for a wide range of SPT phases, the computational power
of ground states is uniform throughout each phase. This computational power,
defined as the Lie group of executable gates in MBQC, is determined by the same
algebraic information that labels the SPT phase itself. We prove that these Lie
groups always contain a full set of single-qubit gates, thereby affirming the
long-standing conjecture that general SPT phases can serve as computationally
useful phases of matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08059</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Q. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>L. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct measurement of the localized-itinerant transition, hybridization
  and antiferromagnetic transition of 5f electrons</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In heavy-fermion compounds, f electrons show both itinerant and localized
behaviour depending on the external conditions, and the hybridization between
localized f electrons and itinerant conduction bands gives rise to their exotic
properties like heavy-fermions, magnetic orders and unconventional
superconductivity. Duo to the risk of handling radioactive actinide materials,
the direct experimental evidence of the band structure evolution across the
localized-itinerant and magnetic transitions for 5f electrons is lacking. Here,
by using angle-resolved photoelectron spectroscopy, we revealed the dual nature
(localized vs itinerant) and the development of two different kinds of heavy
quasi-particle bands of 5f electrons in antiferromagnetic (AFM) USb2. Partially
opened energy gaps were observed on one quasi-particle 5f band cross the AFM
transition around 203 K, indicating that the magnetic orders in USb2 are of
spin density wave (SDW) type similar to Cr. The localized 5f electrons and
itinerant conduction bands hybridize to form another heavy quasi-particle band
at about 120 K, and then open hybridization gaps at even lower temperature. Our
results provide direct spectral demonstration of the localized-itinerant
transition, hybridization and SDW transition of 5f electrons for uranium-based
materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08062</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coladangelo</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goh</keyname><forenames>Koon Tong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarani</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author></authors><title>All Pure Bipartite Entangled States can be Self-Tested</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages. Added self-testing of measurements, corrected typos, and
  improved exposition</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15485 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15485</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Device-independent self-testing allows to uniquely characterize the quantum
state shared by untrusted parties (up to local isometries) by simply inspecting
their correlations, and requiring only minimal assumptions, namely a
no-signaling constraint on the untrusted parties and the validity of quantum
mechanics. The device-independent approach exploits the fact that certain
non-local correlations can be uniquely achieved by measurements on a particular
quantum state. We can think of these correlations as a &quot;classical fingerprint&quot;
of the self-tested quantum state. In this work, we answer affirmatively the
outstanding open question of whether all pure bipartite entangled states can be
self-tested, by providing explicit self-testing correlations for each.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09695</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09695</id><created>2016-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Beckmann</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnack</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of thermalization in giant-spin models by different
  Lindblad schemes</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, submitted to JMMM</comments><journal-ref>J. Magn. Magn. Mater. 437 (2017) 7-11</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2017.04.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theoretical understanding of time-dependence in magnetic quantum systems
is of great importance in particular for cases where a unitary time evolution
is accompanied by relaxation processes. A key example is given by the dynamics
of single-molecule magnets where quantum tunneling of the magnetization
competes with thermal relaxation over the anisotropy barrier. In this article
we investigate how good a Lindblad approach describes the relaxation in giant
spin models and how the result depends on the employed operator that transmits
the action of the thermal bath.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10199</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-01-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>D. Chaitanya Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karmakar</keyname><forenames>Srinibas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Som</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Puffing and micro-explosion behavior in combustion of butanol/Jet A-1
  and acetone-butanol-ethanol (A-B-E)/Jet A-1 fuel droplets</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Submitted to Combustion Science and Technology</comments><journal-ref>Combustion Science and Technology 189 (10), 1796-1812 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00102202.2017.1333502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present investigation deals with the puffing and micro-explosion
characteristics in the combustion of a single droplet comprising butanol/Jet
A-1, acetone-butanol-ethanol (A-B-E)/Jet A-1 blends, and A-B-E. The onset of
nucleation, growth of vapor bubble and subsequent breakup of droplet for
various fuel blends have been analyzed from the high-speed images. Puffing was
observed to be the dominant phenomenon in 30% butanol blend, while
micro-explosion was found to be the dominant one in other fuel blends (blend
with 50% butanol or 30% A-B-E or 50% A-B-E). It was observed that puffing
always preceded the micro-explosion. The probability of micro-explosion in
droplets with A-B-E blends was found to be higher than that of butanol blends.
Although the rate of bubble growth was almost similar for all butanol and A-B-E
blends, the final bubble diameter before the droplet breakup was found to be
higher for 50/50 blends than that of 30/70 blends. The occurrence of
micro-explosion shortened the droplet lifetime, and this effect appeared to be
stronger for droplets with 50/50 composition. Micro-explosion led to the
ejection of both larger and smaller secondary droplets; however, puffing
resulted in relatively smaller secondary droplets compared to micro-explosion.
Puffing/micro-explosion were also observed in the secondary droplets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01028</id><created>2016-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Bussmann-Holder</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohler</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whangbo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianconi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multigap superconductivity at extremely high temperature: a model for
  the case of pressurized H2S</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Superconductivity and Novel Magnetism, 30(1), 151-156
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10948-016-3947-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is known that in pressurized H2S the complex electronic structure in the
energy range of 200 meV near the chemical potential can be separated into two
electronic components, the first characterized by steep bands with a high Fermi
velocity and the second by flat bands with a vanishing Fermi velocity. Also the
phonon modes interacting with electrons at the Fermi energy can be separated
into two components: hard modes with high energy around 150 meV and soft modes
with energies around 60 meV. Therefore we discuss here a multiband scenario in
the standard BCS approximation where the effective BCS coupling coefficient is
in the range 0.1- 0.32. We consider a first (second) BCS condensate in the
strong (weak) coupling regime 0.32 (0.15). We discuss different scenario
segregated in different portions of the material. The results show the
phenomenology of unconventional superconducting phases in this two-gap
superconductivity scenario where there are two electronic components in two
Fermi surface spots, the pairing is mediated by either by a soft or a hard
phonon branch where the inter-band exchange term, also if small, plays a key
role for the emergence of high temperature superconductivity in pressurized
sulfur hydride.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03276</id><created>2016-12-10</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hiluf</keyname><forenames>Dawit</forenames></author></authors><title>Link between Alhassid-Levine and Hioe-Eberly formalisms of $SU(N)$
  equation of motion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>3 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geometric representations of solutions provides intuitive physical insights.
To which end studying dynamics of Quantum systems via $su (n)$ Lie algebra
proves to be convenient way of obtaining geometric solution. In this paper link
is established between two formalisms that made use of Lie algebra to describe
equation of motion for quantum system. In both approaches the Hamiltonian and
the density matrix are expressed as a linear combination of the Lie group. To
exemplify the approach we consider a very well studied two level system coupled
by a laser pulse. Beyond establishing link between these two formalism we
obtained two constants of motion by assuming time dependent detuning whose time
profile is assumed to be same as the laser pulse. Consequently we have shown
how one can have two disjoint subspaces whose evolution vector is independent
of each other.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04335</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rosa</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calloni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caprara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Laurentis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Rosa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grilli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majorana</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepe</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrarca</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puppo</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rapagani</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovelli</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruggi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saini</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stornaiolo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tafuri</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Casimir energy for two and three superconducting coupled cavities</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures. Abstract and title slightly modified. Figures
  and comments added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the behavior of the Casimir energy of a &quot;multi-cavity&quot;
across the transition from the metallic to the superconducting phase of the
constituting plates. Our analysis is carried out in the framework of the
ARCHIMEDES experiment, aiming at measuring the interaction of the
electromagnetic vacuum energy with a gravitational field. For this purpose it
is foreseen to modulate the Casimir energy of a layered structure composing a
multi-cavity coupled system by inducing a transition from the metallic to the
superconducting phase. This implies a thorough study of the behavior of the
cavity, where normal metallic layers are alternated with superconducting
layers, across the transition.
  Our study finds that, because of the coupling between the cavities, mainly
mediated by the transverse magnetic modes of the radiation field, the variation
of energy across the transition can be very large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06660</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-02-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kirschner</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savvidy</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Yangian and SUSY symmetry of High Spin Parton Splitting Amplitudes in
  Generalised Yang-Mills Theory</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures, references added</comments><report-no>NRCPS-HE-01-2017</report-no><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A32 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317501218</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated the high spin parton splitting amplitudes postulating the
Yangian symmetry of the scattering amplitudes for tensorgluons. The resulting
splitting amplitudes coincide with the earlier calculations, which were based
on the BCFW recursion relations. The resulting formula unifies all known
splitting probabilities found earlier in gauge field theories. It describes
splitting probabilities for integer and half-integer spin particles. We also
checked that the splitting probabilities fulfil generalised Kounnas-Ross N=1
supersymmetry relations hinting to the fact that the underlying theory can be
formulated in an explicit supersymmetric manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06789</id><created>2017-01-24</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meister</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moll</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckart</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kajari</keyname><forenames>Endre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efremov</keyname><forenames>Maxim A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walser</keyname><forenames>Reinhold</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schleich</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient description of Bose-Einstein condensates in time-dependent
  rotating traps</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>49 pages, 7 figures, preprint submitted to Advances in Atomic,
  Molecular, and Optical Physics Volume 66</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Atomic, Molecular, and Optical Physics Volume 66,
  375-438 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/bs.aamop.2017.03.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum sensors based on matter-wave interferometry are promising candidates
for high-precision gravimetry and inertial sensing in space. The favorable
source for the coherent matter waves in these devices are Bose-Einstein
condensates. A reliable prediction of their dynamics, which is governed by the
Gross-Pitaevskii equation, requires suitable analytical and numerical methods
which take into account the center-of-mass motion of the condensate, its
rotation and its spatial expansion by many orders of magnitude. In this
chapter, we present an efficient way to study their dynamics in time-dependent
rotating traps that meet this objective. Both, an approximate analytical
solution for condensates in the Thomas-Fermi regime and dedicated numerical
simulations on a variable adapted grid are discussed. We contrast and relate
our approach to previous alternative methods and provide further results, such
as analytical expressions for the one- and two-dimensional spatial density
distributions and the momentum distribution in the long-time limit that are of
immediate interest to experimentalists working in this field of research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07273</id><created>2017-01-25</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Abir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sethi</keyname><forenames>Shiv K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Subinoy</forenames></author></authors><title>The effects of the small-scale behaviour of dark matter power spectrum
  on CMB spectral distortion</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>21 Pages, 7 figures. Accepted in JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After numerous astronomical and experimental searches, the precise particle
nature of dark matter is still unknown. The standard Weakly Interacting Massive
Particle(WIMP) dark matter, despite successfully explaining the large-scale
features of the universe, has long-standing small-scale issues. The spectral
distortion in the Cosmic Microwave Background(CMB) caused by Silk damping in
the pre-recombination era allows one to access information on a range of small
scales $0.3 \, {\rm Mpc} &lt; k &lt; 10^4 \, \rm Mpc^{-1}$, whose dynamics can be
precisely described using linear theory. In this paper, we investigate the
possibility of using the Silk damping induced CMB spectral distortion as a
probe of the small-scale power. We consider four suggested alternative dark
matter candidates---Warm Dark Matter (WDM), Late Forming Dark Matter, Ultra
Light Axion dark matter and Charged Decaying Dark Matter; the matter power in
all these models deviate significantly from the $\Lambda$CDM model at small
scales. We compute the spectral distortion of CMB for these alternative models
and compare our results with the $\Lambda$CDM model. We show that the main
impact of alternative models is to alter the sub-horizon evolution of the
Newtonian potential which affects the late-time behaviour of spectral
distortion of CMB. The $y$-parameter diminishes by a few percent as compared to
the $\Lambda$CDM model for a range of parameters of these models: LFDM for
formation redshift $z_f = 10^5$ (7\%); WDM for mass $m_{\rm wdm} = 1 \, \rm
keV$ (2\%); CHDM for decay redshift $z_{\rm decay} = 10^5$ (5\%); ULA for mass
$m_a = 10^{-24} \, \rm eV$ (3\%). We also briefly discuss the detectability of
this deviation in light of the upcoming CMB experiment PIXIE, which might have
the sensitivity to detect this signal from the pre-recombination phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.09121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.09121</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-02-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zwicknagl</keyname><forenames>Gertrud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jahns</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulde</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical magnetic field of ultrathin superconducting films and
  interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn., Vol.86, No.8, Article ID: 083701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.083701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive an analytic expression for the temperature dependent critical
magnetic field parallel to ultrathin superconducting films with Rashba
spin-orbit interaction. Thereby we cover the range from small to large
spin-orbit interactions $\lambda$ compared with the gap parameter $\Delta_0$.
We find that at a critical spin-orbit energy $\lambda_c$ a first-order phase
transition takes place at which the pairing momentum of the Cooper pairs
changes discontinuously. We speculate that this might give raise to new
phenomena. With increasing $\lambda/\Delta_0$, the pair formation changes from
interband to intraband pairing. For $\lambda&gt;\lambda_c$, a dimensional
cross-over of the critical field from two to one dimension is taking place.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01965</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Balakin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Litvak</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mironov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skobelev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-compression of soliton-like laser pulses in the process of
  self-focusing</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1088/2040-8986/aa792e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the possibility of efficient self-compression of femtosecond laser
pulses in nonlinear media with anomalous dispersion of group velocity during
the self-focusing of wave packets with a power several times greater than the
critical self-focusing power. The results of qualitative analysis of the
evolution of three-dimensional wave packets with the quasi-soliton field
distribution are confirmed by the computer simulation. The simulation proves
that the considered regime of compression of high-power laser pulses with
initial durations of about ten optical cycles is stable relative to
filamentation instability due to the influence of the nonlinear dispersion. We
demonstrate the possibility of self-compression of laser pulses at a
multi-millijoule energy level and up to one optical cycle with an energy
efficiency of more then 50%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02834</id><created>2017-02-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Cuvier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinath</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanislas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foucaut</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laval</keyname><forenames>J. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;hler</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hain</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scharnowski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geisler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agocs</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;se</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willert</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amili</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atkinson</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soria</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extensive characterization of a high Reynolds number decelerating
  boundary layer using advanced optical metrology</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>50 pages</comments><doi>10.1080/14685248.2017.1342827</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An experiment conducted in the framework of the EUHIT project and designed to
characterize large scale structures in an adverse pressure gradient boundary
layer flow is presented. Up to 16 sCMOS cameras were used in order to perform
large scale turbulent boundary layer PIV measurements with a large field of
view and appropriate spatial resolution. To access the span-wise / wall-normal
signature of the structures as well, stereoscopic PIV measurements in
span-wise/wall-normal planes were performed at specific stream-wise locations.
To complement these large field of view measurements, long-range micro-PIV,
time resolved near wall velocity profiles and film-based measurements were
performed in order to determine the wall-shear stress and its fluctuations at
some specific locations along the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03233</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koliogiorgos</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baskoutas</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galanakis</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic and gap properties of lead-free perfect and mixed hybrid
  halide perovskites: An \textit{ab-initio} study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Computational Materials Science 138, 92 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.commatsci.2017.06.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hybrid halide perovskites are currently under intense investigation due to
their potential applications in optoelectronics and solar cells. Among them,
MAPbI$_3$ where MA stands for the methylammonium cation, exhibits ideal
properties for solar cells. In attempt to identify new lead-free halide
perovskites we have studied using \textit{ab-initio} electronic structure
calculations in conjunction with hybrid functionals a series of MABX$_3$
compounds where B is a divalent cation and X a halogen atom. Our results
suggest that the compounds under study exhibit a variety of lattice constants
and energy band gaps. Especially, MAZnCl$_3$, MACdBr$_3$, MAGeCl$_3$ and
MAGeBr$_3$ are susceptible to replace MAPbI$_3$ in devices since they show
comparable energy gaps. Further calculations on the mixed hybrid halide
perovskites show that we can tune the values of the energy gap although no
simplified pattern exists. Our results pave the way for further investigation
on the use of these materials in technology relevant applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00821</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schwartz</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Revised Theory of Tachyons in General Relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages; minor changes in Section 2 and Section 5</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A 32, 1750126 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317501267</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A minus sign is inserted, for good reason, into the formula for the
Energy-Momentum Tensor for tachyons. This leads to remarkable theoretical
consequences and a plausible explanation for the phenomenon called Dark Energy
in the cosmos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04593</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Wen Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Soonwon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukin</keyname><forenames>Mikhail D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abanin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical Time Crystals in Dipolar Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>5 + 4 pages, 3 figures, updated references and corrected some typos,
  paper updated to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 010602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.010602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the quantum dynamics of periodically driven, disordered systems in
the presence of long-range interactions. Focusing on the stability of discrete
time crystalline (DTC) order in such systems, we use a perturbative procedure
to evaluate its lifetime. For 3D systems with dipolar interactions, we show
that the corresponding decay is parametrically slow, implying that robust,
long-lived DTC order can be obtained. We further predict a sharp crossover from
the stable DTC regime into a regime where DTC order is lost, reminiscent of a
phase transition. These results are in good agreement with the recent
experiments utilizing a dense, dipolar spin ensemble in diamond [Nature 543,
221-225 (2017)]. They demonstrate the existence of a novel, critical DTC regime
that is stabilized not by many-body localization but rather by slow, critical
dynamics. Our analysis shows that the DTC response can be used as a sensitive
probe of nonequilibrium quantum matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08320</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Ramos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moro</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Linking structure and dynamics in $(p,pn)$ reactions with Borromean
  nuclei: the $^{11}$Li$(p,pn){^{10}}$Li case</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, submitted to PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B. 772 (2017) 115</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.06.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One-neutron removal $(p,pn)$ reactions induced by two-neutron Borromean
nuclei are studied within a Transfer-to-the-Continuum (TC) reaction framework,
which incorporates the three-body character of the incident nucleus. The
relative energy distribution of the residual unbound two-body subsystem, which
is assumed to retain information on the structure of the original three-body
projectile, is computed by evaluating the transition amplitude for different
neutron-core final states in the continuum. These transition amplitudes depend
on the overlaps between the original three-body ground-state wave function and
the two-body continuum states populated in the reaction, thus ensuring a
consistent description of the incident and final nuclei. By comparing different
$^{11}$Li three-body models, it is found that the $^{11}$Li$(p,pn){^{10}}$Li
relative energy spectrum is very sensitive to the position of the $p_{1/2}$ and
$s_{1/2}$ states in $^{10}$Li and to the partial wave content of these
configurations within the $^{11}$Li ground-state wave function. The possible
presence of a low-lying $d_{5/2}$ resonance is discussed. The coupling of the
single particle configurations with the non-zero spin of the $^{9}$Li core,
which produces a spin-spin splitting of the states, is also studied. Among the
considered models, the best agreement with the available data is obtained with
a $^{11}$Li model that incorporates the actual spin of the core and contains
$\sim$31\% of $p_{1/2}$-wave content in the $n$-$^9$Li subsystem, in accord
with our previous findings for the $^{11}$Li(p,d)$^{10}$Li transfer reaction,
and a near-threshold virtual state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09479</id><created>2017-03-28</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krehlik</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buczek</keyname><forenames>&#x141;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ko&#x142;odziej</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x15a;liwczy&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nawrocki</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noga&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marecki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pazderski</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ablewski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bober</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciury&#x142;o</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cygan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisak</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mas&#x142;owski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morzy&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zawada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pieczerak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binczewski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turza</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fibre-optic delivery of time and frequency to VLBI station</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, matches the version published in A&amp;A, section
  Astronomical instrumentation</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 603, A48 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201730615</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quality of Very Long Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) radio observations
predominantly relies on precise and ultra-stable time and frequency (T&amp;F)
standards, usually hydrogen masers (HM), maintained locally at each VLBI
station. Here, we present an operational solution in which the VLBI
observations are routinely carried out without use of a local HM, but using
remote synchronization via a stabilized, long-distance fibre-optic link. The
T&amp;F reference signals, traceable to international atomic timescale (TAI), are
delivered to the VLBI station from a dedicated timekeeping laboratory.
Moreover, we describe a proof-of-concept experiment where the VLBI station is
synchronized to a remote strontium optical lattice clock during the
observation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00043</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pogrebkov</keyname><forenames>Andrei K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries of the Hirota Difference Equation</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 053, 14 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.053</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Continuous symmetries of the Hirota difference equation, commuting with
shifts of independent variables, are derived by means of the dressing
procedure. Action of these symmetries on the dependent variables of the
equation is presented. Commutativity of these symmetries enables interpretation
of their parameters as &quot;times&quot; of the nonlinear integrable partial
differential-difference and differential equations. Examples of equations
resulting in such procedure and their Lax pairs are given. Besides these,
ordinary, symmetries the additional ones are introduced and their action on the
Scattering data is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00276</id><created>2017-04-02</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bussmann-Holder</keyname><forenames>Annette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohler</keyname><forenames>Jurgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Arndt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whangbo</keyname><forenames>Myung-Hwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianconi</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perali</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>The road map toward room temperature superconductivity: manipulating
  different pairing channels in systems composed of multiple electronic
  components</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Condens. Matter 2(3), 24 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/condmat2030024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While it is known that the amplification of the superconducting critical
temperature Tc is possible in a system of multiple electronic components in
comparison with a single component system, many different road maps for room
temperature superconductivity have been proposed for a variety of
multicomponent scenarios. Here we focus on the scenario where the first
electronic component is assumed to have a vanishing Fermi velocity
corresponding to a case of the intermediate polaronic regime, and the second
electronic component is in the weak coupling regime with standard high Fermi
velocity using a mean field theory for multiband superconductivity. This
roadmap is motivated by compelling experimental evidence for one component in
the proximity of a Lifshitz transition in cuprates, diborides and iron based
superconductors. By keeping a constant and small exchange interaction between
the two electron fluids, we search for the optimum coupling strength in the
electronic polaronic component which gives the largest amplification of the
superconducting critical temperature in comparison with the case of a single
electronic component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03879</id><created>2017-04-12</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>O'Shaughnessy</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerosa</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wysocki</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Inferences about supernova physics from gravitational-wave measurements:
  GW151226 spin misalignment as an indicator of strong black-hole natal kicks</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures. Accepted for publication in PRL. Selected in
  physics.aps.org</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1700066</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 011101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.011101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inferred parameters of the binary black hole GW151226 are consistent with
nonzero spin for the most massive black hole, misaligned from the binary's
orbital angular momentum. If the black holes formed through isolated binary
evolution from an initially aligned binary star, this misalignment would then
arise from a natal kick imparted to the first-born black hole at its birth
during stellar collapse. We use simple kinematic arguments to constrain the
characteristic magnitude of this kick, and find that a natal kick $v_k \gtrsim
50$ km/s must be imparted to the black hole at birth to produce misalignments
consistent with GW151226. Such large natal kicks exceed those adopted by
default in most of the current supernova and binary evolution models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05882</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Riordan</keyname><forenames>Michael O'</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pe'er</keyname><forenames>Asaf</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKinney</keyname><forenames>Jonathan C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Blazar Variability From Turbulence in Jets Launched by Magnetically
  Arrested Accretion Flows</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, removed section from appendix, references added,
  accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7339</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Blazars show variability on timescales ranging from minutes to years, the
former being comparable to and in some cases even shorter than the
light-crossing time of the central black hole. The observed gamma-ray
lightcurves can be described by a power-law power density spectrum (PDS), with
a similar index for both BL Lacs and flat-spectrum radio quasars. We show that
this variability can be produced by turbulence in relativistic jets launched by
magnetically arrested accretion flows (MADs). We perform radiative transport
calculations on the turbulent, highly-magnetized jet launching region of a MAD
with a rapidly rotating supermassive black hole. The resulting synchrotron and
synchrotron self-Compton emission, originating from close to the black hole
horizon, is highly variable. This variability is characterized by PDS which is
remarkably similar to the observed power-law spectrum at frequencies less than
a few per day. Furthermore, turbulence in the jet launching region naturally
produces fluctuations in the plasma on scales much smaller than the horizon
radius. We speculate that similar turbulent processes, operating in the jet at
large radii (and therefore high bulk Lorentz factor), are responsible for
blazar variability over many decades in frequency, including on minute
timescales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07477</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-06-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hait</keyname><forenames>Diptarka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavros</keyname><forenames>Michael G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Voorhis</keyname><forenames>Troy</forenames></author></authors><title>A hybrid memory kernel approach for condensed phase non-adiabatic
  dynamics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 147, 014108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4990739</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin-boson model is a simplified Hamiltonian often used to study
non-adiabatic dynamics in large condensed phase systems, even though it has not
been solved in a fully analytic fashion. Herein, we present an exact analytic
expression for the dynamics of the spin-boson model in the infinitely slow bath
limit and generalize it to approximate dynamics for faster baths. We achieve
the latter by developing a hybrid approach that combines the exact slow-bath
result with the popular NIBA method to generate a memory kernel that is
formally exact to second order in the diabatic coupling but also contains
higher-order contributions approximated from the second order term alone. This
kernel has the same computational complexity as NIBA, but is found to yield
dramatically superior dynamics in regimes where NIBA breaks down---such as
systems with large diabatic coupling or energy bias. This indicates that this
hybrid approach could be used to cheaply incorporate higher order effects into
second order methods, and could potentially be generalized to develop alternate
kernel resummation schemes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08124</id><created>2017-05-23</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Botsch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorite</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esquinazi</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michalsky</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zajadacz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmer</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-filter effect at the interface of magnetic/non-magnetic
  homojunctions in Li doped ZnO nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages with 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After more than a decade of extensive research on the magnetic order
triggered by lattice defects in a wide range of nominally non-magnetic
materials, we report its application in a spintronic device. This device is
based on a spin-filter phenomenon we discovered at the interfaces between
defect-induced magnetic and non-magnetic regions, produced at the surface of a
Li doped ZnO microwire by low-energy proton implantation. Positive
magnetoresistance is observed at 300~K and scales with the number of interfaces
introduced along the wire.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08925</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bosman</keyname><forenames>Sarah E. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>George D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haehnelt</keyname><forenames>Martin G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hewett</keyname><forenames>Paul C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMahon</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mortlock</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venemans</keyname><forenames>Bram P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A deep search for metals near redshift 7: the line-of-sight towards ULAS
  J1120+0641</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 23 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 470 (2): 1919-1934 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a search for metal absorption line systems at the highest
redshifts to date using a deep (30h) VLT/X-Shooter spectrum of the z = 7.084
quasi-stellar object (QSO) ULAS J1120+0641. We detect seven intervening systems
at z &gt; 5.5, with the highest-redshift system being a C IV absorber at z = 6.51.
We find tentative evidence that the mass density of C IV remains flat or
declines with redshift at z &lt; 6, while the number density of C II systems
remains relatively flat over 5 &lt; z &lt; 7. These trends are broadly consistent
with models of chemical enrichment by star formation-driven winds that include
a softening of the ultraviolet background towards higher redshifts. We find a
larger number of weak ( W_rest &lt; 0.3A ) Mg II systems over 5.9 &lt; z &lt; 7.0 than
predicted by a power-law fit to the number density of stronger systems. This is
consistent with trends in the number density of weak Mg II systems at z = 2.5,
and suggests that the mechanisms that create these absorbers are already in
place at z = 7. Finally, we investigate the associated narrow Si IV, C IV, and
N V absorbers located near the QSO redshift, and find that at least one
component shows evidence of partial covering of the continuum source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09430</id><created>2017-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jo</keyname><forenames>Insun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueed</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldwin</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winkler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>Medini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shayegan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tuning of Fermi Contour Anisotropy in GaAs (001) 2D Holes via Strain</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Accepted to Applied Physics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 110, 252103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984954</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate tuning of the Fermi contour anisotropy of two-dimensional (2D)
holes in a symmetric GaAs (001) quantum well via the application of in-plane
strain. The ballistic transport of high-mobility hole carriers allows us to
measure the Fermi wavevector of 2D holes via commensurability oscillations as a
function of strain. Our results show that a small amount of in-plane strain, on
the order of $10^{-4}$, can induce significant Fermi wavevector anisotropy as
large as 3.3, equivalent to a mass anisotropy of 11 in a parabolic band. Our
method to tune the anisotropy \textit{in situ} provides a platform to study the
role of anisotropy on phenomena such as the fractional quantum Hall effect and
composite fermions in interacting 2D systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09630</id><created>2017-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Riddhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Mahendra K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Symmetries in Dynamo Reversals</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, Accepted for publication in Physics of Plasmas</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Plasmas 24 (2017) 062307</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4985307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantification of the velocity and magnetic field reversals in dynamo remains
an interesting challenge. In this paper, using group-theoretic analysis, we
classify the reversing and non-reversing Fourier modes during a dynamo reversal
in a Cartesian box. Based on odd-even parities of the wavenumber indices, we
categorise the velocity and magnetic Fourier modes into 8 classes each. Then,
using the properties of the nonlinear interactions in magnetohydrodynamics, we
show that these 16 elements form Klein 16-group $Z_2 \times Z_2 \times Z_2
\times Z_2$. We demonstrate that field reversals in a class of Taylor-Green
dynamo, as well as the reversals in earlier experiments and models, belong to
one of the classes predicted by our group-theoretic arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10990</id><created>2017-05-31</created><updated>2017-06-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Briscese</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santini</keyname><forenames>Paolo Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>On the occurrence of gauge-dependent secularities in nonlinear
  gravitational waves</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 144001 (19pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7451</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the plane (not necessarily monochromatic) gravitational waves at
nonlinear quadratic order on a flat background in vacuum. We show that, in the
harmonic gauge, the nonlinear waves are unstable. We argue that, at this order,
this instability can not be eliminated by means of a multiscale approach, i.e.
introducing suitable long variables, as it is often the case when secularities
appear in a perturbative scheme. However, this is a non-physical and
gauge-dependent effect that disappears in a suitable system of coordinates. In
facts, we show that in a specific gauge such instability does not occur, and
that it is possible to solve exactly the second order nonlinear equations of
gravitational waves. Incidentally, we note that this gauge coincides with the
one used by Belinski and Zakharov to find exact solitonic solutions of
Einstein's equations, that is to an exactly integrable case, and this fact
makes our second order nonlinear solutions less interesting. However, the
important warning is that one must be aware of the existence of the instability
reported in this paper, when studying nonlinear gravitational waves in the
harmonic gauge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02607</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Downing</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portnoi</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization of massless Dirac particles via spatial modulations of the
  Fermi velocity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 315301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa7884</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electrons found in Dirac materials are notorious for being difficult to
manipulate due to the Klein phenomenon and absence of backscattering. Here we
investigate how spatial modulations of the Fermi velocity in two-dimensional
Dirac materials can give rise to localization effects, with either full
(zero-dimensional) confinement or partial (one-dimensional) confinement
possible depending on the geometry of the velocity modulation. We present
several exactly solvable models illustrating the nature of the bound states
which arise, revealing how the gradient of the Fermi velocity is crucial for
determining fundamental properties of the bound states such as the zero-point
energy. We discuss the implications for guiding electronic waves in few-mode
waveguides formed by Fermi velocity modulation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03069</id><created>2017-06-09</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vethaak</keyname><forenames>Tom Doekle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouassou</keyname><forenames>Jabir Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linder</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium quantum transport and analytical conductance formula in
  spin-textured diffusive superconducting heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Manuscript contains incorrect assumption, analytical method not valid
  for general spin-textured systems</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study non-equilibrium quantum transport of spin, heat, and charge in
diffusive heterostructures including both superconductors and materials with
spin-dependent fields, such as textured ferromagnets and spin-orbit coupled
materials. Using the quasiclassical theory of superconductivity, we derive a
general analytical formula for the zero-temperature charge conductance valid in
the non-linear regime. The analytical results are in excellent agreement with
previous numerical calculations at small but finite temperatures. We predict a
strong deviation between the conductance spectra and local density of states in
certain junctions, which is important to correctly identify spectroscopic
fingerprints of unconventional superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04068</id><created>2017-06-10</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poenaru</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gherghescu</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Alpha decay of nuclei interesting for synthesis of $Z=119, 120$ isotopes</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>28 pages, 4 figures and 14 tables. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1702.05598</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Four groups (even-even, even-odd, odd-even and odd-odd) of heavy and
super-heavy nuclei are of interest for the synthesis of the isotopes with
$Z=119, 120$. We report calculations of $\alpha$~decay half-lives using four
models: AKRA (Akrawy); ASAF (Analytical Super-Asymmetric Fission); UNIV
(Universal Formula), and semFIS (Semi-empirical formula based on Fission
Theory). We compare the experimental $Q_\alpha$ values either with AME16 atomic
mass evaluation (whenever available) and with the theoretical model WS4, able
to give masses of not yet measured nuclides. For $^{92,94}$Sr cluster
radioactivity of $^{300,302}$120 we predict a branching ratio relative to
$\alpha$~decay of -0.10 and 0.49, respectively, meaning that it is worth trying
to detect such kind of decay modes in competition with $\alpha$~decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05063</id><created>2017-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bisigello</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caputi</keyname><forenames>K. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colina</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xe8;vre</keyname><forenames>O. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xf8;rgaard-Nielsen</keyname><forenames>H. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Werf</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilbert</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grogin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koekemoer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recovering the properties of high redshift galaxies with different JWST
  broad-band filters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>21 pages, 11 figures, 4 tables. Accepted for publication at the ApJS</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa7a14</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Imaging with the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST) will allow for observing
the bulk of distant galaxies at the epoch of reionisation. The recovery of
their properties, such as age, color excess E(B-V), specific star formation
rate (sSFR) and stellar mass, will mostly rely on spectral energy distribution
fitting, based on the data provided by JWST's two imager cameras, namely the
Near Infrared Camera (NIRCam) and the Mid Infrared Imager (MIRI). In this work
we analyze the effect of choosing different combinations of NIRCam and MIRI
broad-band filters, from 0.6 {\mu}m to 7.7 {\mu}m, on the recovery of these
galaxy properties. We performed our tests on a sample of 1542 simulated
galaxies, with known input properties, at z=7-10. We found that, with only 8
NIRCam broad-bands, we can recover the galaxy age within 0.1 Gyr and the color
excess within 0.06 mag for 70% of the galaxies. Besides, the stellar masses and
sSFR are recovered within 0.2 and 0.3 dex, respectively, at z=7-9. Instead, at
z=10, no NIRCam band traces purely the {\lambda}&gt; 4000 {\AA} regime and the
percentage of outliers in stellar mass (sSFR) increases by &gt; 20% (&gt; 90%), in
comparison to z=9. The MIRI F560W and F770W bands are crucial to improve the
stellar mass and the sSFR estimation at z=10. When nebular emission lines are
present, deriving correct galaxy properties is challenging, at any redshift and
with any band combination. In particular, the stellar mass is systematically
overestimated in up to 0.3 dex on average with NIRCam data alone and including
MIRI observations improves only marginally the estimation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06508</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Curran</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunstead</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whiting</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadler</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allison</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bignell</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Further Observational Evidence for a Critical Ionising Luminosity in
  Active Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted by MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results of a survey for HI 21-cm absorption at redshifts of z &gt;
2.6 in a new sample of radio sources with the Green Bank and Giant Metrewave
Radio Telescopes. From a total of 25 targets, we report zero detections in the
16 for which optical depth limits could be obtained. Based upon the detection
rate for z &gt; 0.1 associated absorption, we would expect approximately four
detections. Of the 11 which have previously not been searched, there is
sufficient source-frame optical/ultra-violet photometry to determine the
ionising photon rate for four. Adding these to the literature, the hypothesis
that there is a critical rate of logQ = 56 ionising photons per second is now
significant at ~7 sigma. This reaffirms our assertion that searching z &gt; 3
active galaxies for which optical redshifts are available selects sources in
which the ultra-violet luminosity is sufficient to ionise all of the neutral
gas in the host galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06574</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zawadzki</keyname><forenames>Krissia</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Luiz Nunes</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Amico</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetries and boundary conditions with a twist</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Accepted for publication by the Brazilian Journal of Physics. The
  final publication is available at Springer via
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13538-017-0517-9</comments><doi>10.1007/s13538-017-0517-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interest in finite-size systems has risen in the last decades, due to the
focus on nanotechnological applications and because they are convenient for
numerical treatment that can subsequently be extrapolated to infinite lattices.
Independently of the envisioned application, special attention must be given to
boundary condition, which may or may not preserve the symmetry of the infinite
lattice. Here we present a detailed study of the compatibility between boundary
conditions and conservation laws. The conflict between open boundary conditions
and momentum conservation is well understood, but we examine other symmetries,
as well: we discuss gauge invariance, inversion, spin, and particle-hole
symmetry and their compatibility with open, periodic, and twisted boundary
conditions. We develop the reasoning in the framework of the one-dimensional
half-filled Hubbard model, whose Hamiltonian displays a variety of symmetries.
Our discussion includes analytical and numerical results. Our analytical survey
shows that boundary conditions break one or more symmetries of the
infinite-lattice Hamiltonian. The exception is twisted boundary condition with
the special torsion $\Theta=\pi L/2$, where $L$ is the lattice size. Our
numerical results for the ground-state energy at half-filling and the energy
gap for $L=2$--$7$ show how the breaking of symmetry affects the convergence to
the $L\to\infty$ limit. We compare the computed energies and gaps with the
exact results for the infinite lattice drawn from the Bethe-Ansatz solution.
The deviations are boundary-condition dependent. The special torsion yields
more rapid convergence than open or periodic boundary conditions. For sizes as
small as $L=7$, the numerical results for twisted condition are very close to
the $L\to\infty$ limit. We also discuss the ground-state electronic density and
magnetization at half filling under the three boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07947</id><created>2017-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sunagawa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okada</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horigane</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horie</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akimitsu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golias</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchenko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varykhalov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saini</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wakita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muraoka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoya</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of remnant Fermi surface state in lightly-doped correlated
  spin-orbit insulator Sr$_{2-x}$La$_x$IrO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures + Supplemental Material(4 pages, 5 figures),
  accepted for publication in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 041106(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.041106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electronic structure has been studied in lightly electron doped correlated
spin-orbit insulator Sr$_2$IrO$_4$ by angle-resolved photoelectron
spectroscopy. We have observed coexistence of the lower Hubbard band and the
in-gap band, the momentum dependence of the latter traces that of the band
calculations without on-site Coulomb repulsion. The in-gap state remained
anisotropically gapped in all observed momentum area, forming a remnant Fermi
surface state, evolving towards the Fermi energy by carrier doping. These
experimental results show a striking similarity with those observed in deeply
underdoped cuprates, suggesting the common nature of the nodal liquid states
observed in both compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08943</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bang-Gui</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic 2D ferromagnetism, quantum anomalous Hall conductivity, and
  fully-spin-polarized edge states of FeBr3 monolayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is of great interest to explore intrinsic two-dimensional ferromagnetism
and seek better two-dimensional quantum anomalous Hall insulator materials.
Here, we show that the FeBr$_3$ monolayer is an intrinsic two-dimensional
ferromagnetic material whose Curie temperature is 140 K thanks to its strong
spin exchange interaction and giant uniaxial magnetic anisotropy. Our phonon
spectra and mechanical analysis indicate that the FeBr$_3$ monolayer is
dynamically and mechanically stable. Our electronic structure calculation shows
that there is one Dirac cone at K point in the Brillouin zone and the
spin-orbit coupling opens a semiconductor gap of 33.5 meV. Further
tight-binding analysis reveals that the Chern number is equivalent to 1 and
there is a quantum anomalous Hall conductivity $\sigma _{xy} = e^2/h$, and the
chiral edge states are fully spin-polarized when an edge is created.
Furthermore, it is shown that the main results are not affected by electron
correlation effects and biaxial strain. Therefore, this FeBr$_3$ monolayer as
2D material would be useful for spintronic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09730</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09730</id><created>2017-06-29</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haisch</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Yukawas and trilinear Higgs terms from loops</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, 1 table; contribution to the proceedings of the
  Recontres Moriond EW 2017 session; v2: typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is illustrated how LHC precision measurements of rates and distributions
in single-Higgs production can be used to constrain the charm Yukawa as well as
the Higgs trilinear coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00441</id><created>2017-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ptaszynski</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author></authors><title>Waiting time distribution revealing the internal spin dynamics in a
  double quantum dot</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures. Accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035409 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Waiting time distribution and the zero-frequency full counting statistics of
unidirectional electron transport through a double quantum dot molecule
attached to spin-polarized leads are analyzed using the quantum master
equation. The waiting time distribution exhibits a non-trivial dependence on
the value of the exchange coupling between the dots and the gradient of the
applied magnetic field, which reveals the oscillations between the spin states
of the molecule. The zero-frequency full counting statistics, on the other
hand, is independent of the aforementioned quantities, thus giving no insight
into the internal dynamics. The fact that the waiting time distribution and the
zero-frequency full counting statistics give a non-equivalent information is
associated with two factors. Firstly, it can be explained by the sensitivity to
different timescales of the dynamics of the system. Secondly, it is associated
with the presence of the correlation between subsequent waiting times, which
makes the renewal theory, relating the full counting statistics and the waiting
time distribution, not longer applicable. The study highlights the particular
usefulness of the waiting time distribution for the analysis of the internal
dynamics of mesoscopic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01034</id><created>2017-07-04</created><updated>2017-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Phan</keyname><forenames>Khiem Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>A new method for evaluating scalar one-loop Feynman integrals in general
  space-time dimension</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>The calculations of this report are not enough to convince readers</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we propose a new method for evaluating scalar one-loop Feynman
integrals in generalized D-dimension. The calculations play an important
building block for two-loop and higher-loop corrections to the processes at
future colliders such as the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) and the International
Linear Collider (ILC). In this method, scalar one-loop N-point functions will
be presented as the one-fold Mellin-Barnes representation of (N-1)-point ones
with shifting space-time dimension. This representation offers a clear
advantage that we can construct recursively the analytic expressions for
N-point functions from the basic ones which are one-point functions. The
compact formulae for scalar one-loop two-point functions with massive internal
lines and three-point, four-point functions with massless internal lines are
given as examples in this article. In particular, they are written in terms of
generalized hypergeometric series such as Gauss, Appell F 1 functions. We also
perform a sample numerical check for the analytical expressions in this report
by comparing with LoopTools and AMBRE/MB. We find that the numerical results
from this work are in good agreement with LoopTools at $\epsilon^0$ -expansion
and AMBRE/MB at higher-order of $\epsilon$-expansion, at higher D-dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01394</id><created>2017-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Lukas On</forenames></author></authors><title>Development &amp; Implementation of the Trigger for a Short-baseline Reactor
  Antineutrino Experiment (SoLid)</title><categories>physics.ins-det cs.CV hep-ex</categories><comments>University of Bristol, MSc 2017</comments><report-no>MSC-2017-ARNOLD</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SoLid, located at SCK-CEN in Mol, Belgium, is a reactor antineutrino
experiment at a very short baseline of 5.5 - 10m aiming at the search for
sterile neutrinos and for high precision measurement of the neutrino energy
spectrum of Uranium-235. It uses a novel approach using Lithium-6 sheets and
PVT cubes as scintillators for tagging the Inverse Beta-Decay products (neutron
and positron). Being located overground and close to the BR2 research reactor,
the experiment faces a large amount of backgrounds. Efficient real-time
background and noise rejection is essential in order to increase the
signal-background ratio for precise oscillation measurement and decrease data
production to a rate which can be handled by the online software. Therefore, a
reliable distinction between the neutrons and background signals is crucial.
This can be performed online with a dedicated firmware trigger. A peak counting
algorithm and an algorithm measuring time over threshold have been identified
as performing well both in terms of efficiency and fake rate, and have been
implemented onto an FPGA. After having introduced the experimental and
theoretical background of neutrino oscillation physics, as well as SoLid's
detector technology, read-out system and trigger scheme, the thesis presents
the design of the firmware neutron trigger implemented by applying machine
learning methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01900</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sello</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Distinct Periodicities of Sunspot Counts in Flaring and
  Non-flaring Active Regions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent work, Kilcik et al. (2017), have detected the temporal and
periodic behavior of sunspot counts (SSC) in flaring (i.e. C, M, or X class
flares), and non-flaring active regions for the last two solar cycles, covering
the period: 1996 - 2016. The main results obtained are: 1) The temporal
behavior of monthly means of daily total SSC in flaring and non-flaring active
regions are different and these differences are also varying from cycle to
cycle; 2) The periodicities detected in SSC of flaring and non-flaring active
regions are quite different and these variations are also different from one
cycle to another; the highest detected period in the flaring active regions is
113 days, while there are much higher periodicities (327, 312, and 256 days) in
non-flaring regions. The detection of typical different periodicities in
flaring and non-flaring regions can suggests both important differences and
physical interpretation in the magneto-hydrodynamic behavior of the Sun. For
this reason in the present paper we show a further periodicity analysis of the
sunspot counts in flaring and in non-flaring active regions using the same data
source of that used by the above cited authors and applying a powerful wavelet
analysis tool which is particularly useful to detect multiscale features of
complex unsteady and unevenly sampled time series. In order to futher support
the differences and similarities found in the time behavior of SSC in flaring
and non-flaring regions, we also computed the behavior of the wavelet entropy,
a proper time function which allow us to measure the degree of complexity in
the dynamics of the related time series.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01910</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Hernandez-Monteagudo</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames><affiliation>CEFCA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Maio</keyname><forenames>Umberto</forenames><affiliation>AIP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ciardi</keyname><forenames>Benedetta</forenames><affiliation>MPA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sunyaev</keyname><forenames>Rashid A.</forenames><affiliation>MPA</affiliation><affiliation>IKI</affiliation></author></authors><title>Distortions of the Cosmic Microwave Background through cooling lines
  during the epoch of Reionization</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, submitted to A&amp;A in June 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By using N-body hydrodynamical cosmological simulations in which the
chemistry of major metals and molecules is consistently solved for, we study
the interaction of metallic fine-structure lines with the CMB. Our analysis
shows that the collisional induced emissions in the OI 145 $\mu$m and CII 158
$\mu$m lines during reionization introduce a distortion of the CMB spectrum at
low frequencies ($\nu &lt; 300$ GHz) with amplitudes up to $\Delta
I_{\nu}/B_{\nu}(T_{\rm CMB})\sim 10^{-8}$-$10^{-7}$, i.e., at the $\sim 0.1$
percent level of FIRAS upper limits. Shorter wavelength fine-structure
transitions (OI 63 $\mu$m, FeII 26 $\mu$m, and SiII 35 $\mu$m) typically sample
the reionization epoch at higher observing frequencies ($\nu &gt; 400$ GHz). This
corresponds to the Wien tail of the CMB spectrum and the distortion level
induced by those lines may be as high as $\Delta I_{\nu}/B_{\nu}(T_{\rm
CMB})\sim 10^{-4}$. The angular anisotropy produced by these lines should be
more relevant at higher frequencies: while practically negligible at $\nu=145
$GHz, signatures from CII 158 $\mu$m and OI 145 $\mu$m should amount to 1%-5%
of the anisotropy power measured at $l \sim 5000$ and $\nu=220 $GHz by the ACT
and SPT collaborations (after assuming $\Delta \nu_{\rm obs}/\nu_{\rm
obs}\simeq 0.005$ for the line observations). Our simulations show that
anisotropy maps from different lines (e.g., OI 145 $\mu$m and CII 158 $\mu$m)
at the same redshift show a very high degree ($&gt;0.8$) of spatial correlation,
allowing for the use of observations at different frequencies to unveil the
same snapshot of the reionization epoch. Finally, our simulations demonstrate
that line-emission anisotropies extracted in narrow frequency/redshift shells
are practically uncorrelated in frequency space, thus enabling standard methods
for removal of foregrounds that vary smoothly in frequency, just as in HI 21 cm
studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01919</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorshkov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navadeh</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sareh</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tereshchuk</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallah</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sonic metamaterials: reflection on the role of topology on dispersion
  surface morphology</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 15 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.matdes.2017.06.049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigating dispersion surface morphology of sonic metamaterials is crucial
in providing information on related phenomena as inertial coupling, acoustic
transparency, polarisation, and absorption. In the present study, we look into
frequency surface morphology of two-dimensional metamaterials of K3,3 and K6
topologies. The elastic structures under consideration consist of the same
substratum lattice points and form a pair of sublattices with hexagonal
symmetry. We show that, through introducing universal localised mass-in-mass
phononic microstructures at lattice points, six single optical
frequency-surfaces can be formed with required properties including negative
group velocity. Splitting the frequency-surfaces is based on the classical
analog of the quantum phenomenon of &quot;energy-level repulsion&quot;, which can be
achieved only through internal anisotropy of the nodes and allows us to obtain
different frequency band gaps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01923</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Baik</keyname><forenames>Jinho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barraquand</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corwin</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suidan</keyname><forenames>Toufic</forenames></author></authors><title>Facilitated exclusion process</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages. This paper results from splitting the v1 of
  arXiv:1606.00525 in two parts. This paper contains our results on the
  facilitated exclusion process, as well as a detailed derivation of crossover
  kernels. The v2 of arXiv:1606.00525 contains only our results on last passage
  percolation in a half-space</comments><msc-class>60K35, 60G55, 82C23, 60B20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Facilitated TASEP, an interacting particle system on the one
dimensional integer lattice. We prove that starting from step initial
condition, the position of the rightmost particle has Tracy Widom GSE
statistics on a cube root time scale, while the statistics in the bulk of the
rarefaction fan are GUE. This uses a mapping with last-passage percolation in a
half-quadrant which is exactly solvable through Pfaffian Schur processes.
  Our results further probe the question of how first particles fluctuate for
exclusion processes with downward jump discontinuities in their limiting
density profiles. Through the Facilitated TASEP and a previously studied MADM
exclusion process we deduce that cube-root time fluctuations seem to be a
common feature of such systems. However, the statistics which arise are shown
to be model dependent (here they are GSE, whereas for the MADM exclusion
process they are GUE).
  We also discuss a two-dimensional crossover between GUE, GOE and GSE
distribution by studying the multipoint distribution of the first particles
when the rate of the first one varies. In terms of half-space last passage
percolation, this corresponds to last passage times close to the boundary when
the size of the boundary weights is simultaneously scaled close to the critical
point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01933</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Francisco M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of the Kronecker product to simple spin systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the well known Kronecker product is a suitable tool for the
construction of matrix representations of widely used spin Hamiltonians. In
this way we avoid the explicit use of basis sets for the construction of the
matrix elements. As illustrative examples we discuss two isotropic models and
an anisotropic one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01957</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Chiu</keyname><forenames>Shang-Huan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Tsorng-Whay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glowinski</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author></authors><title>A 3D DLM/FD method for simulating the motion of spheres in a bounded
  shear flow of Oldroyd-B fluids</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>26 pages and 14 Figures</comments><msc-class>76T20, 65M60, 65M85</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel distributed Lagrange multiplier/fictitious domain (DLM/FD)
method for simulating fluid-particle interaction in Oldroyd-B fluids under
creeping conditions. The results concerning two ball interaction in a three
dimensional (3D) bounded shear flow are obtained for Weissenberg numbers up to
1 . The pass and return trajectories of the two ball mass centers are similar
to those in a Newtonian fluid; but they lose the symmetry due to the effect of
elastic force arising from viscoelastic fluids. A tumbling chain of two balls
(a dipole) may occur, depending on the value of the Weissenberg number and the
initial vertical displacement of the ball mass center to the middle plane
between two walls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01960</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsunegi</keyname><forenames>Sumito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubota</keyname><forenames>Hitoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Utsumi</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation time and critical slowing down of a spin-torque oscillator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other nlin.AO</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024406 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relaxation phenomena of spin-torque oscillators consisting of
nanostructured ferromagnets are interesting research targets in magnetism. A
theoretical study on the relaxation time of a spin-torque oscillator from one
self-oscillation state to another is investigated. By solving the
Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation both analytically and numerically, it is shown
that the oscillator relaxes to the self-oscillation state exponentially within
a few nanoseconds, except when magnetization is close to a critical point. The
relaxation rate, which is an inverse of relaxation time, is proportional to the
current. On the other hand, a critical slowing down appears near the critical
point, where relaxation is inversely proportional to time, and the relaxation
time becomes on the order of hundreds of nanoseconds. These conclusions are
primarily obtained for a spin-torque oscillator consisting of a perpendicularly
magnetized free layer and an in-plane magnetized pinned layer, and are further
developed for application to arbitrary types of spin-torque oscillators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01985</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Elettro</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vollrath</keyname><forenames>Fritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neukirch</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antkowiak</keyname><forenames>Arnaud</forenames></author></authors><title>Coiling of an elastic beam inside a disk: A model for spider-capture
  silk</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Non-Linear Mechanics, 75:59-66 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijnonlinmec.2015.03.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experimental observations of capillary-induced spooling
of fibers inside droplets both in spider capture silk and in synthetic systems,
we investigate the behavior of a fiber packed in a drop. Using a simplified 2D
model, we provide analytical predictions for the buckling threshold and the
deep post-buckling asymptotic behavior. The threshold for spooling is found to
be in particularly good agreement with experimental results. We further solve
the Elastica equations for a fiber confined in a soft potential, and track the
equilibrium paths using numerical continuation techniques. A wealth of
different paths corresponding to different symmetries is uncovered, and their
stability is finally discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01987</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Fargion</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Observing future Solar Flare Neutrino in Hyper-KamioKande in Japan,
  Korea and in IceCube</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, ICRC 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The largest Solar flare have been recorded in gamma flash and hard spectra up
to tens GeV energy. The present building and upgrade of Hyper-Kamiokande (HK)
and IceCube (as well as Deep Core, PINGU) neutrino detectors do offer a novel
way to largest trace of solar Flare: their sudden anti-neutrino (or neutrino)
flare made by proton scattering and pion decays via Delta resonance production.
These signals might be observable at largest flare by HK via soft spectra up to
tens- hundred MeV energy and by IceCube-PINGU at higher, GeV up to hundred GeV,
energies. We show the expected rate of signals for the most powerful solar
flare occurred in recent decades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01997</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Wahl</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubbard</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Militzer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillot</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miguel</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movshovitz</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaspi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helled</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reese</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galanti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Connerney</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolton</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing Jupiter interior structure models to Juno gravity measurements
  and the role of a dilute core</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>21 Pages, 3 figures, plus Supplementary Information</comments><journal-ref>Geophysical Research Letters, 44, 4649-4659 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2017GL073160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Juno spacecraft has measured Jupiter's low-order, even gravitational
moments, $J_2$--$J_8$, to an unprecedented precision, providing important
constraints on the density profile and core mass of the planet. Here we report
on a selection of interior models based on ab initio computer simulations of
hydrogen-helium mixtures. We demonstrate that a dilute core, expanded to a
significant fraction of the planet's radius, is helpful in reconciling the
calculated $J_n$ with Juno's observations. Although model predictions are
strongly affected by the chosen equation of state, the prediction of an
enrichment of $Z$ in the deep, metallic envelope over that in the shallow,
molecular envelope holds. We estimate Jupiter's core to contain an 7--25 Earth
mass of heavy elements. We discuss the current difficulties in reconciling
measured $J_n$ with the equations of state, and with theory for formation and
evolution of the planet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01998</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhedong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>Kochise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyak</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukamel</keyname><forenames>Shaul</forenames></author></authors><title>Utilizing Microcavities to Suppress Third-order Cascades in Fifth-order
  Raman Spectra</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 2 figures; Accepted by J. Phys. Chem. Lett</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear optical signals in the condensed phase are often accompanied by
sequences of lower-order processes, known as cascades, which share the same
phase matching and power dependence on the incoming fields and are thus hard to
distinguish. The suppression of cascading in order to reveal the desired
nonlinear signal has been a major challenge in multidimensional Raman
spectroscopy, i.e., the $\chi^{(5)}$ signal being masked by cascading signals
given by a product of two $\chi^{(3)}$ processes. Since cascading originates
from the exchange of a virtual photon between molecules, it can be manipulated
by performing the experiment in an optical microcavity. Using a quantum
electrodynamical (QED) treatment we demonstrate that the $\chi^{(3)}$ cascading
contributions can be greatly suppressed. By optimizing the cavity size and the
incoming pulse directions, we show that up to $\sim$99.5\% suppression of the
cascading signal is possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02001</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhedong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Hongchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonequilibrium-induced enhancement of dynamical quantum coherence and
  entanglement of spin arrays</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 144306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.144306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The random magnetic field produced by nuclear spins has long been viewed as
the dominating source of decoherence in the quantum-dot based spins. Here we
obtain in both exact and analytical manner the dynamics of spin qubits coupled
to nuclear spin environments via the hyperfine interaction, going beyond the
weak system-bath interaction and Markovian approximation. We predict that the
detailed-balance breaking produced by chemical potential gradient in nuclear
baths leads to the rapid oscillations of populations, quantum coherence and
entanglement, which are absent in the conventional case (i.e., Overhauser
noise). This is attributed to the nonequilibrium feature of the system as shown
in the relation between the oscillation period and the chemical potential
imbalance. Our results reveal the essentiality of nonequilibriumness with
detailed-balance breaking for enhancing the dynamical coherence and
entanglement of spin qubits. Moreover, our exact solution explicitly
demonstrates that the non-Markovian bath comprised by nuclear spins can
preserve the collective quantum state, due to the recovery of coherence.
Finally, we propose an experiment using ultracold trapped ions to observe these
nonequilibrium and memory effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02006</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Horikiri</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byrnes</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusudo</keyname><forenames>Kenichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>Natsuko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuo</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shikano</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loeffler</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoefling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forchel</keyname><forenames>Alfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Yoshihisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly excited exciton-polariton condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245122 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exciton-polaritons are a coherent electron-hole-photon (e-h-p) system where
condensation has been observed in semiconductor microcavities. In contrast to
equilibrium Bose-Einstein condensation (BEC) for long lifetime systems,
polariton condensates have a dynamical nonequilibrium feature owing to the
similar physical structure that they have to semiconductor lasers. One of the
distinguishing features of a condensate to a laser is the presence of strong
coupling between the matter and photon fields. Irrespective of its equilibrium
or nonequilibrium nature, exciton-polariton have been observed to maintain
strong coupling. We show that by investigating high density regime of
exciton-polariton condensates, the negative branch directly observed in
photoluminescence. This is evidence that the present e-h-p system is still in
the strong coupling regime, contrary to past results where the system reduced
to standard lasing at high density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02008</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Purkayastha</keyname><forenames>Ujjal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Rajib</forenames></author></authors><title>Separating CMB Stokes Q and U polarization signals from Non-Gaussian
  Emissions</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we estimate diffuse foreground minimized Cosmic Microwave
Background (CMB) Stokes Q and U polarization maps based upon the fundamental
concept of Gaussian nature of CMB and strong non-Gaussian nature of
astrophysical polarized foregrounds using WMAP nine year published polarization
maps. We excise regions of the sky that define position of the known point
sources, regions that are strongly contaminated by either the detector noise or
by the diffuse foregrounds or both, and then perform foreground minimizations
over the surviving sky regions that constitute approximately $50\%$ of the full
sky area. We critically evaluate performance of foreground minimizations in
several ways and show that our foreground minimization method removes
significant foregrounds from input maps. The cleaned Stokes \{Q, U\}
polarization maps have less EE and BB power from relevant sky region compared
to WMAP foreground-reduced Stokes \{Q, U\} polarization maps at different
multipole ranges. We validate our methodology by performing detailed Monte
Carlo simulations. The main driving machinery of our method is an
internal-linear-combination (ILC) approach, however, unlike simple variance
minimization performed in usual ILC method, the core of the method being
dependent on the theoretically well motivated concept of Gaussianity of CMB
polarization a direct connection is established between observations and models
of inflation. Additionally, the method, like the usual ILC method, is
independent on modeling uncertainties of polarized foregrounds. It will be
useful to apply our method in future generation low-noise CMB polarization
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02009</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Melrose</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent Emission Mechanisms in Astrophysical Plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>83 pages, 19 figures, accepted for publication in Journal of Modern
  Plasma Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s41614-017-0007-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three known examples of coherent emission in radio astronomical sources are
reviewed: plasma emission, electron cyclotron maser emission (ECME) and pulsar
radio emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02015</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orellana</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosales</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;mer</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dom&#xed;nguez-Adame</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-polarized electric current in silicene nanoribbons induced by
  atomic adsorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 045403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.045403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nonequilibrium transport properties of a silicene armchair
nanoribbon with a random distribution of adsorbed atoms in apex positions. A
ferromagnetic insulator grown below the nanoribbon splits spin-up and spin-down
electron bands and gives rise to a spin polarization of the conductance. The
conductance vanishes when the Fermi energy matches the adatom levels due to the
coupling of adatom localized states with the continuum spectra of the
nanoribbon. This is the well-known Fano effect, resulting in a spin-dependent
antiresonance in the conductance. The different antiresonance energies of
spin-up and spin-down electrons give rise to a full spin polarization of the
conductance in a broad energy window. This spin-dependent Fano effect opens the
possibility to using it in spintronics as a tuneable source of polarized
electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02023</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Chun</forenames></author></authors><title>A flux calibration method for remote sensing satellites using stars</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Star surveys and model analyses show that many stars have absolute stable
fluxes as good as 3% in 0.3-35{\mu}m wavebands and about 1% in the visible
wavebands. The relative flux calibrations between stars are better than 0.2%.
Some stars have extremely stable fluxes and can be used as long term flux
calibration sources. Stellar brightness is several orders of magnitude lower
than most ground objects while the stars do not usually appear in remote
sensing cameras, which makes the stars inappropriate for being calibration
sources. The calibration method using stars discussed in this paper is through
a mini-camera attached to remote sensing satellite. The mini-camera works at
similar wavebands as the remote sensing cameras and it can observe the stars
and the ground objects alternatively. High signal-to-noise ratio is achieved
for the relatively faint stars through longer exposure time. Simultaneous
precise cross-calibration is obtained as the mini-camera and remote sensing
cameras look at the ground objects at the same time. The fluxes from the stars
used as calibration standards are transferred to the remote sensing cameras
through this procedure. Analysis shows that a 2% accurate calibration is
possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02025</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Hai-bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Jing-song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Shu-chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Gang-hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kan</keyname><forenames>Ming-xian</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving the staggered grid Lagrangian hydrodynamics for modeling
  multi-material flows</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>33 pages, 25 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we make two improvements on the staggered grid hydrodynamics
(SGH) Lagrangian scheme for modeling 2-dimensional compressible multi-material
flows on triangular mesh. The first improvement is the construction of a
dynamic local remeshing scheme for preventing mesh distortion. The remeshing
scheme is similar to many published algorithms except that it introduces some
special operations for treating grids around multi-material interfaces. This
makes the simulation of extremely deforming and topology-variable
multi-material processes possible, such as the complete process of a heavy
fluid dipping into a light fluid. The second improvement is the construction of
an Euler-like flow on each edge of the mesh to count for the &quot;edge-bending&quot;
effect, so as to mitigate the &quot;checkerboard&quot; oscillation that commonly exists
in Lagrangian simulations, especially the triangular mesh based simulations.
Several typical hydrodynamic problems are simulated by the improved staggered
grid Lagrangian hydrodynamic method to test its performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02030</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>Kelvin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is QBism the Future of Quantum Physics?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Review of Hans Christian von Baeyer's 'QBism: The Future of Quantum
  Physics' [2016] Published in Quantum Times book reviews:
  http://thequantumtimes.org/2017/07/is-qbism-the-future-of-quantum-physics/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this book is to explain Quantum Bayesianism ('QBism') to
&quot;people without easy access to mathematical formulas and equations&quot; (4-5).
Qbism is an interpretation of quantum mechanics that &quot;doesn't meddle with the
technical aspects of the theory [but instead] reinterprets the fundamental
terms of the theory and gives them new meaning&quot; (3). The most important
motivation for QBism, enthusiastically stated on the book's cover, is that
QBism provides &quot;a way past quantum theory's paradoxes and puzzles&quot; such that
much of the weirdness associated with quantum theory &quot;dissolves under the lens
of QBism&quot;.
  Could a non-technical book that almost fits in your pocket really succeed in
resolving the notorious paradoxes of quantum theory? I believe the answer is:
not in this case. There are three primary reasons. Firstly, the argument that
QBism solves quantum paradoxes is not convincing. Secondly, it proves difficult
to pin down exactly what QBism says. Thirdly, as a scientific theory QBism
seems explanatorily inert, which is maybe why the topic of scientific
explanation is not broached. Sections 2-4 below discuss each of these problems
in turn. However, there is still a wealth of insights that make this book a
worthwhile read, and I shall begin with those.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02042</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Lian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Luis C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ge</keyname><forenames>Junqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaaret</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Shude</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>PHL 6625: A Minor Merger-Associated QSO Behind NGC 247</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>ApJ to appear</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal, Volume 841, Issue 2, 118 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa72f3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PHL 6625 is a luminous quasi-stellar object (QSO) at z = 0.3954 located
behind the nearby galaxy NGC 247 (z = 0.0005). Hubble Space Telescope (HST)
observations revealed an arc structure associated with it. We report on
spectroscopic observations with the Very Large Telescope (VLT) and
multiwavelength observations from the radio to the X-ray band for the system,
suggesting that PHL 6625 and the arc are a close pair of merging galaxies,
instead of a strong gravitational lens system. The QSO host galaxy is estimated
to be (4-28) x 10^10 M_sun, and the mass of the companion galaxy of is
estimated to be M_* = (6.8 +/- 2.4) x 10^9 M_sun, suggesting that this is a
minor merger system. The QSO displays typical broad emission lines, from which
a black hole mass of about (2-5) x 10^8 M_sun and an Eddington ratio of about
0.01-0.05 can be inferred. The system represents an interesting and rare case
where a QSO is associated with an ongoing minor merger, analogous to Arp 142.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02086</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lerner</keyname><forenames>Edan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasilocalized states of self stress in packing-derived networks</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  States of self stress (SSS) are assignments of forces on the edges of a
network that satisfy mechanical equilibrium in the absence of external forces.
In this work we show that a particular class of quasilocalized SSS in
packing-derived networks, first introduced in [D. M. Sussman, C. P. Goodrich,
and A. J. Liu, Soft Matter 12, 3982 (2016)], are characterized by a lengthscale
$\ell_c$ that scales as $1/\sqrt{z_c-z}$ where $z$ is the mean connectivity of
the network, and $z_c\!\equiv\!4$ is the Maxwell threshold in two dimensions,
at odds with previous claims. Our results verify the previously proposed
analogy between quasilocalized SSS and the mechanical response to a local
dipolar force in random networks of relaxed Hookean springs. We show that the
normalization factor that distinguishes between quasilocalized SSS and the
response to a local dipole constitutes a measure of the mechanical coupling of
the forced spring to the elastic network in which it is embedded. We further
demonstrate that the lengthscale that characterizes quasilocalized SSS does not
depend on its associated degree of mechanical coupling, but instead only on the
network connectivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02089</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Serrier-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Lise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Cl&#xe9;cio C. de Souza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timmermans</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van de Vondel</keyname><forenames>Joris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moshchalkov</keyname><forenames>Victor V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stick-slip Phenomena and Memory Effects in Moving Vortex Matter</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Manipulating vortices in non-conventional superconductors is nowadays a
challenging path toward controlling functionalities for superconducting
nanodevices. Here, we directly observe and control single vortex core
trajectories with unmatched resolution using a new scanning tunneling
spectroscopy at very low temperature. Our data show the depinning threshold of
a Bragg-glass in a weakly disordered superconductor, a clean 2H-NbSe2 crystal.
We first experimentally capture the linear and collective response, the
Campbell regime. Upon strong drives, the oscillating trajectories perform a
series of stick-slip motions that mimics the lattice periodicity. We then
theoretically elucidate this peculiar non-linear regime by solving the Langevin
dynamics equations. We additionally explore the impact of initial conditions
and reveal an enhancement of the long-range correlations with the cooling
procedure. Finally, our work establishes a connection between theory of vortex
pinning, memory effects and vortex lineshapes, thus offering a new platform to
investigate the relationship between viscous media and individual controllable
objects in any many-body systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02094</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lodahl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-dot based photonic quantum networks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum dots embedded in photonic nanostructures have in recent years proven
to be a very powerful solid-state platform for quantum optics experiments. The
combination of near-unity radiative coupling of a single quantum dot to a
photonic mode and the ability to eliminate decoherence processes imply that an
unprecedented light-matter interface can be obtained. As a result,
high-cooperativity photon-emitter quantum interfaces can be constructed opening
a path-way to deterministic photonic quantum gates for quantum-information
processing applications. In the present manuscript, I review current
state-of-the-art on quantum dot devices and their applications for quantum
technology. The overarching long-term goal of the research field is to
construct photonic quantum networks where remote entanglement can be
distributed over long distances by photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02103</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02103</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Acevedo-Malav&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamics interactions of clusters of drops: a study of the
  coalescence phenomena with the finite volume method</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work has been proposed a numerical scheme with the aim of simulate
the coalescence process between water drops immersed in a continuous phase
(n-heptane). This numerical scheme is based in the Finite Volume method and two
different values for the initial velocity of the drops were chosen. Depending
of the initial velocity of collision some scenarios emerge, such as: permanent
coalescence, formation of satellite drops etc. For some snap shots the
streamlines are calculated for the different process of permanent coalescence.
These streamlines allow the understanding of the dynamics of the droplets
immersed on the n-heptane phase. The model used for the surface tension is
presented and its effects on the dynamics of coalescence of the droplets are
showed, which after some time tends to the spherical form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02105</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Acevedo-Malav&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamics calculations of clusters of drops using the finite volume
  method</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper is described a numerical scheme that is used to simulate the
coalescence process between clusters of water drops immersed in a continuous
hydrocarbon phase (n-heptane). Two different values for the initial velocity of
the drops were chosen. Depending of the initial velocity of collision some
scenarios emerge, such as: permanent coalescence, formation of satellite drops
etc. For some snap shots the streamlines are calculated for the different
process of permanent coalescence. These streamlines allow the understanding of
the dynamics of the droplets immersed on the n-heptane phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02107</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lazio</keyname><forenames>T. Joseph W.</forenames><affiliation>JPL, CIT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wolszczan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Penn. State Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;del</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Vienna</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Osten</keyname><forenames>Rachel A.</forenames><affiliation>STScI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Forbrich</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Vienna</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jardine</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. St. Andrews</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>P. K. G.</forenames><affiliation>CfA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Radio Exploration of Planetary Habitability: Conference Summary</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Five pages; conference Web site:
  http://aas.org/meetings/aastcs/radiohab</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Radio Exploration of Planetary Habitability was the fifth in the series of
American Astronomical Society's Topical Conference Series. Notable aspects of
the conference included the interdisciplinary nature of both the topics and the
intellectual breadth of the participants, the diversity of approaches to
studying this topic presented by recent discoveries and of the participants
themselves, the expanding meaning of the topic of &quot;star-planet interactions,&quot;
and the expectation of an increasingly statistical approach to the topic.
Potential areas of future research include the actual extent to which planetary
magnetic fields shield planetary atmospheres; the planetary dynamo process
itself, particularly once multiple extrasolar planetary magnetic fields are
confirmed; and &quot;planet-star interactions.&quot; A major major topic of the
conference concerned observational opportunities, highlighted by a number of
new or upcoming, specialized observatories to observe exoplanets especially at
radio wavelengths. This article summarizes these main points of the conference
and expands briefly upon these potential avenues for future investigation. A
future meeting on this topic, given the variety of data sets being generated
over the next few years, is warranted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02114</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Morini</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flandrin</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleury</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venturini</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jensen</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author></authors><title>Revealing evolutions in dynamical networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The description of large temporal graphs requires effective methods giving an
appropriate mesoscopic partition. Many approaches exist today to detect
communities in static graphs. However, many networks are intrinsically
dynamical, and need a dynamic mesoscale description, as interpreting them as
static networks would cause loss of important information. For example, dynamic
processes such as the emergence of new scientific disciplines, their fusion,
split or death need a mesoscopic description of the evolving network of
scientific articles. There are two straightforward approaches to describe an
evolving network using methods developed for static networks.
  The first finds the community structure of the aggregated network; however,
this approach discards most temporal information, and may lead to inappropriate
descriptions, as very different dynamic data can give rise to the identical
static graphs.
  The opposite approach closely follows the evolutions and builds networks for
successive time slices by selecting the relevant nodes and edges, the
mesoscopic structure of each of these slices is found independently and the
structures are connected to obtain a temporal description. By using an optimal
structural description at each time slice, this method avoids the inertia of
the aggregated approach. The inherent fuzziness of the communities leads to
noise and artifacts.
  Here, we present an approach that distinguishes real trends and noise in the
mesoscopic description of data using the continuity of social evolutions. To be
follow the dynamics, we compute partitions for each time slice, but to avoid
transients generated by noise, we modify the community description at time t
using the structures found at times t-1 and t+1. We show the relevance of our
method on the analysis of a scientific network showing the birth of a new
subfield, wavelet analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02135</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Rath</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandra</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raina</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dixit</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-tensor decomposition of nuclear transition matrix elements for
  neutrinoless double-$\beta $ decay of $^{76}$Ge and $^{82}$Se nuclei within
  PHFB approach</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Employing the PHFB model, nuclear transition matrix elements $M^{\left(
K\right) }$ for the neutrinoless double-$\beta^{-} $ decay of $\ ^{76}$Ge and
$^{82}$Se isotopes are calculated within mechanisms involving light as well as
heavy Majorana neutrinos, and classical Majorons by considering the spin-tensor
decomposition of realistic KUO and empirical JUN45 effective two-body
interaction. It is noticed that the effects due to the SRC on NTMEs $M^{\left(
0\nu \right) }$ and $M^{\left( 0N\right) }$ due to the exchange of light and
heavy Majorana neutrinos, respectively, is maximally incorporated by the
central part of the effective two-body interaction, which varies by a small
amount with the inclusion of spin-orbit and tensor components. The maximum
uncertainty in the average NTMEs $\overline{M}^{(0\nu)}$ and
$\overline{M}^{(0N)}$ turns out to be about 10\% and 37\%, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02138</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Koumakis</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurati</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mutch</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdellali</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schofield</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egelhaaf</keyname><forenames>S. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brady</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petekidis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Start-up Shear of Concentrated Colloidal Hard Spheres: Stresses,
  Dynamics and Structure</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>J. Rheol. 60, 603 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1122/1.4949340</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transient response of model hard sphere glasses is examined during the
application of steady rate start-up shear using Brownian Dynamics (BD)
simulations, experimental rheology and confocal microscopy. With increasing
strain the glass initially exhibits an almost linear elastic stress increase, a
stress peak at the yield point and then reaches a constant steady state. The
stress overshoot has a non-monotonic dependence with Peclet number, Pe, and
volume fraction, {\phi}, determined by the available free volume and a
competition between structural relaxation and shear advection. Examination of
the structural properties under shear revealed an increasing anisotropic radial
distribution function, g(r), mostly in the velocity - gradient (xy) plane,
which decreases after the stress peak with considerable anisotropy remaining in
the steady-state. Low rates minimally distort the structure, while high rates
show distortion with signatures of transient elongation. As a mechanism of
storing energy, particles are trapped within a cage distorted more than
Brownian relaxation allows, while at larger strains, stresses are relaxed as
particles are forced out of the cage due to advection. Even in the steady
state, intermediate super diffusion is observed at high rates and is a
signature of the continuous breaking and reformation of cages under shear.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02142</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02142</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Yates</keyname><forenames>Stephen J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baryshev</keyname><forenames>Andrey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurduseven</keyname><forenames>Ozan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bueno</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Kristina K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>Lorenza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jellema</keyname><forenames>Willem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llombart</keyname><forenames>Nuria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murugesan</keyname><forenames>Vignesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thoen</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baselmans</keyname><forenames>Jochem J. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface wave control for large arrays of microwave kinetic inductance
  detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>accepted for publication in IEEE Transactions on Terahertz Science
  and Technology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large ultra-sensitive detector arrays are needed for present and future
observatories for far infra-red, submillimeter wave (THz), and millimeter wave
astronomy. With increasing array size, it is increasingly important to control
stray radiation inside the detector chips themselves, the surface wave. We
demonstrate this effect with focal plane arrays of 880 lens-antenna coupled
Microwave Kinetic Inductance Detectors (MKIDs). Presented here are near field
measurements of the MKID optical response versus the position on the array of a
reimaged optical source. We demonstrate that the optical response of a detector
in these arrays saturates off-pixel at the $\sim-30$ dB level compared to the
peak pixel response. The result is that the power detected from a point source
at the pixel position is almost identical to the stray response integrated over
the chip area. With such a contribution, it would be impossible to measure
extended sources, while the point source sensitivity is degraded due to an
increase of the stray loading. However, we show that by incorporating an
on-chip stray light absorber, the surface wave contribution is reduced by a
factor $&gt;$10. With the on-chip stray light absorber the point source response
is close to simulations down to the $\sim-35$ dB level, the simulation based on
an ideal Gaussian illumination of the optics. In addition, as a crosscheck we
show that the extended source response of a single pixel in the array with the
absorbing grid is in agreement with the integral of the point source
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02143</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dove</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trachenko</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>Yu. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brazhkin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supercritical Gr\&quot;uneisen parameter and its universality at the Frenkel
  line</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review E 96, 012107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study thermo-mechanical properties of matter at extreme conditions deep in
the supercritical state, at temperatures exceeding the critical one up to four
orders of magnitude. We calculate the Gr\&quot;{u}neisen parameter {\gamma} and find
that it decreases with temperature from 3 to 1 on isochores depending on the
density. Our results indicate that from the perspective of thermo-mechanical
properties, the supercritical state is characterized by the wide range of
{\gamma} which includes the solid-like values - an interesting finding in view
of the common perception of the supercritical state as being an intermediate
state between gases and liquids. We rationalize this result by considering the
relative weights of oscillatory and diffusive components of the supercritical
system below the Frenkel line. We also find that {\gamma} is nearly constant at
the Frenkel line above the critical point and explain this universality in
terms of pressure and temperature scaling of system properties along the lines
where particle dynamics changes qualitatively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02145</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Dean-Ben</keyname><forenames>Xose Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Razansky</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization optoacoustic tomography</title><categories>physics.optics physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Localization-based imaging has revolutionized fluorescence optical microscopy
and has also enabled unprecedented ultrasound images of microvascular
structures in deep tissues. Herein, we introduce a new concept of localization
optoacoustic tomography (LOAT) that employs rapid sequential acquisition of
three-dimensional optoacoustic images from flowing absorbing particles. We show
that the new method enables breaking through the spatial resolution barrier of
acoustic diffraction while further enhancing the visibility of structures under
limited-view tomographic conditions. Given the intrinsic sensitivity of
optoacoustics to multiple hemodynamic and oxygenation parameters, LOAT may
enable new level of performance in studying functional and anatomical
alterations of microcirculation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02160</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>TOPCAT: Desktop Exploration of Tabular Data for Astronomy and Beyond</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures, journal special issue on Scalable Interactive
  Visualization</comments><journal-ref>Informatics, 4(3), 18 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/informatics4030018</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  TOPCAT, the Tool for OPerations on Catalogues And Tables, is an interactive
desktop application for retrieval, analysis and manipulation of tabular data,
offering a powerful and flexible range of interactive visualization options
amongst other features. Its visualization capabilities focus on enabling
interactive exploration of large static local tables - millions of rows and
hundreds of columns can easily be handled on a standard desktop or laptop
machine, and various options are provided for meaningful graphical
representation of such large datasets. TOPCAT has been developed in the context
of astronomy, but many of its features are equally applicable to other domains.
The software, which is free and open source, is written in Java, and the
underlying high-performance visualisation library is suitable for re-use in
other applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02162</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhole</keyname><forenames>Gaurav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahesh</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rapid Exponentiation using Discrete Operators: Applications in
  Optimizing Quantum Controls and Simulating Quantum Dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Matrix exponentiation (ME) is widely used in various fields of science and
engineering. For example, the unitary dynamics of quantum systems is described
by exponentiation of Hamiltonian operators. However, despite a significant
attention, the numerical evaluation of ME remains computationally expensive,
particularly for large dimensions. Often this process becomes a bottleneck in
algorithms requiring iterative evaluation of ME. Here we propose a method for
approximating ME of a single operator with a bounded coefficient into a product
of certain discrete operators. This approach, which we refer to as Rapid
Exponentiation using Discrete Operators (REDO), is particularly efficient for
iterating ME over large numbers. We describe REDO in the context of a quantum
system with a constant as well as a time-dependent Hamiltonian, although in
principle, it can be adapted in a more general setting. As concrete examples,
we choose two applications. First, we incorporate REDO in optimal quantum
control algorithms and report a speed-up of several folds over a wide range of
system size. Secondly, we propose REDO for numerical simulations of quantum
dynamics. In particular, we study exotic quantum freezing with noisy drive
fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02168</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Vexiau</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borsalino</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lepers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orb&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aymar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dulieu</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouloufa-Maafa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic dipole polarizabilities of heteronuclear alkali dimers: optical
  response, trapping and control of ultracold molecules</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Accepted in International Reviews of Physical Chemistry</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we address the general approach for calculating dynamical
dipole polarizabilities of small quantum systems, based on a sum-over-states
formula involving in principle the entire energy spectrum of the system. We
complement this method by a few-parameter model involving a limited number of
effective transitions, allowing for a compact and accurate representation of
both the isotropic and anisotropic components of the polarizability. We apply
the method to the series of ten heteronuclear molecules composed of two of
($^7$Li,$^{23}$Na,$^{39}$K,$^{87}$Rb,$^{133}$Cs) alkali-metal atoms. We rely on
both up-to-date spectroscopically-determined potential energy curves for the
lowest electronic states, and on our systematic studies of these systems
performed during the last decade for higher excited states and for permanent
and transition dipole moments. Such a compilation is timely for the
continuously growing researches on ultracold polar molecules. Indeed the
knowledge of the dynamic dipole polarizabilities is crucial to model the
optical response of molecules when trapped in optical lattices, and to
determine optimal lattice frequencies ensuring optimal transfer to the absolute
ground state of initially weakly-bound molecules. When they exist, we determine
the so-called &quot;magic frequencies&quot; where the ac-Stark shift and thus the viewed
trap depth, is the same for both weakly-bound and ground-state molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02169</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Guccione</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>Mahdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirzaei</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slatyer</keyname><forenames>Harry J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchler</keyname><forenames>Ben C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>Ping Koy</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced photothermal cooling of nanowires</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Science and Technology, 2 (3), 034005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa7645</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the optomechanical interaction between light and metallic
nanowires through the action of bolometric forces. We show that the response
time of the photothermal forces induced on the nanowire is fast and the
strength of the interaction can overcome the radiation pressure force.
Furthermore, we suggest the photothermal forces can be enhanced by surface
plasmon excitation to cool the sub-megahertz vibrational modes of the nanowires
close to its quantum limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02177</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Potashov</keyname><forenames>M. Sh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blinnikov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Utrobin</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-Dependent Ionization in theEnvelopes of Type II Supernovae at the
  Photospheric Phase</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters 43(1) (2017) 36-49</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773717010030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The importance of allowance for the time-dependent effect in the kinetics at
the photospheric phase during a supernova explosion has been confirmed by
several independent research groups. The time-dependent effect provides a
higher degree of hydrogen ionization in comparison with the steady-state
solutions and strengthens the H$\alpha$ line in the resulting simulated
spectrum, with the intensity of the effect increasing with time. However, some
researchers argue that the time-dependent ionization effect is unimportant. Its
allowance leads to an insignificant strengthening of H$\alpha$ in their
modeling only in the first days after explosion. We have demonstrated the
importance of the time-dependent effect with the models of SN 1999em as an
example using the new original LEVELS software package. The role of a number of
factors that can weaken the time-dependent effect has been checked. We have
confirmed that the intensity of the effect is affected by the abundance of
metal admixtures in the envelope, while the addition of extra levels to
themodel hydrogen atom weakens the time-dependent effect to a lesser degree and
never removes it completely.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02185</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Unicomb</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>I&#xf1;iguez</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karsai</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rton</forenames></author></authors><title>Threshold driven contagion on weighted networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><comments>24 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weighted networks capture the structure of complex systems where interaction
strength is meaningful. This information is essential to a large number of
processes, such as threshold dynamics, where link weights reflect the amount of
influence that neighbours have in determining a node's behaviour. Despite
describing numerous cascading phenomena, such as neural firing or social
contagion, threshold models have never been explicitly addressed on weighted
networks. We fill this gap by studying a dynamical threshold model over
synthetic and real weighted networks with numerical and analytical tools. We
show that the time of cascade emergence depends non-monotonously on weight
heterogeneities, which accelerate or decelerate the dynamics, and lead to
non-trivial parameter spaces for various networks and weight distributions. Our
methodology applies to arbitrary binary state processes and link properties,
and may prove instrumental in understanding the role of edge heterogeneities in
various natural and social phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02216</id><created>2017-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Shi</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Nonsingular Solutions for the Scalar Meson Field of a Point
  Charge in General Relativity Theory</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><journal-ref>Soviet Physics JETP Vol 31, 1098-1099 (1956)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been shown that in investigating the electromagnetic and meson fields
of elementary particles, the effects of gravitational interaction cannot be
neglected. The present note is an attempt to find solutions to the equations of
the general relativistic gravitational and scalar meson fields of a point
nuclear charge. The solution is nonsingular at all points of the gravitational
and meson fields. Although it contains several functions whose form is not
given, this solution can be used to obtain the potential of the scalar meson
field, which is a generalization of the Yukawa potential; furthermore, it makes
it possible to calculate the mass and self-energy of the nucleon, which turn
out to be finite.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02217</id><created>2017-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Shi</forenames></author></authors><title>General Covariant Equations for Fields of Arbitrary Spin</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages. The general covariant field equations for arbitrary spin
  were obtained In this paper. This is the foundation for a gauge theory of
  gravitation. Therefore, this work is one of the earliest references to
  explore gauge theories of gravitation</comments><journal-ref>Soviet Physics JETP Vol 34(7), 632-636 (1958)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To obtain a generalized wave equation for a field in general covariant form,
one must define covariant differentiation of a generalized wave function
describing particles with arbitrary spin. Gel'fand and Iaglom, Dirac, and Fierz
and Pauli have studied the generalized wave equation in the special theory of
relativity. In this paper, the Gel'fand-Iaglom field equation was generalized
to the curved space based on the veilbein framework. The general covariant
field equations for arbitrary spin were obtained. More importantly, in this
work, we introduced the gauge covariant derivative with the local Lorentz
transformation, which is the foundation for a gauge theory of gravitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02220</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Morarka</keyname><forenames>Amit R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Aditee C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattered light intensity measurements of plasma treated
  Polydimethylsiloxane films: A measure to detect surface modification</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>there are 10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polydimethylsiloxane (PDMS) films possess different chemical and physical
properties based on surface modification. The bond structure of pristine PDMS
films and plasma treated PDMS films differ in a particular region of silicate
bonds. We have studied the surface physical properties of pristine PDMS films
and plasma treated PDMS films through optical technique. It is already known
that plasma treated PDMS films forms very thin SiO2 layer on its surface. Due
to difference in coefficient of thermal expansion of the surface SiO2 and the
remaining bulk layer, the SiO2 layer develops cracks. These formations are
explored to characterize PDMS surface by observing intensity of scattered light
while the films are stretched. Pristine PDMS films do not show such optical
scattering. Further the intensity measurements were repeated over period of
time to monitor surface properties with time. It was observed that plasma
treated PDMS film; the scattered light intensity is linearly dependent on the
applied force for stretching. After a substantial time, scattering intensity is
reduced to the value which is almost equal to that of pristine PDMS surface. It
is proposed that basic light scattering through plasma treated PDMS occurs due
to the decrease in the width of the cracks when the PDMS film is stretched. The
change in the scattering property of plasma treated PDMS surface over time
could be attributed to healing of cracks by the migration of polymer chain
molecules from the bulk to the surface. It is also reported that with reference
to various bonds present on surface plasma treated PDMS surface regains its
original properties as that of pristine PDMS with time. Therefore the optical
technique could be employed to study surface characteristics of PDMS surface as
an alternative approach to conventional spectroscopic techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02223</id><created>2017-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Rakotoson</keyname><forenames>Hanitriarivo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andriambololona</keyname><forenames>Raoelina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranaivoson</keyname><forenames>Ravo Tokiniaina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roland</keyname><forenames>Raboanary</forenames></author></authors><title>Coordinate, Momentum and Dispersion operators in Phase space
  representation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to present a study on the representations of
coordinate, momentum and dispersion operators in the framework of a phase space
representation of quantum mechanics that we have introduced and studied in
previous works. We begin in the introduction section with a recall about the
concept of representation of operators on wave function spaces. Then, we show
that in the case of the phase space representation the coordinate and momentum
operators can be represented either with differential operators or with
matrices. The explicit expressions of both the differential operators and
matrices representations are established. Multidimensional generalization of
the obtained results are performed and phase space representation of dispersion
operators are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02248</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Bourdin</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzotta</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozmanyan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vikhlinin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure profiles of distant galaxy clusters in the Planck catalog</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 843, 72 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa74d0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Successive releases of Planck data have demonstrated the strength of the
Sunyaev--Zeldovich (SZ) effect in detecting hot baryons out to the galaxy
cluster peripheries. To infer the hot gas pressure structure from nearby galaxy
clusters to more distant objects, we developed a parametric method that models
the spectral energy distribution and spatial anisotropies of both the Galactic
thermal dust and the Cosmic Microwave Background, that are mixed-up with the
cluster SZ and dust signals. Taking advantage of the best angular resolution of
the High Frequency Instrument channels (5 arcmin) and using X-ray priors in the
innermost cluster regions that are not resolved with Planck, this modelling
allowed us to analyze a sample of 61 nearby members of the Planck catalog of SZ
sources ($0 &lt; z &lt; 0.5$, $\tilde{z} = 0.15$) using the full mission data, as
well as to examine a distant sample of 23 clusters ($0.5 &lt; z &lt; 1$, $\tilde{z} =
0.56$) that have been recently followed-up with XMM-Newton and Chandra
observations. We find that (i) the average shape of the mass-scaled pressure
profiles agrees with results obtained by the Planck collaboration in the nearby
cluster sample, and that (ii) no sign of evolution is discernible between
averaged pressure profiles of the low- and high-redshift cluster samples. In
line with theoretical predictions for these halo masses and redshift ranges,
the dispersion of individual profiles relative to a self-similar shape stays
well below 10 % inside $r_{500}$ but increases in the cluster outskirts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02269</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Krejcirik</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotoreichik</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimisation of the lowest Robin eigenvalue in the exterior of a compact
  set, II: non-convex domains and higher dimensions</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP math.OC</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of geometric optimisation of the lowest eigenvalue of
the Laplacian in the exterior of a compact set in any dimension, subject to
attractive Robin boundary conditions.
  As an improvement upon our previous work (arXiv:1608.04896, to appear in J.
Convex Anal.), we show that under either a constraint of fixed perimeter or
area, the maximiser within the class of exteriors of simply connected planar
sets is always the exterior of a disk, without the need of convexity
assumption. Moreover, we generalise the result to disconnected compact planar
sets. Namely, we prove that under a constraint of fixed average value of the
perimeter over all the connected components, the maximiser within the class of
disconnected compact planar sets, consisting of finitely many simply connected
components, is again a disk.
  In higher dimensions, we prove a completely new result that the lowest point
in the spectrum is maximised by the exterior of a ball among all sets exterior
to bounded convex sets satisfying a constraint on the integral of a dimensional
power of the mean curvature of their boundaries. Furthermore, it follows that
the critical coupling at which the lowest point in the spectrum becomes a
discrete eigenvalue emerging from the essential spectrum is minimised under the
same constraint by the critical coupling for the exterior of a ball.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02281</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Strasser</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Abelian sandpiles and algebraic models</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the coincidence of topological entropies the connection between
abelian sandpiles and harmonic models was established by K. Schmidt and E.
Verbitskiy (2009). The dissipative sandpile models were shown to be symbolic
representations of algebraic $Z^d$-actions of the harmonic models. Both models
are determined by so-called simple sandpile polynomials. We extend this result
to arbitrary sandpile polynomials. Moreover, we show that any sandpile model
determined by a factor of a sandpile polynomial acts as an equal entropy cover
of the corresponding algebraic model. For a special class of factors these
covers are shown to be symbolic representations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0612042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0612042</id><created>2006-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Zhiguo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Hang</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum dynamics of the dissipative two-state system coupled with a
  sub-Ohmic bath</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26pages,13figures,submitted to Phys. Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>PhysRevB.75.054302 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.75.054302</doi><abstract>  The decoherence of a two-state system coupled with a sub-Ohmic bath is
investigated theoretically by means of the perturbation approach based on a
unitary transformation. It is shown that the decoherence depends strongly and
sensitively on the structure of environment. Nonadiabatic effect is treated
through the introduction of a function $\xi_k$ which depends on the boson
frequency and renormalized tunneling. The results are as follows:(1) the
non-equilibrium correlation function $P(t)$, the dynamical susceptibility
$\chi''(\omega)$ and the equilibrium correlation function $C(t)$ are
analytically obtained for $s\leq 1$; (2) the phase diagram of thermodynamic
transition shows the delocalized-localized transition point $\alpha_l$ which
agrees with exact results and numerical data from the Numerical Renormalization
Group; (3) the dynamical transition point $\alpha_c$ between coherent and
incoherent phase is explicitly given for the first time. A crossover from the
coherent oscillation to incoherent relaxation appears with increasing coupling
(for $\alpha &gt; \alpha_c $, the coherent dynamics disappear); (4) the Shiba's
relation and sum rule are exactly satisfied when $\alpha \leq \alpha_c $; (5)
an underdamping-overdamping transition point $\alpha_c^{*}$ exists in the
function $S(\omega)$. Consequently, the dynamical phase diagrams in both ohmic
and sub-Ohmic case are mapped out. For $\Delta \ll \omega_c$, the critical
couplings ($\alpha_l, \alpha_c$ and $\alpha_c^{*}$) are proportional to
$\Delta^{1-s}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
