<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:31:34Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-20" from="2017-07-20" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0707.4025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0707.4025</id><created>2007-07-26</created><updated>2017-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Danehkar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Cohomological Derivation of Yang-Mills Theory in the Antifield
  Formalism</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, few typos corrected, final version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP Grav.Cosmol.3:368-387,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jhepgc.2017.32031</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a brief review of the cohomological solutions of self-coupling
interactions of the fields in the free Yang-Mills theory. All consistent
interactions among the fields have been obtained using the antifield formalism
through several order BRST deformations of the master equation. It is found
that the coupling deformations halt exclusively at the second order, whereas
higher order deformations are obstructed due to non-local interactions. The
results demonstrate the BRST cohomological derivation of the interacting
Yang-Mills theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.5505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.5505</id><created>2013-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Sangeetha</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamizhavel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomy</keyname><forenames>C. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Saurabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awasthi</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramakrishnan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple charge density wave transitions in Lu_{2} Ir_{3} Si_{5} single
  crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 91, 205131 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.205131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physical properties of the single-crystalline samples of Lu_{2} Ir_{3}
Si_{5} have been investigated by magnetic susceptibility, resistivity and heat
capacity studies. We observed multiple charge density wave (CDW) transitions in
all the measurements. A strong thermal hysteresis at these transitions suggests
a possible first order CDW ordering. In addition, the first order nature is
ascertained by a very narrow and a huge cusp (62 J/mol K) in the zero field
specific heat data which also suggests a strong interchain coupling. By
applying a field of 9T in the specific heat measurement, one of the CDW
transitions is suppressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00943</id><created>2015-01-05</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Purvine</keyname><forenames>Emilie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotilla-Sanchez</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halappanavar</keyname><forenames>Mahantesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Zhenyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shaobu</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparative Study of Clustering Techniques for Real-Time Dynamic Model
  Reduction</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SY</categories><comments>Statistical Analysis and Data Mining, in press, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamic model reduction in power systems is necessary for improving
computational efficiency. Traditional model reduction using linearized models
or online analysis is not adequate to capture dynamic behaviors of the power
system, especially with the new mix of intermittent generation and intelligent
consumption making the power system more dynamic and non-linear. Real-time
dynamic model reduction has emerged to fill this important need. This paper
explores using clustering techniques to analyze real-time phasor measurements
to identify groups of generators with similar behavior, as well as a
representative generator from each group for dynamic model reduction. Two
clustering techniques -- graph clustering and k-means -- are considered. These
techniques are compared with a previously developed dynamic model reduction
approach using Singular Value Decomposition. Two sample power grid data sets
are used to test these different model reduction techniques. Based on the
algorithms' relative performance, recommendations are provided for practical
use.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01957</id><created>2015-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>An.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popolitov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix model and dimensions at hypercube vertices</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.GT math.MP</categories><comments>37 pages</comments><report-no>IITP/TH-09/15</report-no><journal-ref>Theoretical and Mathematical Physics, 192 (1) (2017) 1039-1079</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S004057791707008X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In hypercube approach to correlation functions in Chern-Simons theory (knot
polynomials) the central role is played by the numbers of cycles, in which the
link diagram is decomposed under different resolutions. Certain functions of
these numbers are further interpreted as dimensions of graded spaces,
associated with hypercube vertices. Finding these functions is, however, a
somewhat non-trivial problem. In arXiv:1506.07516 it was suggested to solve it
with the help of the matrix model technique, in the spirit of AMM/EO
topological recursion. In this paper we further elaborate on this idea and
provide a vast collection of non-trivial examples, related both to ordinary and
virtual links and knots. Remarkably, most powerful versions of the formalism
freely convert ordinary knots/links to virtual and back -- moreover, go beyond
the knot-related set of the (2,2)-valent graphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02084</id><created>2015-08-09</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saidy-Sarjoubi</keyname><forenames>Maryam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamani</keyname><forenames>Davoud</forenames></author></authors><title>Moving Fractional Branes with Background Fields: Interaction and Tachyon
  Condensation</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, no figure, Latex2e</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 046003 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.046003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the bosonic boundary state corresponding to a moving fractional
D$p$-brane in a partially orbifoldized spacetime $\mathbb{R}^{1, d-5}
\times\mathbb{C}^{2}/\mathbb{Z}_{2}$ in the presence of the Kalb-Ramond field,
the $U(1)$ gauge potential and the tachyon field. Using this boundary state we
obtain interaction amplitude of two parallel moving D$p$-branes with the above
background fields. Various properties of the interaction will be investigated.
Besides, we study effects of the tachyon condensation on a moving fractional
D$p$-brane with the above background fields through the boundary state
formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03644</id><created>2015-12-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gontchar</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames><affiliation>Omsk State Transport University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chushnyakova</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames><affiliation>Omsk State Technical University, Tomsk Polytechnic University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Thermal decay rate of a metastable state with two degrees of freedom:
  dynamical modeling versus approximate analytical formula</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Pramana J. Physics 88 (2017) 90</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12043-017-1410-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accuracy of the Kramers approximate formula for the thermal decay rate of the
metastable state is studied for the two-dimensional potential pocket. This is
done by the comparison with the quasistationary rate resulting from the
dynamical modeling. It is shown that the Kramers rate is in agreement with the
quasistationary rate within the statistical errors provided the absorptive
border is far enough from the potential ridge restricting the metastable state.
As the absorptive border (or its part) gets closer to the ridge the Kramers
formula underestimate the quasistationary rate. The difference reaches
approximately the factor of 2 when the absorptive border coincides with the
ridge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06542</id><created>2016-02-21</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caputa</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Numasawa</keyname><forenames>Tokiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veliz-Osorio</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Scrambling without chaos in RCFT</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>Minor typographical error corrected. Matches published version</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2016-6, YITP-16-10</report-no><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2016) 113B06</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate measures of chaos and entanglement in rational
conformal field theories in 1+1 dimensions. First, we derive a universal
formula for the late time value of the out-of-time-ordered correlators for this
class of theories. Our universal result can be expressed as a particular
combination of the modular S-matrix elements known as the anyon monodromy
scalar. Next, in the explicit setup of a $SU(N)_k$ Wess-Zumino-Witten model, we
compare the late time behavior of the out-of-time-ordered correlators and the
purity. Interestingly, in the large-c limit, the purity grows logarithmically
as in holographic theories; in contrast, the out-of-time-ordered correlators
remain, in general, non-vanishing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00899</id><created>2016-02-28</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ogilvie</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave mechanics of the hydrogen atom</title><categories>physics.gen-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, one figure and 26 cited papers</comments><journal-ref>Revista de Ciencia y Tecnologia (UCR) 32 (1), 1 - 24, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The hydrogen atom is a system amenable to an exact treatment within
Schroedinger's formulation of quantum mechanics according to coordinates in
four systems -- spherical polar, paraboloidal, ellipsoidal and spheroconical
coordinates; the latter solution is reported for the first time. Applications
of these solutions include angular momenta, a quantitative calculation of the
absorption spectrum and accurate plots of surfaces of amplitude functions. The
shape of an amplitude function, and even the quantum numbers in a particular
set to specify such an individual function, depend on the coordinates in a
particular chosen system, and are therefore artefacts of that particular
coordinate representation within wave mechanics. All discussion of atomic or
molecular properties based on such shapes or quantum numbers therefore lacks
general significance
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05527</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>O'Naraigh</keyname><forenames>Lennon</forenames></author></authors><title>Advection of nematic liquid crystals by chaotic flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>28 pages, 17 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4979528</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Consideration is given to the effects of inhomogeneous shear flow (both
regular and chaotic) on nematic liquid crystals in a planar geometry. The
Landau--de Gennes equation coupled to an externally-prescribed flow field is
the basis for the study: this is solved numerically in a periodic spatial
domain. The focus is on a limiting case where the advection is passive, such
that variations in the liquid-crystal properties do not feed back into the
equation for the fluid velocity. The main tool for analyzing the results (both
with and without flow) is the identification of the fixed points of the
dynamical equations without flow, which are relevant (to varying degrees) when
flow is introduced. The fixed points are classified as stable/unstable and
further as either uniaxial or biaxial. Accordingly, various models of passive
shear flow are investigated, with the main focus being on the case where
tumbling is absent from the model. In this scenario, not only must advection of
the $Q$-tensor be considered, but also its co-rotation relative to the local
vorticity field. Thus, only the biaxial fixed point survives as a solution of
the $Q$-tensor dynamics under the imposition of a general flow field. For
certain flows for which co-rotation effects can effectively be ignored along
trajectories, both families of fixed points survive. In this scenario, the
system exhibits coarsening arrest, whereby the liquid-crystal domains are
`frozen in' to the flow structures and the growth in their size is thus
limited. The outcome (biaxial final state or a mixture of both families of
fixed points) can be understood in terms of the flow time- and length-scales
that manifest themselves through the co-rotational derivative. Some
consideration is also given to the specific case where tumbling is present;
here, the flow has a strong effect on the liquid-crystal morphology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06024</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Boris O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic Levy Differential Operators and Yang-Mills Equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>70S15, 81S25</msc-class><journal-ref>Infin. Dimens. Anal. Quantum Probab. Relat. Top., 20:2 (2017),
  1750008</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219025717500084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relationship between the Yang-Mills equations and the stochastic analogue
of Levy differential operators is studied. The value of the stochastic Levy
Laplacian is found by means of Cesaro averaging of directional derivatives on
the stochastic parallel transport. It is shown that the Yang-Mills equations
and the Levy-Laplace equation for such Laplacian are not equivalent as in the
deterministic case. An equation equivalent to the Yang-Mills equations is
obtained. The equation contains the stochastic Levy divergence. It is proved
that the Yang-Mills action functional can be represented as an
infinite-dimensional analogue of the Direchlet functional of chiral field. This
analogue is also derived using Cesaro averaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07306</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe4;htz</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dur&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Orencio</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluid forces or impacts: What governs the entrainment of soil particles
  in sediment transport mediated by a Newtonian fluid?</title><categories>physics.geo-ph cond-mat.soft physics.ao-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Fluids 2 (7), 074303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.2.074303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In steady sediment transport, sediment deposition is balanced by entrainment
of bed particles by fluid forces or particle-bed impacts. Here we propose a
proxy to determine the role of impact entrainment relative to entrainment by
the mean turbulent flow: the &quot;bed velocity&quot; $V_b$, which is an effective
near-bed-surface value of the average horizontal particle velocity that
generalizes the classical slip velocity, used in studies of aeolian saltation
transport, to sediment transport in an arbitrary Newtonian fluid. We study
$V_b$ for a wide range of the particle-fluid-density ratio $s$, Galileo number
$\mathrm{Ga}$, and Shields number $\Theta$ using direct sediment transport
simulations. We find that transport is fully sustained through impact
entrainment (i.e., $V_b$ is constant in natural units) when the &quot;impact number&quot;
$\mathrm{Im}=\mathrm{Ga}\sqrt{s+0.5}\gtrsim20$ or $\Theta\gtrsim5/\mathrm{Im}$.
These conditions are obeyed for the vast majority of transport regimes,
including steady turbulent bedload, which has long been thought to be sustained
solely through fluid entrainment. In fact, we find that transport is fully
sustained through fluid entrainment (i.e., $V_b$ scales with the near-bed
horizontal fluid velocity) only for sufficiently viscous bedload transport at
grain scale (i.e., for $\mathrm{Im}\lesssim20$ and
$\Theta\lesssim1/\mathrm{Im}$). Finally, we do not find a strong correlation
between, $V_b$, or the classical slip velocity, and the
transport-layer-averaged horizontal particle velocity $\overline{v_x}$, which
challenges the long-standing consensus that predominant impact entrainment is
responsible for a linear scaling of the transport rate with $\Theta$. For
turbulent bedload in particular, $\overline{v_x}$ increases with $\Theta$
despite $V_b$ remaining constant, which we propose is linked to the formation
of a liquid-like bed on top of the static-bed surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09626</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-07-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yumisaki</keyname><forenames>Hikaru</forenames></author></authors><title>Several solutions of the Klein-Gordon equation in Kerr-Newman spacetime
  and the BSW effect</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>44 pages, errors corrected</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2017) 063B04</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptx075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the radial part of the charged massive Klein-Gordon equation
in Kerr-Newman spacetime, and in several specific situations, obtain exact
solutions by means of essentially hypergeometric functions or their confluent
types. Using these global solutions and generally obtained local solutions, we
calculate a sort of intensity of the collision of two field excitations, which
is a slight generalization of the trace of the stress tensor. We find that when
the black hole is nonextremal, the intensity of the collision of two ingoing
modes is bounded. However, in the extremal limit, more precisely $\hbar
\kappa_H \rightarrow 0$, the upper bound grows so that when the frequency of
one of the two modes satisfies the critical relation, the intensity of the
collision at the horizon becomes unboundedly large. Furthermore, the intensity
of the collision of ingoing and outgoing modes is always unbounded, as well as
in the classical particle theory. Our results suggest that the BSW effect is
inherited by the quantum theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06724</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Matthew G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Unified Perspective of Complex Band Structure: Interpretations,
  Formulations, and Applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>50 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter, 29, 053001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/29/5/053001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex band structure generalizes conventional band structure by also
considering wavevectors with complex components. In this way, complex band
structure describes both the bulk-propagating states from conventional band
structure and the evanescent states that grow or decay from one unit cell to
the next. Even though these latter states are excluded by translational
symmetry, they become important when translational symmetry is broken via, for
example, a surface or impurity.
  Many studies over the last 80 years have directly or indirectly developed
complex band structure for an impressive range of applications, but very few
discuss its fundamentals or compare its various results. In this work we build
upon these previous efforts to expose the physical foundation of complex band
structure, which mathematically implies the existence of complex band
structure. We find that a material's static and dynamic electronic structure
are both completely described by complex band structure. Furthermore, we show
that complex band structure reflects the minimal, intrinsic information
contained in the material's Hamiltonian. These realizations then provide a
context for discussing, comparing, and unifying the different formulations and
applications of complex band structure that have been developed over the years.
Ultimately, this discussion introduces the idea of examining the amount of
information contained in a material's Hamiltonian so that we can find and
exploit the minimal information necessary for understanding a material's
properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08017</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chavez-Angel</keyname><forenames>Emigdio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komar</keyname><forenames>Paulina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakob</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Alloy-like behaviour of the thermal conductivity of non-symmetric
  superlattices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><doi>10.1080/15567265.2017.1354106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we show a phenomenological alloy-like fit of the thermal
conductivity of (A)d1:(B)d2 superlattices with d1 /= d2, i.e. non-symmetric
structure. The presented method is a generalization of the Norbury rule of the
summation of thermal resistivities in alloy compounds. Namely, we show that
this approach can be also extended to describe the thermal properties of
crystalline and ordered-system composed by two or more elements, and, has a
potentially much wider application range. Using this approximation we estimate
that the interface thermal resistance depends on the period and the ratio of
materials that form the superlattice structure
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02330</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-12-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Weller</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urvoy</keyname><forenames>Alban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rico</keyname><forenames>Andy</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;w</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;bler</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge-induced optical bistability in thermal Rydberg vapor</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063820 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063820</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the phenomenon of optical bistability in a driven ensemble of
Rydberg atoms. By performing two experiments with thermal vapors of rubidium
and cesium, we are able to shed light onto the underlying interaction
mechanisms causing such a non-linear behavior. Due to the different properties
of these two atomic species, we conclude that the large polarizability of
Rydberg states in combination with electric fields of spontaneously ionized
Rydberg atoms is the relevant interaction mechanism. In the case of rubidium,
we directly measure the electric field in a bistable situation via two-species
spectroscopy. In cesium, we make use of the different sign of the
polarizability for different l-states and the possibility of applying electric
fields. Both these experiments allow us to rule out dipole-dipole interactions,
and support our hypothesis of a charge-induced bistability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06562</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schenkel</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zahn</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author></authors><title>Global anomalies on Lorentzian space-times</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>v2: Final version published in Annales Henri Poincare</comments><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincare 18 (2017) 2693</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-017-0590-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate an algebraic criterion for the presence of global anomalies on
globally hyperbolic space-times in the framework of locally covariant field
theory. We discuss some consequences and check that it reproduces the
well-known global $SU(2)$ anomaly in four space-time dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09258</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical ergodicity and quantum eigenstate thermalization: Analysis in
  fully connected Ising ferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012134 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the relation between the classical ergodicity and the quantum
eigenstate thermalization in the fully connected Ising ferromagnets. In the
case of spin-1/2, an expectation value of an observable in a single energy
eigenstate coincides with the long-time average in the underlying classical
dynamics, which is a consequence of the Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin
approximation. In the case of spin-1, the underlying classical dynamics is not
necessarily ergodic. In that case, it turns out that, in the thermodynamic
limit, the statistics of the expectation values of an observable in the energy
eigenstates coincides with the statistics of the long-time averages in the
underlying classical dynamics starting from random initial states sampled
uniformly from the classical phase space. This feature seems to be a general
property in semiclassical systems, and the result presented here is crucial in
discussing equilibration, thermalization, and dynamical transitions of such
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01053</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Khaydukov</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morari</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zdravkov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkel</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidlhofer</keyname><forenames>B. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Nidda</keyname><forenames>H. A. Krug</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steitz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sidorenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horn</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tidecks</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keimer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic state of Nb(1-7nm)/Cu$_{30}$Ni$_{70}$(6nm) superlattices
  revealed by Polarized Neutron Reflectometry and SQUID magnetometry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conf. Series 862 (2017) 012013</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/862/1/012013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report results of a magnetic characterization of
[Cu$_{30}$Ni$_{70}$(6nm)]$_{20}$ (x=1-7nm) superlattices using Polarized
Neutron Reflectometry (PNR) and SQUID magnetometry. The study has shown that
the magnetic moment of the structures growths almost linearly from H = 0 to
H$_{sat}$ = 1.3kOe which is an indirect evidence of antiferromagnetic (AF)
coupling of the magnetic moments in neighbouring layers. PNR, however, did not
detect any in-plane AF coupling. Taking into account the out-of-plane easy axis
of the Cu$_{30}$Ni$_{70}$ layers, this may mean that only the out-of-plane
component of the magnetic moments are AF coupled.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01948</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janson</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Zhicheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhaoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koster</keyname><forenames>Gertjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Anomalous Hall State in Ferromagnetic SrRuO$_3$ (111) Bilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 026402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.026402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SrRuO$_3$ heterostructures grown in the (111) direction are a rare example of
thin film ferromagnets. By means of density functional theory plus dynamical
mean field theory we show that the half-metallic ferromagnetic state with an
ordered magnetic moment of 2$\mu_{B}$/Ru survives the ultimate dimensional
confinement down to a bilayer, even at elevated temperatures of 500$\,$K. In
the minority channel, the spin-orbit coupling opens a gap at the linear band
crossing corresponding to $\frac34$ filling of the $t_{2g}$ shell. We
demonstrate that the respective state is Haldane's quantum anomalous Hall state
with Chern number $C$=1, without an external magnetic field or magnetic
impurities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03850</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sparre</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springel</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author></authors><title>The unorthodox evolution of major merger remnants into star-forming
  spiral galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galaxy mergers are believed to play a key role in transforming star-forming
disk galaxies into quenched ellipticals. Most of our theoretical knowledge
about such morphological transformations does, however, rely on idealised
simulations where processes such as cooling of hot halo gas into the disk and
gas accretion in the post-merger phase are not treated in a self-consistent
cosmological fashion. In this paper we study the morphological evolution of the
stellar components of four major mergers occurring at z=0.5 in cosmological
hydrodynamical zoom-simulations. In all simulations the merger reduces the disk
mass-fraction, but all galaxies simulated at our highest resolution regrow a
significant disk by z=0 (with a disk fraction larger than 24%). For runs with
our default physics model, which includes galactic winds from star formation
and black hole feedback, none of the merger remnants are quenched, but in a set
of simulations with stronger black hole feedback we find that major mergers can
indeed quench galaxies. We conclude that major merger remnants commonly evolve
into star-forming disk galaxies, unless sufficiently strong AGN feedback
assists in the quenching of the remnant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04238</id><created>2016-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Torlai</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melko</keyname><forenames>Roger G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Neural Decoder for Topological Codes</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 030501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.030501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an algorithm for error correction in topological codes that
exploits modern machine learning techniques. Our decoder is constructed from a
stochastic neural network called a Boltzmann machine, of the type extensively
used in deep learning. We provide a general prescription for the training of
the network and a decoding strategy that is applicable to a wide variety of
stabilizer codes with very little specialization. We demonstrate the neural
decoder numerically on the well-known two dimensional toric code with
phase-flip errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04507</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kassner</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Theoretische Physik, Otto-von-Guericke-Universit&#xe4;t Magdeburg, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Dust ball physics and the Schwarzschild metric</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures This is the version that has been accepted for
  publication in the American Journal of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Am. J. Phys. 85, 619 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4982785</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A physics-first derivation of the Schwarzschild metric is given. Gravitation
is described in terms of the effects of tidal forces (or of spacetime
curvature) on the volume of a small ball of test particles (a dust ball),
freely falling after all particles were at rest with respect to each other
initially. The possibility to express Einstein's equation this way and some of
its ramifications have been enjoyably discussed by Baez and Bunn [Am. J. Phys.
73, 644 (2005)]. Since the formulation avoids the use of tensors, neither
advanced tensor calculus nor sophisticated differential geometry are needed in
the calculation. The derivation is not lengthy and it has visual appeal, so it
may be useful in teaching.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05078</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Streltsov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampermann</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bru&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>Dagmar</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement distribution and quantum discord</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, contribution to &quot;Lectures on general quantum
  correlations and their applications&quot;, edited by Felipe Fanchini, Diogo
  Soares-Pinto, and Gerardo Adesso</comments><journal-ref>Fanchini F., Soares Pinto D., Adesso G. (eds) Lectures on General
  Quantum Correlations and their Applications. Quantum Science and Technology.
  Springer, Cham (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-53412-1_10</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Establishing entanglement between distant parties is one of the most
important problems of quantum technology, since long-distance entanglement is
an essential part of such fundamental tasks as quantum cryptography or quantum
teleportation. In this lecture we review basic properties of entanglement and
quantum discord, and discuss recent results on entanglement distribution and
the role of quantum discord therein. We also review entanglement distribution
with separable states, and discuss important problems which still remain open.
One such open problem is a possible advantage of indirect entanglement
distribution, when compared to direct distribution protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06405</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krutov</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troitsky</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troitsky</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The K-meson form factor and charge radius: linking low-energy data to
  future high-energy Jefferson Laboratory results</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>V2: minor clarifications, version accepted by EPJC. 13 pages, 5
  figures, EPJC style</comments><report-no>INR-TH-2016-040</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77 (2017) 464</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5038-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from a successful model of the pi-meson electromagnetic form factor,
we calculate the similar form factor, f_K(Q^2), of the charged K meson for a
wide range of the momentum transfer squared, Q^2. The only remaining free
parameter is to be determined from the measurements of the K-meson charge
radius, r_K. We fit this single parameter to the published data of the NA-7
experiment which measured f_K(Q^2) at Q^2-&gt;0 and determine our preferred range
of r_K, which happens to be close to recent lattice results. Still, the
accuracy in the determination of r_K is poor. However, future measurements of
the K-meson electromagnetic form factor at Q^2&lt;~5.5 GeV^2, scheduled in
Jefferson Laboratory for 2017, will test our approach and will reduce the
uncertainty in r_K significantly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08976</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grozdanov</keyname><forenames>Sa&#x161;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Schee</keyname><forenames>Wilke</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling constant corrections in a holographic model of heavy ion
  collisions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>V2: 6 pages, 5 figures. Second-order coupling constant corrections
  added. Version appeared in PRL</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4850</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 011601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.011601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We initiate a holographic study of coupling-dependent heavy ion collisions by
analysing for the first time the effects of leading-order, inverse coupling
constant corrections. In the dual description, this amounts to colliding
gravitational shock waves in a theory with curvature-squared terms. We find
that at intermediate coupling, nuclei experience less stopping and have more
energy deposited near the lightcone. When the decreased coupling results in an
80% larger shear viscosity, the time at which hydrodynamics becomes a good
description of the plasma created from high energy collisions increases by 25%.
The hydrodynamic phase of the evolution starts with a wider rapidity profile
and smaller entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09707</id><created>2016-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Budaca</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budaca</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape phase mixing in critical point nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 054306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.054306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spectral properties of nuclei near the critical point of the quantum phase
transition between spherical and axially symmetric shapes are studied in a
hybrid collective model which combines the $\gamma$-stable and $\gamma$-rigid
collective conditions through a rigidity parameter. The model in the lower and
upper limits of the rigidity parameter recovers the X(5) and X(3) solutions
respectively, while in the equally mixed case it corresponds to the X(4)
critical point symmetry. Numerical applications of the model on nuclei from
regions known for critical behavior reveal a sizable shape phase mixing and its
evolution with neutron or proton numbers. The model also enables a better
description of energy spectra and electromagnetic transitions for these nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05129</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chinnamsetty</keyname><forenames>Sambasiva Rao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griebel</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamaekers</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>An Adaptive Multiscale Approach for Electronic Structure Methods</title><categories>math.NA physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><msc-class>65D15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce a new scheme for the efficient numerical
treatment of the electronic Schr\&quot;odinger equation for molecules. It is based
on the combination of a many-body expansion, which corresponds to the so-called
bond order dissection Anova approach, with a hierarchy of basis sets of
increasing order. Here, the energy is represented as a finite sum of
contributions associated to subsets of nuclei and basis sets in a telescoping
sum like fashion. Under the assumption of data locality of the electronic
density (nearsightedness of electronic matter), the terms of this expansion
decay rapidly and higher terms may be neglected. We further extend the approach
in a dimension-adaptive fashion to generate quasi-optimal approximations, i.e.
a specific truncation of the hierarchical series such that the total benefit is
maximized for a fixed amount of costs. This way, we are able to achieve
substantial speed up factors compared to conventional first principles methods
depending on the molecular system under consideration. In particular, the
method can deal efficiently with molecular systems which include only a small
active part that needs to be described by accurate but expensive models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06555</id><created>2016-11-20</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ye&#x15f;ilta&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zlem</forenames></author></authors><title>The bound states of the massless Dirac equation on the torus</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Because of the old-fashion written manuscript, I have updated it and
  I have written the paper again and I'm submitting the paper today. Thank you
  in advance</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac equation on the toroidal surface is studied. The non-constant Fermi
velocity functions are used in the Dirac Hamiltonian to get trigonometric Scarf
and Rosen-Morse potentials using the method given in [19], then, the exact
solutions are written. On the other hand, consecutive mappings are used to get
a trigonometric Scarf I-like potential model and the solutions are obtained in
the second part of the paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07459</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Albarr&#xe1;n-Arriagada</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrios</keyname><forenames>G. Alvarado</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardenas-L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Retamal</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of higher dimensional entangled states in quantum Rabi
  systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Special Issue: Semiclassical and quantum Rabi models</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 184001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa66a0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present protocols for the generation of high-dimensional entangled states
of anharmonic oscillators by means of coherent manipulation of light-matter
systems in the ultrastrong coupling regime. Our protocols consider a pair of
ultrastrong coupled qubit-cavity systems, each coupled to an ancilla qubit, and
combine classical pulses plus the selection rules imposed by the parity
symmetry. We study the robustness of the entangling protocols under dissipative
effects. This proposal may have applications within state-of-art circuit
quantum electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09372</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Lizhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Lucia</keyname><forenames>Gabriella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschmann</keyname><forenames>Michaela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontanot</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoldan</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>H$_2$-based star formation laws in hierarchical models of galaxy
  formation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>28 pages, 21 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><journal-ref>2017MNRAS.469..968X</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx889</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We update our recently published model for GAlaxy Evolution and Assembly
(GAEA), to include a self-consistent treatment of the partition of cold gas in
atomic and molecular hydrogen. Our model provides significant improvements with
respect to previous ones used for similar studies. In particular, GAEA (i)
includes a sophisticated chemical enrichment scheme accounting for
non-instantaneous recycling of gas, metals, and energy; (ii) reproduces the
measured evolution of the galaxy stellar mass function; (iii) reasonably
reproduces the observed correlation between galaxy stellar mass and gas
metallicity at different redshifts. These are important prerequisites for
models considering a metallicity dependent efficiency of molecular gas
formation. We also update our model for disk sizes and show that model
predictions are in nice agreement with observational estimates for the gas,
stellar and star forming disks at different cosmic epochs. We analyse the
influence of different star formation laws including empirical relations based
on the hydro-static pressure of the disk, analytic models, and prescriptions
derived from detailed hydro-dynamical simulations. We find that modifying the
star formation law does not affect significantly the global properties of model
galaxies, neither their distributions. The only quantity showing significant
deviations in different models is the cosmic molecular-to-atomic hydrogen
ratio, particularly at high redshift. Unfortunately, however, this quantity
also depends strongly on the modelling adopted for additional physical
processes. Useful constraints on the physical processes regulating star
formation can be obtained focusing on low mass galaxies and/or at higher
redshift. In this case, self-regulation has not yet washed out differences
imprinted at early time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09629</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Byung-Geel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Kook-Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating convergence of the reaction $\gamma p\to\pi^\pm\Delta$ and
  tensor meson $a_2$ exchange at high energy</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B769, 262 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.03.070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Regge approach to the reaction processes $\gamma p\to\pi^-\Delta^{++}$ and
$\gamma p\to\pi^+\Delta^0$ is presented for the description of existing data up
to $E_\gamma= 16$ GeV. The model consists of the $t$-channel
$\pi(139)+\rho(775)+a_2(1320)$ exchanges which are reggeized from the relevant
Born amplitude. Discussion is given on the minimal gauge prescription for the
$\pi$ exchange to render convergent the divergence of the $u$-channel
$\Delta$-pole in the former process. A new Lagrangian is constructed for the
$a_2N\Delta$ coupling in this work and applied to the process for the first
time with the coupling constant deduced from the duality plus vector dominance.
It is shown that, while the $\pi$ exchange dominates over the process, the role
of the $a_2$ exchange is crucial rather than the $\rho$ in reproducing the
cross sections for total, differential, and photon polarization asymmetry to
agree with data at high energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02259</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lorenzo</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>Jamir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plastina</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palma</keyname><forenames>G. Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apollaro</keyname><forenames>Tony J. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Critical Scaling under Periodic Driving</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 5672 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-06025-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Universality is key to the theory of phase transition stating that the
equilibrium properties of observables near a phase transition can be classified
according to few critical exponents. These exponents rule an universal scaling
behaviour that witnesses the irrelevance of the model's microscopic details at
criticality. Here we discuss the persistence of such a scaling in a
one-dimensional quantum Ising model under sinusoidal modulation in time of its
transverse magnetic field. We show that scaling of various quantities
(concurrence, entanglement entropy, magnetic and fidelity susceptibility)
endures up to a stroboscopic time $\tau_{bd}$, proportional to the size of the
system. This behaviour is explained by noticing that the low-energy modes,
responsible for the scaling properties, are resilient to the absorption of
energy. Our results suggest that relevant features of the universality do hold
also when the system is brought out-of-equilibrium by a periodic driving.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02692</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Balodhi</keyname><forenames>Ashiwini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Yogesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis and pressure and field dependent magnetic properties of the
  Kagome-bilayer spin liquid Ca$_{10}$Cr$_7$O$_{28}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Revised Version accepted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Materials 1, 024407 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.024407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report synthesis of polycrystalline samples of the recently discovered
spin liquid material Ca$_{10}$Cr$_7$O$_{28}$ and present measurements of the
ambient and high pressure magnetic susceptibility $\chi$ versus temperature
$T$, magnetization $M$ versus magnetic field $H$ at various $T$, and heat
capacity $C$ versus $T$ at various $H$. The ambient pressure magnetic
measurements indicate the presence of both ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic
exchange interactions with dominant ferromagnetic interactions and with the
largest magnetic energy scale $\sim 10$~K\@. The $\chi(T)$ measurements under
externally applied pressure of up to $P \approx 1$~GPa indicate the robust
nature of the spin-liquid state despite relative increase in the ferromagnetic
exchanges. $C(T)$ shows a broad anomaly at $T\approx 2.5$~K which moves to
higher temperatures in a magnetic field. The evolution of the low temperature
$C(T,H)$ and the magnetic entropy is consistent with frustrated magnetism in
Ca$_{10}$Cr$_7$O$_{28}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05080</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leverrier</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author></authors><title>$SU(p,q)$ coherent states and a Gaussian de Finetti theorem</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2: 39 pages, including new application to truncations of Haar random
  matrices. Comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a generalization of the quantum de Finetti theorem when the local
space is an infinite-dimensional Fock space. In particular, instead of
considering the action of the permutation group on $n$ copies of that space, we
consider the action of the unitary group $U(n)$ on the creation operators of
the $n$ modes and define a natural generalization of the symmetric subspace as
the space of states invariant under unitaries in $U(n)$. Our first result is a
complete characterization of this subspace, which turns out to be spanned by a
family of generalized coherent states related to the special unitary group
$SU(p,q)$ of signature $(p,q)$. More precisely, this construction yields a
unitary representation of the noncompact simple real Lie group $SU(p,q)$. We
therefore find a dual unitary representation of the pair of groups $U(n)$ and
$SU(p,q)$ on an $n(p+q)$-mode Fock space.
  The (Gaussian) $SU(p,q)$ coherent states resolve the identity on the
symmetric subspace, which implies a Gaussian de Finetti theorem stating that
tracing over a few modes of a unitary-invariant state yields a state close to a
mixture of Gaussian states. As an application of this de Finetti theorem, we
show that the $n\times n$ upper-left submatrix of an $n\times n$ Haar-invariant
unitary matrix is close in total variation distance to a matrix of independent
normal variables if $n^3 =O(m)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07743</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wadud</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bingham</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregori</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion-like particle production in a laser-induced dynamical spacetime</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the dynamics of a charged particle (e.g., an electron)
oscillating in a laser field in flat spacetime and describe it in terms of the
variable mass metric. By applying Einstein's equivalence principle, we show
that, after representing the electron motion in a time-dependent manner, the
variable mass metric takes the form of the
Friedmann-Lema\^itre-Robertson-Walker metric. We quantize a massive complex
scalar or pseudo-scalar field in this spacetime and derive the production rate
of electrically neutral, spinless particle-antiparticle pairs. We show that
this approach can provide an alternative experimental method to axion searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07856</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-03-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gavin</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moschelli</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zin</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Boltzmann-Langevin Approach to Pre-equilibrium Correlations in Nuclear
  Collisions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C95 (2017) no.6, 064901</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.064901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Correlations born before the onset of hydrodynamic flow can leave observable
traces on the final state particles. Measurement of these correlations can
yield important information on the isotropization and thermalization process.
Starting from a Boltzmann-like kinetic theory in the presence of dynamic
Langevin noise, we derive a new partial differential equation for the
two-particle correlation function that respects the microscopic conservation
laws. We illustrate how this equation can be used to study the effect of
thermalization on long range correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01336</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Arda</keyname><forenames>Altug</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical Solution of two-body spinless Salpeter Equation for Hellmann
  Potential</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Ind. J. Phys. 91, 903 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12648-017-0988-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Approximate bound state solutions of the spinless Salpeter equation for the
Hellmann potential are studied for heavy particles. By using functional
analysis method, an analytical expression for the energy levels, and the
corresponding eigenfunctions of the system are obtained in terms of the
hypergeometric functions. The analytical results for the Yukawa and Coulomb
potentials are also studied as special cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01020</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schemmer</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Aisling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Photopoulos</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchoule</keyname><forenames>Isabelle</forenames></author></authors><title>A Monte Carlo wavefunction description of losses in a 1D Bose gas and
  cooling to the ground state by quantum feedback</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physical Review A, American Physical Society, 2017, 95, pp.043641</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of atom losses on a homogeneous one-dimensional Bose gas lying
within the quasi-condensate regime is investigated using a Monte Carlo
wavefunction approach. The evolution of the system is calculated, conditioned
by the loss sequence, namely the times of individual losses and the position of
the removed atoms. We describe the gas within the linearized Bogoliubov
approach. For each mode, we find that, for a given quantum trajectory, the
state of the system converges towards a coherent state, i.e. the ground state,
displaced in phase space. Provided losses are recorded with a temporal and
spatially resolved detector, we show that quantum feedback can be implemented
and cooling to the ground state of one or several modes can be realized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01341</id><created>2017-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Sam-ang</keyname><forenames>Panu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Matthew G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizing Destructive Quantum Interference in Electron Transport</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 053002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa6c23</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Destructive quantum interference in electron transport through molecules
provides an unconventional route for suppressing electric current. In this work
we introduce &quot;interference vectors&quot; for each interference and use them to
characterize the interference. An interference vector may be an orbital of the
bare molecule, in which case the interference is very sensitive to
perturbation. In contrast, an interference vector may be a combination of
multiple molecular orbitals, leading to more robust interference that is
likelier to be experimentally observable. Our characterization scheme
quantifies these two possibilities through the degree of rotation and also
assigns an order to each interference that describes the shape of the
Landauer-B\&quot;uttiker transmission function around the interference. Several
examples are then presented, showcasing the generality of our theory and
characterization scheme, which is not limited to specific classes of molecules
or particular molecule-electrode coupling patterns.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03055</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-02-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Seenithurai</keyname><forenames>Sonai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Jeng-Da</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Li Termination on the Electronic and Hydrogen Storage
  Properties of Linear Carbon Chains: A TAO-DFT Study</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.str-el physics.atm-clus physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 11 figures. This is an extension of our previous work
  [e.g., see arXiv:1606.03489]</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 4966 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-05202-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate prediction of the electronic and hydrogen storage properties of
linear carbon chains (Cn) and Li-terminated linear carbon chains (Li2Cn), with
n carbon atoms (n = 5 - 10), has been very challenging for traditional
electronic structure methods, due to the presence of strong static correlation
effects. To meet the challenge, we study these properties using our newly
developed thermally-assisted-occupation density functional theory (TAO-DFT), a
very efficient electronic structure method for the study of large systems with
strong static correlation effects. Owing to the alteration of the reactivity of
Cn and Li2Cn with n, odd-even oscillations in their electronic properties are
found. In contrast to Cn, the binding energies of H2 molecules on Li2Cn are in
(or close to) the ideal binding energy range (about 20 to 40 kJ/mol per H2). In
addition, the H2 gravimetric storage capacities of Li2Cn are in the range of
10.7 to 17.9 wt%, satisfying the United States Department of Energy (USDOE)
ultimate target of 7.5 wt%. On the basis of our results, Li2Cn can be
high-capacity hydrogen storage materials for reversible hydrogen uptake and
release at near-ambient conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07372</id><created>2017-02-23</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>Jean-Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorignac</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorman</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rech</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouet</keyname><forenames>Jean-Yves</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nollmann</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmeri</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parmeggiani</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geniet</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Surfing on protein waves: proteophoresis as a mechanism for bacterial
  genome partitioning</title><categories>q-bio.SC cond-mat.soft nlin.AO</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters Vol.119, 028101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.028101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Efficient bacterial chromosome segregation typically requires the coordinated
action of a three-components, fueled by adenosine triphosphate machinery called
the partition complex. We present a phenomenological model accounting for the
dynamic activity of this system. The model is obtained by coupling simple
linear reaction-diffusion equations with a proteophoresis, or &quot;volumetric&quot;
chemophoresis, force field. This minimal description, in the sense of Occam's
Razor principle, captures most known experimental observations: dynamic
oscillations of complex components, complex separation and subsequent
symmetrical positioning. The predictions of our model are in phenomenological
agreement with and provide substantial insights into recent experiments. From a
non-linear physics view point, this system explores the active separation of
matter at micrometric scales with a dynamical instability between static
positioning and travelling wave regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07567</id><created>2017-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Semay</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buisseret</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bound cyclic systems with the envelope theory</title><categories>quant-ph hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst (2017) 58:151</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-017-1313-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Approximate but reliable solutions of a quantum system with $N$ identical
particles can be easily computed with the envelope theory, also known as the
auxiliary field method. This technique has been developed for Hamiltonians with
arbitrary kinematics and one- or two-body potentials. It is adapted here for
cyclic systems with $N$ identical particles, that is to say systems in which a
particle $i$ has only an interaction with particles $i-1$ and $i+1$ (with
$N+1\equiv 1$).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03099</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Shi-Zeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and inertia of a skyrmion in chiral magnets and interfaces: A
  linear response approach based on magnon excitations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci nlin.PS</categories><comments>10 pages and 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 014407 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.014407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Taking all the magnon modes into account, we derive the skyrmion dynamics in
response to a weak external drive. A skyrmion has rotational symmetry and the
magnon modes can be characterized by an angular momentum. For a weak distortion
of a skyrmion, only the magnon modes with an angular momentum $|m|=1$ govern
the dynamics of skyrmion topological center. The skyrmion inertia is determined
by the magnon modes in the continuum spectrum. For a skyrmion driven by a
magnetic field gradient or by a spin transfer torque generated by a current,
the dynamical response is practically instantaneous. This justifies the rigid
skyrmion approximation used in Thiele's collective coordinate approach. For a
skyrmion driven by a spin Hall torque, the torque couples to the skyrmion
motion through the magnons in the continuum and damping, therefore the skyrmion
dynamics shows sizable inertia in this case. The trajectory of a skyrmion is an
ellipse for an ac drive of spin Hall torque.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04572</id><created>2017-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Janika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakore</keyname><forenames>Vaibhav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ala-Nissila</keyname><forenames>Tapio</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonically Enhanced Reflectance of Heat Radiation from Low-Bandgap
  Semiconductor Microinclusions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Main article (8 Figures and 2 Tables) + Supporting Information (8
  Figures)</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 5696 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-05630-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Increased reflectance from the inclusion of highly scattering particles at
low volume fractions in an insulating dielectric offers a promising way to
reduce radiative thermal losses at high temperatures. Here, we investigate
plasmonic resonance driven enhanced scattering from microinclusions of
low-bandgap semiconductors (InP, Si, Ge, PbS, InAs and Te) in an insulating
composite to tailor its infrared reflectance for minimizing thermal losses from
radiative transfer. To this end, we compute the spectral properties of the
microcomposites using Monte Carlo modeling and compare them with results from
Fresnel equations. The role of particle size-dependent Mie scattering and
absorption efficiencies, and, scattering anisotropy are studied to identify the
optimal microinclusion size and material parameters for maximizing the
reflectance of the thermal radiation. For composites with Si and Ge
microinclusions we obtain reflectance efficiencies of 57 - 65% for the incident
blackbody radiation from sources at temperatures in the range 400 - 1600
{\deg}C. Furthermore, we observe a broadbanding of the reflectance spectra from
the plasmonic resonances due to charge carriers generated from defect states
within the semiconductor bandgap. Our results thus open up the possibility of
developing efficient high-temperature thermal insulators through use of the
low-bandgap semiconductor microinclusions in insulating dielectrics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06879</id><created>2017-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bliokh</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzzinati</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Boxem</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe9;ch&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juchtmans</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schattschneider</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verbeeck</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory and applications of free-electron vortex states</title><categories>quant-ph hep-ph hep-th physics.optics</categories><comments>87 pages, 34 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rep. 690, 1-70 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2017.05.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Both classical and quantum waves can form vortices: with helical phase fronts
and azimuthal current densities. These features determine the intrinsic orbital
angular momentum carried by localized vortex states. In the past 25 years,
optical vortex beams have become an inherent part of modern optics, with many
remarkable achievements and applications. In the past decade, it has been
realized and demonstrated that such vortex beams or wavepackets can also appear
in free electron waves, in particular, in electron microscopy. Interest in
free-electron vortex states quickly spread over different areas of physics:
from basic aspects of quantum mechanics, via applications for fine probing of
matter (including individual atoms), to high-energy particle collision and
radiation processes. Here we provide a comprehensive review of theoretical and
experimental studies in this emerging field of research. We describe the main
properties of electron vortex states, experimental achievements and possible
applications within transmission electron microscopy, as well as the possible
role of vortex electrons in relativistic and high-energy processes. We aim to
provide a balanced description including a pedagogical introduction, solid
theoretical basis, and a wide range of practical details. Special attention is
paid to translate theoretical insights into suggestions for future experiments,
in electron microscopy and beyond, in any situation where free electrons occur.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06906</id><created>2017-03-20</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masella</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ratcliff</keyname><forenames>Laura E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author></authors><title>Complexity Reduction in Large Quantum Systems: Reliable Electrostatic
  Embedding for Multiscale Approaches via Optimized Minimal Basis Functions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given a partition of a large system into an active quantum mechanical (QM)
region and its environment, we present a simple way of embedding the QM region
into an effective electrostatic potential representing the environment. This
potential is generated by partitioning the environment into well defined
fragments, and assigning each one a set of electrostatic multipoles, which can
then be used to build up the electrostatic potential. We show that, providing
the fragments and the projection scheme for the multipoles are chosen properly,
this leads to an effective electrostatic embedding of the active QM region
which is of equal quality as a full QM calculation. We coupled our formalism to
the DFT code BigDFT, which uses a minimal set of localized in-situ optimized
basis functions; this property eases the fragment definition while still
describing the electronic structure with great precision. Thanks to the linear
scaling capabilities of BigDFT, we can compare the modeling of the
electrostatic embedding with results coming from unbiased full QM calculations
of the entire system. This enables a reliable and controllable setup of an
effective coarse-graining approach, coupling together different levels of
description, which yields a considerable reduction in the degrees of freedom
and thus paves the way towards efficient QM/QM and QM/MM methods for the
treatment of very large systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07250</id><created>2017-03-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Ambichl</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandst&#xf6;tter</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hmayer</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Focusing inside Disordered Media with the Generalized Wigner-Smith
  Operator</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, including supplemental material section</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 033903 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.033903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a wavefront shaping protocol for focusing inside disordered
media based on a generalization of the established Wigner-Smith time-delay
operator. The key ingredient for our approach is the scattering (or
transmission) matrix of the medium and its derivative with respect to the
position of the target one aims to focus on. A specifc experimental realization
in the microwave regime is presented showing that the eigenstates of a
corresponding operator are sorted by their focusing strength - ranging from
strongly focusing on the designated target to completely bypassing it. Our
protocol works without optimization or phase-conjugation and we expect it to be
particularly attractive for optical imaging in disordered media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07287</id><created>2017-03-21</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Kenan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisch</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser Pulse Sharpening with Electromagnetically Induced Transparency in
  Plasma</title><categories>physics.optics physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas 24, 073108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4990440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a laser-controlled plasma shutter technique to generate sharp
laser pulses using a process analogous to electromagnetically-induced
transparency in atoms. The shutter is controlled by a laser with moderately
strong intensity, which induces a transparency window below the cutoff
frequency, and hence enables propagation of a low frequency laser pulse.
Numerical simulations demonstrate it is possible to generate a sharp pulse
wavefront (sub-ps) using two broad pulses in high density plasma. The technique
can work in a regime that is not accessible by plasma mirrors when the pulse
pedestals are stronger than the ionization intensity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07901</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-07-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoang</keyname><forenames>Michael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stacey</keyname><forenames>Blake C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The SIC Question: History and State of Play</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 1 figure, many references; v3: updating bibliography,
  dimension eight hundred forty four</comments><journal-ref>Axioms 2017, 6(3), 21</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/axioms6030021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent years have seen significant advances in the study of symmetric
informationally complete (SIC) quantum measurements, also known as maximal sets
of complex equiangular lines. Previously, the published record contained
solutions up to dimension 67, and was with high confidence complete up through
dimension 50. Computer calculations have now furnished solutions in all
dimensions up to 151, and in several cases beyond that, as large as dimension
844. These new solutions exhibit an additional type of symmetry beyond the
basic definition of a SIC, and so verify a conjecture of Zauner in many new
cases. The solutions in dimensions 68 through 121 were obtained by Andrew
Scott, and his catalogue of distinct solutions is, with high confidence,
complete up to dimension 90. Additional results in dimensions 122 through 151
were calculated by the authors using Scott's code. We recap the history of the
problem, outline how the numerical searches were done, and pose some
conjectures on how the search technique could be improved. In order to
facilitate communication across disciplinary boundaries, we also present a
comprehensive bibliography of SIC research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00706</id><created>2017-03-30</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>S. Rathna</forenames></author></authors><title>Crash testing difference-smoothing algorithm on a large sample of
  simulated light curves from TDC1</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS, 12 pages, 5 figures, 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 470, 2918-2928 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1364</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we propose refinements to the difference-smoothing algorithm
for measurement of time delay from the light curves of the images of a
gravitationally lensed quasar. The refinements mainly consist of a more
pragmatic approach to choose the smoothing time-scale free parameter,
generation of more realistic synthetic light curves for estimation of time
delay uncertainty and using a plot of normalized $\chi^2$ computed over a wide
range of trial time delay values to assess the reliability of a measured time
delay and also for identifying instances of catastrophic failure. We rigorously
tested the difference-smoothing algorithm on a large sample of more than
thousand pairs of simulated light curves having known true time delays between
them from the two most difficult `rungs' -- rung3 and rung4 -- of the first
edition of Strong Lens Time Delay Challenge (TDC1) and found an inherent
tendency of the algorithm to measure the magnitude of time delay to be higher
than the true value of time delay. However, we find that this systematic bias
is eliminated by applying a correction to each measured time delay according to
the magnitude and sign of the systematic error inferred by applying the time
delay estimator on synthetic light curves simulating the measured time delay.
Following these refinements, the TDC performance metrics for the
difference-smoothing algorithm are found to be competitive with those of the
best performing submissions of TDC1 for both the tested `rungs'. The MATLAB
codes used in this work and the detailed results are made publicly available at
https://github.com/rathnakumars/difference-smoothing
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01973</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wessel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Normand</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mila</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honecker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient Quantum Monte Carlo simulations of highly frustrated magnets:
  the frustrated spin-1/2 ladder</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>26 pages including 12 figures; this version: minor modifications in
  sections 3.3 and 4.5</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 3, 005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.3.1.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum Monte Carlo simulations provide one of the more powerful and
versatile numerical approaches to condensed matter systems. However, their
application to frustrated quantum spin models, in all relevant temperature
regimes, is hamstrung by the infamous &quot;sign problem.&quot; Here we exploit the fact
that the sign problem is basis-dependent. Recent studies have shown that
passing to a dimer (two-site) basis eliminates the sign problem completely for
a fully frustrated spin model on the two-leg ladder. We generalize this result
to all partially frustrated two-leg spin-1/2 ladders, meaning those where the
diagonal and leg couplings take any antiferromagnetic values. We find that,
although the sign problem does reappear, it remains remarkably mild throughout
the entire phase diagram. We explain this result and apply it to perform
efficient quantum Monte Carlo simulations of frustrated ladders, obtaining
accurate results for thermodynamic quantities such as the magnetic specific
heat and susceptibility of ladders up to L=200 rungs (400 spins 1/2) and down
to very low temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05609</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sou</keyname><forenames>Isamu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okamoto</keyname><forenames>Ryuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komura</keyname><forenames>Shigeyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author></authors><title>Coexistences of lamellar phases in ternary surfactant solutions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate the coexistences of lamellar phases both in
binary and ternary surfactant solutions. The previous free energy of a lamellar
stack is extended to take into account the translational entropy of membrane
segments. The obtained phase diagram for binary surfactant solutions
(surfactant/water mixtures) shows a phase separation between two lamellar
phases and also exhibits a critical point. For lamellar phases in ternary
surfactant solutions (surfactant/surfactant/water mixtures), we explore
possible phase behaviors and show that the phase diagrams exhibit various
three-phase regions as well as two-phase regions in which different lamellar
phases coexist. We also find that finite surface tension suppresses undulation
fluctuations of membranes and leads to a wider three-phase and two-phase
coexistence regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06237</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Yongbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Tai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mou</keyname><forenames>Daixiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Lunan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bud'ko</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canfield</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaminski</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure of RSb (R = Y, Ce, Gd, Dy, Ho, Tm, Lu) studied by
  angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035134 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use high resolution angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES) and
electronic structure calculations to study the electronic properties of
rare-earth monoantimonides RSb (R = Y, Ce, Gd, Dy, Ho, Tm, Lu). The
experimentally measured Fermi surface (FS) of RSb consists of at least two
concentric hole pockets at the $\Gamma$ point and two intersecting electron
pockets at the $X$ point. These data agree relatively well with the electronic
structure calculations. Detailed photon energy dependence measurements using
both synchrotron and laser ARPES systems indicate that there is at least one
Fermi surface sheet with strong three-dimensionality centered at the $\Gamma$
point. Due to the &quot;lanthanide contraction&quot;, the unit cell of different
rare-earth monoantimonides shrinks when changing rare-earth ion from CeSb to
LuSb. This results in the differences in the chemical potentials in these
compounds, which is demonstrated by both ARPES measurements and electronic
structure calculations. Interestingly, in CeSb, the intersecting electron
pockets at the $X$ point seem to be touching the valence bands, forming a
four-fold degenerate Dirac-like feature. On the other hand, the remaining
rare-earth monoantimonides show significant gaps between the upper and lower
bands at the $X$ point. Furthermore, similar to the previously reported results
of LaBi, a Dirac-like structure was observed at the $\Gamma$ point in YSb,
CeSb, and GdSb, compounds showing relatively high magnetoresistance. This
Dirac-like structure may contribute to the unusually large magnetoresistance in
these compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07331</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ellis</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Marcos A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagata</keyname><forenames>Natsumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nanopoulos</keyname><forenames>Dimitri V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olive</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Starobinsky-like Inflation, Supercosmology and Neutrino Masses in
  No-Scale Flipped SU(5)</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>51 pages, 13 figures</comments><report-no>KCL-PH-TH/2017-17, CERN-PH-TH/2017-071, UT-17-16, ACT-03-17,
  MI-TH-1752, UMN-TH-3623/17, FTPI-MINN-17/08</report-no><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We embed a flipped ${\rm SU}(5) \times {\rm U}(1)$ GUT model in a no-scale
supergravity framework, and discuss its predictions for cosmic microwave
background observables, which are similar to those of the Starobinsky model of
inflation. Measurements of the tilt in the spectrum of scalar perturbations in
the cosmic microwave background, $n_s$, constrain significantly the model
parameters. We also discuss the model's predictions for neutrino masses, and
pay particular attention to the behaviours of scalar fields during and after
inflation, reheating and the GUT phase transition. We argue in favor of strong
reheating in order to avoid excessive entropy production which could dilute the
generated baryon asymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07423</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-07-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutchinson</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antono</keyname><forenames>Erin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paradiso</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meredig</keyname><forenames>Bryce</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Dimensional Materials and Process Optimization using Data-driven
  Experimental Design with Well-Calibrated Uncertainty Estimates</title><categories>stat.ML cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Integrating Materials and Manufacturing Innovation, (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40192-017-0098-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The optimization of composition and processing to obtain materials that
exhibit desirable characteristics has historically relied on a combination of
scientist intuition, trial and error, and luck. We propose a methodology that
can accelerate this process by fitting data-driven models to experimental data
as it is collected to suggest which experiment should be performed next. This
methodology can guide the scientist to test the most promising candidates
earlier, and can supplement scientific intuition and knowledge with data-driven
insights. A key strength of the proposed framework is that it scales to
high-dimensional parameter spaces, as are typical in materials discovery
applications. Importantly, the data-driven models incorporate uncertainty
analysis, so that new experiments are proposed based on a combination of
exploring high-uncertainty candidates and exploiting high-performing regions of
parameter space. Over four materials science test cases, our methodology led to
the optimal candidate being found with three times fewer required measurements
than random guessing on average.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08668</id><created>2017-04-27</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kissinger</keyname><forenames>Aleks</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tull</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westerbaan</keyname><forenames>Bas</forenames></author></authors><title>Picture-perfect Quantum Key Distribution</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, many string diagrams</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a new way to bound the security of quantum key distribution using
only two high-level, diagrammatic features of quantum processes: the
compositional behavior of complementary measurements and the essential
uniqueness of purification. We begin by demonstrating a proof in the simplest
case, where the eavesdropper doesn't noticeably disturb the channel at all and
has no quantum memory. We then show how this approach extends straightforwardly
to account for an eavesdropper with quantum memory and the presence of noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04783</id><created>2017-05-12</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Kang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rao</keyname><forenames>Junjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>Derivation of Feynman Rules for Higher Order Poles Using Cross-ratio
  Identities in CHY Construction</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1706 (2017) 091</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)091</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to generalize the integration rules to general CHY integrands which
include higher order poles, algorithms are proposed in two directions. One is
to conjecture new rules, and the other is to use the cross-ratio identity
method. In this paper,we use the cross-ratio identity approach to re-derive the
conjectured integration rules involving higher order poles for several special
cases: the single double pole, single triple pole and duplex-double pole. The
equivalence between the present formulas and the previously conjectured ones is
discussed for the first two situations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05819</id><created>2017-05-16</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dowell</keyname><forenames>Jayce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Gregory B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schinzel</keyname><forenames>Frank K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kassim</keyname><forenames>Namir E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stovall</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>The LWA1 Low Frequency Sky Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>MNRAS accepted: 15 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (4): 4537-4550</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a survey of the radio sky accessible from the first station of the
Long Wavelength Array (LWA1). Images are presented at nine frequencies between
35 and 80 MHz with spatial resolutions ranging from $4.7^\circ$ to $2.0^\circ$,
respectively. The maps cover the sky north of a declination of $-40^\circ$ and
represent the most modern systematic survey of the diffuse Galactic emission
within this frequency range. We also combine our survey with other low
frequency sky maps to create an updated model of the low frequency sky. Due to
the low frequencies probed by our survey, the updated model better accounts for
the effects of free-free absorption from Galactic ionized Hydrogen. A longer
term motivation behind this survey is to understand the foreground emission
that obscures the redshifted 21 cm transition of neutral hydrogen from the
cosmic dark ages ($z&gt;10$) and, at higher frequencies, the epoch of reionization
($z&gt;6$).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05853</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05853</id><created>2017-05-16</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bozorgnia</keyname><forenames>Nassim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertone</keyname><forenames>Gianfranco</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of hydrodynamical simulations for the interpretation of
  direct dark matter searches</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>31 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables; v2: added Sec. 6.2 and Fig. 3, version
  accepted for publication in IJMPA</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17300162</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, realistic hydrodynamical simulations of galaxies like the
Milky Way have become available, enabling a reliable estimate of the dark
matter density and velocity distribution in the Solar neighborhood. We review
here the status of hydrodynamical simulations and their implications for the
interpretation of direct dark matter searches. We focus in particular on: the
criteria to identify Milky Way-like galaxies; the impact of baryonic physics on
the dark matter velocity distribution; the possible presence of substructures
like clumps, streams, or dark disks; and on the implications for the direct
detection of dark matter with standard and non-standard interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10251</id><created>2017-05-29</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>ZEUS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Studies of the diffractive photoproduction of isolated photons at HERA</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>46 pages, 10 figures. The second version has some textual
  clarifications</comments><report-no>DESY-17-077</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The photoproduction of isolated photons has been measured in diffractive
events recorded by the ZEUS detector at HERA. Cross sections are evaluated in
the photon transverse-energy and pseudorapidity ranges $5 &lt; E_T &lt; 15$ GeV and
$-0.7 &lt; \eta &lt; 0.9,$ inclusively and also with a jet with transverse energy and
pseudorapidity in the ranges $4 &lt; E_{jet} &lt; 35$ GeV and $-1.5 &lt; \eta_{jet} &lt;
1.8,$ using a total integrated electron-proton luminosity of 456 pb$^{-1}$. A
number of kinematic variables were studied and compared to predictions from the
Rapgap Monte Carlo model. An excess of data is observed above the Rapgap
predictions for $z^{meas}_{Pomeron} &gt; 0.9,$ where $z^{meas}_{Pomeron}$ is the
fraction of the longitudinal momentum of the colourless &quot;Pomeron&quot; exchange that
is transferred to the photon-jet final state, giving evidence for direct
Pomeron interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10761</id><created>2017-05-30</created><updated>2017-06-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gambaro</keyname><forenames>Joao Paulo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crokidakis</keyname><forenames>Nuno</forenames></author></authors><title>The influence of contrarians in the dynamics of opinion formation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, to appear in Physica A</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 486, 465 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2017.05.040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we consider the presence of contrarian agents in discrete
3-state kinetic exchange opinion models. The contrarians are individuals that
adopt the choice opposite to the prevailing choice of their contacts, whatever
this choice is. We consider binary as well as three-agent interactions, with
stochastic parameters, in a fully-connected population. Our numerical results
suggest that the presence of contrarians destroys the absorbing state of the
original model, changing the transition to the para-ferromagnetic type. In this
case, the consequence for the society is that the three opinions coexist in the
population, in both phases (ordered and disordered). Furthermore, the
order-disorder transition is suppressed for a sufficient large fraction of
contrarians. In some cases the transition is discontinuous, and it changes to
continuous before it is suppressed. Some of our results are complemented by
analytical calculations based on the master equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01203</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Hyde</keyname><forenames>Elaina A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filipovic</keyname><forenames>Miroslav D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaper</keyname><forenames>Lex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grieve</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>Andrew N.</forenames></author></authors><title>LMC X-1: A New Spectral Analysis of the O-star in the binary and
  surrounding nebula</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>7 Figures, 4 Tables</comments><doi>10.1088/1538-3873/aa7407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide new observations of the LMC X-1 O star and its extended nebula
structure using spectroscopic data from VLT/UVES as well as H$\alpha$ imaging
from the Wide Field Imager on the Max Planck Gesellschaft / European Southern
Observatory 2.2m telescope and ATCA imaging of the 2.1 GHz radio continuum.
This nebula is one of the few known to be energized by an X-ray binary. We use
a new spectrum extraction technique that is superior to other methods to obtain
both radial velocities and fluxes. This provides an updated spatial velocity of
$\simeq 21.0~\pm~4.8$ km s$^{-1}$ for the O star. The slit encompasses both the
photo-ionized and shock-ionized regions of the nebula. The imaging shows a
clear arc-like structure reminiscent of a wind bow shock in between the
ionization cone and shock-ionized nebula. The observed structure can be fit
well by the parabolic shape of a wind bow shock. If an interpretation of a wind
bow shock system is valid, we investigate the N159-O1 star cluster as a
potential parent of the system, suggesting a progenitor mass of $\sim 60$
M$_{\odot}$ for the black hole. We further note that the radio emission could
be non-thermal emission from the wind bow shock, or synchrotron emission
associated with the jet inflated nebula. For both wind and jet-powered origins,
this would represent one of the first radio detections of such a structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01880</id><created>2017-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Mazzuoli</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uhlmann</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct numerical simulation of open-channel flow over a fully-rough wall
  at moderate relative submergence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>46 pages, 26 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal Fluid Mechanics, vol. 824, pp. 722-765, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.371</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct numerical simulation of open-channel flow over a bed of spheres
arranged in a regular pattern has been carried out at bulk Reynolds number and
roughness Reynolds number (based on sphere diameter) of approximately 6900 and
120, respectively, for which the flow regime is fully-rough. The open-channel
height was approximately 5.5 times the diameter of the spheres. Extending the
results obtained by Chan-Braun et al. (J. Fluid Mech., vol. 684, 2011, 441) for
an open-channel flow in the transitionally-rough regime, the present purpose is
to show how the flow structure changes as the fully-rough regime is attained
and, for the first time, to enable a direct comparison with experimental
observations. The results indicate that, in the vicinity of the roughness
elements, the average flow field is affected both by Reynolds number effects
and by the geometrical features of the roughness, while at larger
wall-distances this is not the case, and roughness concepts can be applied. The
flow-roughness interaction occurs mostly in the region above the virtual origin
of the velocity profile, and the effect of form-induced velocity fluctuations
is maximum at the level of sphere crests. The spanwise length scale of
turbulent velocity fluctuations in the vicinity of the sphere crests shows the
same dependence on the distance from the wall as that observed over a smooth
wall, and both vary with Reynolds number in a similar fashion. Moreover, the
hydrodynamic force and torque experienced by the roughness elements are
investigated. Finally, the possibility either to adopt an analogy between the
hydrodynamic forces associated with the interaction of turbulent structures
with a flat smooth wall or with the surface of the spheres is also discussed,
distinguishing the skin-friction from the form-drag contributions both in the
transitionally-rough and in the fully-rough regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03594</id><created>2017-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Heonoh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sang Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Osung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Han Seb</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-photon interference of polarization-entangled photons in a Franson
  interferometer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication in Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 5772 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present two-photon interference experiments with polarization-entangled
photon pairs in a polarization-based Franson-type interferometer. Although the
two photons do not meet at a common beamsplitter, a phase-insensitive
Hong-Ou-Mandel type two-photon interference peak and dip fringes are observed,
resulting from the two-photon interference effect between two indistinguishable
two-photon probability amplitudes leading to a coincidence detection. A spatial
quantum beating fringe is also measured for nondegenerate photon pairs in the
same interferometer, although the two-photon states have no frequency
entanglement. When unentangled polarization-correlated photons are used as an
input state, the polarization entanglement is successfully recovered through
the interferometer via delayed compensation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03769</id><created>2017-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Moshin</keyname><forenames>Pavel Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sudhaker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Ricardo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite BRST Mapping in Higher Derivative Models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, published in Braz. J. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Braz. J. Phys. 47 (2017) 411-418</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s13538-017-0503-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We continue the study of finite field dependent BRST (FFBRST) symmetry in the
quantum theory of gauge fields. An expression for the Jacobian of path integral
measure is presented, depending on a finite field-dependent parameter, and the
FFBRST symmetry is then applied to a number of well-established quantum gauge
theories in a form which includes higher-derivative terms. Specifically, we
examine the corresponding versions of the Maxwell theory, non-Abelian vector
field theory, and gravitation theory. We present a systematic mapping between
different forms of gauge-fixing, including those with higher-derivative terms,
for which these theories have better renormalization properties. In doing so,
we also provide the independence of the S-matrix from a particular gauge-fixing
with higher derivatives. Following this method, a higher-derivative quantum
action can be constructed for any gauge theory in the FFBRST framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04085</id><created>2017-06-13</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Midya</keyname><forenames>Bikashkali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konotop</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Waveguides with Absorbing Boundaries: Nonlinearity Controlled by an
  Exceptional Point and Solitons</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci math-ph math.MP nlin.PS physics.app-ph</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 119, 033905 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.033905</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reveal the existence of continuous families of guided single-mode solitons
in planar waveguides with weakly nonlinear active core and absorbing
boundaries. Stable propagation of TE and TM-polarized solitons is accompanied
by attenuation of all other modes, i.e. the waveguide features properties of
conservative and dissipative systems. If the linear spectrum of the waveguide
possesses exceptional points, which occurs in the case of TM-polarization, an
originally focusing (defocusing) material nonlinearity may become effectively
defocusing (focusing). This occurs due to the geometric phase of the carried
eigenmode when the surface impedance encircles the exceptional point. In its
turn the change of the effective nonlinearity ensures the existence of dark
(bright) solitons in spite of focusing (defocusing) Kerr nonlinearity of the
core. The existence of an exceptional point can also result in anomalous
enhancement of the effective nonlinearity. In terms of practical applications
the nonlinearity of the reported waveguide can be manipulated by controlling
the properties of the absorbing cladding.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06373</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osaka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagayama</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamasaki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishiwata</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-pressure synthesis of an unusual antiferromagnetic metal
  CaCoO$_{3}$ with GdFeO$_{3}$-type perovskite structure</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 224440 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.224440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The GdFeO$_{3}$-type perovskite CaCoO$_{3}$ has been successfully synthesized
by high-pressure oxygen annealing for the oxygen deficient perovskite. A
detailed structural analysis based on synchrotron X-ray diffraction data and a
thermogravimetric analysis show that the valence of Co is +4 and the sample is
free from oxygen deficiency. This compound shows an antiferromagnetic ordering
at 95 K, which has presumably helical spin arrangement, with keeping the
incoherent metallic state down to the lowest temperature. This work
demonstrates that the Co$^{4+}$-perovskite oxides exhibit a variety of magnetic
phases by the band-width control through the lattice distortion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06404</id><created>2017-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Camenen</keyname><forenames>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Descantes</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical properties of rigid frictionless granular packings as a
  function of particle size and shape</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 figures, 12 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 96, 012904 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012904</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three-dimensional discrete numerical simulation is used to investigate the
properties of close-packed frictionless granular assemblies as a function of
particle polydispersity and shape. Unlike some experimental results,
simulations show that disordered packings of pinacoids (eight-face convex
polyhedron) achieve higher solid fraction values than amorphous packings of
spherical or rounded particles, thus fulfilling the analogue of Ulam's
conjecture stated by Jiao and co-workers for random packings [Y. Jiao and S.
Torquato, Phys. Rev. E $\textbf{84}$, $041309$ ($2011$)]. This seeming
discrepancy between experimental and numerical results is believed to lie with
difficulties in overcoming interparticle friction through experimental
densification processes. Moreover, solid fraction is shown to increase further
with bidispersity and peak when the volume proportion of small particles
reaches $30\%$. Contrarywise, substituting up to $50\%$ of flat pinacoids for
isometric ones yields solid fraction decrease, especially when flat particles
are also elongated. Nevertheless, particle shape seems to play a minor role on
packing solid fraction compared to polydispersity. Additional investigations
focused on the packing microstructure confirm that pinacoid packings fulfill
the isostatic conjecture and that they are free of order except beyond $30$ to
$50\%$ of flat or flat \&amp; elongated polyhedra in the packing. This order
increase progressively takes the form of a nematic phase caused by the
reorientation of flat or flat \&amp; elongated particles to minimize the packing
potential energy. Simultaneously, this reorientation seems to increase the
solid fraction value slightly above the maximum achieved by monodisperse
isometric pinacoids, as well as the coordination number. Finally, partial
substitution of elongated pinacoids for isometric ones has limited effect on
packing solid fraction or order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06561</id><created>2017-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bezchastnov</keyname><forenames>Victor G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>George G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cyclotron transitions of bound ions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, including 3 figures. Submitted to PRA</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A charged particle in a magnetic field possesses discrete energy levels
associated with particle's rotation around the field lines. The radiative
transitions between these levels are the well-known cyclotron transitions. We
show that a bound complex of particles with a non-zero net charge displays
analogous transitions between the states of confined motion of the entire
complex in the field. The latter {\em bound-ion cyclotron transitions} are
affected by a coupling between the collective and internal motions of the
complex and, as a result, differ from the transitions of a &quot;reference&quot; bare ion
with the same mass and charge. We analyze the cyclotron transitions for complex
ions by including the coupling within a rigorous quantum approach. Particular
attention is paid to comparison of the transition energies and oscillator
strengths to those of the bare ion. Selection rules based on integrals of
collective motion are derived for the bound-ion cyclotron transitions
analytically, and the perturbation and coupled-channel approaches are developed
to study the transitions quantitatively. Representative examples are considered
and discussed for positive and negative atomic and cluster ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08844</id><created>2017-06-23</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bishi</keyname><forenames>Binaya K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pacif</keyname><forenames>S. K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>LRS Bianchi type-I cosmological model with constant deceleration
  parameter in $f(R,T)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Published version</comments><msc-class>83D05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Geom. Methods Mod. Phys. 14 (2017) 1750158</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887817501584</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A spatially homogeneous anisotropic LRS Bianchi type-I cosmological model is
studied in $f(R,T)$ gravity with a special form of Hubble's parameter, which
leads to constant deceleration parameter. The parameters involved in the
considered form of Hubble parameter can be tuned to match, our models with the
$\Lambda $CDM model. With the present observed value of the deceleration
parameter, we have discussed physical and kinematical properties of a specific
model. Moreover, we have discussed the cosmological distances for our model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01360</id><created>2017-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>P. H. R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The simplest non-minimal matter-geometry coupling in the $f(R,T)$
  cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages (two column) 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77:480</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5062-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $f(R,T)$ gravity is an extended theory of gravity in which the
gravitational action contains general terms of both the Ricci scalar $R$ and
trace of the energy-momentum tensor $T$. In this way, $f(R,T)$ models are
capable of describing a non-minimal coupling between geometry (through terms in
$R$) and matter (through terms in $T$). In this article we construct a
cosmological model from the simplest non-minimal matter-geometry coupling
within the $f(R,T)$ gravity formalism, by means of an effective energy-momentum
tensor, given by the sum of the usual matter energy-momentum tensor with a dark
energy contribution, with the latter coming from the matter-geometry coupling
terms. We apply the energy conditions to our solutions in order to obtain a
range of values for the free parameters of the model which yield a healthy and
well-behaved scenario. For some values of the free parameters which are
submissive to the energy conditions application, it is possible to predict a
transition from a decelerated period of the expansion of the universe to a
period of acceleration (dark energy era). We also propose further applications
of this particular case of the $f(R,T)$ formalism in order to check its
reliability in other fields, rather than cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05781</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wenhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Hongchang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tongqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author></authors><title>Gross beta determination using a scintillating fiber array detector for
  drinking water</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A scintillating fiber array measurement system for gross beta is developed to
achieve real-time monitoring of radioactivity in drinking water. The detector
consists of 1,096 scintillating fibers, both sides of the fibers connect to a
photomultiplier tube, and they are placed in a stainless steel tank. The
detector parameters of working voltage, background counting rate and stability
of the detector were tested, and the detection efficiency was calibrated using
a standard solution of potassium chloride. Through experiment, the background
counting rate of the detector is 38.31 cps and the detection efficiency for
$\beta$ particles is 0.37 cps per Bq per liter; the detector can reach its
detection limit of 1.0 Bq per liter for $\beta$ particles within 100 minutes
without pre-concentration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05796</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Leo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Shanshan</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Near Horizon Canonical Quantum Microstates from $AdS_2/CFT_1$ and
  Conformal Weyl Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, no figures. Accepted version contributed to mdpi's Universe
  collection on open questions in black hole physics</comments><journal-ref>Universe 2017, 3, 56</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/universe3030056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the full asymptotic symmetry group of black holes belonging to the
same equivalence class of solutions within the Conformal Weyl Gravity
formalism. We do this within an $AdS_2/CFT_1$ correspondence and by performing
a Robinson-Wilczek two dimensional reduction, thus enabling the construction of
an effective quantum theory of the remaining field content. The resulting
energy momentum tensors generate asymptotic Virasoro algebras, to $s$-wave,
with calculable central extensions. These centers in conjunction with their
proper regularized lowest Virasoro eigen-modes yield the Bekenstein-Hawking
black hole entropy via the statistical Cardy formula. We also analyze quantum
holomorphic fluxes of the dual CFTs in the near horizon, giving rise to finite
Hawking temperatures weighted by the central charges of the respective black
hole spacetimes. We conclude with a discussion and outlook for future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05802</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purtseladze</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnova</keyname><forenames>Daria A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slobozhanyuk</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanikaev</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin and valley polarized one-way Klein tunneling in photonic
  topological insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Advances of condensed matter physics in exploiting the spin degree of freedom
of electrons led to the emergence of the field of spintronics, which envisions
new and more efficient approaches to data transfer, computing, and storage
[1-3]. These ideas have been inspiring analogous approaches in photonics, where
the manipulation of an artificially engineered pseudo-spin degrees of freedom
is enabled by synthetic gauge fields acting on light [4,5,6]. The ability to
control these additional degrees of freedom can significantly expand the
landscape of available optical responses, which may revolutionize optical
computing and the basic means of controlling light in photonic devices across
the entire electromagnetic spectrum. Here we demonstrate a new class of
photonic systems, described by effective Hamiltonians in which competing
synthetic gauge fields engineered in pseudo-spin, chirality/sublattice and
valley subspaces result in band gap opening at one of the valleys, while the
other valley exhibits Dirac-like conical dispersion. It is shown that such
effective response has dramatic implications on photon transport, among which:
(i) spin-polarized and valley-polarized one-way Klein tunneling and (ii)
topological edge states that coexist within the Dirac continuum for opposite
valley and spin polarizations. These phenomena offer new ways to control light
in photonics, in particular for on-chip optical isolation, filtering and
wave-division multiplexing by selective action on their pseudo-spin and valley
degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05803</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Shivamoggi</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Slipping Motion on the Hasimoto Soliton on a Vortex Filament
  in Self-Induced Motion: An Exact Solution</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A vortex filament immersed in a non-ideal fluid, thanks to viscous diffusion,
experiences a slipping motion with respect to the fluid. In recognition of
this, in this paper, the effect of this slipping motion on the Hasimoto soliton
propagating on a vortex filament is investigated, and an exact solution is
given to describe this process. A strong slipping motion is shown to prevent
the existence of the Hasimoto soliton. The critical slipping speed (above which
the Hasimoto soliton fails to exist) is shown to be equal to the torsion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05811</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ibanez</keyname><forenames>Luis E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Lozano</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenzuela</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining the EW Hierarchy from the Weak Gravity Conjecture</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this addendum we complement the remarks made in ref[1] constraining the
value of the cosmological constant $\Lambda_4$ in terms of neutrino masses.
Those were based on a sharpened version of the Weak Gravity Conjecture as
applied to compactifications of the SM to lower dimensions. We argue that the
same line of reasoning implies that for fixed values of $\Lambda_4$ and the
Yukawa coupling of the lightest neutrino $Y_{\nu_1}$, the EW scale is bounded
above. This is a trivial consequence of neutrino masses depending on the Higgs
vev. In the case of massive Majorana neutrinos with a see-saw mechanism
associated to a large scale $M\simeq 10^{10-14}$ GeV and $Y_{\nu_1}\simeq
10^{-3}$, one obtains that the EW scale cannot exceed $M_{EW}\lesssim
10^2-10^4$ GeV. From this point of view, the delicate fine-tuning required to
get a small EW scale would be a mirage, since parameters yielding higher EW
scales would be in the swampland and would not count as possible consistent
theories. This would bring a new perspective into the issue of the EW
hierarchy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05829</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Prokhorov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraghan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A search for cyclical sources of gamma-ray emission on the period range
  from days to years in the Fermi-LAT sky</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1742</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A systematic search for cyclical sources of gamma-ray emission on the period
range from days to years in the Fermi-LAT sky is performed. Looking for
cyclical emission, the sky is binned into equal-area pixels and the generalised
Lomb-Scargle periodogram is computed for each of these pixels. The search on
the period range between 2.5 and 30 days in the Galactic plane confirms
periodicities of three binaries, LSI +61 303, LS 5039, and 1FGL J1018.6-5856.
The all-sky search on the period range between 30 days and 2.5 years confirms
periodicities of three blazars, PG 1553+113, PKS 2155-304, and BL Lacertae.
Evidence for periodic behaviours of four blazars, 4C +01.28, S5 0716+71, PKS
0805-07, and PKS 2052-47, are presented. Three of these blazars, 4C +01.28, PKS
0805-07, and PKS 2052-47, are located at high redshifts. These three sources
are potential candidates to binary systems of supermassive black holes provided
that major galaxy mergers are more frequent and that galaxies are more gas-rich
at high redshifts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05868</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hongjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xuan</keyname><forenames>Minjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Guosheng</forenames></author></authors><title>From anti-perovskite to double anti-perovskite: lattice chemistry basis
  for super-fast transportation of Li+ ions in cubic solid lithium
  halogen-chalcogenides</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a materials genome approach on the basis of the density functional
theory, we have formulated a new class of inorganic electrolytes for fast
diffusion of Li+ ions, through fine-tuning of lattice chemistry of
anti-perovskite structures. Systematic modelling has been carried out to
elaborate the structural stability and ion transportation characteristics in
Li3AX based cubic anti-perovskite, through alloying on the chalcogen lattice
site (A) and alternative occupancy of the halogen site (X). In addition to
identifying effective ways for reduction of diffusion barriers for Li+ ions in
anti-perovskite phases via suitable designation of lattice occupancy, the
current theoretical study leads to discovery and synthesis of a new phase with
a double-anti-perovskite structure, Li6OSI2 (or Li3O0.5S0.5I). Such a new
compound is of fairly low activation barrier for Li+ diffusion, together with a
wide energy band gap to hinder conduction of electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05876</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scalo</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hesselink</keyname><forenames>Lambertus</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk viscosity model for near-equilibrium acoustic wave attenuation</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Submitted manuscript</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Acoustic wave attenuation due to vibrational and rotational molecular
relaxation, under simplifying assumptions of near-thermodynamic equilibrium and
absence of molecular dissociations, can be accounted for by specifying a bulk
viscosity coefficient $\mu_B$. In this paper, we propose a simple
frequency-dependent bulk viscosity model which, under such assumptions,
accurately captures wave attenuation rates from infrasonic to ultrasonic
frequencies in Navier--Stokes and lattice Boltzmann simulations. The proposed
model can be extended to any gas mixture for which molecular relaxation
timescales and attenuation measurements are available. The performance of the
model is assessed for air by varying the base temperature, pressure, relative
humidity $h_r$, and acoustic frequency. Since the vibrational relaxation
timescales of oxygen and nitrogen are a function of humidity, for certain
frequencies an intermediate value of $h_r$ can be found which maximizes
$\mu_B$. The contribution to bulk viscosity due to rotational relaxation is
verified to be a function of temperature, confirming recent findings in the
literature. While $\mu_B$ decreases with higher frequencies, its effects on
wave attenuation become more significant, as shown via a dimensionless
analysis. The proposed bulk viscosity model is designed for frequency-domain
linear acoustic formulations but is also extensible to time-domain simulations
of narrow-band frequency content flows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05887</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Weatherall</keyname><forenames>James Owen</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical Spacetime Structure</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 3 figures. Prepared for the Routledge Companion to
  Philosophy of Physics, edited by Eleanor Knox and Alastair Wilson</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I discuss several issues related to &quot;classical&quot; spacetime structure. I review
Galilean, Newtonian, and Leibnizian spacetimes, and briefly describe more
recent developments. The target audience is undergraduates and early graduate
students in philosophy; the presentation avoids mathematical formalism as much
as possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05894</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varn</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crutchfield</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Islands in the Gap: Intertwined Transport and Localization in
  Structurally Complex Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci nlin.CD quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, supplementary material;
  http://csc.ucdavis.edu/~cmg/compmech/pubs/talisdm.htm</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Localized waves in disordered one-dimensional materials have been studied for
decades, including white-noise and correlated disorder, as well as
quasi-periodic disorder. How these wave phenomena relate to those in
crystalline (periodic ordered) materials---arguably the better understood
setting---has been a mystery ever since Anderson discovered disorder-induced
localization. Nonetheless, together these revolutionized materials science and
technology and led to new physics far beyond the solid state. We introduce a
broad family of structurally complex materials---chaotic crystals---that
interpolate between these organizational extremes---systematically spanning
periodic structures and random disorder. Within the family one can tune the
degree of disorder to sweep through an intermediate structurally disordered
region between two periodic lattices. This reveals new transport and
localization phenomena reflected in a rich array of energy-dependent
localization degree and density of states. In particular, strong localization
is observed even with a very low degree of disorder. Moreover, markedly
enhanced localization and delocalization coexist in a very narrow range of
energies. Most notably, beyond the simply smoothed bands found in previous
disorder studies, islands of transport emerge in band gaps and sharp band
boundaries persist in the presence of substantial disorder. Finally, the family
of materials comes with rather direct specifications of how to assemble the
requisite material organizations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05901</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Hirvijoki</keyname><forenames>Eero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brizard</keyname><forenames>Alain J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfefferl&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Differential formulation of the gyrokinetic Landau operator</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Plasma Physics, Volume 83, Issue 1, February 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0022377816001203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Subsequent to the recent rigorous derivation of an energetically consistent
gyrokinetic collision operator in the so-called Landau representation, this
paper investigates the possibility of finding a differential formulation of the
gyrokinetic Landau collision operator. It is observed that, while a
differential formulation is possible in the gyrokinetic phase space, reduction
of the resulting system of partial differential equations to five dimensions
via gyroaveraging poses a challenge. Based on the present work, it is likely
that the gyrocentre analogues of the Rosenbluth-MacDonald-Judd potential
functions must be kept gyroangle dependent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05903</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Yaqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molinero</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palego</keyname><forenames>Cristiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>James CM</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldsmith</keyname><forenames>Charles L</forenames></author></authors><title>Intermodulation distortion of actuated MEMS capacitive switches</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Microwave Measurement Conference (ARFTG), 2013 81st ARFTG</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ARFTG.2013.6579053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the first time, intermodulation distortion of micro-electromechanical
capacitive switches in the actuated state was analyzed both theoretically and
experimentally. The distortion, although higher than that of switches in the
suspended state, was found to decrease with increasing bias voltage but to
depend weakly on modulation frequencies between 55 kHz and 1.1 MHz. This
dependence could be explained by the orders-of-magnitude increase of the spring
constant when the switches were actuated. Additionally, the analysis suggested
that increasing the spring constant and decreasing the contact roughness could
improve the linearity of actuated switches. These results are critical to
micro-electromechanical capacitive switches used in tuners, filters, phase
shifters, etc. where the linearity of both suspended and actuated states are
critical.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05908</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Springer</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of production cross sections, using stacked targets at the
  88&quot; Cyclotron with focus on $^{\rm nat}{\rm Fe}(\rm p,x)^{51}{\rm Mn}$</title><categories>nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the investigation of the production cross section of $\ ^{51}\rm Mn$ off
of $\ ^{\rm nat}\rm Fe$ in mind, two stacked target experiments were conducted
at the Berkeley Lab 88-Inch Cyclotron. Proton beams with energies of $25$ and
$55\,\rm MeV$ result in a total of 14 data points for various reactions. Gamma
spectra of the activated foils were taken and analyzed, then cross sections
calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05927</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Fessler</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Medical image reconstruction: a brief overview of past milestones and
  future directions</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Part of a submission to IEEE Signal Processing Magazine</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper briefly reviews past milestones in the field of medical image
reconstruction and describes some future directions. It is part of an overview
paper on &quot;open problems in signal processing&quot; that will appear in IEEE Signal
Processing Magazine, but presented here with citations and equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05942</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobakhidze</keyname><forenames>Archil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Shelley</forenames></author></authors><title>Scale Invariant Top Condensate</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scale invariant model of dynamical electroweak symmetry breaking
via top condensation within the minimal top condensate see-saw model. The
classical scale invariance is realized nonlinearly by introducing conformal
compensator scalar field, the dilaton, which plays crucial role in successful
predictions for the Higgs boson. The dilaton mass and its mixing with the
composite Higgs boson appears only at 2-loop level, both being proportional to
the hierarchy between the electroweak and compositeness scales, $\propto
v/\Lambda$. The mass scales in our model are generated via the mechanism of
dimensional transmutation and the hierarchy $v/\Lambda \ll 1$ is radiatively
stable, thus resolving the fine-tuning problem of the standard top condensate
models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05951</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Nairat</keyname><forenames>Mazen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voelz</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Compton Scattering of a Twisted Light</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The variation of photonic orbital angular momentum at Compton scattering is
characterized. We determine scattering matrix of a twisted light based on the
fundamental conservation of orbital angular momenta. Numerical values for two
different twisted light modes: Laguerre Gaussian and Bessel Gaussian, are
generated and illustrated. Our analysis indicate that states of photonic
orbital angular momentum are highly changeable at wide angle scattering but
more consistent at small angle scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05975</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>HosseinKhani</keyname><forenames>Zohreh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hajabdollahi</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karimi</keyname><forenames>Nader</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soroushmehr</keyname><forenames>S. M. Reza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirani</keyname><forenames>Shahram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samavi</keyname><forenames>Shadrokh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Najarian</keyname><forenames>Kayvan</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-Time Impulse Noise Removal from MR Images for Radiosurgery
  Applications</title><categories>cs.AR physics.med-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the recent years image processing techniques are used as a tool to improve
detection and diagnostic capabilities in the medical applications. Medical
applications have been so much affected by these techniques which some of them
are embedded in medical instruments such as MRI, CT and other medical devices.
Among these techniques, medical image enhancement algorithms play an essential
role in removal of the noise which can be produced by medical instruments and
during image transfer. It has been proved that impulse noise is a major type of
noise, which is produced during medical operations, such as MRI, CT, and
angiography, by their image capturing devices. An embeddable hardware module
which is able to denoise medical images before and during surgical operations
could be very helpful. In this paper an accurate algorithm is proposed for
real-time removal of impulse noise in medical images. All image blocks are
divided into three categories of edge, smooth, and disordered areas. A
different reconstruction method is applied to each category of blocks for the
purpose of noise removal. The proposed method is tested on MR images.
Simulation results show acceptable denoising accuracy for various levels of
noise. Also an FPAG implementation of our denoising algorithm shows acceptable
hardware resource utilization. Hence, the algorithm is suitable for embedding
in medical hardware instruments such as radiosurgery devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05981</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Umemoto</keyname><forenames>Tomofumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamidani</keyname><forenames>Tetsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuno</keyname><forenames>Nario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuo</keyname><forenames>Mitsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torii</keyname><forenames>Kazufumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tosaki</keyname><forenames>Tomoka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohno</keyname><forenames>Mikito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuriki</keyname><forenames>Mika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuda</keyname><forenames>Yuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirota</keyname><forenames>Akihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohashi</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamagishi</keyname><forenames>Mitsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Handa</keyname><forenames>Toshihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakanishi</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omodaka</keyname><forenames>Toshihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koide</keyname><forenames>Nagito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Naoko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>Toshikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokuda</keyname><forenames>Kazuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seta</keyname><forenames>Masumichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Yukinori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tachihara</keyname><forenames>Kengo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sano</keyname><forenames>Hidetoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hattori</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onodera</keyname><forenames>Sachiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oasa</keyname><forenames>Yumiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamegai</keyname><forenames>Kazuhisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuboi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sofue</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higuchi</keyname><forenames>Aya E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chibueze</keyname><forenames>James O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuno</keyname><forenames>Norikazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honma</keyname><forenames>Mareki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muller</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inoue</keyname><forenames>Tsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morokuma-Matsui</keyname><forenames>Kana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shinnaga</keyname><forenames>Hiroko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ozawa</keyname><forenames>Takeaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshiike</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costes</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuwahara</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author></authors><title>FOREST Unbiased Galactic plane Imaging survey with the Nobeyama 45-m
  telescope (FUGIN) I: Project Overview and Initial Results</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 14 figures, accepted for publication in PASJ</comments><doi>10.1093/pasj/psx061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The FOREST Unbiased Galactic plane Imaging survey with the Nobeyama 45-m
telescope (FUGIN) project is one of the legacy projects using the new
multi-beam FOREST receiver installed on the Nobeyama 45-m telescope. This
project aims to investigate the distribution, kinematics, and physical
properties of both diffuse and dense molecular gas in the Galaxy at once by
observing 12CO, 13CO, and C18O J=1-0 lines simultaneously. The mapping regions
are a part of the 1st quadrant (10d &lt; l &lt; 50d, |b| &lt; 1d) and the 3rd quadrant
(198d &lt; l &lt;236d, |b| &lt; 1d) of the Galaxy, where spiral arms, bar structure, and
the molecular gas ring are included. This survey achieves the highest angular
resolution to date (~20&quot;) for the Galactic plane survey in the CO J=1-0 lines,
which makes it possible to find dense clumps located farther away than the
previous surveys. FUGIN will provide us with an invaluable dataset for
investigating the physics of the galactic interstellar medium (ISM),
particularly the evolution of interstellar gas covering galactic scale
structures to the internal structures of giant molecular clouds, such as small
filament/clump/core. We present an overview of the FUGIN project, observation
plan, and initial results, which reveal wide-field and detailed structures of
molecular clouds, such as entangled filaments that have not been obvious in
previous surveys, and large-scale kinematics of molecular gas such as spiral
arms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05988</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoodi</keyname><forenames>Korosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>Bruce J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigolini</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Dynamical Foundation of Multifractality</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The crucial aspect of this demonstration is the discovery of renewal events,
hidden in the computed dynamics of a multifractal metronome, which enables the
replacement of the phenomenon of strong anticipation with a time delayed
cross-correlation between the driven and the driving metronome. We establish
that the phenomenon of complexity matching, which is the theme of an increasing
number of research groups, has two distinct measures. One measure is the
sensitivity of a complex system to environmental multi-fractality; another is
the level of information transfer, between two complex networks at criticality.
The cross-correlation function is evaluated in the ergodic long-time limit, but
its delayed maximal value is the signature of information transfer occurring in
the non ergodic short-time regime. It is shown that a more complex system
transfers its multifractality to a less complex system while the reverse case
is not possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06009</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>Chenoa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hurley-Walker</keyname><forenames>Natasha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunningham</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Paul A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hancock</keyname><forenames>Paul J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wayth</keyname><forenames>Randall</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jordan</keyname><forenames>Christopher H.</forenames></author></authors><title>A First Look for Molecules between 103 and 133 MHz using the Murchison
  Widefield Array</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Accepted MNRAS, 13 pages, 6 figures, 3 Tables</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1838</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We detail and present results from a pilot study to assess the feasibility of
detecting molecular lines at low radio frequencies. We observed a 400 square
degree region centred on the Galactic Centre with the Murchison Widefield Array
(MWA) between 103 and 133\,MHz targeting 28 known molecular species that have
significant transitions. The results of this survey yield tentative detections
of nitric oxide (NO) and the mercapto radical (SH). Both of these molecules
appear to be associated with evolved stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06010</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Alesini</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babusci</keyname><forenames>Danilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Gioacchino</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamanna</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ligi</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>The KLASH Proposal</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex hep-ph</categories><report-no>INFN-17-14/LNF</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a search of galactic axions with mass about 0.2 microeV using a
large volume resonant cavity, about 50 m^3, cooled down to 4 K and immersed in
a moderate axial magnetic field of about 0.6 T generated inside the
superconducting magnet of the KLOE experiment located at the National
Laboratory of Frascati of INFN. This experiment, called KLASH (KLoe magnet for
Axion SearcH) in the following, has a potential sensitivity on the
axion-to-photon coupling, g_agg, of about 6x10^-17 GeV-1, reaching the region
predicted by KSVZ and DFSZ models of QCD axions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06013</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Jyotirmay Das</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debnath</keyname><forenames>Ujjal</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical System Analysis of Interacting Hessence Dark Energy in $f(T)$
  Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, Accepted in AHEP</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we have carried on dynamical system analysis of hessence field
coupling with dark matter in $f(T)$ gravity. We have analysed the critical
points due to autonomous system. The resulting autonomous system is non-linear.
So, we have approached via the the theory of non-linear dynamical system.We
have noticed very few papers are devoted to this kind of study.Maximum works in
literature are done treating the dynamical system as done in linear dynamical
analysis, which are unable to predict correct evolution.Our work is totally
different from those kind of works.We have used theory of non-linear dynamical
system theory,developed till date,in our analysis.This approach gives totally
different stable solutions, in contrast what the linear analysis would have
predicted. We have discussed the stability analysis in details due to
exponential potential through computational method in tabular form and analyzed
the evolution of the universe. Some plots are drawn to investigate the
behaviour of the system (this plotting technique is different from usual phase
plot, and devised by us.). Interestingly, the analysis shows the universe may
resemble the `cosmological constant' like evolution (i.e., $\Lambda$CDM model
is a subset of the solution set). Also, all the fixed points of our model are
able to avoid Big rip singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06026</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06026</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Weller</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yilmaz</keyname><forenames>Arzu</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;bler</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;w</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>High vacuum compatible fiber feedthrough for hot alkali vapor cells</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>4 Pages, 4 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Optics Vol. 56, Issue 5, pp. 1546-1549 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/AO.56.001546</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a method to produce vacuum tight, metal free, bakeable and
alkali compatible feedthroughs for optical fibers. The manufacturing process
mainly relies on encasing fibers made of fused silica with glass materials with
lower melting points by heating. We analyze the vacuum and optical performance
of the devices by various methods including helium leak checking and several
spectroscopic schemes, among others electromagnetically induced transparency
involving Rydberg states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06035</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Pym</keyname><forenames>Brent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schedler</keyname><forenames>Travis</forenames></author></authors><title>Holonomic Poisson manifolds and deformations of elliptic algebras</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.MP math.QA math.SG</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a natural nondegeneracy condition for Poisson structures, called
holonomicity, which is closely related to the notion of a log symplectic form.
Holonomic Poisson manifolds are privileged by the fact that their deformation
spaces are as finite-dimensional as one could ever hope: the corresponding
derived deformation complex is a perverse sheaf. We develop some basic
structural features of these manifolds, highlighting the role played by the
divergence of Hamiltonian vector fields. As an application, we establish the
deformation-invariance of certain families of Poisson manifolds defined by
Feigin and Odesskii, along with the &quot;elliptic algebras&quot; that quantize them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06041</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jeantet</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chassagneux</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claude</keyname><forenames>Th&#xe9;o</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roussignol</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauret</keyname><forenames>Jean-S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichel</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploiting one-dimensional exciton-phonon coupling for tunable and
  efficient single-photon generation with a carbon nanotube</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Letters 17, 4184 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b00973</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Condensed-matter emitters offer enriched cavity quantum electrodynamical
effects due to the coupling to external degrees of freedom. In the case of
carbon nanotubes a very peculiar coupling between localized excitons and the
one-dimensional acoustic phonon modes can be achieved, which gives rise to
pronounced phonon wings in the luminescence spectrum. By coupling an individual
nanotube to a tunable optical micro-cavity, we show that this peculiar
exciton-phonon coupling is a valuable resource to enlarge the tuning range of
the single-photon source while keeping an excellent exciton-photon coupling
efficiency and spectral purity. Using the unique flexibility of our scanning
fiber cavity, we are able to measure the efficiency spectrum of the very same
nanotube in the Purcell regime for several mode volumes. Whereas this
efficiency spectrum looks very much like the free-space luminescence spectrum
when the Purcell factor is small (large mode volume), we show that the
deformation of this spectrum at lower mode volumes can be traced back to the
strength of the exciton-photon coupling. It shows an enhanced efficiency on the
red wing that arises from the asymmetry of the incoherent energy exchange
processes between the exciton and the cavity. This allows us to obtain a tuning
range up to several hundred times the spectral width of the source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06048</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Wenjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Meizhen</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher Order Elastic Instabilities of Metals: From Atom to Continuum
  Level</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>30 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strain-based theory on elastic instabilities is being widely employed for
studying onset of plasticity, phase transition or melting in crystals. And size
effects, observed in nano-materials or solids under dynamic loadings, needs to
account for contributions from strain gradient. However, the strain gradient
based higher order elastic theories on the elastic instabilities are not well
established to enable one to predict high order instabilities of solids
directly at atom level. In present work, a general continuum theory for higher
order elastic instabilities is established and justified by developing an
equivalent description at atom level. Our results show that mechanical
instability of solids, triggered by either strain or strain gradient, is
determined by a simple stability condition consisting of strain or strain
gradient related elastic constants. With the atom-level description of the
higher order elasticity, the strain-gradient elastic constants could be
directly obtained by a molecular statics procedure and then serve as inputs of
the stability condition. In this way, mechanical instabilities of three metals,
i.e., copper, aluminum and iron, are predicted. Alternatively, ramp compression
technique by nonequilibrium molecular dynamics (NEMD) simulations is employed
to study the higher order instabilities of the three metals. The predicted
critical strains at onset of instabilities agree well with the results from the
NEMD simulations for all the metals. Since the only inputs for the established
higher order elastic theory are the same as atomic simulations, i.e., atomic
potentials and structures of solids, the established theory is completely
equivalent to empirical-potential based atomic simulations methods, at least,
for crystals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06049</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Okumura</keyname><forenames>Ko</forenames></author></authors><title>Viscous dynamics of drops and bubbles in Hele-Shaw cells: drainage, drag
  friction, coalescence, and bursting</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>34 pages, 16 figures, accepted for publication in Adv. Colloid
  Interface Sci</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this review article, we discuss recent studies on drops and bubbles in
Hele-Shaw cells, focusing on how scaling laws exhibit crossovers from the
three-dimensional counterparts and focusing on topics in which viscosity plays
an important role. By virtue of progresses in analytical theory and high-speed
imaging, dynamics of drops and bubbles have actively been studied with the aid
of scaling arguments. However, compared with three dimensional problems,
studies on the corresponding problems in Hele-Shaw cells are still limited.
This review demonstrates that the effect of confinement in the Hele-Shaw cell
introduces new physics allowing different scaling regimes to appear. For this
purpose, we discuss various examples that are potentially important for
industrial applications handling drops and bubbles in confined spaces by
showing agreement between experiments and scaling theories. As a result, this
review provides a collection of problems in hydrodynamics that may be
analytically solved or that may be worth studying numerically in the near
future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06074</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Benoist</keyname><forenames>Tristan</forenames><affiliation>IMT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gamboa</keyname><forenames>F</forenames><affiliation>IMT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pellegrini</keyname><forenames>C</forenames><affiliation>IMT</affiliation></author></authors><title>Quantum non demolition measurements: parameter estimation for mixtures
  of multinomials</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP math.ST stat.TH</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Quantum Non Demolition measurements, the sequence of observations is
distributed as a mixture of multinomial random variables. Parameters of the
dynamics are naturally encoded into this family of distributions. We show the
local asymptotic mixed normality of the underlying statistical model and the
consistency of the maximum likelihood estimator. Furthermore, we prove the
asymptotic optimality of this estimator as it saturates the usual Cram\'er Rao
bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06086</id><created>2017-07-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Aguilar-Maldonado</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escudero</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties of the intermetallic compound HoCuBi</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted in Journal of Superconductivity and Novel Magnetism</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an investigation on the intermetallic compound formed by HoCuBi
which has a monoclinic crystalline P2 structure with lattice parameters; a =
9:8012(26)A, b = 6:0647(6)A, c = 6:1663(13)A. In this report we performed an
extensive analysis of the magnetic characteristics, specific heat at low
temperature mainly close to the region of the observed antiferromagnetic
transition with Neel temperature about 7 K, and to the field induced
spin-crossover; the metamagnetic transition typically observed in
antiferromagnetic systems by measurements of M-H, (Magnetization - Magnetic
Field) at low temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06099</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Coaquira</keyname><forenames>L. Le&#xf3;n F&#xe9;nix J. A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>M. A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goya</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mantilla</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sousa</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valladares</keyname><forenames>L. de los Santos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>C. H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morais</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural and magnetic properties of core-shell Au/Fe3O4 nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Reps. 2017. 7:41732</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep41732</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a systematic study of core-shell Au/Fe_3O_4 nanoparticles produced
by thermal decomposition under mild conditions. The morphology and crystal
structure of the nanoparticles revealed the presence of Au core of &lt;d&gt; =
(6.9\pm 1.0) nm surrounded by Fe_3O_4 shell with a thickness of ~3.5 nm,
epitaxially grown onto the Au core surface. The Au/Fe_3O_4 core-shell structure
was demonstrated by high angle annular dark field scanning transmission
electron microscopy analysis. The magnetite shell grown on top of the Au
nanoparticle displayed a thermal blocking state at temperatures below T_B = 59
K and a relaxed state well above T_B. Remarkably, an exchange bias effect was
observed when cooling down the samples below room temperature under an external
magnetic field. Moreover, the exchange bias field (H_{EX}) started to appear at
T~40 K and its value increased by decreasing the temperature. This effect has
been assigned to the interaction of spins located in the magnetically
disordered regions (in the inner and outer surface of the Fe_3O_4 shell) and
spins located in the ordered region of the Fe_3O_4 shell.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06131</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ried</keyname><forenames>Katja</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacLean</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spekkens</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Resch</keyname><forenames>Kevin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum to classical transitions in causal relations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev A. 95 062102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The landscape of causal relations that can hold among a set of systems in
quantum theory is richer than in classical physics. In particular, a pair of
time-ordered systems can be related as cause and effect or as the effects of a
common cause, and each of these causal mechanisms can be coherent or not.
Furthermore, one can combine these mechanisms in different ways: by
probabilistically realizing either one or the other or by having both act
simultaneously (termed a physical mixture). In the latter case, it is possible
for the two mechanisms to be combined quantum-coherently. Previous work has
shown how to experimentally realize one example of each class of possible
causal relations. Here, we make a theoretical and experimental study of the
transitions between these classes. In particular, for each of the two distinct
types of coherence that can exist in mixtures of common-cause and cause-effect
relations--coherence in the individual causal pathways and coherence in the way
the causal relations are combined--we determine how it degrades under noise and
we confirm these expectations in a quantum-optical experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06135</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Szenes</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe1;nhelyi</keyname><forenames>Bal&#xe1;zs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csendes</keyname><forenames>Tibor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szab&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>G&#xe1;bor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csete</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;ria</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing diamond fluorescence via optimized nanorod dimer
  configurations</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical response of silicon (SiV) and nitrogen (NV) vacancy diamond color
centers coupled to silver and gold nanorod dimers was numerically inspected.
Optimization of the coupled emitter - nanorod dimer configurations was
performed to attain the highest possible fluorescence enhancement by enhancing
the excitation and emission of color centers simultaneously through plasmonic
antenna resonances. To minimize losses conditional optimization was realized by
setting a criterion regarding the minimum quantum efficiency of the coupled
system (cQE). Restricted symmetric and allowed asymmetric antenna designs were
also inspected to prove the potential advantages of asymmetric configurations
tuneability. Among all inspected systems the highest 2.59*10^8 fluorescence
enhancement with 46.08% cQE was achieved in case of NV color center coupled to
asymmetric silver nanoantenna dimer. This is 3.17-times larger than the
enhancement in corresponding symmetric configuration, which has larger 68.52%
cQE. In case of SiV color center the highest 1.04*10^8 fluorescence enhancement
with 37.83% cQE was achieved via asymmetric silver nanoantenna dimer. This is
1.06-times larger than the enhancement in the corresponding symmetric
configuration, which has larger 57.46% cQE. The highest fluorescence
enhancement achieved by gold nanorods is 4.75*10^4 with 21.8% cQE, which was
shown in case of SiV color center coupled to asymmetric dimer. The attained
enhancement is 8.48- (92.42-) times larger than the fluorescence enhancement
achievable via symmetric (asymmetric) gold nanorod dimer coupled to SiV (NV)
color center.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06136</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ye&#x15f;ilta&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zlem</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac Equation on the Torus and Rationally Extended Trigonometric
  Potentials within Supersymmetric QM</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exact solutions of the (2+1) dimensional Dirac equation on the torus and
the new extension and generalization of the trigonometric Poschl-Teller
potential families in terms of the torus parameters are obtained.
Supersymmetric quantum mechanical techniques are used to get the extended
potentials when the inner and outer radii of the torus are both equal and
inequal. In addition, using the aspects of the Lie algebraic approaches, the
iso(2; 1) algebra is also applied to the system where we have arrived at the
spectrum solutions of the extended potentials using the Casimir operator that
matches with the results of the exact solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06141</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Fajman</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joudioux</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;mie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smulevici</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author></authors><title>The Stability of the Minkowski space for the Einstein-Vlasov system</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>139 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the global stability of the Minkowski space viewed as the trivial
solution of the Einstein-Vlasov system. To estimate the Vlasov field, we use
the vector field and modified vector field techniques developed in [FJS15;
FJS17]. In particular, the initial support in the velocity variable does not
need to be compact. To control the effect of the large velocities, we identify
and exploit several structural properties of the Vlasov equation to prove that
the worst non-linear terms in the Vlasov equation either enjoy a form of the
null condition or can be controlled using the wave coordinate gauge. The basic
propagation estimates for the Vlasov field are then obtained using only weak
interior decay for the metric components. Since some of the error terms are not
time-integrable, several hierarchies in the commuted equations are exploited to
close the top order estimates. For the Einstein equations, we use wave
coordinates and the main new difficulty arises from the commutation of the
energy-momentum tensor, which needs to be rewritten using the modified vector
fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06146</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiangyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Huanyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Chong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shining</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-focusing and the Talbot effect in conformal transformation optics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>24 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 033902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.033902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transformation optics (TO) has been used to propose various novel optical
devices. With the help of metamaterials, several intriguing designs, such as
invisibility cloaks, have been implemented. However, as the basic units should
be much smaller than the working wavelengths to achieve the effective material
parameters, and the sizes of devices should be much larger than the wavelengths
of illumination to work within the light-ray approximation, it is a big
challenge to implement an experimental system that works simultaneously for
both geometric optics and wave optics. In this letter, by using a
gradient-index micro-structured optical waveguide, we realize a device of
conformal transformation optics (CTO) and demonstrate its self-focusing
property for geometry optics and Talbot effect for wave optics. In addition,
the Talbot effect in such a system has a potential application to transfer
digital information without diffraction. Our findings demonstrate the photon
controlling ability of CTO in a feasible experiment system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06150</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Andrianov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrianov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espriu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putilova</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iakubovich</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Decays of light mesons triggered by chiral chemical potential</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, Talk given on the conference &quot;Excited QCD&quot; (Sintra,
  Portugal,7 - 13 May 2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light meson ( $\pi,\ \sigma,\ a_0$) properties in the environment with chiral
imbalance are analyzed with the help of meson effective Lagrangian associated
with QCD. New spatial parity violating decays of scalar mesons arise as a
result of mixing of $\pi$ and $a_0$ mesons under influence of chiral charge
density. The pion electromagnetic form-factor gets an unusual parity-odd
contribution. Pion effective masses depend on their velocities and may vanish
in flight. The possible determination of chiral chemical potential in heavy ion
collisions based on above mentioned phenomena is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06162</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalization of Zak's phase for lattice models with non-centered
  inversion symmetry axis</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how the presence of inversion symmetry in a one-dimensional (1D)
lattice model is not a sufficient condition for a quantized Zak's phase. This
is only the case when the inversion axis is at the center of the unit cell.
When the inversion axis is not at the center, the modified inversion operator
within the unit cell gains a k-dependence in some of its matrix elements which
adds a correction term to the usual Zak's phase expression1, making it in
general deviate from its quantized value. A general expression that recovers a
quantized Zak's phase in a lattice model with a unit cell of arbitrary size and
arbitrarily positioned inversion axis is provided in this paper, which relates
the quantized value with the eigenvalues of a modified parity operator at the
inversion invariant momenta.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06181</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Arjona</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominguez-Adame</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Bloch oscillations in optical waveguide arrays with arbitrary
  long-range coupling</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.other</categories><comments>Accepted in Journal of Optics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find the exact Bloch oscillations in zigzag arrays of curved optical
waveguides under the influence of arbitrary long-range coupling. The curvature
induces a linear transverse potential gradient in the equations of the light
evolution. In the case of arrays with second-order coupling, steady states can
be obtained as linear combinations of Bessel functions of integer index. The
corresponding eigenvalues are equally spaced and form the well-known
Wannier-Stark ladder, the spacing being independent of the second-order
coupling. We also solve exactly the wave packet dynamics and compare it with
experimental results. Accordingly we find that a broad optical pulse performs
Bloch oscillations. Frequency doubling of the fundamental Bloch frequency sets
up at finite values of the second-order coupling. On the contrary when a single
waveguide is initially excited, a breathing mode is activated with no signature
of Bloch oscillations. We present a generalization of our results to waveguide
arrays subject to long-range coupling. In the general case the centroid of the
wave packet shows the occurrence of multiples of the Bloch frequency up to the
order of the interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06190</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>T-H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juska</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moroni</keyname><forenames>S. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pescaglini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gocalinska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelucchi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Engineering of selective carrier injection in patterned arrays of
  single-quantum-dot entangled photon light-emitting diodes</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 10, 782, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2016.203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scalability and foundry compatibility (as for example in conventional silicon
based integrated computer processors) in developing quantum technologies are
exceptional challenges facing current research. Here we introduce a quantum
photonic technology potentially enabling large scale fabrication of
semiconductor-based, site-controlled, scalable arrays of electrically driven
sources of polarization-entangled photons, with the potential to encode quantum
information. The design of the sources is based on quantum dots grown in
micron-sized pyramidal recesses along the crystallographic direction (111)B
theoretically ensuring high symmetry of the quantum dots - the condition for
actual bright entangled photon emission. A selective electric injection scheme
in these non-planar structures allows obtaining a high density of
light-emitting diodes, with some producing entangled photon pairs also
violating Bell's inequality. Compatibility with semiconductor fabrication
technology, good reproducibility and control of the position make these devices
attractive candidates for integrated photonic circuits for quantum information
processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06201</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Galvan</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic velocities in quantum and Bohmian mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the relations between the asymptotic velocity operators of a
quantum system and the asymptotic velocities of the associated Bohmian
trajectories are studied. In particular it is proved that, under suitable
conditions of asymptotic regularity, the probability distribution of the
asymptotic velocities of the Bohmian trajectories is equal to the one derived
from the asymptotic velocity operators of the associated quantum system. It is
also shown that in the relativistic case the distribution of the asymptotic
velocities of the Bohmian trajectories is covariant, or equivalently, it does
not depend on a preferred foliation (it is well known that this is not the case
for the structure of the Bohmian trajectories or for their spatial distribution
at a finite time). This result allows us to develop a covariant formulation of
relativistic Bohmian mechanics; such a formulation is proposed here merely as a
mathematical possibility, while its empirical adequacy will be discussed
elsewhere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06202</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Britt</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Humble</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Instruction Set Architectures for Quantum Processing Units</title><categories>cs.ET quant-ph</categories><comments>To be published in the proceedings in the International Super
  Computing Conference 2017 publication</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Progress in quantum computing hardware raises questions about how these
devices can be controlled, programmed, and integrated with existing
computational workflows. We briefly describe several prominent quantum
computational models, their associated quantum processing units (QPUs), and the
adoption of these devices as accelerators within high-performance computing
systems. Emphasizing the interface to the QPU, we analyze instruction set
architectures based on reduced and complex instruction sets, i.e., RISC and
CISC architectures. We clarify the role of conventional constraints on memory
addressing and instruction widths within the quantum computing context.
Finally, we examine existing quantum computing platforms, including the D-Wave
2000Q and IBM Quantum Experience, within the context of future ISA development
and HPC needs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
