<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:33:16Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-24" from="2017-07-24" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0708.3716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0708.3716</id><created>2007-08-28</created><updated>2008-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author></authors><title>The Impact of a Percolating IGM on Redshifted 21 cm Observations of
  Quasar HII Regions</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. Significant
  revision of sensitivity analysis</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2008) 386 (3): 1683-1694</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.13159.x</doi><abstract>  We assess the impact of inhomogeneous reionization on detection of HII
regions surrounding luminous high redshift quasars using planned low frequency
radio telescopes. Our approach is to implement a semi-numerical scheme to
calculate the 3-dimensional structure of ionized regions surrounding a massive
halo at high redshift, including the ionizing influence of a luminous quasar.
As part of our analysis we briefly contrast our scheme with published
semi-numerical models. We calculate mock 21cm spectra along the line of sight
towards high redshift quasars, and estimate the ability of the planned
Murchison Widefield Array to detect the presence of HII regions. The
signal-to-noise for detection will drop as the characteristic bubble size grows
during reionization because the quasar's influence becomes less prominent.
However, quasars will imprint a detectable signature on observed 21cm spectra
that is distinct from a region of typical IGM. At epochs where the mean
hydrogen neutral fraction is ~30% or greater we find that neutral gas in the
IGM surrounding a single quasar will be detectable (at a significance of 5
sigma) within 100 hour integrations in more than 50% of cases. 1000 hour
integrations will be required to detect a smaller neutral fraction of 15% in
more than 50% of cases. A highly significant detection will be possible in only
100 hours for a stack of 10 smaller 3 proper Mpc HII regions. The accurate
measurement of the global average neutral fraction (&lt;x_HI&gt;) will be limited by
systematic fluctuations between lines of sight for single HII regions. We
estimate the accuracy with which the global neutral fraction could be measured
from a single HII region to be 50%, 30% and 20% for &lt;x_HI&gt; ~ 0.15, 0.3 and 0.5
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0805.0038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0805.0038</id><created>2008-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrovic</keyname><forenames>Nada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of Galactic foreground subtraction on redshifted 21-cm
  observations of quasar HII regions</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2008) 390 (4): 1496-1504</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2008.13798.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assess the impact of Galactic synchrotron foreground removal on the
observation of high-redshift quasar HII regions in redshifted 21-cm emission.
We consider the case where a quasar is observed in an intergalactic medium
(IGM) whose ionisation structure evolves slowly relative to the light crossing
time of the HII region, as well as the case where the evolution is rapid. The
latter case is expected towards the end of the reionisation era where the
highest redshift luminous quasars will be observed. In the absence of
foregrounds the fraction of neutral hydrogen in the IGM could be measured
directly from the contrast between the HII region and surrounding IGM. However,
we find that foreground removal lowers the observed contrast between the HII
region and the IGM. This indicates that measurement of the neutral fraction
would require modelling to correct for this systematic effect. On the other
hand, foreground removal does not modify the most prominent features of the
21-cm maps. Using a simple algorithm we demonstrate that measurements of the
size and shape of observed HII regions will not be affected by continuum
foreground removal. Moreover, measurements of these quantities will not be
adversely affected by the presence of a rapidly evolving IGM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0811.2354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0811.2354</id><created>2008-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>CALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Response of the CALICE Si-W Electromagnetic Calorimeter Physics
  Prototype to Electrons</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 17 figs</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Instrum.Meth. A608 (2009) 372-383</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2009.07.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A prototype Silicon-Tungsten electromagnetic calorimeter (ECAL) for an
International Linear Collider (ILC) detector was installed and tested during
summer and autumn 2006 at CERN. The detector had 6480 silicon pads of dimension
1x1 cm^2. Data were collected with electron beams in the energy range 6 to 45
GeV. The analysis described in this paper focuses on electromagnetic shower
reconstruction and characterises the ECAL response to electrons in terms of
energy resolution and linearity. The detector is linear to within approximately
the 1% level and has a relative energy resolution of (16.6 +- 0.1)/
\sqrt{E(GeV}) + 1.1 +- 0.1 (%). The spatial uniformity and the time stability
of the ECAL are also addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0904.3163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0904.3163</id><created>2009-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>J. Stuart B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modification of the 21-cm power spectrum by quasars during the epoch of
  reionisation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2009) 399 (4): 1877-1887</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2009.15451.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assess the effect of a population of high-redshift quasars on the 21-cm
power spectrum during the epoch of reionisation. Our approach is to implement a
semi-numerical scheme to calculate the three-dimensional structure of ionised
regions surrounding massive halos at high redshift. We include the ionising
influence of luminous quasars by populating a simulated overdensity field with
quasars using a Monte Carlo Markov Chain algorithm. We find that quasars modify
both the amplitude and shape of the power spectrum at a level which is of the
same order as the fractional contribution to reionisation. The modification is
found both at constant redshift and at constant global neutral fraction, and
arises because ionising photons produced by quasars are biased relative to the
density field at a level that is higher than steller ionising photons. Our
results imply that quasar ionisation will need to be included in detailed
modelling of observed 21-cm power spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1002.3148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1002.3148</id><created>2010-02-16</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Navarro</keyname><forenames>F. A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H</keyname><forenames>Karina L. D. Barturen</forenames></author></authors><title>A Model for the Pr1-xCaxMnO3 Series with x = 0.30-0.50 under Application
  of Weak Magnetic Fields</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>The unit system that has been utilized is wrong</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a proposal for explaining manganites behavior, in the
Pr1-xCaxMnO3 series with x=0.30-0.50. We carry out computer simulations for the
Oguchi model along with the crystal field contribution. We contrast the
outcomings to experimental measurements made with a commercial magnetometer
SQUID. For analyzing the magnetization drop at low temperatures, we take into
account quasi-probability distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.2321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.2321</id><created>2010-11-10</created><updated>2011-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames><affiliation>U. Melbourne</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gaensler</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames><affiliation>U. Sydney</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>J. Stuart B.</forenames><affiliation>U. Melbourne</affiliation></author></authors><title>Polarised foreground removal at low radio frequencies using rotation
  measure synthesis: uncovering the signature of hydrogen reionisation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>22 pages including 11 figures. Minor revisions following referee's
  report. MNRAS, in press</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2011) 418 (1): 516-535</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.19509.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurement of redshifted 21-cm emission from neutral hydrogen promises to be
the most effective method for studying the reionisation history of hydrogen
and, indirectly, the first galaxies. These studies will be limited not by raw
sensitivity to the signal, but rather, by bright foreground radiation from
Galactic and extragalactic radio sources and the Galactic continuum. In
addition, leakage due to gain errors and non-ideal feeds conspire to further
contaminate low-frequency radio obsevations. This leakage leads to a portion of
the complex linear polarisation signal finding its way into Stokes I, and
inhibits the detection of the non-polarised cosmological signal from the epoch
of reionisation. In this work, we show that rotation measure synthesis can be
used to recover the signature of cosmic hydrogen reionisation in the presence
of contamination by polarised foregrounds. To achieve this, we apply the
rotation measure synthesis technique to the Stokes I component of a synthetic
data cube containing Galactic foreground emission, the effect of instrumental
polarisation leakage, and redshifted 21-cm emission by neutral hydrogen from
the epoch of reionisation. This produces an effective Stokes I Faraday
dispersion function for each line of sight, from which instrumental
polarisation leakage can be fitted and subtracted. Our results show that it is
possible to recover the signature of reionisation in its late stages (z ~ 7) by
way of the 21-cm power spectrum, as well as through tomographic imaging of
ionised cavities in the intergalactic medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.0281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.0281</id><created>2011-08-01</created><updated>2012-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ponte</keyname><forenames>P. Rodriguez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabra</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reentrant behaviour in Landau Fermi liquids with spin-split Pomeranchuk
  instabilities</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters B Vol. 26, No. 19 (2012) 1250125 (9 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217984912501254</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of spin-antisymmetric interactions on the stability of a
Landau-Fermi liquid on the square lattice, using the generalized Pomeranchuk
method for two-dimensional lattice systems. In particular, we analyze
interactions that could induce instabilities of the so called spin-split type,
that is when spin-up and spin-down Fermi surfaces are displaced with respect to
each other. The phase space is studied as a function of the strength of the
interaction $V$, the electron chemical potential $\mu$ and an external magnetic
field $h$. We find that such interactions produce in general an enhancement of
the instability region of the Landau-Fermi liquid. More interestingly, in
certain regions of the $V$-$\mu$ phase space, we find a reentrant behaviour as
a function of the magnetic field $h$, similar to that found in recent
experiments, e.g. in URu$_2$Si$_2$ and Sr$_3$Ru$_2$O$_7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2618</id><created>2014-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Ponte</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de F&#xed;sica de La Plata and Departamento de F&#xed;sica, Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grandi</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xe1;s</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de F&#xed;sica de La Plata and Departamento de F&#xed;sica, Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina</affiliation><affiliation>Abdus Salam International Centre for Theoretical Physics, Associate Scheme, Trieste, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cabra</keyname><forenames>Daniel C.</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de F&#xed;sica de La Plata and Departamento de F&#xed;sica, Universidad Nacional de La Plata, Argentina</affiliation><affiliation>Abdus Salam International Centre for Theoretical Physics, Associate Scheme, Trieste, Italy</affiliation></author></authors><title>Generalized susceptibilities and Landau parameters for anisotropic Fermi
  liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics B, Vol. 29, No. 16 (2015)
  1550102 (20 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217979215501027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study Fermi liquids with a Fermi surface that lacks continuous rotational
invariance, and in the presence of an arbitrary quartic interaction. We obtain
the expressions of the generalized static susceptibilities that measure the
linear response of a generic order parameter to a perturbation of the
Hamiltonian. We apply our formulae to the spin and charge susceptibilities.
Based on the resulting expressions, we make a proposal for the definition of
the Landau parameters in non-isotropic Fermi liquid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.8373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.8373</id><created>2014-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerbeth</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giesecke</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gundrum</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herault</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nore</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steglich</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards a precession driven dynamo experiment</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, submitted to Magnetohydrodynamics</comments><journal-ref>Magnetohydrodynamics, Vol. 51, No. 2, pp. 275-284 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The most ambitious project within the DREsden Sodium facility for DYNamo and
thermohydraulic studies (DRESDYN) at Helmholtz-Zentrum Dresden-Rossendorf
(HZDR) is the set-up of a precession-driven dynamo experiment. After discussing
the scientific background and some results of water pre-experiments and
numerical predictions, we focus on the numerous structural and design problems
of the machine. We also outline the progress of the building's construction,
and the status of some other experiments that are planned in the framework of
DRESDYN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03510</id><created>2015-02-11</created><updated>2017-05-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Kwokwai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leung</keyname><forenames>Naichung Conan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author></authors><title>BV quantization of the Rozansky-Witten model</title><categories>math.QA hep-th math.AG math.DG math.GT</categories><comments>51 pages, 27 figures. v3: minor modifications, references added,
  final version to appear in CMP</comments><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 355 (2017), no. 1, 97-144</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2924-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the perturbative aspects of Rozansky-Witten's 3d
$\sigma$-model using Costello's approach to the Batalin-Vilkovisky (BV)
formalism. We show that the BV quantization (in Costello's sense) of the model,
which produces a perturbative quantum field theory, can be obtained via the
configuration space method of regularization due to Kontsevich and
Axelrod-Singer. We also study the factorization algebra structure for quantum
observables following Costello-Gwilliam. In particular, we show that the
cohomology of local quantum observables on a genus $g$ handle body is given by
$H^*(X,(\wedge^*T_X)^{\otimes g})$ (where $X$ is the target manifold), and
prove that the partition function reproduces the Rozansky-Witten invariants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07944</id><created>2015-03-26</created><updated>2017-04-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turyshev</keyname><forenames>Slava G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spangelo</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werne</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Chengxing</forenames></author></authors><title>A constellation of CubeSats with synthetic tracking cameras to search
  for 90% of potentially hazardous near-Earth objects</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>14 pages, 16 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 603, A126 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new space mission concept that is capable of finding, detecting,
and tracking 90% of near-Earth objects (NEO) with H magnitude of $\rm H\leq22$
(i.e., $\sim$140 m in size) that are potentially hazardous to the Earth. The
new mission concept relies on two emerging technologies: the technique of
synthetic tracking and the new generation of small and capable interplanetary
spacecraft. Synthetic tracking is a technique that de-streaks asteroid images
by taking multiple fast exposures. With synthetic tracking, an 800 sec
observation with a 10 cm telescope in space can detect a moving object with
apparent magnitude of 20.5 without losing sensitivity from streaking. We refer
to NEOs with a minimum orbit intersection distance of $&lt; 0.002$ au as
Earth-grazers (EGs), representing typical albedo distributions. We show that a
constellation of six SmallSats (comparable in size to 9U CubeSats) equipped
with 10 cm synthetic tracking cameras and evenly-distributed in 1.0 au
heliocentric orbit could detect 90% of EGs with $\rm H \leq 22~mag$ in
$\sim$3.8 years of observing time. A more advanced constellation of nine 20 cm
telescopes could detect 90% of $\rm H=24.2~mag$ (i.e., $\rm \sim 50~m$ in size)
EGs in less than 5 years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00565</id><created>2015-05-04</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>A Korn-type inequality in SBD for functions with small jump sets</title><categories>math.AP cond-mat.mtrl-sci math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>74R10, 49J45, 70G75</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Korn-type inequality in a planar setting for special functions
of bounded deformation. We prove that for each function in SBD$^2$ with
sufficiently small jump set the distance of the function and its derivative
from an infinitesimal rigid motion can be controlled in terms of the linearized
elastic strain outside of a small exceptional set of finite perimeter.
Particularly the result shows that each function in SBD$^2$ has bounded
variation away from an arbitrarily small part of the domain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03302</id><created>2015-07-12</created><updated>2017-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aryshev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shevelev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terunuma</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urakawa</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Femtosecond response time measurements of a Cs2Te photocathode</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4994224</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the response time measurements of a Cs2Te photocathode illuminated
with two 100 fs duration, variable time separation laser pulses at 266 nm
wavelength. The response time was confirmed in dispersive region downstream of
a 12-cell standing wave S-band acceleration structure using a well-known RF
zero-crossing technique. At the same time it was also measured by changing
mechanical path-length difference between two micro-bunches. Both methods agree
that Cs2Te photocathode time response is of the order of 250 fs and thereby it
is possible to generate and control a THz sequence of relativistic electron
bunches by a conventional S-band RF gun. This result further opens a
possibility to construct wide-range tunable THz FEL.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07328</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07328</id><created>2015-07-27</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Wenxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grefe</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paschen</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Qimiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Hall effect and quantum criticality in geometrically
  frustrated heavy fermion metals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>v2: 5 pages, 4 figures, plus supplementary material; added
  calculation for the case of a Kagome lattice</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studies on the heavy-fermion pyrochlore iridate (Pr$_2$Ir$_2$O$_7$) point to
the role of time-reversal-symmetry breaking in geometrically frustrated Kondo
lattices. With this motivation, here we study the effect of Kondo coupling and
chiral spin liquids in a frustrated $J_1-J_2$ model on a square lattice. We
treat the Kondo effect within a slave-fermion approach, and discuss our results
in the context of a proposed global phase diagram for heavy fermion metals. We
calculate the anomalous Hall response for the chiral states of both the Kondo
destroyed and Kondo screened phases. Across the quantum critical point, a
reconstruction of the Fermi surface leads to a sudden change of the Berry
curvature distribution and, consequently, a jump of the anomalous Hall
conductance. We discuss the implications of our results for the heavy-fermion
pyrochlore iridate and propose an interface structure based on Kondo insulators
to further explore such effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07374</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Feister</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Austin</keyname><forenames>Drake R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrison</keyname><forenames>John T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frische</keyname><forenames>Kyle D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orban</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ngirmang</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Handler</keyname><forenames>Abraham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Joseph R. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schillaci</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>LaVerne</keyname><forenames>Jay A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chowdhury</keyname><forenames>Enam A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeman</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roquemore</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic electron acceleration by mJ-class kHz lasers normally
  incident on liquid targets</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures. Accepted for publication in Optics Express</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report observation of kHz-pulsed-laser-accelerated electron energies up to
3 MeV in the -$k_\text{laser}$ (backward) direction from a 3 mJ laser
interacting at normal incidence with a solid density, flowing-liquid target.
The electrons/MeV/s.r. &gt;1 MeV recorded here using a mJ-class laser exceeds or
equals that of prior super-ponderomotive electron studies employing lasers at
lower repetition-rates and oblique incidence. Focal intensity of the
40-fs-duration laser is 1.5 $\cdot$ 10$^{18}$ W cm$^{-2}$, corresponding to
only ~80 keV electron ponderomotive energy. Varying laser intensity confirms
electron energies in the laser-reflection direction well above what might be
expected from ponderomotive scaling in normal-incidence laser-target geometry.
This direct, normal-incidence energy spectrum measurement is made possible by
modifying the final focusing off-axis-paraboloid (OAP) mirror with a central
hole that allows electrons to pass, and restoring laser intensity through
adaptive optics. A Lanex-based, optics-free high-acquisition rate (&gt;100 Hz)
magnetic electron-spectrometer was developed for this study to enable
shot-to-shot statistical analysis and real-time feedback, which was leveraged
in finding optimal pre-plasma conditions. 3D Particle-in-cell simulations of
the interaction show qualitative super-ponderomotive spectral agreement with
experiment. The demonstration of a high-repetition-rate, high-flux source
containing &gt;MeV electrons from a few-mJ, 40 fs laser and a simple liquid target
encourages development of future $\geq$kHz-repetition, fs-duration
electron-beam applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01444</id><created>2015-09-04</created><updated>2015-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barbaroux</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hundertmark</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ried</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vugalter</keyname><forenames>Semjon</forenames></author></authors><title>Gevrey smoothing for weak solutions of the fully nonlinear homogeneous
  Boltzmann and Kac equations without cutoff for Maxwellian molecules</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>43 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>35D10 (Primary), 35B65, 35Q20, 82B40 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Archive for Rational Mechanics and Analysis 225 (2017), 601-661</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00205-017-1101-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has long been suspected that the non-cutoff Boltzmann operator has similar
coercivity properties as a fractional Laplacian. This has led to the hope that
the homogenous Boltzmann equation enjoys similar regularity properties as the
heat equation with a fractional Laplacian. In particular, the weak solution of
the fully nonlinear non-cutoff homogenous Boltzmann equation with initial datum
in $L^1_2(\mathbb{R}^d)\cap L\log L(\mathbb{R}^d)$, i.e., finite mass, energy
and entropy, should immediately become Gevrey regular for strictly positive
times. We prove this conjecture for Maxwellian molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00564</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-08-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mutch</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>Gregory B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angel</keyname><forenames>Paul W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duffy</keyname><forenames>Alan R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesinger</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>J. Stuart B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark-ages reionization &amp; galaxy formation simulation V: morphology and
  statistical signatures of reionization</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures, published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2016) 462 (1): 804-817</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1718</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the Dark-ages, Reionization And Galaxy-formation Observables from
Numerical Simulations (DRAGONS) framework to investigate the effect of
galaxy-formation physics on the morphology and statistics of ionized hydrogen
(HII) regions during the Epoch of Reioinization (EoR). DRAGONS
self-consistently couples a semi-analytic galaxy-formation model with the
inhomogeneous ionizing UV background, and can therefore be used to study the
dependence of morphology and statistics of reionization on feedback phenomena
of the ionizing source galaxy population. Changes in galaxy-formation physics
modify the sizes of HII regions and the amplitude and shape of 21-cm power
spectra. Of the galaxy physics investigated, we find that supernova feedback
plays the most important role in reionization, with HII regions up to $\approx
20$ per cent smaller and a fractional difference in the amplitude of power
spectra of up to $\approx 17$ per cent at fixed ionized fraction in the absence
of this feedback. We compare our galaxy-formation-based reionization models
with past calculations that assume constant stellar-to-halo mass ratios and
find that with the correct choice of minimum halo mass, such models can mimic
the predicted reionization morphology. Reionization morphology at fixed neutral
fraction is therefore not uniquely determined by the details of galaxy
formation, but is sensitive to the mass of the haloes hosting the bulk of the
ionizing sources. Simple EoR parametrizations are therefore accurate predictors
of reionization statistics. However, a complete understanding of reionization
using future 21-cm observations will require interpretation with realistic
galaxy-formation models, in combination with other observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05134</id><created>2015-12-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Barbaroux</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hundertmark</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ried</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vugalter</keyname><forenames>Semjon</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong smoothing for the non-cutoff homogeneous Boltzmann equation for
  Maxwellian molecules with Debye-Yukawa type interaction</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><msc-class>35D10 (Primary), 35B65, 35Q20, 82B40 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Kinetic and Related Models 10 (2017), 901-924</journal-ref><doi>10.3934/krm.2017036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study weak solutions of the homogeneous Boltzmann equation for Maxwellian
molecules with a logarithmic singularity of the collision kernel for grazing
collisions. Even though in this situation the Boltzmann operator enjoys only a
very weak coercivity estimate, it still leads to strong smoothing of weak
solutions in accordance to the smoothing expected by an analogy with a
logarithmic heat equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03607</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arbel&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>Carolina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>A. E. C&#xe1;rcamo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative Seesaw-type Mechanism of Fermion Masses and Non-trivial Quark
  Mixing</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures. Final version published in European Physical
  Journal C</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.6, 422</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4948-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a predictive inert 2 Higgs doublet model, where the Standard Model
(SM) symmetry is extended by $S_{3}\otimes Z_{2}\otimes Z_{12}$ and the field
content is enlarged by extra scalar fields, charged exotic fermions and two
heavy right-handed Majorana neutrinos. The charged exotic fermions generate a
nontrivial quark mixing and provide one-loop-level masses for the first- and
second-generation charged fermions. The masses of the light active neutrinos
are generated from a one loop-level radiative seesaw mechanism. Our model
successfully explains the observed SM fermion mass and mixing pattern.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01438</id><created>2016-08-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Jensen</keyname><forenames>Iwan</forenames></author></authors><title>Three friendly walkers</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.CA math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><journal-ref>J Phys A 50, 024003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/50/2/024003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  More than 15 years ago Guttmann and V\&quot;oge [J. Statist. Plann. Inference,
{\bf 101}, 107 (2002)], introduced a model of friendly walkers. Since then it
has remained unsolved. In this paper we provide the exact solution to a closely
allied model, originally introduced by Tsuchiya and Katori [J. Phys. Soc. Japan
{\bf 67}, 1655 (1988)], which essentially only differs in the boundary
conditions. The exact solution is expressed in terms of the reciprocal of the
generating function for vicious walkers which is a D-finite function. However,
ratios of D-finite functions are inherently not D-finite and in this case we
prove that the friendly walkers generating function is the solution to a
non-linear differential equation with polynomial coefficients, it is in other
words D-algebraic. We then show via numerically exact calculations that the
generating function of the original model can also be expressed as a D-finite
function times the reciprocal of the generating function for vicious walkers.
We obtain an expression for this D-finite function in terms of a ${}_{2}F_{1}$
hypergeometric function with a rational pullback and its first and second
derivatives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01665</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tourkine</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanhove</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-loop amplitude monodromy relations in string and gauge theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, feynmp graphs. v2: Signs and factor 2 corrected.
  Various clarifications and references added. v3: Some clarifications and
  minor corrections, version to be published in PRL. v4: Sign corrected in
  non-planar phases cuts</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 211601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.211601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The monodromy relations in string theory provide a powerful and elegant
formalism to understand some of the deepest properties of tree-level field
theory amplitudes, like the color-kinematics duality. This duality has been
instrumental in tremendous progress on the computations of loop amplitudes in
quantum field theory, but a higher-loop generalisation of the monodromy
construction was lacking.
  In this letter, we extend the monodromy relations to higher loops in open
string theory. Our construction, based on a contour deformation argument inside
open string diagrams, leads to new identities that relate planar and non-planar
topologies in string theory. We write one and two-loop monodromy formulae
explicitly at any multiplicity. In the field theory limit, at one-loop we
obtain identities that reproduce known results. At two loops, we check our
formulae by unitarity in the case of the four-point N=4 super-Yang-Mills
amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04854</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04854</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Junjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Changqin</forenames></author></authors><title>Green's functions for spin boson systems: Beyond conventional
  perturbation theories</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>in press, accepted by Chem. Phys..This work is dedicated to Vladimir
  Chernyak on the occasion of his 60th birthday</comments><journal-ref>Chem. Phys. 481, 42 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.07.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unraveling general properties of Green's functions of quantum dissipative
systems is of both experimental relevance and theoretical interest. Here, we
study the spin-boson model as a prototype. By utilizing the Majorana- Fermion
representation together with the polaron transformation, we establish a
theoretical approach to analyze Green's functions of the spin-boson model. In
contrast to conventional perturbation theories either in the tunneling energy
or in the system-bath coupling strength, the proposed scheme gives reliable
results over wide regimes of the coupling strength, bias, as well as
temperature. To demonstrate the utility of the approach, we consider the
susceptibility as well as the symmetrized spin correlation function (SSCF)
which can be expressed in terms of Green's functions. Thorough investigations
are made on systems embedded in Ohmic or sub-Ohmic bosonic baths. We found the
so-obtained SSCF is the same as that of the non-interacting blip approximation
(NIBA) in unbiased systems while it is applicable for a wider range of
temperature in the biased systems compared with the NIBA. We also show that a
previous perturbation result is recovered as a weak coupling limit of the
so-obtained SSCF. Furthermore, by studying the quantum criticality of the
susceptibility, we confirm the validity of the quantum-toclassical mapping in
the whole sub-Ohmic regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05342</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tanner</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cecil</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heitsch</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling Relations of Starburst-Driven Galactic Winds</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, Submitted to ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa78a8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using synthetic absorption lines generated from 3D hydro-dynamical
simulations we explore how the velocity of a starburst-driven galactic wind
correlates with the star formation rate (SFR) and SFR density. We find strong
correlations until the scaling relations flatten abruptly at a point set by the
mass loading of the starburst. Below this point the scaling relation depends on
the temperature regime being probed by the absorption line, not on the mass
loading. The exact scaling relation depends on whether the maximum or mean
velocity of the absorption line is used. We find that the outflow velocity of
neutral gas is four to five times lower than the average velocity of the
hottest gas, with the difference in velocity between the neutral and ionized
gas increasing with gas ionization. Thus, absorption lines of neutral or low
ionized gas will underestimate the outflow velocity of hot gas, severely
underestimating outflow energetics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05598</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karrasch</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>A geometric heat-flow theory of Lagrangian coherent structures</title><categories>math.DS math.AP math.DG nlin.CD nlin.PS</categories><comments>50 pages, 19 figures, submitted. v4: major revision incorporating
  comments by the referees. v3: major revision with new material. v2: minor
  revision</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define Lagrangian coherent structures (LCSs) as maximal material subsets
whose advective evolution is maximally persistent to weak diffusion. For their
detection, we first transform the Eulerian Fokker--Planck equation (FPE) into a
diffusion-only equation in Lagrangian coordinates. In this framework, LCSs
express themselves as almost-invariant sets under this diffusion process. The
Eulerian-to-Lagrangian coordinate transformation separates the reversible
effects of advection from the irreversible joint effects of advection and
diffusion. We approximate the Lagrangian FPE in two steps: first, we take the
time-average of the diffusion tensors and identify Froyland's dynamic Laplacian
as the associated generator; second, we introduce a deformed Riemannian
geometry that is consistent with the averaged anisotropic diffusion. The latter
turns the diffusion equation into a geometric heat equation, where the
distribution of heat is governed by the dynamically induced intrinsic geometry
on the material manifold, to which we refer as the geometry of mixing. We study
and visualize this geometry in detail, and discuss the connections to diffusion
barriers, i.e., boundaries of LCSs. We demonstrate the consistency with the
geometric analysis in several numerical examples. Our approach facilitates the
discovery of strong mathematical connections between several prominent methods
for coherent structure detection, including the probabilistic transfer
operator, the dynamic Laplacian, the variational geometric approaches to
elliptic and parabolic LCSs and the effective diffusivity approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05531</id><created>2016-09-18</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Einarsson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehlig</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical particle sedimenting in weakly viscoelastic shear flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, revised version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Fluids 2, 063301 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the dynamics of a small spherical particle driven through an
unbounded viscoelastic shear flow by an external force. We give analytical
solutions to both the mobility problem (velocity of forced particle) and the
resistance problem (force on fixed particle), valid to second order in the
dimensionless Deborah and Weissenberg numbers, which represent the elastic
relaxation time of the fluid relative to the rate of translation and the
imposed shear rate. We find a shear-induced lift at $O({\rm Wi})$, a modified
drag at $O({\rm De}^2)$ and $O({\rm Wi}^2)$, and a second lift that is
orthogonal to the first, at $O({\rm Wi}^2)$. The relative importance of these
effects depends strongly on the orientation of the forcing relative to the
shear. We discuss how these forces affect the terminal settling velocity in an
inclined shear flow. We also describe a new basis set of symmetric Cartesian
tensors, and demonstrate how they enable general tensorial perturbation
calculations such as the present theory. In particular this scheme allows us to
write down a solution to the inhomogenous Stokes equations, required by the
perturbation expansion, by a sequence of algebraic manipulations well suited to
computer implementation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06659</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pich</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosell</keyname><forenames>Ignasi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Joaquin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz-Cillero</keyname><forenames>Juan Jose</forenames></author></authors><title>Fingerprints of heavy scales in electroweak effective Lagrangians</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>57 pages, 1 pdf figure. Version published at JHEP</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-49, FTUV/16-0921</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The couplings of the electroweak effective theory contain information on the
heavy-mass scales which are no-longer present in the low-energy Lagrangian. We
build a general effective Lagrangian, implementing the electroweak chiral
symmetry breaking $SU(2)_L\otimes SU(2)_R\to SU(2)_{L+R}$, which couples the
known particle fields to heavier states with bosonic quantum numbers
$J^P=0^\pm$ and $1^\pm$. We consider colour-singlet heavy fields that are in
singlet or triplet representations of the electroweak group. Integrating out
these heavy scales, we analyze the pattern of low-energy couplings among the
light fields which are generated by the massive states. We adopt a generic
non-linear realization of the electroweak symmetry breaking with a singlet
Higgs, without making any assumption about its possible doublet structure.
Special attention is given to the different possible descriptions of massive
spin-1 fields and the differences arising from naive implementations of these
formalisms, showing their full equivalence once a proper short-distance
behaviour is required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00531</id><created>2016-10-03</created><updated>2016-12-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuniba</keyname><forenames>Atsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okado</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author></authors><title>A $q$-boson representation of Zamolodchikov-Faddeev algebra for
  stochastic $R$ matrix of $U_q(A^{(1)}_n)$</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA nlin.SI</categories><comments>13 pages. Minor changes</comments><msc-class>81R50, 60C99</msc-class><journal-ref>Lett. Math. Phys. 107 (2017) 1111-1130</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11005-016-0934-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a $q$-boson representation of the Zamolodchikov-Faddeev algebra
whose structure function is given by the stochastic $R$ matrix of
$U_q(A^{(1)}_n)$ introduced recently. The representation involves quantum
dilogarithm type infinite products in the $n(n-1)/2$-fold tensor product of
$q$-bosons. It leads to a matrix product formula of the stationary
probabilities in the $U_q(A_n^{(1)})$-zero range process on a one-dimensional
periodic lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02571</id><created>2016-10-08</created><updated>2016-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kasprzyk</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaplan</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seilmayer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transitions in a magnetized quasi-laminar spherical Couette Flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, submitted to Magnetohydrodynamics</comments><journal-ref>Magnetohydrodynamics, Vol. 53, No. 2, pp. 393-402 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First results of a new spherical Couette experiment are presented. The liquid
metal flow in a spherical shell is exposed to a homogeneous axial magnetic
field. For a Reynolds number Re=1000, we study the effect of increasing
Hartmann number Ha. The resulting flow structures are inspected by ultrasound
Doppler velocimetry. With a weak applied magnetic field, we observe an
equatorially anti-symmetric jet instability with azimuthal wave number m=3. As
the magnetic field strength increases, this instability vanishes. When the
field is increased further, an equatorially symmetric return flow instability
arises. Our observations are shown to be in good agreement with linear
stability analysis and non-linear flow simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02577</id><created>2016-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giesecke</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Tayler instability at low magnetic Prandtl numbers: Chiral symmetry
  breaking and synchronizable helicity oscillations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, extended proceedings paper of the PAMIR 2016
  conference</comments><journal-ref>Magnetohydrodynamics, Vol. 53, No. 1, pp. 169-178 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The current-driven, kink-type Tayler instability (TI) is a key ingredient of
the Tayler-Spruit dynamo model for the generation of stellar magnetic fields,
but is also discussed as a mechanism that might hamper the up-scaling of liquid
metal batteries. Under some circumstances, the TI involves a helical flow
pattern which goes along with some alpha effect. Here we focus on the chiral
symmetry breaking and the related impact on the alpha effect that would be
needed to close the dynamo loop in the Tayler-Spruit model. For low magnetic
Prandtl numbers, we observe intrinsic oscillations of the alpha effect. These
oscillations serve then as the basis for a synchronized Tayler-Spruit dynamo
model, which could possibly link the periodic tidal forces of planets with the
oscillation periods of stellar dynamos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04661</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Yao-Lung L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baranger</keyname><forenames>Harold U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple Emitters in a Waveguide: Non-Reciprocity and Correlated Photons
  at Perfect Elastic Transmission</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published version with minor changes in title, text, and Fig.9. A
  Mathematica notebook is uploaded as the supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013842 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013842</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate interference and correlation effects when several detuned
emitters are placed along a one-dimensional photonic waveguide. Such a setup
allows multiple interactions between the photons and the strongly coupled
emitters, and underlies proposed devices for quantum information processing. We
show, first, that a pair of detuned two-level systems (2LS) separated by a half
wavelength mimic a driven {\Lambda}-type three-level system (3LS) in both the
single- and two- photon sectors. There is an interference-induced transparency
peak at which the fluorescence is quenched, leaving the transmitted photons
completely uncorrelated. Slightly away from this separation, we find that the
inelastic scattering (fluorescence) is large, leading to nonlinear effects such
as non-reciprocity (rectification). We connect this non-reciprocity to
inelastic scattering caused by driving a dark pole and so derive a condition
for maximum rectification. Finally, by placing a true 3LS midway between the
two 2LS, we show that elastic scattering produces only transmission, but
inelastic scattering nevertheless occurs (the fluorescence is not quenched)
causing substantial photon correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05865</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arakawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasetsu</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-lisse vertex algebras and modular linear differential equations</title><categories>math.QA hep-th math.RT</categories><comments>18 pages, v4</comments><msc-class>17B69, 17B67, 11F22, 81R10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a notion of quasi-lisse vertex algebras, which generalizes
admissible affine vertex algebras. We show that the normalized character of an
ordinary module over a quasi-lisse vertex operator algebra has a modular
invariance property, in the sense that it satisfies a modular linear
differential equation. As an application we obtain the explicit character
formulas of simple affine vertex algebras associated with the Deligne
exceptional series at level $-h^{\vee}/6-1$, which express the homogeneous
Schur indices of 4d SCFTs studied by Beem, Lemos, Liendo, Peelaers, Rastelli
and van Rees, as quasi-modular forms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03034</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baule</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape universality classes in the random sequential addition of
  non-spherical particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 028003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.028003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random sequential addition (RSA) models are used in a large variety of
contexts to model particle aggregation and jamming. A key feature of these
models is the algebraic time dependence of the asymptotic jamming coverage as
$t\to\infty$. For the RSA of monodisperse non-spherical particles the scaling
is generally believed to be $~t^{-\nu}$, where $\nu=1/d_{\rm f}$ for a particle
with $d_{\rm f}$ degrees of freedom. While the $d_{\rm f}=1$ result of spheres
(Renyi's classical car parking problem) can be derived analytically, evidence
for the $1/d_{\rm f}$ scaling for arbitrary particle shapes has so far only
been provided from empirical studies on a case-by-case basis. Here, we show
that the RSA of arbitrary non-spherical particles, whose centres of mass are
constrained to fall on a line, can be solved analytically for moderate aspect
ratios. The asymptotic jamming coverage is determined by a Laplace-type
integral, whose asymptotics is fully specified by the contact distance between
two particles of given orientations. The analysis of the contact function $r$
shows that the scaling exponent depends on particle shape and falls into two
universality classes for generic shapes with $\tilde{d}$ orientational degrees
of freedom: (i) $\nu=1/(1+\tilde{d}/2)$ when $r$ is a smooth function of the
orientations as for smooth convex shapes, e.g., ellipsoids; (ii)
$\nu=1/(1+\tilde{d})$ when $r$ contains singularities due to flat sides as for,
e.g., spherocylinders and polyhedra. The exact solution explains in particular
why many empirically observed scalings in $2d$ and $3d$ fall in between these
two limiting values.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03568</id><created>2016-11-10</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for dijet resonances in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 13
  TeV and constraints on dark matter and other models</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference. All
  the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/EXO-16-032/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-EXO-16-032, CERN-EP-2016-277</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 769 (2017) 520</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.02.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is presented for narrow resonances decaying to dijet final states in
proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 13 TeV using data corresponding to an
integrated luminosity of 12.9 inverse femtobarns. The dijet mass spectrum is
well described by a smooth parameterization and no significant evidence for the
production of new particles is observed. Upper limits at 95% confidence level
are reported on the production cross section for narrow resonances with masses
above 0.6 TeV. In the context of specific models, the limits exclude string
resonances with masses below 7.4 TeV, scalar diquarks below 6.9 TeV, axigluons
and colorons below 5.5 TeV, excited quarks below 5.4 TeV, color-octet scalars
below 3.0 TeV, W' bosons below 2.7 TeV, Z' bosons below 2.1 TeV and between 2.3
and 2.6 TeV, and RS gravitons below 1.9 TeV. These extend previous limits in
the dijet channel. Vector and axial-vector mediators in a simplified model of
interactions between quarks and dark matter are excluded below 2.0 TeV. The
first limits in the dijet channel on dark matter mediators are presented as
functions of dark matter mass and are compared to the exclusions of dark matter
in direct detection experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04861</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghonge</keyname><forenames>Sushrut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vural</keyname><forenames>Dervis Can</forenames></author></authors><title>Inferring Network Structure from Cascades</title><categories>cs.SI cond-mat.dis-nn physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Published in Physical Review E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012319 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012319</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many physical, biological, and social phenomena can be described by cascades
taking place on a network. Often, the activity can be empirically observed, but
not the underlying network of interactions. In this paper we offer three
topological methods to infer the structure of any directed network given a set
of cascade arrival times. Our formulas hold for a very general class of models
where the activation probability of a node is a generic function of its degree
and the number of its active neighbors. We report high success rates for
synthetic and real networks, for several different cascade models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06300</id><created>2016-11-18</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Puggioni</keyname><forenames>Danilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovannetti</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rondinelli</keyname><forenames>James M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polar metals as electrodes to suppress the critical-thickness limit in
  ferroelectric nanocapacitors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Enhancing the performance of nanoscale ferroelectric (FE) field-effect
transistors and FE capacitors for memory devices and logic relies on
miniaturizing the metal electrode/ferroelectric area and reducing the thickness
of the insulator. Although size reductions improve data retention, deliver
lower voltage threshold switching, and increase areal density, they also
degrade the functional electric polarization. There is a critical, nanometer
length $t_\mathrm{FE}^*$ below which the polarization disappears owing to
depolarizing field effects. Here we show how to overcome the critical thickness
limit imposed on ferroelectricity by utilizing electrodes formed from a novel
class of materials known as polar metals. Electronic structure calculations on
symmetric polar-metal electrode/FE capacitor structures demonstrate that
electric polarizations can persist to the sub-nanometer scale with
$t_\mathrm{FE}^*\rightarrow0$ when a component of the polar axis in the
electrode is perpendicular to the electrode/insulator interface. Our results
reveal the importance of interfacial dipolar coherency in sustaining the
polarization, which provides a platform for atomic scale structure-based design
of functions that deteriorate in reduced dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07851</id><created>2016-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez-Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Unai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamata</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Approximate Quantum Adders with Genetic Algorithms: An IBM Quantum
  Experience</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Meas. Quantum Metrol. 4,1 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/qmetro-2017-0001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been proven that quantum adders are forbidden by the laws of quantum
mechanics. We analyze theoretical proposals for the implementation of
approximate quantum adders and optimize them by means of genetic algorithms,
improving previous protocols in terms of efficiency and fidelity. Furthermore,
we experimentally realize a suitable approximate quantum adder with the cloud
quantum computing facilities provided by IBM Quantum Experience. The
development of approximate quantum adders enhances the toolbox of quantum
information protocols, paving the way for novel applications in quantum
technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01849</id><created>2016-12-06</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bartolo</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minganti</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lolli</keyname><forenames>Jared</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciuti</keyname><forenames>Cristiano</forenames></author></authors><title>Homodyne versus photon-counting quantum trajectories for dissipative
  Kerr resonators with two-photon driving</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>To appear on Eur. Phys. J. Special Topics, Quantum Gases and Quantum
  Coherence; 8 pages, 2 composed figures (5 panels)</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J Special Topics 226 (12), 2705 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60385-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate two different kinds of quantum trajectories for a nonlinear
photon resonator subject to two-photon pumping, a configuration recently
studied for the generation of photonic Schroedinger cat states. In the absence
of feedback control and in the strong-driving limit, the steady-state density
matrix is a statistical mixture of two states with equal weight. While along a
single photon-counting trajectory the systems intermittently switches between
an odd and an even cat state, we show that upon homodyne detection the
situation is different. Indeed, homodyne quantum trajectories reveal switches
between coherent states of opposite phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02151</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Abu-Shady</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Catalysis in the Higher-Order Quark Sigma Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1507.01372</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Particle Physics, Vol. 1, No. 1, 58 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of the higher-order mesonic interactions is investigated on the
chiral symmetry breaking in the presence of an external magnetic field. The
effective of higher-order mesonic potential is employed and is numerically
solved in the mean-field approximation. The chiral symmetry breaking increases
with increasing magnetic field. Two sets of free parameterization are
investigated on the magnetic catalysis. A comparison is discussed with the
original sigma model and other studies. The obtained results are included that
the higher-order mesonic interactions play an important role in the magnetic
catalysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03076</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Celi</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author></authors><title>Different models of gravitating Dirac fermions in optical lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>14 pages, Submitted to EPJ Special Topics for the special issue on
  &quot;Quantum Gases and Quantum Coherence&quot;; v2: minor changes, figures and
  references added, similar to the published version, 21 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Euro. J. Phys.J. Special Topics &quot;Quantum Gases and Quantum
  Coherence&quot; 226, 2729 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60390-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper I construct the naive lattice Dirac Hamiltonian describing the
propagation of fermions in a generic 2D optical metric for different lattice
and flux-lattice geometries. First, I apply a top-down constructive approach
that we first proposed in [Boada {\it et al.,New J. Phys.} {\bf 13} 035002
(2011)] to the honeycomb and to the brickwall lattices. I carefully discuss how
gauge transformations that generalize momentum (and Dirac cone) shifts in the
Brillouin zone in the Minkowski homogeneous case can be used in order to change
the phases of the hopping. In particular, I show that lattice Dirac Hamiltonian
for Rindler spacetime in the honeycomb and brickwall lattices can be realized
by considering real and isotropic (but properly position dependent) tunneling
terms. For completeness, I also discuss a suitable formulation of Rindler Dirac
Hamiltonian in semi-synthetic brickwall and $\pi$-flux square lattices (where
one of the dimension is implemented by using internal spin states of atoms as
we originally proposed in [Boada {\it et al.,Phys. Rev. Lett. } {\bf 108}
133001 (2012)] and [Celi {\it et al.,Phys. Rev. Lett. } {\bf 112} 043001
(2012)]).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03126</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Krishnendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singisetti</keyname><forenames>Uttam</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab Initio Velocity-Field Curves in Monoclinic
  \(\beta\)-Ga\textsubscript{2}O\textsubscript{3}}</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics, 122(3), p. 035702, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the high-field transport in monoclinic
\(\beta\)-Ga\textsubscript{2}O\textsubscript{3}} using a combination of ab
initio calculations and full band Monte Carlo (FBMC) simulation. Scattering
rate calculation and the final state selection in the FBMC simulation use
complete wave-vector (both electron and phonon) and crystal direction dependent
electron phonon interaction (EPI) elements. We propose and implement a
semi-coarse version of the Wannier-Fourier interpolation method [F. Giustino,
M. L. Cohen, and S. G. Louie, Physical Review B, vol. 76, no. 16, 2007] for
short-range non-polar optical phonon (EPI) elements in order to ease the
computational requirement in FBMC simulation. During the interpolation of the
EPI, the inverse Fourier sum over the real-space electronic grids is done on a
coarse mesh while the unitary rotations are done on a fine mesh. This paper
reports the high field transport in monoclinic
\(\beta\)-Ga\textsubscript{2}O\textsubscript{3}} with deep insight on the
contribution of electron-phonon interactions, and velocity-field
characteristics for electric fields ranging up to 450 kV/cm in different
crystal directions. A peak velocity of $2\times10^{7}&amp; cm/s is estimated at an
electric field of 200 kV/cm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03884</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Sheng-Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>The production rate of the system-bath mutual information</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure, comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012139 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012139</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When an open system is contacted with several thermal baths, the entropy
produced by the irreversible processes
($dS_{\mathrm{i}}=dS-\sum_{\alpha}\text{\dj}Q_{\alpha}/T_{\alpha}$) keeps
increasing, and this entropy production rate is always non-negative. But when
the system is contacted with some non-thermal baths containing quantum
coherence or squeezing, this entropy production formula does not apply. In this
paper, we study the increasing rate of the mutual information between the open
system and its environment. When the baths are canonical thermal ones, we prove
that this mutual information production rate could exactly return to the
previous entropy production rate. Further, we study an example of a single
boson mode contacted with multiple squeezed thermal baths, where the
conventional entropy production rate does not apply, and we find that this
mutual information production rate still keeps non-negative, which means the
monotonic increasing of the correlation between the system and its environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04556</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Masuko</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraoka</keyname><forenames>Takayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Nobuyasu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimada</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of laziness in chasers in group chase and escape model</title><categories>nlin.AO cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 085002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.085002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of laziness in the group chase and escape problem is studied using
a simple model. The laziness is introduced as random walks in two ways:
uniformly and in a &quot;division of labor&quot; way. It is shown that, while the former
is always ineffective, the latter can improve the efficiency of catching,
through the formation of pincer attack configuration by diligent and lazy
chasers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05331</id><created>2016-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Weimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Haoshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valles</keyname><forenames>Connie M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarmoff</keyname><forenames>Jory A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preparation of clean surfaces and Se vacancy formation in
  Bi$_{2}$Se$_{3}$ by ion bombardment and annealing</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>32 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Surf. Sci. 662, 67-73 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.susc.2017.04.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bismuth Selenide (Bi$_{2}$Se$_{3}$) is a topological insulator (TI) with a
structure consisting of stacked quintuple layers. Single crystal surfaces are
commonly prepared by mechanical cleaving. This work explores the use of low
energy Ar$^{+}$ ion bombardment and annealing (IBA) as an alternative method to
produce reproducible and stable Bi$_{2}$Se$_{3}$ surfaces under ultra-high
vacuum (UHV). It is found that a well-ordered surface can be prepared by a
single cycle of 1 keV Ar$^{+}$ ion bombardment and 30 min of annealing. Low
energy electron diffraction (LEED) and detailed low energy ion scattering
(LEIS) measurements show no differences between IBA-prepared surfaces and those
prepared by $\textit{in situ}$ cleaving in UHV. Analysis of the LEED patterns
shows that the optimal annealing temperature is 450{\deg}C. Angular LEIS scans
reveal the formation of surface Se vacancies when the annealing temperature
exceeds 520{\deg}C.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07175</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-06-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Tony E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakker</keyname><forenames>Alexander M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Impacts of Antarctic fast dynamics on sea-level projections and coastal
  flood defense</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><doi>10.1007/s10584-017-2039-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strategies to manage the risks posed by future sea-level rise hinge on a
sound characterization of the inherent uncertainties. One of the major
uncertainties is the possible rapid disintegration of large fractions of the
Antarctic ice sheet in response to rising global temperatures. This could
potentially lead to several meters of sea-level rise during the next few
centuries. Previous studies have typically been silent on two coupled
questions: (i) What are probabilistic estimates of this &quot;fast dynamics&quot;
contribution to sea-level rise? (ii) What are the implications for strategies
to manage coastal flooding risks? Here, we present probabilistic hindcasts and
projections of sea-level rise to 2100. The fast dynamics mechanism is
approximated by a simple parameterization, designed to allow for a careful
quantification of the uncertainty in its contribution to sea-level rise. We
estimate that global temperature increases ranging from 1.9 to 3.1{\deg}C
coincide with fast Antarctic disintegration, and these contributions account
for sea-level rise of 21-74 centimeters this century (5-95% range,
Representative Concentration Pathway 8.5). We use a simple cost-benefit
analysis of coastal defense to demonstrate in a didactic exercise how
neglecting this mechanism and associated uncertainty can (i) lead to strategies
which fall sizably short of protection targets and (ii) increase the expected
net costs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07986</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Man'ko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marmo</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ventriglia</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitale</keyname><forenames>Patrizia</forenames></author></authors><title>Metric on the space of quantum states from relative entropy. Tomographic
  reconstruction</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages. No figures. Abstract and Introduction rewritten. Minor
  corrections. References added</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 335302</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7d7d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of quantum information geometry, we derive, from quantum
relative Tsallis entropy, a family of quantum metrics on the space of full
rank, N level quantum states, by means of a suitably defined coordinate free
differential calculus. The cases N = 2, N = 3 are discussed in detail and
notable limits are analyzed. The radial limit procedure has been used to
recover quantum metrics for lower rank states, such as pure states. By using
the tomographic picture of quantum mechanics we have obtained the Fisher- Rao
metric for the space of quantum tomograms and derived a reconstruction formula
of the quantum metric of density states out of the tomographic one. A new
inequality obtained for probabilities of three spin-1/2 projections in three
perpendicular directions is proposed to be checked in experiments with
superconducting circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01504</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-01-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Weimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Haoshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarmoff</keyname><forenames>Jory A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A detailed analysis of impact collision ion scattering spectroscopy of
  bismuth selenide</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Vac. Sci. Technol. A 35, 03E104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.7b00386</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Impact collision ion scattering spectroscopy (ICISS), which is a variation of
low energy ion scattering (LEIS) that employs large scattering angles, is
performed on Bi2Se3 surfaces prepared by ion bombardment and annealing (IBA).
ICISS angular scans are collected experimentally and simulated numerically
along the [120] and [-1 -2 0] azimuths, and the match of the positions of the
flux peaks shows that the top three atomic layers are bulk-terminated. A newly
observed feature is identified as a minimum in the multiple scattering
background when the ion beam incidence is along a low index direction.
Calculated scans as a function of scattering angle are employed to identify the
behavior of flux peaks to show whether they originate from shadowing, blocking
or both. This new method for analysis of large-angle LEIS data is shown to be
useful for accurately investigating complex surface structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.08502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.08502</id><created>2017-01-30</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Quansheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Hongming</forenames></author></authors><title>From Nodal Chain Semimetal To Weyl Semimetal in HfC</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>https://journals.aps.org/prl/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.036401</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 036401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.036401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on first-principles calculations and effective model analysis, we
propose that the WC-type HfC, in the absence of spin-orbit coupling (SOC), can
host a three-dimensional nodal chain semimetal state. Distinguished from the
previous material IrF4 [T. Bzdusek et al., Nature 538, 75 (2016)], the nodal
chain here is protected by mirror reflection symmetries of a simple space
group, while in IrF4 the nonsymmorphic space group with a glide plane is a
necessity. Moreover, in the presence of SOC, the nodal chain in WC type HfC
evolves into Weyl points. In the Brillouin zone, a total of 30 pairs of Weyl
points in three types are obtained through the first-principles calculations.
Besides, the surface states and the pattern of the surface Fermi arcs
connecting these Weyl points are studied, which may be measured by future
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01356</id><created>2017-02-04</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reeves</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerstoft</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Worcester</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzieciuch</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thode</keyname><forenames>Aaron</forenames></author></authors><title>Eastern Arctic ambient noise on a drifting vertical array</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>The following article has been submitted to the Journal of the
  Acoustical Society of America. After it is published, it will be found at
  http://scitation.aip.org/JASA</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ambient noise in the eastern Arctic was studied from April to September 2013
using a 22 element vertical hydrophone array as it drifted from 89$^\circ$23'N,
64$^\circ$35'W to 83$^\circ$45'N, 4$^\circ$28'W. The hydrophones recorded for
108 min/day on six days/week with a sampling rate of 1953.125 Hz. After removal
of data corrupted by non-acoustic transients, 19 days throughout the transit
period were analyzed. Noise contributors identified include broadband and tonal
ice noises, bowhead whale calling, seismic airgun surveys, and earthquake $T$
phases. The bowhead whale or whales detected are believed to belong to the
endangered Spitsbergen population and were recorded when the array was as far
north as 86$^\circ$24'N. Median power spectral estimates and empirical
probability density functions (PDFs) along the array transit show a change in
the ambient noise levels corresponding to seismic survey airgun occurrence and
received level at low frequencies and transient ice ice noises at high
frequencies. Median power for the same periods across the array show that this
change is consistent in depth. The median ambient noise for May 2013 was among
the lowest of the sparse reported observations in the eastern Arctic but
comparable to the more numerous observations of western Arctic noise levels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03347</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ochoa</keyname><forenames>Hector</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Se Kwon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tchernyshyov</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tserkovnyak</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav</forenames></author></authors><title>Gyrotropic elastic response of skyrmion crystals to current-induced
  tensions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages + sup. mat., 2 figures; to appear in PRB as a Rapid
  Communication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 020410 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.020410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study the dynamics of skyrmion crystals in
electrically-insulating chiral magnets subjected to current-induced spin
torques by adjacent metallic layers. We develop an elasticity theory that
accounts for the gyrotropic force engendered by the non-trivial topology of the
spin texture, tensions at the boundaries due to the exchange of linear and spin
angular momentum with the metallic reservoirs, and dissipation in the bulk of
the film. A steady translation of the skyrmion crystal is triggered by the
current-induced tensions and subsequently sustained by dissipative forces,
generating an electromotive force on itinerant spins in the metals. This
phenomenon should be revealed as a negative drag in an open two-terminal
geometry, or equivalently, as a positive magnetoresistance when the terminals
are connected in parallel. We propose non-local transport measurements with
these salient features as a tool to characterize the phase diagram of
insulating chiral magnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06208</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bairey</keyname><forenames>Eyal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Refael</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>Netanel H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Driving induced many-body localization</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 020201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.020201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Subjecting a many-body localized system to a time-periodic drive generically
leads to delocalization and a transition to ergodic behavior if the drive is
sufficiently strong or of sufficiently low frequency. Here we show that a
specific drive can have an opposite effect, taking a static delocalized system
into the many-body localized phase. We demonstrate this effect using a
one-dimensional system of interacting hardcore bosons subject to an oscillating
linear potential. The system is weakly disordered, and is ergodic absent the
driving. The time-periodic linear potential leads to a suppression of the
effective static hopping amplitude, increasing the relative strengths of
disorder and interactions. Using numerical simulations, we find a transition
into the many-body localized phase above a critical driving frequency and in a
range of driving amplitudes. Our findings highlight the potential of driving
schemes exploiting the coherent suppression of tunneling for engineering
long-lived Floquet phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07517</id><created>2017-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yinxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Xinloong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Shengshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>Congcong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qiang-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jiangping</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust d-wave pairing symmetry in multi-orbital cobalt high temperature
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024506 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pairing symmetry of the newly proposed cobalt high temperature
(high-$T_c$) superconductors formed by vertex shared cation-anion tetrahedral
complexes is studied by the methods of mean field, random phase approximation
(RPA) and functional renormalization group (FRG) analysis. The results of all
these methods show that the $d_{x^2-y^2}$ pairing symmetry is robustly favored
near half filling. The RPA and FRG methods, which are valid in weak interaction
regions, predict that the superconducting state is also strongly orbital
selective, namely the $d_{x^2-y^2}$ orbital that has the largest density near
half filling among the three $t_{2g}$ orbitals dominates superconducting
pairing. These results suggest that the new materials, if synthesized, can
provide indisputable test to high-$T_c$ pairing mechanism and the validity of
different theoretical methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00622</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mandr&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katzgraber</keyname><forenames>Helmut G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Creighton</forenames></author></authors><title>The pitfalls of planar spin-glass benchmarks: Raising the bar for
  quantum annealers (again)</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Sci. Technol. 2, 038501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa7877</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In an effort to overcome the limitations of random spin-glass benchmarks for
quantum annealers, focus has shifted to carefully-crafted gadget-based problems
whose logical structure has typically a planar topology. Recent experiments on
these gadget problems using a commercially-available quantum annealer have
demonstrated an impressive performance over a selection of commonly-used
classical optimization heuristics. Here we show that efficient classical
optimization techniques, such as minimum-weight perfect matching, can solve
these gadget problems exactly and in polynomial time. We present approaches on
how to mitigate this shortcoming of commonly-used benchmark problems based on
planar logical topologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04597</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bostelmann</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cadamuro</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lechner</keyname><forenames>Gandalf</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum backflow and scattering</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>minor changes, as published in Phys. Rev. A; 13 pages, 11 figures, 3
  videos, computer code</comments><msc-class>81U99 (Primary), 81-04, 47G10 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 012112 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Backflow is the phenomenon that the probability current of a quantum particle
on the line can flow in the direction opposite to its momentum. In this
article, previous investigations of backflow, pertaining to interaction-free
dynamics or purely kinematical aspects, are extended to scattering situations
in short-range potentials. It is shown that backflow is a universal quantum
effect which exists in any such potential, and is always of bounded spatial
extent in a specific sense. The effects of reflection and transmission
processes on backflow are investigated, both analytically for general
potentials, and numerically in various concrete examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05568</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Daskin</keyname><forenames>Ammar</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Spectral Clustering through a Biased Phase Estimation Algorithm</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS</categories><comments>5 pages, submitted to a conference, and any comments are welcomed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this brief paper, we go through the theoretical steps of the spectral
clustering on quantum computers by employing the phase estimation and the
amplitude amplification algorithms. We discuss circuit designs for each step
and show how to obtain the clustering solution from the output state. In
addition, we introduce a biased version of the phase estimation algorithm which
significantly speeds up the amplitude amplification process. The complexity of
the whole process is analyzed: it is shown that when the circuit representation
of a data matrix of order $N$ is produced through an ancilla based circuit in
which the matrix is written as a sum of $L$ number of Householder matrices; the
computational complexity is bounded by $O(2^mLN)$ number of quantum gates.
Here, $m$ represents the number of qubits (e.g., 6) involved in the phase
register of the phase estimation algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05786</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crivellin</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>Giancarlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitahara</keyname><forenames>Teppei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nierste</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>$K\to \pi \nu\overline{\nu}$ in the MSSM in Light of the
  $\epsilon^{\prime}_K/\epsilon_K$ Anomaly</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures; references added, version published in PRD</comments><report-no>PSI-PR-17-03, TTP-17-013</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 015023 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.015023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Standard-Model (SM) prediction for the CP-violating quantity
$\epsilon_K^{\prime}/\epsilon_K$ deviates from its measured value by 2.8
$\sigma$. It has been shown that this tension can be resolved within the
Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model (MSSM) through gluino-squark box
diagrams, even if squarks and gluinos are much heavier than 1 TeV. The rare
decays $K_L \to \pi^0\nu\bar{\nu}$ and $K^+ \to \pi^+\nu\bar{\nu}$ are
similarly sensitive to very high mass scales and the first one also measures CP
violation. In this article, we analyze the correlations between
$\epsilon^{\prime}_K/\epsilon_K$ and $B(K_L \to \pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})$ and $B(K^+
\to \pi^+\nu\bar{\nu})$ within the MSSM aiming at an explanation of
$\epsilon_K^{\prime}/\epsilon_K$ via gluino-squark box diagrams. The dominant
MSSM contribution to the $K \to \pi\nu\bar{\nu}$ branching fractions stems from
box diagrams with squarks, sleptons, charginos, and neutralinos, and the
pattern of the correlations is different from the widely studied $Z$-penguin
scenarios. This is interesting in light of future precision measurements by
KOTO and NA62 at J-PARC and CERN, respectively. We find $B(K_L \to
\pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})/B^{SM} (K_L \to \pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})\lesssim 2\,(1.2)$ and
$B(K^+ \to \pi^+\nu\bar{\nu})/B^{SM}(K^+ \to \pi^+\nu\bar{\nu}) \lesssim
1.4\,(1.1)$, if all squark masses are above 1.5 TeV, gaugino masses obey GUT
relations, and if one allows for a fine-tuning at the $1\%\,(10\%)$ level for
the gluino mass. Larger values are possible for a tuned CP violating phase.
Furthermore, the sign of the MSSM contribution to $\epsilon_K^{\prime}$ imposes
a strict correlation between $B(K_L \to \pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})$ and the hierarchy
between the masses $m_{\bar{U}}$, $m_{\bar{D}}$ of the right-handed up-squark
and down-squark: sgn$[B(K_L \to \pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})-B^{SM} (K_L \to
\pi^0\nu\bar{\nu})] = $sgn$(m_{\bar{U}}-m_{\bar{D}}) $.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07165</id><created>2017-03-21</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pinhero</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Supratik</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-canonical Conformal Attractors for Single Field Inflation</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables. Section 2 modified</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the idea of conformal attractors in inflation to non-canonical
sectors by developing a non-canonical conformally invariant theory from two
different approaches. In the first approach, namely, ${\cal N}=1$ supergravity,
the construction is more or less phenomenological, where the non-canonical
kinetic sector is derived from a particular form of the K$\ddot{a}$hler
potential respecting shift symmetry. In the second approach i.e.,
superconformal theory, we derive the form of the Lagrangian from a
superconformal action and it turns out to be exactly of the same form as in the
first approach. Conformal breaking of these theories results in a new class of
non-canonical models which can govern inflation with modulated shape of the
T-models. We further employ this framework to explore inflationary
phenomenology with a representative example and show how the form of the
K$\ddot{a}$hler potential can possibly be constrained in non-canonical models
using the latest confidence contour in the $n_s-r$ plane given by Planck.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09040</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Xian-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Hongming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shengyuan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>$d$-Orbital Topological Insulator and Semimetal in Antifluorite Cu$_2$S
  Family: Contrasting Spin Helicities, Nodal Box, and Hybrid Surface States</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5+2 pages, 5+2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. Lett., 8, 3506 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01390</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reveal a class of three-dimensional $d$-orbital topological materials in
the antifluorite Cu$_2$S family. Derived from the unique properties of
low-energy $t_{2g}$ states, their phases are solely determined by the sign of
spin-orbit coupling (SOC): topological insulator for negative SOC, whereas
topological semimetal for positive SOC; both having Dirac-cone surface states
but with contrasting helicities. With broken inversion symmetry, the semimetal
becomes one with a nodal box consisting of butterfly-shaped nodal lines that
are robust against SOC. Further breaking the tetrahedral symmetry by strain
leads to an ideal Weyl semimetal with four pairs of Weyl points. Interestingly,
the Fermi arcs coexist with a surface Dirac cone on the (010) surface, as
required by a $Z_2$-invariant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10008</id><created>2017-03-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Ezawa</keyname><forenames>Motohiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Triplet Fermions and Dirac Fermions in Borophene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035425 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Borophene is a monolayer materials made of boron. A perfect planar boropehene
called $\beta_{12}$ borophene has Dirac cones and they are well reproduced by a
tight-binding model according to recent experimental and first-principles
calculation results. We explicitly derive a Dirac theory for them. Dirac cones
are gapless when the inversion symmetry exists, while they are gapped when it
is broken. In addition, three-band touching points emerge together with
pseudospin triplet fermions when all transfer energy is equal and all on-site
energy is equal. The three-band touching is slightly resolved otherwise. We
construct effective three-band theories for triplet fermions. We also study the
edge states of borophene nanoribbons, which show various behaviors depending on
the way of edge terminations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10042</id><created>2017-03-26</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Olendski</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on 'Fisher information for quasi-one-dimensional hydrogen atom'</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A further argument is provided in the discussion on the correct form of the
bound-state momentum wave function of the quasi-one-dimensional hydrogen atom;
namely, considering its behavior at the large quantum indices, it is
reconfirmed that the complex expression from Olendski (2017) {\it Eur. J.
Phys.} {\bf 38} 038001 is a correct one. Groundlessness of other
interpretations is also highlighted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10154</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gwak</keyname><forenames>Bogeun</forenames></author></authors><title>Collision of Two Rotating Hayward Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 43 figures, published version in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, no. 7, 482 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5055-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spin interaction and the gravitational radiation thermally
allowed in a head-on collision of two rotating Hayward black holes. The Hayward
black hole is a regular black hole in a modified Einstein equation, and hence
it can be an appropriate model to describe the extent to which the regularity
effect in the near-horizon region affects the interaction and the radiation. If
one black hole is assumed to be considerably smaller than the other, the
potential of the spin interaction can be analytically obtained and is dependent
on the alignment of angular momenta of the black holes. For the collision of
massive black holes, the gravitational radiation is numerically obtained as the
upper bound by using the laws of thermodynamics. The effect of the Hayward
black hole tends to increase the radiation energy, but we can limit the effect
by comparing the radiation energy with the gravitational waves GW150914 and
GW151226.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00762</id><created>2017-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Valentino</keyname><forenames>Eleonora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchiorri</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linder</keyname><forenames>Eric V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silk</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining Dark Energy Dynamics in Extended Parameter Space</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 Pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 023523 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.023523</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical dark energy has been recently suggested as a promising and physical
way to solve the 3.4 sigma tension on the value of the Hubble constant $H_0$
between the direct measurement of Riess et al. (2016) (R16, hereafter) and the
indirect constraint from Cosmic Microwave Anisotropies obtained by the Planck
satellite under the assumption of a $\Lambda$CDM model. In this paper, by
parameterizing dark energy evolution using the $w_0$-$w_a$ approach, and
considering a $12$ parameter extended scenario, we find that: a) the tension on
the Hubble constant can indeed be solved with dynamical dark energy, b) a
cosmological constant is ruled out at more than $95 \%$ c.l. by the Planck+R16
dataset, and c) all of the standard quintessence and half of the &quot;downward
going&quot; dark energy model space (characterized by an equation of state that
decreases with time) is also excluded at more than $95 \%$ c.l. These results
are further confirmed when cosmic shear, CMB lensing, or SN~Ia luminosity
distance data are also included. However, tension remains with the BAO dataset.
A cosmological constant and small portion of the freezing quintessence models
are still in agreement with the Planck+R16+BAO dataset at between 68\% and 95\%
c.l. Conversely, for Planck plus a phenomenological $H_0$ prior, both thawing
and freezing quintessence models prefer a Hubble constant of less than 70
km/s/Mpc. The general conclusions hold also when considering models with
non-zero spatial curvature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01786</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Girish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Prashant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jha</keyname><forenames>Anand K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transfer of temporal coherence in parametric down-conversion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 34(8), 1637-1643 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.34.001637</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that in parametric down-conversion the coherence properties of a
temporally partially coherent pump field get entirely transferred to the
down-converted entangled two-photon field. Under the assumption that the
frequency-bandwidth of the down-converted signal-idler photons is much larger
than that of the pump, we derive the temporal coherence functions for the
down-converted field, for both infinitely-fast and time-averaged detection
schemes. We show that in each scheme the coherence function factorizes into two
separate coherence functions with one of them carrying the entire statistical
information of the pump field. In situations in which the pump is a Gaussian
Schell-model field, we derive explicit expressions for the coherence functions.
Finally, we show that the concurrence of time-energy-entangled two-qubit states
is bounded by the degree of temporal coherence of the pump field. This study
can have important implications for understanding how correlations of the pump
field manifest as two-particle entanglement as well as for harnessing
energy-time entanglement for long-distance quantum communication protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03480</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barato</keyname><forenames>Andre C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seifert</keyname><forenames>Udo</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic cost of external control</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 (2017) 073021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa77d0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Artificial molecular machines are often driven by the periodic variation of
an external parameter. This external control exerts work on the system of which
a part can be extracted as output if the system runs against an applied load.
Usually, the thermodynamic cost of the process that generates the external
control is ignored. Here, we derive a refined second law for such small
machines that include this cost, which is, for example, generated by free
energy consumption of a chemical reaction that modifies the energy landscape
for such a machine. In the limit of irreversible control, this refined second
law becomes the standard one. Beyond this ideal limiting case, our analysis
shows that due to a new entropic term unexpected regimes can occur: The control
work can be smaller than the extracted work and the work required to generate
the control can be smaller than this control work. Our general inequalities are
illustrated by a paradigmatic three-state system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05705</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zeisner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brockmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei&#xdf;e</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thede</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ressouche</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Povarov</keyname><forenames>K. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheludev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xfc;mper</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chner</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;hmann</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic magnetic interactions and spin dynamics in the spin-chain
  compound Cu(py)$_2$Br$_2$: An experimental and theoretical study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>26 pages, 12 figures, section V.A.2 revised, appendices A and B
  shortened</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024429 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024429</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare theoretical results for electron spin resonance (ESR) properties
of the Heisenberg-Ising Hamiltonian with ESR experiments on the
quasi-one-dimensional magnet Cu(py)$_2$Br$_2$ (CPB). Our measurements were
performed over a wide frequency and temperature range giving insight into spin
dynamics, spin structure, and magnetic anisotropy of this compound. By
analyzing the angular dependence of ESR parameters (resonance shift and
linewidth) at room temperature we show that the two weakly coupled inequivalent
spin chain types inside the compound are well described by Heisenberg-Ising
chains with their magnetic anisotropy axes perpendicular to the chain direction
and almost perpendicular to each other. We further determine the full
$g$-tensor from these data. In addition, the angular dependence of the
linewidth at high temperatures gives us access to the exponent of the algebraic
decay of a dynamical correlation function of the isotropic Heisenberg chain.
From the temperature dependence of static susceptibilities we extract the
strength of the exchange coupling ($J/k_B = 52.0\,\text{K}$) and the anisotropy
parameter ($\delta\approx -0.02$) of the model Hamiltonian. An independent
compatible value of $\delta$ is obtained by comparing the exact prediction for
the resonance shift at low temperatures with high-frequency ESR data recorded
at $4\,\text{K}$. The spin structure in the ordered state implied by the two
(almost) perpendicular anisotropy axes is in accordance with the propagation
vector determined from neutron scattering experiments. In addition to undoped
samples we study the impact of partial substitution of Br by Cl ions on spin
dynamics. From the dependence of the ESR linewidth on doping level we infer an
effective decoupling of the anisotropic component $J\delta$ from the isotropic
exchange $J$ in these systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05761</id><created>2017-04-18</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ke-Jia</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximum Likelihood Estimation based on Random Subspace EDA: Application
  to Extrasolar Planet Detection</title><categories>stat.ME astro-ph.IM cs.LG cs.NE</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper addresses maximum likelihood (ML) estimation based model fitting
in the context of extrasolar planet detection. This problem is featured by the
following properties: 1) the candidate models under consideration are highly
nonlinear; 2) the likelihood surface has a huge number of peaks; 3) the
parameter space ranges in size from a few to dozens of dimensions. These
properties make the ML search a very challenging problem, as it lacks any
analytical or gradient based searching solution to explore the parameter space.
A population based searching method, called estimation of distribution
algorithm (EDA), is adopted to explore the model parameter space starting from
a batch of random locations. EDA is featured by its ability to reveal and
utilize problem structures. This property is desirable for characterizing the
detections. However, it is well recognized that EDAs can not scale well to
large scale problems, as it consists of iterative random sampling and model
fitting procedures, which results in the well-known dilemma curse of
dimensionality. A novel mechanism to perform EDAs in interactive random
subspaces spanned by correlated variables is proposed and the hope is to
alleviate the curse of dimensionality for EDAs by performing the operations of
sampling and model fitting in lower dimensional subspaces. The effectiveness of
the proposed algorithm is verified via both benchmark numerical studies and
real data analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06524</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sanchez-Puente</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Black Holes, Geons, and Singularities in Metric-Affine Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>PhD Dissertation, 196 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis deals with the problem of singularities in a family of extensions
of General Relativity in the Metric-Affine formalism. I introduce the
Metric-Affine formalism as a framework in which study extensions of GR. I
review its features and motivate it through its application in Bravais
crystals, where ideal crystals can be described through Riemannian formalism,
but a crystal with defects have to be described with in terms of an independent
connection. The simplest way to construct solutions different from GR in this
formalism is to take a quadratic gravity lagrangian with an electrovacuum
stress-energy tensor. This way, charged black hole solutions are obtained.
  The geometry of these new charged black hole solutions is analysed. Far from
the sources, the geometry of these new solutions is equal to the GR one up to
$1/r^4$ corrections. However, instead of a central singularity, they have a
wormhole structure, which can be completely regular or where the curvature
scalars diverge, depending on the mass and charge of the black hole. I study
the geodesics around the wormhole throat and conclude that the geodesics are
always complete even in the case of a curvature divergence. To analyse in more
detail the geometry, I also study the evolution of a scalar wave sent towards
the wormhole. The evolution is shown to be regular and I calculate the
transmission coefficients and transmission cross section for a naked wormhole.
  Finally, I study the same case for a Born-Infeld lagrangian in an arbitrary
number of dimension ($d&gt;4$). In this setting, the wormhole structure is also
present and the geodesics are still complete, therefore showing that the
metric-affine formalism can resolve singularities for a variety of models, and
is not a particular feature of the quadratic Lagrangian for $d=4$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07936</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bienzobaz</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandvik</keyname><forenames>Anders W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulated phases in a three-dimensional Maier-Saupe model with competing
  interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures, title modified, minor typos corrected, improved
  interpretation of results, published version</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 96, 012137 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012137</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work is dedicated to the study of the discrete version of the
Maier-Saupe model in the presence of competing interactions. The competition
between interactions favoring different orientational ordering produces a rich
phase diagram including modulated phases. Using a mean-field approach and Monte
Carlo simulations, we show that the proposed model exhibits isotropic and
nematic phases and also a series of modulated phases that meet at a
multicritical point, a Lifshitz point. Though the Monte Carlo and mean-field
phase diagrams show some quantitative disagreements, the Monte Carlo
simulations corroborate the general behavior found within the mean-field
approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08014</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Ryan B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corfdir</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herranz</keyname><forenames>Jes&#xfa;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;pers</keyname><forenames>Hanno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jahn</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geelhaar</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-assembly of InAs nanostructures on the sidewalls of GaAs nanowires
  directed by a Bi surfactant</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 2017, 17, 4255-4260</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01185</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface energies play a dominant role in the self-assembly of three
dimensional (3D) nanostructures. In this letter, we show that using surfactants
to modify surface energies can provide a means to externally control
nanostructure self-assembly, enabling the synthesis of novel hierarchical
nanostructures. We explore Bi as a surfactant in the growth of InAs on the
{1-10} sidewall facets of GaAs nanowires. The presence of surface Bi induces
the formation of InAs 3D islands by a process resembling the Stranski-Krastanov
mechanism, which does not occur in the absence of Bi on these surfaces. The
InAs 3D islands nucleate at the corners of the {1-10} facets above a critical
shell thickness and then elongate along &lt;110&gt; directions in the plane of the
nanowire sidewalls. Exploiting this growth mechanism, we realize a series of
novel hierarchical nanostructures, ranging from InAs quantum dots on single
{1-10} nanowire facets to zig-zag shaped nanorings completely encircling
nanowire cores. Photoluminescence spectroscopy and cathodoluminescence spectral
line scans reveal that small surfactant-induced InAs 3D islands behave as
optically active quantum dots. This work illustrates how surfactants can
provide an unprecedented level of external control over nanostructure
self-assembly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01766</id><created>2017-05-04</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baggioli</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wei-Jia</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusivities bounds and chaos in holographic Horndeski theories</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages + 3 appendices, 2 figures; v2: references added, typo
  corrected ; v3: minor revisions, references added, version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>CCTP-2017-2 CCTP-2017-2, ITCP-IPP 2017/11</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1707 (2017) 055</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the thermoelectric DC conductivities of Horndeski holographic models
with momentum dissipation. We compute the butterfly velocity $v_B$ and we
discuss the existence of universal bounds on charge and energy diffusivities in
the incoherent limit related to quantum chaos. We find that the Horndeski
coupling represents a subleading contribution to the thermoelectric
conductivities in the incoherent limit and therefore it does not affect any of
the proposed bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03940</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Logan G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wise</keyname><forenames>Frank W.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-power femtosecond pulses without a modelocked laser</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000831</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a fiber system which amplifies and compresses pulses from a
gain-switched diode. A Mamyshev regenerator shortens the pulses and improves
their coherence, enabling subsequent amplification by parabolic pre-shaping. As
a result, we are able to control nonlinear effects and generate nearly
transform-limited, 140-fs pulses with 13-MW peak power---an order-of-magnitude
improvement over previous gain-switched diode sources. Seeding with a
gain-switched diode results in random fluctuations of 2% in the pulse energy,
which future work using known techniques may ameliorate. Further development
may allow such systems to compete directly with sources based on modelocked
oscillators in some applications while enjoying unparalleled robustness and
repetition rate control.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04836</id><created>2017-05-13</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>Kazutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hida</keyname><forenames>Kazuo</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial Ferrimagnetism in S=1/2 Heisenberg Ladders with a Ferromagnetic
  Leg, an Antiferromagnetic Leg, and Antiferromagnetic Rungs</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 084706 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.084706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ground-state and finite-temperature properties of $S=1/2$ Heisenberg ladders
with a ferromagnetic leg, an antiferromagnetic leg, and antiferromagnetic rungs
are studied. It is shown that a partial ferrimagnetic phase extends over a wide
parameter range in the ground state. The numerical results are supported by an
analytical calculation based on a mapping onto the nonlinear $\sigma$ model and
a perturbation calculation from the strong-rung limit. It is shown that the
partial ferrimagnetic state is a spontaneously magnetized Tomonaga--Luttinger
liquid with incommensurate magnetic correlation, which is confirmed by a DMRG
calculation. The finite-temperature magnetic susceptibility is calculated using
the thermal pure quantum state method. It is suggested that the susceptibility
diverges as $T^{-2}$ in the ferrimagnetic phases as in the case of
ferromagnetic Heisenberg chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05400</id><created>2017-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kawagoe</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Greg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradas</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkinson</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pumir</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ben-Naim</keyname><forenames>Eli</forenames></author></authors><title>Aggregation-fragmentation-diffusion model for trail dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012142 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate statistical properties of trails formed by a random process
incorporating aggregation, fragmentation, and diffusion. In this stochastic
process, which takes place in one spatial dimension, two neighboring trails may
combine to form a larger one and also, one trail may split into two. In
addition, trails move diffusively. The model is defined by two parameters which
quantify the fragmentation rate and the fragment size. In the long-time limit,
the system reaches a steady state, and our focus is the limiting distribution
of trail weights. We find that the density of trail weight has power-law tail
$P(w) \sim w^{-\gamma}$ for small weight $w$. We obtain the exponent $\gamma$
analytically, and find that it varies continuously with the two model
parameters. The exponent $\gamma$ can be positive or negative, so that in one
range of parameters small-weight tails are abundant, and in the complementary
range, they are rare.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08577</id><created>2017-05-23</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>R. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>H. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimized contraction scheme for tensor-network states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, accepted version for Phys. Rev. B. The title is
  changed for easier understanding</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 045128 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.045128</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the tensor-network framework, the expectation values of two-dimensional
quantum states are evaluated by contracting a double-layer tensor network
constructed from initial and final tensor-network states. The computational
cost of carrying out this contraction is generally very high, which limits the
largest bond dimension of tensor-network states that can be accurately studied
to a relatively small value. We propose an optimized contraction scheme to
solve this problem by mapping the double-layer tensor network onto an
intersected single-layer tensor network. This reduces greatly the bond
dimensions of local tensors to be contracted and improves dramatically the
efficiency and accuracy of the evaluation of expectation values of
tensor-network states. It almost doubles the largest bond dimension of
tensor-network states whose physical properties can be efficiently and reliably
calculated, and it extends significantly the application scope of
tensor-network methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10979</id><created>2017-05-31</created><updated>2017-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuniba</keyname><forenames>Atsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mangazeev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density and current profiles in $U_q(A^{(1)}_2)$ zero range process</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>31 pages, 12 figures. Minor revision from version 1</comments><msc-class>81R50, 60C99</msc-class><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B922 (2017) 148--185</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.07.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stochastic $R$ matrix for $U_q(A^{(1)}_n)$ introduced recently gives rise
to an integrable zero range process of $n$ classes of particles in one
dimension. For $n=2$ we investigate how finitely many first class particles
fixed as defects influence the grand canonical ensemble of the second class
particles. By using the matrix product stationary probabilities involving
infinite products of $q$-bosons, exact formulas are derived for the local
density and current of the second class particles in the large volume limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.11075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.11075</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Joon-Young</forenames></author><author><keyname>LaRock</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>On emergence from the perspective of physical science</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we summarize the development of the concept of emergence in
physical science and propose key concepts of emergence in the form of
conjectures. Our conjectures are threefold: I. A system having a
broken-symmetry in membership relation with respect to micro and macro scales
can have emergent properties. II. Spontaneous symmetry-breaking is an example
of an emergent property. III. The phenomenon of hysteresis accompanies
spontaneous symmetry-breaking. We argue that these conjectures and their
relationship can illuminate the concept of emergence from the perspective of
symmetry breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06283</id><created>2017-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Maucher</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutcliffe</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>The length of excitable knots</title><categories>nlin.PS cond-mat.soft hep-th math.GT</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>DCPT-17/17</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012218 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012218</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The FitzHugh-Nagumo equation provides a simple mathematical model of cardiac
tissue as an excitable medium hosting spiral wave vortices. Here we present
extensive numerical simulations studying long-term dynamics of knotted vortex
string solutions for all torus knots up to crossing number 11. We demonstrate
that FitzHugh-Nagumo evolution preserves the knot topology for all the examples
presented, thereby providing a novel field theory approach to the study of
knots. Furthermore, the evolution yields a well-defined minimal length for each
knot that is comparable to the ropelength of ideal knots. We highlight the role
of the medium boundary in stabilizing the length of the knot and discuss the
implications beyond torus knots. By applying Moffatt's test we are able to show
that there is not a unique attractor within a given knot topology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10042</id><created>2017-06-30</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabello</keyname><forenames>Adan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum correlations with a gap between the sequential and spatial cases</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 012122 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the problem of whether parties who cannot communicate but share
nonsignaling quantum correlations between the outcomes of sharp measurements
can distinguish, just from the value of a correlation observable, whether their
outcomes were produced by sequential compatible measurements on single systems
or by measurements on spatially separated subsystems. We show that there are
quantum correlations between the outcomes of sequential measurements which
cannot be attained with spatially separated systems. We present examples of
correlations between spatially separated systems whose quantum maximum tends to
the sequential maximum as the number of parties increases and examples of
correlations between spatially separated systems whose quantum maximum fails to
violate the noncontextual bound while its corresponding sequential version
does.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04575</id><created>2017-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Chengyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Sanjeev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Kalarikad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepper</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>See</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrer</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritchie</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffiths</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>G. A. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct observation of exchange-driven spin interactions in
  one-dimensional system</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4989374</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present experimental results of transverse electron focusing measurements
performed on an n-type GaAs based mesoscopic device consisting of
one-dimensional (1D) quantum wires as injector and detector. We show that
non-adiabatic injection of 1D electrons at a conductance of e$^2$/h results in
a single first focusing peak, which on gradually increasing the injector
conductance up to 2e$^2$/h , produces asymmetric two sub-peaks in the first
focusing peak, each sub-peak representing the population of spin-state arising
from the spatially separated spins in the injector. Further increasing the
conductance flips the spin-states in the 1D channel thus reversing the
asymmetry in the sub-peaks. On applying a source-drain bias, the spin-gap, so
obtained, can be resolved thus providing evidence of exchange interaction
induced spin polarisation in the 1D systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04698</id><created>2017-07-15</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Senatore</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaldarriaga</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effective Field Theory of Large-Scale Structure in the presence of
  Massive Neutrinos</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>67 pages, 23 figures; v2: minor corrections</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a formalism to analytically describe the clustering of matter in
the mildly non-linear regime in the presence of massive neutrinos. Neutrinos,
whose free streaming wavenumber ($k_{\rm fs}$) is typically longer than the
non-linear scale ($k_{\rm NL}$) are described by a Boltzmann equation coupled
to the effective fluid-like equations that describe dark matter. We solve the
equations expanding in the neutrino density fraction $(f_\nu)$ and in $k/
k_{\rm NL}$, and add suitable counterterms to renormalize the theory. This
allows us to describe the contribution of short distances to long-distance
observables. Equivalently, we construct an effective Boltzmann equation where
we add additional terms whose coefficients renormalize the contribution from
short-distance physics. We argue that neutrinos with $k_{\rm fs}\gtrsim k_{\rm
NL}$ require an additional counterterm similar to the speed of sound ($c_s$)
for dark matter. We compute the one-loop total-matter power spectrum, and find
that it is roughly equal to $16f_\nu$ times the dark matter one for $k$'s
larger that the typical $k_{\rm fs}$. It is about half of that for smaller
$k$'s. The leading contribution results from the back-reaction of the neutrinos
on the dynamics of the dark matter. The counterterms contribute in a
hierarchical way: the leading ones can either be computed in terms of $c_s$, or
can be accounted for by shifting $c_s$ by an amount proportional to $f_\nu$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05284</id><created>2017-07-17</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amaryan</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames><affiliation>ODU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bashkanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Edinburgh U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ritman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Ruhr-U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames><affiliation>W&amp;M</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Strakovsky</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>GWU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>GlueX</forenames></author></authors><title>Strange Hadron Spectroscopy with a Secondary KL Beam at GlueX</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>97 pages, 63 figures, Proposal for JLab PAC45, PR12-17-001; v3 missed
  citation in Sec 9 (pg 22)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose to create a secondary beam of neutral kaons in Hall D at Jefferson
Lab to be used with the GlueX experimental setup for strange hadron
spectroscopy. A flux on the order of 3 x 10^4 KL/s will allow a broad range of
measurements to be made by improving the statistics of previous data obtained
on hydrogen targets by three orders of magnitude. Use of a deuteron target will
provide first measurements on the neutron which is {\it terra incognita}.
  The experiment will measure both differential cross sections and
self-analyzed polarizations of the produced {\Lambda}, {\Sigma}, {\Xi}, and
{\Omega} hyperons using the GlueX detector at the Jefferson Lab Hall D. The
measurements will span c.m. cos{\theta} from -0.95 to 0.95 in the c.m. range
above W = 1490 MeV and up to 3500 MeV. These new GlueX data will greatly
constrain partial-wave analyses and reduce model-dependent uncertainties in the
extraction of strange resonance properties (including pole positions), and
provide a new benchmark for comparisons with QCD-inspired models and lattice
QCD calculations.
  The proposed facility will also have an impact in the strange meson sector by
providing measurements of the final-state K{\pi} system from threshold up to 2
GeV invariant mass to establish and improve on the pole positions and widths of
all K*(K{\pi}) P-wave states as well as for the S-wave scalar meson
{\kappa}(800).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06199</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bogomazov</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherepashchuk</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lipunov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tutukov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wolf-Rayet stars, black holes and the first detected gravitational wave
  source</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>52 pages, 23 figures, 5 tables, accepted by New Astronomy</comments><doi>10.1016/j.newast.2017.07.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently discovered burst of gravitational waves GW150914 provides a good
new chance to verify the current view on the evolution of close binary stars.
Modern population synthesis codes help to study this evolution from two main
sequence stars up to the formation of two final remnant degenerate dwarfs,
neutron stars or black holes [Massevich 1988]. To study the evolution of the
GW150914 predecessor we use the &quot;Scenario Machine&quot; code presented by [Lipunov
1996]. The scenario modelling conducted in this study allowed to describe the
evolution of systems for which the final stage is a massive BH+BH merger. We
find that the initial mass of the primary component can be $100\div 140
M_{\odot}$ and the initial separation of the components can be $50\div 350
R_{\odot}$. Our calculations show the plausibility of modern evolutionary
scenarios for binary stars and the population synthesis modelling based on it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06361</id><created>2017-07-19</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>J. F. O</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furtado</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac states in armchair- and zigzag-edged graphene M\&quot;obius strips</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures, author added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Edge structure plays an essential role in the nature of electronic states in
graphene nanoribbons. By focusing on the interplay between this feature and
non-trivial topology in the domain of the Dirac confinement problem, this paper
proposes to examine how effects associated with edge shape manifest themselves
in conjunction with the topological signature typical of M\&quot;{o}bius strips
within a low-energy regime. Aiming to provide an alternative to prevailing
tight-binding approaches, zigzag and armchair M\&quot;{o}bius strips are modeled by
proposing compatible sets of boundary conditions, prescribing profiles of
terminations in both transverse and longitudinal directions which are
demonstrated to be coherent in describing consistently transverse edge patterns
in combination with a proper M\&quot;{o}bius periodicity. Of particular importance
is the absence of constraints on the solution, in contrast with infinite mass
analogues, as well as an energy spectrum with a characteristic dual structure
responding exclusively to the parity associated with the transverse quantum
number. Zigzag ribbons are predicted to possess an intrinsic mechanism for
parity inversion, while the armchair ones carry the possibility of a coexistent
gapless and gapped band structure. We also inspect the influence of the edge
structure on persistent currents. In zigzag-edged configurations they are found
to be sensitive to a length-dependent term which behaves as an effective flux.
Armchair rings show a quite distinctive property: alternation of constant and
flux-dependent currents according to the width of the ring, for a fixed
transverse quantum number. In the flux-free case the effects of topology are
found to be entirely suppressed, and conventional odd and even currents become
undistinguishable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06442</id><created>2017-07-20</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karpat</keyname><forenames>G&#xf6;ktu&#x11f;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Addis</keyname><forenames>Carole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maniscalco</keyname><forenames>Sabrina</forenames></author></authors><title>Frozen and Invariant Quantum Discord under Local Dephasing Noise</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Lectures on General Quantum Correlations and their Applications
  (Springer, 2017) pp 339-366</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-53412-1_16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this chapter, we intend to explore and review some remarkable dynamical
properties of quantum discord under various different open quantum system
models. Specifically, our discussion will include several concepts connected to
the phenomena of time invariant and frozen quantum discord. Furthermore, we
will elaborate on the relation of these two phenomena to the non-Markovian
features of the open system dynamics and to the usage of dynamical decoupling
protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06558</id><created>2017-07-20</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arreola-Lucas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe1;ez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervera</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Climente</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe9;ndez-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez-Dehesa</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanical Rainbow Trapping and Bloch Oscillations in Structured Elastic
  Beams</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate, both experimentally and numerically, the mechanical rainbow
trapping effect and the mechanical Bloch oscillations for torsional waves
propagating in chirped mechanical beams. After extensive simulations, three
quasi-one-dimensional chirped structures were designed, constructed and
experimentally characterized by Doppler spectroscopy. When the chirp intensity
vanishes a perfect periodic system, with bands and gaps, is obtained. The
mechanical rainbow trapping effect occurs for small values of the chirp
intensity. The wave packet traveling along the beam is progressively slowing
down and is reflected back at a certain depth, which depends on its central
frequency. In this case a new kind of oscillation, here named &quot;{\em rectified
rainbow-Bloch oscillation}&quot;, appears since the wave packet is reflected at one
side by the interface between the structure and the uniform rod and by the
minigap at the opposite side. For larger values of the chirp parameter the
rainbow trapping yields the penetration length where the mechanical Bloch
oscillations emerge. Numerical simulations based on the transfer matrix method
are in agreement with experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06568</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Parent</keyname><forenames>Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerard</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashyap</keyname><forenames>Raman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadoury</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author></authors><title>UV Exposed Optical Fibers with Frequency Domain Reflectometry for Device
  Tracking in Intra-Arterial Procedures</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Shape tracking of medical devices using strain sensing properties in optical
fibers has seen increased attention in recent years. In this paper, we propose
a novel guidance system for intra-arterial procedures using a distributed
strain sensing device based on optical frequency domain reflectometry (OFDR) to
track the shape of a catheter. Tracking enhancement is provided by exposing a
fiber triplet to a focused ultraviolet beam, producing high scattering
properties. Contrary to typical quasi-distributed strain sensors, we propose a
truly distributed strain sensing approach, which allows to reconstruct a fiber
triplet in real-time. A 3D roadmap of the hepatic anatomy integrated with a 4D
MR imaging sequence allows to navigate the catheter within the
pre-interventional anatomy, and map the blood flow velocities in the arterial
tree. We employed Riemannian anisotropic heat kernels to map the sensed data to
the pre-interventional model. Experiments in synthetic phantoms and an in vivo
model are presented. Results show that the tracking accuracy is suitable for
interventional tracking applications, with a mean 3D shape reconstruction
errors of 1.6 +/- 0.3 mm. This study demonstrates the promising potential of
MR-compatible UV-exposed OFDR optical fibers for non-ionizing device guidance
in intra-arterial procedures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06644</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ota</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Galaxy Scale Interstellar Infrared Spectrum Reproduced By A Hydrocarbon
  Pentagon-Hexagon Combined Molecule</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 page, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interstellar dust shows ubiquitous interstellar infrared spectrum (IR) due to
polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH). By our previous quantum chemistry
calculation, it was suggested that a molecule group having hydrocarbon
pentagon-hexagon combined skeleton could reproduce observed IR of dust clouds
in Milky Way galaxy. This paper extends to other many galaxies. Typical
galaxies are NGC6946 and M83. Those infrared spectrum were compared with that
of a model molecule (C23H12)2+ having hydrocarbon two pentagons combined with
five hexagons. Observed major infrared bands of 6.2, 7.7, 8.6, and 11.3
micrometer were successfully reproduced as 6.4, 7.7, 8.5, and 11.2 micrometer.
Even observed weaker bands of 12.0, 12.7, 14.2 micrometer were predicted well
by computed bands as 12.0, 12.6, and 13.9 micrometer. IR intensity ratio was
compared to check theoretical validity. Calculated intensity ratio between 7.7
versus 11.3 micrometer (PAH7.7/11.3) was 4.0, whereas observed ratio was in a
range of 2~6, also calculated PAH6.2/11.3 was 1.4 for observed range of
0.9~2.6. Especially, every calculated ratio was so close to that of M83 arm
region. It should be noted that both calculated wavelength and intensity could
reproduce observed galaxy scale infrared spectrum. Hydrocarbon pentagon-hexagon
molecule would be general carrier in many galaxies including Milky Way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06660</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Simion</keyname><forenames>Iulia T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belokurov</keyname><forenames>Vasily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koposov</keyname><forenames>Sergey E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Fernandez</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robin</keyname><forenames>Annie C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Juntai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>A parametric description of the 3D structure of the Galactic Bar/Bulge
  using the VVV survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>24 pages, 4 tables, 21 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1832</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the structure of the inner Milky Way using the latest data release
of the Vista Variables in Via Lactea (VVV) survey. The VVV is a deep
near-infrared, multi-colour photometric survey with a coverage of 300 square
degrees towards the Bulge/Bar. We use Red Clump (RC) stars to produce a
high-resolution dust map of the VVV's field of view. From de-reddened
colour-magnitude diagrams we select Red Giant Branch stars to investigate their
3D density distribution within the central 4 kpc. We demonstrate that our
best-fit parametric model of the Bulge density provides a good description of
the VVV data, with a median percentage residual of 5$\%$ over the fitted
region. The strongest of the otherwise low-level residuals are overdensities
associated with a low-latitude structure as well as the so-called X-shape
previously identified using the split RC. These additional components
contribute only $\sim5\%$ and $\sim7\%$ respectively to the Bulge mass budget.
The best-fit Bulge is `boxy' with an axis ratio of [1:0.44:0.31] and is rotated
with respect to the Sun-Galactic Centre line by at least $20^{\circ}$. We
provide an estimate of the total, full sky, mass of the Bulge of
$M_\mathrm{Bulge}^{\mathrm{Chabrier}} = 2.36 \times 10^{10} M_{\odot}$ for a
Chabrier initial mass function. We show there exists a strong degeneracy
between the viewing angle and the dispersion of the Red Clump absolute
magnitude distribution. The value of the latter is strongly dependent on the
assumptions made about the intrinsic luminosity function of the Bulge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06679</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Lamb</keyname><forenames>Masen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correia</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauvage</keyname><forenames>Jean-Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veran</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vigan</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wizinowich</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dam</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mugnier</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bond</keyname><forenames>Charlotte</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying telescope phase discontinuities external to AO-systems by
  use of Phase Diversity and Focal Plane Sharpening</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures, Accepted for publication in JATIS</comments><journal-ref>J. Astron. Telesc. Instrum. Syst. 3(3), 039001 (Jun 16, 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.3.3.039001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and apply two methods to estimate pupil plane phase
discontinuities for two realistic scenarios on VLT and Keck. The methods use
both Phase Diversity and a form of image sharpening. For the case of VLT, we
simulate the `low wind effect' (LWE) which is responsible for focal plane
errors in the SPHERE system in low wind and good seeing conditions. We
successfully estimate the simulated LWE using both methods, and show that they
are complimentary to one another. We also demonstrate that single image Phase
Diversity (also known as Phase Retrieval with diversity) is also capable of
estimating the simulated LWE when using the natural de-focus on the SPHERE/DTTS
imager. We demonstrate that Phase Diversity can estimate the LWE to within 30
nm RMS WFE, which is within the allowable tolerances to achieve a target SPHERE
contrast of 10$^{-6}$. Finally, we simulate 153 nm RMS of piston errors on the
mirror segments of Keck and produce NIRC2 images subject to these effects. We
show that a single, diverse image with 1.5 waves (PV) of focus can be used to
estimate this error to within 29 nm RMS WFE, and a perfect correction of our
estimation would increase the Strehl ratio of a NIRC2 image by 12\%
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06686</id><created>2017-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Patrascu</keyname><forenames>Andrei T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomaly cancellation by generalised cohomology</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetric states in M-theory are mapped after compactification to
perturbatively non-supersymmetric states in type IIA string theory, with the
supersymmetric parts being encoded in the non-perturbative section of the
string theory. An observer unable to recognise certain topological features of
string theory will not detect supersymmetry. Such relativity of symmetry can
also be derived in the context of Theorem 3 in ref. [11]. The tool of choice in
this context is the universal coefficient theorem linking cohomology theories
with coefficients that reveal respectively hide certain topological features.
As a consequence of these observations, it is shown that the same theorem is
capable of linking perturbative with non-perturbative string theoretical
domains. A discussion of inflow anomaly cancellation is also included in the
context of universal coefficient theorems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06710</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuzmicheva</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muratov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzmichev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadakov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aleshchenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlasenko</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martovitsky</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pervakov</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eltsev</keyname><forenames>Yu. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pudalov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Structure of Superconducting Order Parameter in High-Temperature
  Fe-Based Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Physics-Uspekhi 60(4), 419-429 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3367/UFNe.2016.10.038002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses the synthesis, characterization, and comprehensive study
of Ba-122 single crystals with various substitutions and various $T_c$. The
paper uses five complementary techniques to obtain a self-consistent set of
data on the superconducting properties of Ba-122. A major conclusion of the
authors work is the coexistence of two superconducting condensates differing in
the electron-boson coupling strength. The two gaps that develop in distinct
Fermi surface sheets are nodeless in the $k_xk_y$-plane and exhibit s-wave
symmetry, the two-band model represents a sufficient data description tool. A
moderate interband coupling and a considerable Coulomb repulsion in the
description of the two-gap superconducting state of barium pnictides favor the
$s^{++}$-model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06717</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Papadakis</keyname><forenames>Georgia T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narang</keyname><forenames>Prineha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sundararaman</keyname><forenames>Ravishankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivera</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buljan</keyname><forenames>Hrvoje</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engheta</keyname><forenames>Nader</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soljacic</keyname><forenames>Marin</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-light \AA-scale Optimal Optical Reflectors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-reflectance in many state-of-the-art optical devices is achieved with
noble metals. However, metals are limited by losses, and for certain
applications, by their high mass density. Using a combination of ab initio and
optical transfer matrix calculations, we evaluate the behavior of
graphene-based \AA-scale metamaterials and find that they could act as
nearly-perfect reflectors in the mid-long wave infrared (IR) range. The low
density of states for electron-phonon scattering and interband excitations
leads to unprecedented optical properties for graphene heterostructures,
especially alternating atomic layers of graphene and hexagonal boron nitride,
at wavelengths greater than $10~\mu$m. At these wavelengths, these materials
exhibit reflectivities exceeding 99.7% at a fraction of the weight of noble
metals, as well as plasmonic mode confinement and quality factors that are
greater by an order of magnitude compared to noble metals. These findings hold
promise for ultra-compact optical components and waveguides for mid-IR
applications. Moreover, unlike metals, the photonic properties of these
heterostructures could be actively tuned via chemical and/or electrostatic
doping, providing exciting possibilities for tunable devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06743</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac equation in one dimensional transformation optics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the propagation of transverse electric (TE) polarized waves in
one dimensional inhomogeneous settings can be written in the form of the Dirac
equation in one space dimension with a Lorentz scalar potential, and
consequently perform photonic simulations of the Dirac equation in optical
structures. In particular, we propose how the zero energy state of the
Jackiw-Rebbi model can be implemented in a optical set up by controlling the
refractive index landscape, where TE polarized waves mimic the Dirac particles
and the soliton field can be implemented and tuned by adjusting the refractive
index.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06746</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ai</keyname><forenames>Bao-quan</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport and diffusion properties of Brownian particles powered by a
  rotating wheel</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 96, 012131 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diffusion and rectification of Brownian particles powered by a rotating wheel
are numerically investigated in a two-dimensional channel. The nonequilibrium
driving comes from the rotating wheel, which can break thermodynamical
equilibrium and induce the directed transport in an asymmetric potential. It is
found that the direction of the transport along the potential is determined by
the asymmetry of the potential and the position of the wheel. The average
velocity is a peaked function of the angular speed (or the diffusion
coefficient) and the position of the peak shifts to large angular speed(or
diffusion coefficient) when the diffusion coefficient (or the angular speed)
increases. There exists an optimal angular speed (or diffusion coefficient) at
which the effective diffusion coefficient takes its maximal value. Remarkably,
the giant acceleration of diffusion is observed by suitably adjusting the
system parameters. The parameters corresponding to the maximum effective
diffusion coefficient are not the same as the parameters at which average
velocity is maximum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06755</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Gott</keyname><forenames>J. Richard</forenames><suffix>III</suffix><affiliation>Princeton University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Colley</keyname><forenames>Wesley N.</forenames><affiliation>University of Alabama in Huntsville</affiliation></author></authors><title>Reanalysis of the BICEP2, Keck and Planck Data: No Evidence for
  Gravitational Radiation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>LaTeX (MNRAS style), 10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A joint analysis of data collected by the Planck and BICEP2+Keck teams has
previously given $r = 0.09^{+0.06}_{-0.04}$ for BICEP2 and $r =
0.02^{+0.04}_{-0.02}$ for Keck. Analyzing BICEP2 using its published noise
estimate, we had earlier (Colley &amp; Gott 2015) found $r = 0.09 \pm 0.04$,
agreeing with the final joint results for BICEP2. With the Keck data now
available, we have done something the joint analysis did not: a correlation
study of the BICEP2 vs. Keck B-mode maps. Knowing the correlation coefficient
between the two and their amplitudes allows us to determine the noise in each
map (which we check using the E-modes). We find the noise power in the BICEP2
map to be twice the original BICEP2 published estimate, explaining the
anomalously high $r$ value obtained by BICEP2. We now find $r = 0.004 \pm 0.04$
for BICEP2 and $r = -0.01 \pm 0.04$ for Keck. Since $r \ge 0$ by definition,
this implies a maximum likelihood value of $r = 0$, or no evidence for
gravitational waves. Starobinsky Inflation ($r = 0.0036$) is not ruled out,
however. Krauss &amp; Wilzcek (2014) have already argued that &quot;measurement of
polarization of the CMB due to a long-wavelength stochastic background of
gravitational waves from Inflation in the early Universe would firmly establish
the quantization of gravity,&quot; and, therefore, the existence of gravitons. We
argue it would also constitute a detection of gravitational Hawking radiation
(explicitly from the causal horizons due to Inflation).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06762</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Qi-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Dao-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical Current Anomaly at the Topological Quantum Phase Transition in
  a Majorana Josephson Junction</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A 381 (2017) 2033</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.04.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Majorana bound states in topological Josephson junctions induce a 4? period
current-phase relation. Direct detection of the 4? periodicity is complicated
by the quasiparticle poisoning. We reveal that Majorana bound states are also
signaled by the anomalous enhancement on the critical current of the junction.
We show the landscape of the critical current for a nanowire Josephson junction
under a varying Zeeman field, and reveal a sharp step feature at the
topological quantum phase transition point, which comes from the anomalous
enhancement of the critical current at the topological regime. In multi-band
wires, the anomalous enhancement disappears for an even number of bands, where
the Majorana bound states fuse into Andreev bound states. This anomalous
critical current enhancement directly signals the existence of the Majorana
bound states, and also provides a valid signature for the topological quantum
phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06767</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yunshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Lingyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nai</keyname><forenames>Mui Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiam</keyname><forenames>Sing Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chim</keyname><forenames>Wai Kin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Chwee Teck</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Baowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thong</keyname><forenames>John T L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hippalgaonkar</keyname><forenames>Kedar</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultralow thermal conductivity of single crystalline porous silicon
  nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Porous materials provide a large surface to volume ratio, thereby providing a
knob to alter fundamental properties in unprecedented ways. In thermal
transport, porous nanomaterials can reduce thermal conductivity by not only
enhancing phonon scattering from the boundaries of the pores and therefore
decreasing the phonon mean free path, but also by reducing the phonon group
velocity. Here we establish a structure-property relationship by measuring the
porosity and thermal conductivity of individual electrolessly etched single
crystalline silicon nanowires using a novel electron beam heating technique.
Such porous silicon nanowires exhibit extremely low diffusive thermal
conductivity (as low as 0.33 Wm-1K-1 at 300K for 43% porosity), even lower than
that of amorphous silicon. The origin of such ultralow thermal conductivity is
understood as a reduction in the phonon group velocity, experimentally verified
by measuring the Young modulus, as well as the smallest structural size ever
reported in crystalline Silicon (less than 5nm). Molecular dynamics simulations
support the observation of a drastic reduction in thermal conductivity of
silicon nanowires as a function of porosity. Such porous materials provide an
intriguing platform to tune phonon transport, which can be useful in the design
of functional materials towards electronics and nano-electromechanical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06785</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Viaggiu</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy, temperature and internal energy of trapped gravitons and
  corrections to the Black Hole entropy</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication on Physica A</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 488 (2017) 72</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2017.07.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the proposal present in \cite{1} concerning the
statistical description of trapped gravitons and applied to derive the
semi-classical black hole (BH) entropy $S_{BH}$. We study the possible
configurations depending on physically reasonable expressions for the internal
energy $U$. In particular, we show that expressions for $U\sim R^k, k\geq 1$,
with $R$ the radius of the confining spherical box, can have a semi-classical
description, while behaviors with $k&lt;1$ derive from thermodynamic or quantum
fluctuations. There, by taking a suitable physically motivated expression for
$U(R)$, we obtain the well known logarithmic corrections to the BH entropy,
with the usual behaviors present in the literature of BH entropy. Moreover, a
phase transition emerges with a positive specific heat $C$ at Planckian lengths
instead of the usual negative oneat non-Planckian scales, in agreement with
results present in the literature. Finally, we show that evaporation stops at a
radius $R$ of the order of the Planck length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06790</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yijia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhengyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Improvement of two-way continuous-variable quantum key distribution with
  virtual photon subtraction</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf Process 16, 184 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-017-1617-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to improve the performance of two-way continuous-variable
quantum key distribution protocol by virtual photon subtraction. The Virtual
photon subtraction implemented via non-Gaussian post-selection not only
enhances the entanglement of two-mode squeezed vacuum state but also has
advantages in simplifying physical operation and promoting efficiency. In
two-way protocol, virtual photon subtraction could be applied on two sources
independently. Numerical simulations show that the optimal performance of
renovated two-way protocol is obtained with photon subtraction only used by
Alice. The transmission distance and tolerable excess noise are improved by
using the virtual photon subtraction with appropriate parameters. Moreover, the
tolerable excess noise maintains a high value with the increase of distance so
that the robustness of two-way continuous-variable quantum key distribution
system is significantly improved, especially at long transmission distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06796</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Roehner</keyname><forenames>Bertrand M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial and historical determinants of separatism and integration. 1.
  Qualitative analysis</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Separatism is examined in a long-run perspective. Accordingly, many political
or economic factors which may be crucial in dealing with short-term episodes
can be safely disregarded. Extending an approach pioneered by J. Jenkins, the
paper assesses the role of spatial and historical factors. It shows that the
means used to stage a separatist struggle are to a notable extent borrowed from
former historical episodes, an analysis which supports and illustrates Charles
Tilly's thesis of restricted repertoires of action. The purpose of the present
paper is to introduce the model, to make it plausible and to demonstrate its
potential usefulness by examining a number of critical examples. A more
systematic analysis is carried out in a follow-up paper by using a data set
that includes about 40 cases of separatist struggles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06800</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Roehner</keyname><forenames>Bertrand M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial and historical determinants of separatism and integration. 2.
  Quantitative analysis</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In part 1 we have discussed the role played by geographical and historical
conditions. Here we wish to test our model and to estimate its parameters. Ti
this effect two indexes are introduced. The geographical index is aimed at
characterizing the degree of separateness of a given region with respect to the
national state to which it belongs. This index turns out to be closely
connected to the number of minority-speakers; it is also correlated with the
level of separatist disturbances, at least for samples having the same
historical background. The purpose of the second index is precisely to specify
the role of past episodes in shaping current separatist outbreaks. To a large
extent, current episodes are modeled on former ones; typically this process of
semi-replication appears to be characterized by a &quot;memory&quot; that extends over at
least one and a half century. Note that this study concentrates on the
occurrence and forms of separatist struggles rather than on their short-term
political causes. In so doing, it follows a methodological track that has been
pioneered by Stanley Lieberson (1985, the &quot;stardom&quot; paradigm) and Charles Tilly
(1993, the &quot;traffic jam&quot; paradigm).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06801</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Giuseppe</keyname><forenames>Rosi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luca</keyname><forenames>Placidi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolas</keyname><forenames>Auffray</forenames></author></authors><title>On the validity range of strain-gradient elasticity: a mixed
  static-dynamic identification procedure</title><categories>physics.class-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wave propagation in architectured materials, or materials with
microstructure, is known to be dependent on the ratio between the wavelength
and a characteristic size of the microstructure. Indeed, when this ratio
decreases (i.e. when the wavelength approaches this characteristic size)
important quantities, such as phase and group velocity, deviate considerably
from their low frequency/long wavelength values. This well-known phenomenon is
called dispersion of waves. Objective of this work is to show that
strain-gradient elasticity can be used to quantitatively describe the behaviour
of a microstructured solid, and that the validity domain (in terms of frequency
and wavelength) of this model is sufficiently large to be useful in practical
applications. To this end, the parameters of the overall continuum are
identified for a periodic architectured material, and the results of a
transient problem are compared to those obtained from a finite element full
field computation on the real geometry. The quality of the overall description
using a strain-gradient elastic continuum is compared to the classical
homogenization procedure that uses Cauchy continuum. The extended model of
elasticity is shown to provide a good approximation of the real solution over a
wider frequency range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06805</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Touati</keyname><forenames>Selim</forenames></author></authors><title>EDM with and beyond flavor invariants</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the flavor structure of quark and lepton EDMs in the SM and
beyond is investigated using tools inspired from Minimal Flavor Violation.
While Jarlskog-like flavor invariants are adequate for estimating CP-violation
from closed fermion loops, non-invariant structures arise from rainbow-like
processes. Our goal is to systematically construct these latter flavor
structures in the quark and lepton sectors, assuming different mechanisms for
generating neutrino masses. Numerically, they are found typically much larger,
and not necessarily correlated with, Jarlskog-like invariants. Finally, the
formalism is adapted to deal with a third class of flavor structures, sensitive
to the flavored U(1) phases, and used to study the impact of the strong
CP-violating interaction and the interplay between the neutrino Majorana phases
and possible baryon and/or lepton number violating interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06812</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>H. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mottola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hviid</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hrt</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skorov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vincent</keyname><forenames>J. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oklay</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidsson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pajola</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodewits</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toth</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preusker</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholten</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sierks</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbieri</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koschny</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rickman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>A'Hearn</keyname><forenames>M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barucci</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertaux</keyname><forenames>J. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertini</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cremonese</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Da Deppo</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debei</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Cecco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deller</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fornasier</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulle</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groussin</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;ttler</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ip</keyname><forenames>W. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jorda</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knollenberg</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramm</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;ppers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>L. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazzarin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>J. J. Lopez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzari</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naletto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tubiana</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seasonal Mass Transfer on the Nucleus of Comet 67P/Chuyumov-Gerasimenko</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>17 pages, 20 figures</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society stx1726, 13 July
  2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1726</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We collect observational evidence that supports the scheme of mass transfer
on the nucleus of comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko. The obliquity of the
rotation axis of 67P causes strong seasonal variations. During perihelion the
southern hemisphere is four times more active than the north. Northern
territories are widely covered by granular material that indicates back fall
originating from the active south. Decimetre sized chunks contain water ice and
their trajectories are influenced by an anti-solar force instigated by
sublimation. OSIRIS observations suggest that up to 20 % of the particles
directly return to the nucleus surface taking several hours of travel time. The
back fall covered northern areas are active if illuminated but produce mainly
water vapour. The decimetre chunks from the nucleus surface are too small to
contain more volatile compounds such as CO 2 or CO. This causes a north-south
dichotomy of the composition measurements in the coma. Active particles are
trapped in the gravitational minimum of Hapi during northern winter. They are
&quot;shock frozen&quot; and only reactivated when the comet approaches the sun after its
aphelion passage. The insolation of the big cavity is enhanced by self-heating,
i. e. reflection and IR radiation from the walls. This, together with the
pristinity of the active back fall, explains the early observed activity of the
Hapi region. Sobek may be a role model for the consolidated bottom of Hapi.
Mass transfer in the case of 67P strongly influences the evolution of the
nucleus and the interpretation of coma measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06823</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Barabash</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basharina-Freshville</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blot</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bongrand</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgeois</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breton</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brudanin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bure&#x161;ov&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busto</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caffrey</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvez</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cascella</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerna</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cesar</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauveau</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chopra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claverie</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Capua</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delalee</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchesneau</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egorov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eurin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fajt</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filosofov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flack</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrido</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillon</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hod&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hol&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugon</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeremie</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jullian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kauer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kochetov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konovalov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemi&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noblet</keyname><forenames>T. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liptak</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loaiza</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lutter</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maalmi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamedov</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquet</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauger</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreau</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mott</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemchenok</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomachi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nova</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohsumi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pahlka</keyname><forenames>R. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pater</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrot</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piquemal</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Povinec</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#x159;idal</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramachers</keyname><forenames>Y. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebii</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Remoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richards</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricol</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riddle</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rukhadze</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saakyan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salazar</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarazin</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedgbeer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shitov</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;imkovic</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simard</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smetana</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolek</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolnikov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snow</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xf6;ldner-Rembold</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soul&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;pavorov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;tekl</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timkin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torre</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyak</keyname><forenames>Vl. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyak</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umatov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilela</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorobel</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17d;ukauskas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calorimeter development for the SuperNEMO double beta decay experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.06.044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SuperNEMO is a double-$\beta$ decay experiment, which will employ the
successful tracker-calorimeter technique used in the recently completed NEMO-3
experiment. SuperNEMO will implement 100 kg of double-$\beta$ decay isotope,
reaching a sensitivity to the neutrinoless double-$\beta$ decay
($0\nu\beta\beta$) half-life of the order of $10^{26}$ yr, corresponding to a
Majorana neutrino mass of 50-100 meV. One of the main goals and challenges of
the SuperNEMO detector development programme has been to reach a calorimeter
energy resolution, $\Delta$E/E, around 3%/$sqrt(E)$(MeV) $\sigma$, or
7%/$sqrt(E)$(MeV) FWHM (full width at half maximum), using a calorimeter
composed of large volume plastic scintillator blocks coupled to photomultiplier
tubes. We describe the R\&amp;D programme and the final design of the SuperNEMO
calorimeter that has met this challenging goal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06824</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Yim</keyname><forenames>Chanyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Passi</keyname><forenames>Vikram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemme</keyname><forenames>Max C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duesberg</keyname><forenames>Georg S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pallechi</keyname><forenames>Cormac &#xd3; Coile&#xe1;in Emiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fadil</keyname><forenames>Dalal</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEvoy</keyname><forenames>Niall</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical characterization of structured platinum diselenide devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Platinum diselenide (PtSe2) is an exciting new member of the two-dimensional
(2D) transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) family. it has a semimetal to
semiconductor transition when approaching monolayer thickness and has already
shown significant potential for use in device applications. Notably, PtSe2 can
be grown at low temperature making it potentially suitable for industrial
usage. Here, we address thickness dependent transport properties and
investigate electrical contacts to PtSe2, a crucial and universal element of
TMD-based electronic devices. PtSe2 films have been synthesized at various
thicknesses and structured to allow contact engineering and the accurate
extraction of electrical properties. Contact resistivity and sheet resistance
extracted from transmission line method (TLM) measurements are compared for
different contact metals and different PtSe2 film thicknesses. Furthermore, the
transition from semimetal to semiconductor in PtSe2 has been indirectly
verified by electrical characterization of field-effect devices. Finally, the
influence of edge contacts at the metal - PtSe2 interface has been studied by
nanostructuring the contact area using electron beam lithography. By increasing
the edge contact length, the contact resistivity was improved by up to 70%
compared to devices with conventional top contacts. The results presented here
represent crucial steps towards realizing high-performance nanoelectronic
devices based on group-10 TMDs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06839</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>van de Bruck</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dimopoulos</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longden</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>Charlotte</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauss-Bonnet-coupled Quintessential Inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>26 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study in detail a new model of quintessential inflation where the inflaton
field is coupled to the Gauss-Bonnet term. This coupling ensures that the
variation of the field is kept sub-Planckian, which avoids the 5th force
problem as well as the lifting of the flatness of the quintessential tail in
the runaway scalar potential due to radiative corrections. We find that the
inflationary predictions of the model are in excellent agreement with CMB
observations, while the coincidence requirement of dark energy is satisfied
with natural values of the parameters, overcoming thereby the extreme
fine-tuning of the cosmological constant in $\Lambda$CDM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06851</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>The Efficacy of Fiction or More on the Charge State of Ti in TiO2 and
  Formal Oxidation States</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that Ti4+ is not a realistic description of Ti in TiO2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06857</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Poshadel</keyname><forenames>Andrew C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gharghouri</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>Paul R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Initiation and Propagation of Plastic Yielding in Duplex Stainless Steel</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>48 pages with 27 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The elastoplastic behavior of a two-phase stainless steel alloy is explored
at the crystal scale for five levels of stress biaxiality. The crystal lattice
(elastic) strains were measured with neutron diffraction using tubular samples
subjected to different combinations of axial load and internal pressure to
achieve a range of biaxial stress ratios. Finite element simulations were
conducted on virtual polycrystals using loading histories that mimicked the
experimental protocols. For this, two-phase microstructures were instantiated
based on microscopy images of the grain and phase topologies and on
crystallographic orientation distributions from neutron diffraction. Detailed
comparisons were made between the measured and computed lattice strains for
several crystal reflections in both phases for scattering vectors in the axial,
radial and hoop directions that confirm the model's ability to accurate predict
the evolving local stress states. A strength-to-stiffness parameter for
multiaxial stress states was applied to explain the initiation of yielding
across the polycrystalline samples across the five levels of stress biaxiality.
Finally, building off the multiaxial strength-to-stiffness, the propagation of
yielding over the volume of a polycrystal was estimated in terms of an equation
that provides the local stress necessary to initiate within crystals in terms
of the macroscopic stress.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06861</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>Shreyash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shastri</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sivasankaran</keyname><forenames>B. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rani</keyname><forenames>Luxmi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaila</keyname><forenames>Bipin K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Navinder</forenames></author></authors><title>The Kelvin Water Dropper: Converting a physics toy into an educational
  device</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kelvin Water Dropper was discovered by Lord Kelvin in 1867 and it works
on the principle of electrostatic induction. A working model of Kelvin Water
Dropper is fabricated in the workshop facility of Physical Research Laboratory,
Ahmedabad. We, for the first time, performed a quantitative measurement of the
temporal development of charge using a new method that we call &quot;Effective
Capacitance method&quot;. With this, the Kelvin Water Dropper experiment can be
introduced in undergraduate curriculum, where students can perform quantitative
measurements with the apparatus using our &quot;Effective Capacitance method&quot;. This
should change the generally held view of Kelvin water dropper as being an
entertaining toy to a mature educational device.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06862</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Cordero</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Gosson</keyname><forenames>Maurice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicola</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>A characterization of modulation spaces by symplectic rotations</title><categories>math.FA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This note contains a new characterization of modulation spaces
$M^p(\mathbb{R}^n)$, $1\leq p\leq \infty$, by symplectic rotations. Precisely,
instead to measure the time-frequency content of a function by using
translations and modulations of a fixed window as building blocks, we use
translations and metaplectic operators corresponding to symplectic rotations.
Technically, this amounts to replace, in the computation of the
$M^p(\mathbb{R}^n)$-norm, the integral in the time-frequency plane with an
integral on $\mathbb{R}^n\times U(2n,\mathbb{R})$ with respect to a suitable
measure, $U(2n,\mathbb{R})$ being the group of symplectic rotations. More
conceptually, we are considering a sort of polar coordinates in the
time-frequency plane. In this new framework, the Gaussian invariance under
symplectic rotations yields to choose Gaussians as suitable window functions.
We also provide a similar characterization with the group $U(2n,\mathbb{R})$
being reduced to the $n$-dimensional torus $\mathbb{T}^n$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06871</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Siegert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Positron Annihilation in the Milky Way and beyond</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, accepted contribution to the 11th INTEGRAL
  Conference, &quot;Gamma-Ray Astrophysics in Multi-Wavelength Perspective&quot;, 10-14
  October 2016, Amsterdam, The Netherlands</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electron-positron annihilation gamma-ray signal at 511 keV in the Milky
Way is investigated towards a possible dark matter interpretation. If all bulge
positrons were created by dark matter particle annihilation, the satellite
galaxies of the Milky Way, apparently being dominated by dark matter, should
also show measurable 511 keV signals. Using INTEGRAL/SPI, we test for emission
in 39 neighbouring dwarf satellite galaxies, and found a consistent trend
against a dark matter scenario. One galaxy, Reticulum II, shows up as a strong
source of annihilation emission, which we interpret as the presence of a
microquasar, ejecting pair-plasma into the galaxy's interstellar medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06882</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Schlichting</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Berlin, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>G. M. O.</forenames><affiliation>Bundesanstalt f&#xfc;r Materialforschung und -pr&#xfc;fung</affiliation></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;&#xdf;ener</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Universit&#xe4;t Bremen, Bremen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hille</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Universit&#xe4;t Bremen, Bremen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grieb</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Universit&#xe4;t Bremen, Bremen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Teubert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>I. Physikalisches Institut, Justus-Liebig Universit&#xe4;t Giessen, Heinrich-Buff-Ring, Giessen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;rmann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>I. Physikalisches Institut, Justus-Liebig Universit&#xe4;t Giessen, Heinrich-Buff-Ring, Giessen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Berlin, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rosenauer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Universit&#xe4;t Bremen, Bremen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eickhoff</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Universit&#xe4;t Bremen, Bremen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Berlin, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Callsen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Technische Universit&#xe4;t Berlin, Berlin, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Tuning of the Quantum-Confined Stark Effect in Wurtzite $[000\bar{1}]$
  Group-III-Nitride Nanostructures by the Internal-Field-Guarded-Active-Region
  Design</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, we suggested an unconventional approach [the so-called
Internal-Field-Guarded-Active-Region Design (IFGARD)] for the elimination of
the crystal polarization field induced quantum confined Stark effect (QCSE) in
polar semiconductor heterostructures. And in this work, we demonstrate by means
of micro-photoluminescence techniques the successful tuning as well as the
elimination of the QCSE in strongly polar $[000\bar{1}]$ wurtzite GaN/AlN
nanodiscs while reducing the exciton life times by more than two orders of
magnitude. The IFGARD based elimination of the QCSE is independent of any
specific crystal growth procedures. Furthermore, the cone-shaped geometry of
the utilized nanowires (which embeds the investigated IFGARD nanodiscs)
facilitates the experimental differentiation between quantum confinement- and
QCSE-induced emission energy shifts. Due to the IFGARD, both effects become
independently adaptable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06890</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Duming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ha</keyname><forenames>Jeonghoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baek</keyname><forenames>Hongwoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Yang-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natterer</keyname><forenames>Fabian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myers</keyname><forenames>Alline F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumacher</keyname><forenames>Joshua D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cullen</keyname><forenames>William G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>Albert V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuk</keyname><forenames>Young</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhitenev</keyname><forenames>Nikolai B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stroscio</keyname><forenames>Joseph A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain Engineering a $4a\times\sqrt{3}a$ Charge Density Wave Phase in
  Transition Metal Dichalcogenide 1T-VSe$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Materials, 1, 024005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.024005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a rectangular charge density wave (CDW) phase in strained
1T-VSe$_2$ thin films synthesized by molecular beam epitaxy on c-sapphire
substrates. The observed CDW structure exhibits an unconventional rectangular
4a{\times}{\sqrt{3a}} periodicity, as opposed to the previously reported
hexagonal $4a\times4a$ structure in bulk crystals and exfoliated thin layered
samples. Tunneling spectroscopy shows a strong modulation of the local density
of states of the same $4a\times\sqrt{3}a$ CDW periodicity and an energy gap of
$2\Delta_{CDW}=(9.1\pm0.1)$ meV. The CDW energy gap evolves into a full gap at
temperatures below 500 mK, indicating a transition to an insulating phase at
ultra-low temperatures. First-principles calculations confirm the stability of
both $4a\times4a$ and $4a\times\sqrt{3}a$ structures arising from soft modes in
the phonon dispersion. The unconventional structure becomes preferred in the
presence of strain, in agreement with experimental findings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06896</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Kadobianskyi</keyname><forenames>Mykola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papadopoulos</keyname><forenames>Ioannis N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaigne</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horstmeyer</keyname><forenames>Roarke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Judkewitz</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering correlations of time-gated light</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Manipulating the propagation of light through scattering media remains a
major challenge for many applications, including astronomy, biomedical imaging
and colloidal optics. Wavefront shaping is one of the most promising ways to
mitigate scattering and focus through inhomogeneous samples. However, wavefront
correction remains accurate over only a limited spatial extent within the
scattering medium - a correlation range referred to as the optical memory
effect. Here, by selecting only the weakly scattered light for wavefront
shaping, we show that the addition of temporal degrees of freedom enhances this
correlation range. We investigate spatial scattering correlations by digitally
time-gating the early arriving light in the spectral domain. We demonstrate
that the range of the translational memory effect for the early arriving light
is increased almost fourfold, paving the way for a range of scattering media
imaging applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06902</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Shcherbinin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LaForge</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devetta</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richter</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moshammer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeifer</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mudrich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interatomic Coulombic decay in helium nanodroplets</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013407 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interatomic Coulombic decay (ICD) is induced in helium (He) nanodroplets by
photoexciting the n=2 excited state of He^+ using XUV synchrotron radiation. By
recording multiple coincidence electron and ion images we find that ICD occurs
in various locations at the droplet surface, inside the surface region, or in
the droplet interior. ICD at the surface gives rise to energetic He^+ ions as
previously observed for free He dimers. ICD deeper inside leads to the ejection
of slow He^+ ions due to Coulomb explosion delayed by elastic collisions with
neighboring He atoms, and to the formation of He_k^+ complexes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06911</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wituschek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Vangerow</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grzesiak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stienkemeier</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mudrich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple photoionization scheme for characterizing electron and ion
  spectrometers</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Review of Scientific Instruments 87, 083105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4960401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple diode laser-based photoionization scheme for generating
electrons and ions with well-defined spatial and energetic (&lt;2 eV) structures.
This scheme can easily be implemented into ion or electron imaging
spectrometers for the purpose of off-line characterization and calibration. The
low laser power ~1$ mW needed from a passively stabilized diode laser and the
low flux of potassium atoms in an effusive beam make our scheme a versatile
source of ions and electrons for applications in research and education.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06925</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Suess</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogler</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruckner</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abert</keyname><forenames>Claas</forenames></author></authors><title>A repulsive skyrmion chain as guiding track for a race track memory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A skyrmion racetrack design is proposed that allows for thermally stable
skyrmions to code information and dynamical pinning sites that move with the
applied current. This concept solves the problem of intrinsic distributions of
pinning times and pinning currents of skyrmions at static geometrical or
magnetic pinning sites. The dynamical pinning sites are realized by a skyrmion
carrying wire, where the skyrmion repulsion is used in order to keep the
skyrmions at equal distances. The information is coded by an additional layer
where the presence and absence of a skyrmion is used to code the information.
The lowest energy barrier for a data loss is calculated to be DE = 55 kBT300
which is sufficient for long time thermal stability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06947</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>Pedro J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Euzzor</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallas</keyname><forenames>Jason A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meucci</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chac&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Impulse-induced optimum control of chaos in dissipative driven systems</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>Main text (6 figs and 5 pages) and Supplemental material (9 figs and
  12 pages)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Taming chaos arising from dissipative non-autonomous nonlinear systems by
applying additional harmonic excitations is a reliable and widely used
procedure nowadays. But the suppressory effectiveness of generic non-harmonic
periodic excitations continues to be a significant challenge both to our
theoretical understanding and in practical applications. Here we show how the
effectiveness of generic suppressory excitations is optimally enhanced when the
impulse transmitted by them (time integral over two consecutive zeros) is
judiciously controlled in a not obvious way. This is demonstrated
experimentally by means of an analog version of a universal model, and
confirmed numerically by simulations of such a damped driven system including
the presence of noise. Our theoretical analysis shows that the controlling
effect of varying the impulse is due to a correlative variation of the energy
transmitted by the suppressory excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06951</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mota</keyname><forenames>H. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakke</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noninertial effects on nonrelativistic topological quantum scattering</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, no figure</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Relativ. Gravit., v. 49, pp. 104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2266-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate noninertial effects on the scattering problem of a
nonrelativistic particle in the cosmic string spacetime. By considering the
nonrelativistic limit of the Dirac equation we are able to show, in the regime
of small rotational frequencies, that the phase shift has two contribution: one
related to the noninertial reference frame, and the other, due to the cosmic
string conical topology. We also show that both the incident wave and the
scattering amplitude are altered as a consequence of the noninertial reference
frame and depend on the rotational frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06966</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Eknapakul</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fongkaew</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siriroj</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidyasagar</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denlinger</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bawden</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>S. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>P. D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takagi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limpijumnong</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meevasana</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nearly-free-electron system of monolayer Na on the surface of
  single-crystal HfSe$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 201121(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.201121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic structure of a single Na monolayer on the surface of
single-crystal HfSe$_2$ is investigated using angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy. We find that this system exhibits an almost perfect
&quot;nearly-free-electron&quot; behavior with an extracted effective mass of
$\sim\!1m_e$, in contrast to heavier masses found previously for alkali metal
monolayers on other substrates. Our density-functional-theory calculations
indicate that this is due to the large lattice constant, causing both exchange
and correlation interactions to be suppressed, and to the weak hybridization
between the overlayer and the substrate. This is therefore an ideal model
system for understanding the properties of two-dimensional materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06977</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Machado</keyname><forenames>A. C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monta&#xf1;o</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquini</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pleitez</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical solution for the Zee mechanism</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>2 figures, 10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We found an analytical solution for the neutrino mass matrix in the most
general case of the Zee model. Using the recent data on the neutrino parameters
besides generating neutrino masses at 1-loop level we fit also the masses of
the charged leptons and the leptonic mixing matrix. We also show in what
conditions the model is not compatible with neutrino data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06984</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Frassino</keyname><forenames>Antonia M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panella</keyname><forenames>Orlando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Pinaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of Quantum Phase Transitions of a Dirac oscillator in a
  homogenous magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac oscillator in a homogenous magnetic field exhibits a chirality
phase transition at a particular (critical) value of the magnetic field.
Recently, this system has also been shown to be exactly solvable in the context
of noncommutative quantum mechanics featuring the interesting phenomenon of
re-entrant phase transitions. In this work we provide a detailed study of the
thermodynamics of such quantum phase transitions (both in the standard and in
the noncommutative case) within the Maxwell-Boltzmann statistics pointing out
that the magnetization has discontinuities at critical values of the magnetic
field even at finite temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ex/0211018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ex/0211018</id><created>2002-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Casadei</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Design and test results of the AMS RICH detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 9 figures. Talk given at the &quot;8th Topical Seminar on
  Innovative Particle and Radiation Detectors&quot;, Siena (Italy), 21-24 October
  2002. To be published on Nuclear Physics B - Proceedings Supplement</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys.Proc.Suppl. 125 (2003) 303-307</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0920-5632(03)91007-3</doi><abstract>  The AMS-02 detector will operate for at least 3 years on the International
Space Station, measuring cosmic ray spectra at about 400 km above sea level
over a wide range of geomagnetic latitude.
  The proximity focusing ring imaging \v{C}erenkov counter of AMS-02 will
measure the particle velocity $\beta$ with $\approx 0.1%$ uncertainty, making
possible to discriminate Beryllium isotopes up to about 15 GeV/nucl. In
addition its charge measurement will allow to study the elemental composition
of cosmic rays up to Iron. A prototype of the RICH detector was tested with
cosmic rays and on a ion beam accelerated by SPS, at CERN (October 2002).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
