<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:34:17Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-27" from="2017-07-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.0112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.0112</id><created>2012-05-01</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Awasthi</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhardwaj</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awana</keyname><forenames>V. P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albisetti</keyname><forenames>A. Figini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giunchi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narlikar</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Carrier Transport in Magnesium Diboride: Role of Nano-inclusions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, 28 references</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 103, 112601 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4821135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anisotropic-gap and two-band effects smear out the superconducting transition
(Tc) in literature reported thermal conductivity of MgB2, where large
electronic contributions also suppress anomaly-manifestation in their
negligible phononic-parts. Present thermal transport results on scarcely
explored specimens featuring nano-inclusions exhibit a small but clear
Tc-signature, traced to relatively appreciable phononic conduction, and its
dominant electronic-scattering. The self-formed MgO as extended defects
strongly scatter the charge carriers and minutely the phonons with their
longer-mean-free-path near Tc. Conversely, near room temperature, the
shorter-dominant-wavelength phonon's transport is hugely affected by these
nanoparticles, undergoing ballistic to diffusive crossover and eventually
entering the Ioffe-Regel mobility threshold regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.5673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.5673</id><created>2012-12-22</created><updated>2013-01-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Challenges in theoretical investigations on configurations of lipid
  membranes</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math-ph math.DG math.MP physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Chin. Phys. B 22, 028701 (2013)</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B 22, 028701 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/22/2/028701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This review reports some key results in theoretical investigations on
configurations of lipid membranes and presents several challenges in this field
which involve (i) exact solutions to the shape equation of lipid vesicles; (ii)
exact solutions to the governing equations of open lipid membranes; (iii) neck
condition of two-phase vesicles in the budding state; (iv) nonlocal theory of
membrane elasticity; (v) relationship between symmetry and the magnitude of
free energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.3586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.3586</id><created>2013-04-12</created><updated>2013-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armaroli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biancalana</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Vector modulational instability induced by parametric resonance in
  periodically tapered highly-birefringent optical fibers</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, generalizes the methods of arXiv:1208.3484</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.87.063848</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the modulational instability induced by periodic variations of
group-velocity dispersion and nonlinear coefficients in a highly birefringent
fiber. We observe, for each resonance order, the presence of two pairs of
genuine vector type sidebands, which are spectrally unbalanced between the
polarization components for nonzero group-index mismatch, and one pair of
balanced sidebands emerging and dominating at increasing group-index mismatch.
As the conventional modulational instability manifests itself, it is partially
suppressed by the proximity of these new unstable regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.7173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.7173</id><created>2013-11-27</created><updated>2017-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frassino</keyname><forenames>Antonia M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolini</keyname><forenames>Piero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panella</keyname><forenames>Orlando</forenames></author></authors><title>Unparticle Casimir effect</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures; v2: improved discussion, additional references,
  v3: title slightly changed, version matching that in press on Physics Letters
  B</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 772 (2017) 675--680</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.07.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present the un-Casimir effect, namely the study of the
Casimir energy in the presence of an unparticle component in addition to the
electromagnetic field contribution. The distinctive feature of the un-Casimir
effect is a fractalization of metallic plates. This result emerges through a
new dependence of the Casimir energy on the plate separation that scales with a
continuous power controlled by the unparticle dimension. As long as the perfect
conductor approximation is valid, we find bounds on the unparticle scale that
are independent of the effective coupling constant between the scale invariant
sector and ordinary matter. We find regions of the parameter space such that
for plate distances around $5\mu$m and larger the un-Casimir bound wins over
the other bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.0651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.0651</id><created>2014-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ou-Yang</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent theoretical advances in elasticity of membranes following
  Helfrich's spontaneous curvature model</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math-ph math.DG math.MP physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Colloid. Interface Sci. 208 (2014) 66-75</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cis.2014.01.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent theoretical advances in elasticity of membranes following Helfrich's
famous spontaneous curvature model are summarized in this review. The governing
equations describing equilibrium configurations of lipid vesicles, lipid
membranes with free edges, and chiral lipid membranes are presented. Several
analytic solutions to these equations and their corresponding configurations
are demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3956</id><created>2014-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sobol</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational method for the calculation of critical distance between two
  Coulomb centers in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ukrainian Journal of Physics, 2014, Vol. 59, no. 5, pp. 531-540</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ujpe59.05.0531</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The supercritical instability in a system of two identical charged impurities
in gapped graphene described in the continuous limit by the two-dimensional
Dirac equation has been studied. The case where the charge of each impurity is
subcritical, but their sum exceeds the critical value calculated in the version
with a single Coulomb center, is considered. Using the developed variational
method, the dependence of the critical distance $R_{\rm cr}$ between the
impurities on their total charge is calculated. The $R_{\rm cr}$-value is found
to grow as the total impurity charge increases and the quasiparticle band gap
decreases. The results of calculations are compared with those obtained in
earlier researches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1301</id><created>2014-11-05</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jack</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The a-function for gauge theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages; uses axodraw; typos corrected, also some sign errors
  corrected in Sect 5</comments><report-no>LTH 1017</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2015)138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The a-function is a proposed quantity defined for quantum field theories
which has a monotonic behaviour along renormalisation group flows, being
related to the beta-functions via a gradient flow equation involving a positive
definite metric. We construct the a-function at four loop order for a general
gauge theory with fermions and scalars, using only one and two loop
beta-functions; we are then able to provide a stringent consistency check on
the general three-loop gauge beta-function. In the case of an N=1
supersymmetric gauge theory, we present a general condition on the chiral field
anomalous dimension which guarantees an exact all-orders expression for the
a-function; and we verify this up to fifth order (corresponding to the
three-loop anomalous dimension).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02903</id><created>2015-01-13</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Argos</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>A Silicon Strip Detector for the Phase II High Luminosity Upgrade of the
  ATLAS Detector at the Large Hadron Collider</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>PhD Thesis. Defence held on Jan 8, 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis presents the work carried out in the testing of the ATLAS
Phase-II Upgrade electronic systems in the future strips tracker after 2023, to
be installed for operations in the HL-LHC period. The high luminosity and
number of interactions per crossing that will happen after the HL-LHC starts
require a complete replacement of the ATLAS tracker. The systems that have been
defined for the Phase-II Upgrade will be designed to cope with that increased
radiation and have the right granularity to maintain the performance with
higher pile-up.
  In this thesis I present results on single modules and larger structures
comprising multiple modules.
  In the context of the current ATLAS Semiconductor Tracker studies, I present
an analysis of the data taken by the detector from the beginning of operation
in 2010 until the first Long Shut-down in 2013. The analysis consists of an
energy loss study in the Semiconductor Tracker, a task the detector was not
designed to perform.
  However, the availability of the Time-over-Threshold of the signals generated
by particles traversing the detector elements allows an estimation of the
charge deposited by the particles. This calculation of the energy loss is
typically used to perform particle identification, a feature that is usually
not required from the tracker. In addition, I present a study that proposes the
use of this energy loss calculation as a means of tracking radiation damage in
the silicon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05734</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05734</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2016-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Jin-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yun-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Dong-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Wei-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>del Campo</keyname><forenames>Adolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Yong-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guang-Can</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Trapped-ion Quantum Simulation of the Kibble-Zurek dynamics
  in momentum space</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures Published in Scientific Reports,
  http://www.nature.com/articles/srep33381</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 33381 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep33381</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kibble-Zurek mechanism is the paradigm to account for the nonadiabatic
dynamics of a system across a continuous phase transition. Its study in the
quantum regime is hindered by the requisite of ground state cooling. We report
the experimental quantum simulation of critical dynamics in the
transverse-field Ising model by a set of Landau-Zener crossings in
pseudo-momentum space, that can be probed with high accuracy using a single
trapped ion. We test the Kibble-Zurek mechanism in the quantum regime in the
momentum space and find the measured scaling of excitations is in accordance
with the theoretical prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05405</id><created>2015-07-20</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruce</keyname><forenames>Andrew James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grabowska</keyname><forenames>Katarzyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grabowski</keyname><forenames>Janusz</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on Contact and Jacobi Geometry</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP math.SG</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><msc-class>53D05, 53D10, 53D17, 58E40, 58H05</msc-class><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 059, 22 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.059</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present an approach to Jacobi and contact geometry that makes many facts,
presented in the literature in an overcomplicated way, much more natural and
clear. The key concepts are Kirillov manifolds and linear Kirillov structures,
i.e., homogeneous Poisson manifolds and, respectively, homogeneous linear
Poisson manifolds. The difference with the existing literature is that the
homogeneity of the Poisson structure is related to a principal ${\rm
GL}(1,{\mathbb R})$-bundle structure on the manifold and not just to a vector
field. This allows for working with Jacobi bundle structures on nontrivial line
bundles and drastically simplifies the picture of Jacobi and contact geometry.
Our results easily reduce to various basic theorems of Jacobi and contact
geometry when the principal bundle structure is trivial, while giving new
insights into the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02151</id><created>2015-08-10</created><updated>2017-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Pan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>General neck condition for the limit shape of budding vesicles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math-ph math.DG math.MP physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 042403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.042403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The shape equation and linking conditions for a vesicle with two-phase
domains are derived. We refine the conjecture on the general neck condition for
the limit shape of a budding vesicle proposed by J\&quot;{u}licher and Lipowsky
[Phys. Rev. Lett. \textbf{70}, 2964 (1993); Phys. Rev. E \textbf{53}, 2670
(1996)], and then we use the shape equation and linking conditions to prove
that this conjecture holds not only for axisymmetric budding vesicles, but also
for asymmetric ones. Our study reveals that the mean curvature at any point on
the membrane segments adjacent to the neck satisfies the general neck condition
for the limit shape of a budding vesicle when the length scale of the membrane
segments is much larger than the characteristic size of the neck but still much
smaller than the characteristic size of the vesicle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03598</id><created>2015-09-11</created><updated>2016-06-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armaroli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xe9;ron</keyname><forenames>Patrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumeige</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable integrated hyper-parametric oscillator based on coupled optical
  microcavities</title><categories>physics.optics math.DS nlin.PS</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 40, Issue 23, pp. 5622-5625 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.40.005622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a flexible scheme based on three coupled optical microcavities
which permits to achieve stable oscillations in the microwave range, the
frequency of which depends only on the cavity coupling rates. We find the
different dynamical regimes (soft and hard excitation) to affect the
oscillation intensity but not their period. This configuration may permit to
implement compact hyper-parametric sources on an integrated optical circuit,
with interesting applications in communications, sensing and metrology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05155</id><created>2015-09-17</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakata</keyname><forenames>Yoshifumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirche</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Ciara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoupling with random diagonal unitaries</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 3 figures. v2: 19 pages, 3 figures, both results and
  presentations are improved. One conjecture in the previous version was
  proven. v3: 16 pages, 1 figure. v4: doi links are added, published version</comments><journal-ref>Quantum 1, 18 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-07-21-18</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate decoupling, one of the most important primitives in quantum
Shannon theory, by replacing the uniformly distributed random unitaries
commonly used to achieve the protocol, with repeated applications of random
unitaries diagonal in the Pauli-$Z$ and -$X$ bases. This strategy was recently
shown to achieve an approximate unitary $2$-design after a number of
repetitions of the process, which implies that the strategy gradually achieves
decoupling. Here, we prove that even fewer repetitions of the process achieve
decoupling at the same rate as that with the uniform ones, showing that rather
imprecise approximations of unitary $2$-designs are sufficient for decoupling.
We also briefly discuss efficient implementations of them and implications of
our decoupling theorem to coherent state merging and relative thermalisation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04228</id><created>2015-10-14</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Stephanie B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karr</keyname><forenames>William A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Convex Functions and Geodesic Connectedness of Space-times</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, references added, minor changes</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper explores the relation between convex functions and the geometry of
space-times and semi-Riemannian manifolds (an investigation initiated by
Gibbons-Ishibashi). Specifically, we study geodesic connectedness. We give
geometric-topological proofs of geodesic connectedness for classes of
space-times to which known methods do not apply. For instance: A
null-disprisoning space-time is geodesically connected if it supports a proper,
nonnegative strictly convex function whose critical set is a point. Timelike
strictly convex hypersurfaces of Minkowski space are geodesically connected. We
also give a criterion for the existence of a convex function on a
semi-Riemannian manifold. We compare our work with previously known results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04916</id><created>2015-10-16</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eckhardt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>The inverse spectral transform for the conservative Camassa-Holm flow
  with decaying initial data</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><msc-class>37K15, 34L05 (Primary) 34A55, 35Q51 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Arch. Ration. Mech. Anal. 224 (2017), no. 1, 21-52</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00205-016-1066-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish the inverse spectral transform for the conservative Camassa-Holm
flow with decaying initial data. In particular, it is employed to prove
existence of weak solutions for the corresponding Cauchy problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07461</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ay&#xf3;n-Beato</keyname><forenames>Eloy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vel&#xe1;zquez-Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Residual Symmetries of the Gravitational Field</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Affiliations have been updated</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 044040 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.044040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a geometric criterion that unambiguously characterizes and also
provides a systematic and effective computational procedure for finding all the
residual symmetries of any gravitational Ansatz . We apply the criterion to
several examples starting with the Collinson Ansatz for circular stationary
axisymmetric spacetimes. We reproduce the residual symmetries already known for
this Ansatz including their conformal symmetry, for which we identify the
corresponding infinite generators spanning the two related copies of the Witt
algebra. We also consider the noncircular generalization of this Ansatz and
show how the noncircular contributions on the one hand break the conformal
invariance and on the other hand enhance the standard translations symmetries
of the circular Killing vectors to supertranslations depending on the direction
along which the circularity is lost. As another application of the method, the
well-known relation defining conjugate gravitational potentials introduced by
Chandrasekhar, that makes possible the derivation of the Kerr black hole from a
trivial solution of the Ernst equations, is deduced as a special point of the
general residual symmetry of the Papapetrou Ansatz. We emphasize how the
election of Weyl coordinates, which determines the Papapetrou Ansatz, breaks
also the conformal freedom of the stationary axisymmetric spacetimes.
Additionally, we study AdS waves for any dimension generalizing the residual
symmetries already known for lower dimensions and exhibiting a very complex
infinite-dimensional Lie algebra containing three families: two of them span
the semidirect sum of the Witt algebra and scalar supertranslations and the
third generates vector supertranslations. We manage to comprehend that the
infinite connected group is the precise diffeomorphisms subgroup allowing to
locally deform the AdS background into AdS waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03956</id><created>2015-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Eckhardt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gesztesy</keyname><forenames>Fritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holden</keyname><forenames>Helge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostenko</keyname><forenames>Aleksey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teschl</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-valued algebro-geometric solutions of the two-component
  Camassa-Holm hierarchy</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:nlin/0208021</comments><msc-class>Primary 35Q51, 35Q53, 37K15, Secondary 37K10, 37K20</msc-class><journal-ref>Ann. Inst. Fourier (Grenoble) 67 (2017), no. 3, 1185-1230</journal-ref><doi>10.5802/aif.3107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a construction of the two-component Camassa-Holm (CH-2) hierarchy
employing a new zero-curvature formalism and identify and describe in detail
the isospectral set associated to all real-valued, smooth, and bounded
algebro-geometric solutions of the $n$th equation of the stationary CH-2
hierarchy as the real $n$-dimensional torus $\mathbb{T}^n$. We employ
Dubrovin-type equations for auxiliary divisors and certain aspects of direct
and inverse spectral theory for self-adjoint singular Hamiltonian systems. In
particular, we employ Weyl-Titchmarsh theory for singular (canonical)
Hamiltonian systems.
  While we focus primarily on the case of stationary algebro-geometric CH-2
solutions, we note that the time-dependent case subordinates to the stationary
one with respect to isospectral torus questions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02281</id><created>2016-06-07</created><updated>2016-09-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sobol</keyname><forenames>O. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pyatkovskiy</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbar</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gusynin</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Screening of a charged impurity in graphene in a magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures; final version published in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electron states in the field of a charged impurity in graphene in a
magnetic field are studied numerically. It is shown that a charged impurity
removes the degeneracy of Landau levels converting them into bandlike
structures. As the charge of impurity grows, the repulsion of sublevels of
different Landau levels with the same value of orbital momentum takes place
leading to the redistribution of the wave function profiles of these sublevels
near the impurity. By studying the polarization effects, it is shown in
agreement with the recent experiments that the effective charge of impurity can
be very effectively tuned by chemical potential. If the chemical potential is
situated inside a Landau level, then the charge of impurity is strongly
diminished. In addition, the polarization function in this case has a peak at
zero momentum, which leads to the sign-changing oscillations of the screened
potential as a function of distance. If the chemical potential lies between the
Landau levels, then the screened potential does not change sign, the screening
is minimal, and the charged impurity can strongly affect the electron spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02384</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02384</id><created>2016-06-07</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delcamp</keyname><forenames>Clement</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dittrich</keyname><forenames>Bianca</forenames></author></authors><title>From 3D topological quantum field theories to 4D models with defects</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages</comments><journal-ref>J.Math.Phys. 58 (2017) no.6, 062302</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4989535</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  (2+1) dimensional topological quantum field theories with defect excitations
are by now quite well understood, while many questions are still open for (3+1)
dimensional TQFTs. Here we propose a strategy to lift states and operators of a
(2+1) dimensional TQFT to states and operators of a (3+1) dimensional theory
with defects. The main technical tool are Heegard splittings, which allow to
encode the topology of a three--dimensional manifold with line defects into a
two--dimensional Heegard surface. We apply this idea to the example of BF
theory which describes locally flat connections. This shows in particular how
the curvature excitation generating surface operators of the (3+1) dimensional
theory can be obtained from closed ribbon operators of the (2+1) dimensional BF
theory. We hope that this technique allows the construction and study of more
general models based on unitary fusion categories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07650</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Trulsson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeGiuli</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyart</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Friction on Dense Suspension Flows of Hard Particles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 012605 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.012605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use numerical simulations to study the effect of particle friction on
suspension flows of non-Brownian hard particles. By systematically varying the
microscopic friction coefficient $\mu_p$ and the viscous number $J$, we build a
phase diagram that identifies three regimes of flow: Frictionless, Frictional
Sliding, and Rolling. Using energy balance in flow, we predict relations
between kinetic observables, confirmed by numerical simulations. For realistic
friction coefficient and small viscous numbers (below $J\sim 10^{-3}$) we show
that the dominating dissipative mechanism is sliding of frictional contacts,
and we characterize asymptotic behaviors as jamming is approached. Outside this
regime, our observations support that flow belongs to the universality class of
frictionless particles. We discuss recent experiments in the context of our
phase diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02691</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Shi-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Charmonium dissociation in collision with phi meson in hadronic matter</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C41 (2017) 024101</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/2/024101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phi-charmonium dissociation reactions in hadronic matter are studied.
Unpolarised cross sections for 12 reactions are calculated in the Born
approximation, in the quark-interchange mechanism and with a
temperature-dependent quark potential. The potential leads to remarkable
temperature dependence of the cross sections. With the cross sections and the
phi distribution function we calculate the dissociation rates of the charmonia
in the interactions with the phi meson in hadronic matter. The dependence of
the rates on temperature and charmonium momentum is meaningful to the influence
of phi mesons on charmonium suppression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05262</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Haoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilde</keyname><forenames>Mark M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Saikat</forenames></author></authors><title>On the minimum output entropy of single-mode phase-insensitive Gaussian
  channels</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math-ph math.IT math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently de Palma et al. [IEEE Trans. Inf. Theory 63, 728 (2017)]
proved---using Lagrange multiplier techniques---that under a non-zero input
entropy constraint, a thermal state input minimizes the output entropy of a
pure-loss bosonic channel. In this note, we present our attempt to generalize
this result to all single-mode gauge-covariant Gaussian channels by using
similar techniques. Unlike the case of the pure-loss channel, we cannot prove
that the thermal input state is the only local extremum of the optimization
problem. %It is unclear to us why the same techniques do not lead to a proof
for amplifier channels. However, we do prove that, if the conjecture holds for
gauge-covariant Gaussian channels, it would also hold for gauge-contravariant
Gaussian channels. The truth of the latter leads to a solution of the triple
trade-off and broadcast capacities of quantum-limited amplifier channels. We
note that de Palma et al. [Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 160503 (2017)] have now proven
the conjecture for all single-mode gauge-covariant Gaussian channels by
employing a different approach from what we outline here. Proving a multi-mode
generalization of de Palma et al.'s above mentioned result---i.e., given a
lower bound on the von Neumann entropy of the input to an $n$-mode lossy
thermal-noise bosonic channel, an $n$-mode product thermal state input
minimizes the output entropy---will establish an important special case of the
conjectured Entropy Photon-number Inequality (EPnI). The EPnI, if proven true,
would take on a role analogous to Shannon's EPI in proving coding theorem
converses involving quantum limits of classical communication over bosonic
channels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08560</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egusquiza</keyname><forenames>I. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamata</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>del Campo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Digital Quantum Simulation of Minimal AdS/CFT</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 040501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.040501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the digital quantum simulation of a minimal AdS/CFT model in
controllable quantum platforms. We consider the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model
describing interacting Majorana fermions with randomly distributed all-to-all
couplings, encoding nonlocal fermionic operators onto qubits to efficiently
implement their dynamics via digital techniques. Moreover, we also give a
method for probing non-equilibrium dynamics and the scrambling of information.
Finally, our approach serves as a protocol for reproducing a simplified
low-dimensional model of quantum gravity in advanced quantum platforms as
trapped ions and superconducting circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05558</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhatt</keyname><forenames>Jitesh R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>Manu</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino induced vorticity, Alfven waves and the normal modes</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5100-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider plasma consisting of electrons and ions in presence of a
background neutrino gas and develop the magneto hydrodynamic equations for the
system. We show that electron neutrino interaction can induce vorticity in the
plasma even in the absence of any electromagnetic perturbations if the
background neutrino density is left-right asymmetric. This induced vorticity
support a new kind of Alfv\'en wave whose velocity depends on both the external
magnetic field and on the neutrino asymmetry. The normal mode analysis show
that in the presence of neutrino background the Alfv\'en waves can have
different velocities. We also discuss our results in the context of dense
astrophysical plasma such as magnetars and show that the difference in the
Alfv\'en velocities can be used to explain the observed pulsar kick. We discuss
also the relativistic generalization of electron fluid in presence of
asymmetric neutrino background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02264</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kasai</keyname><forenames>Aya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okumura</keyname><forenames>Ken-ichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>A dilaton-pion mass relation</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><report-no>KYUSHU-HET-168</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, Golterman and Shamir presented an effective field theory which is
supposed to describe the low-energy physics of the pion and the dilaton in an
$SU(N_c)$ gauge theory with $N_f$ Dirac fermions in the fundamental
representation. By employing this formulation with a slight but important
modification, we derive a relation between the dilaton mass squared~$m_\tau^2$,
with and without the fermion mass~$m$, and the pion mass squared~$m_\pi^2$ to
the leading order of the chiral logarithm. This is analogous to a similar
relation obtained by Matsuzaki and~Yamawaki on the basis of a somewhat
different low-energy effective field theory. Our relation reads
$m_\tau^2=m_\tau^2|_{m=0}+KN_f\hat{f}_\pi^2m_\pi^2/(2\hat{f}_\tau^2)+O(m_\pi^4\ln
m_\pi^2)$ with~$K=9$, where $\hat{f}_\pi$ and~$\hat{f}_\tau$ are decay
constants of the pion and the dilaton, respectively. This mass relation differs
from the one derived by Matsuzaki and~Yamawaki on the points that
$K=(3-\gamma_m)(1+\gamma_m)$, where $\gamma_m$ is the mass anomalous dimension,
and the leading chiral logarithm correction is~$O(m_\pi^2\ln m_\pi^2)$.
For~$\gamma_m\sim1$, the value of the decay constant~$\hat{f}_\tau$ estimated
from our mass relation becomes $\sim50\%$ larger than $\hat{f}_\tau$ estimated
from the relation of Matsuzaki and~Yamawaki.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08035</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Sayak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanier</keyname><forenames>Lewis L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Jayajit</forenames></author></authors><title>Connecting the dots across time: Reconstruction of single cell signaling
  trajectories using time-stamped data</title><categories>q-bio.QM cond-mat.stat-mech cs.CG cs.CV</categories><comments>revised version, accepted for publication in Royal Society Open
  Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single cell responses are shaped by the geometry of signaling kinetic
trajectories carved in a multidimensional space spanned by signaling protein
abundances. It is however challenging to assay large number (&gt;3) of signaling
species in live-cell imaging which makes it difficult to probe single cell
signaling kinetic trajectories in large dimensions. Flow and mass cytometry
techniques can measure a large number (4 - &gt;40) of signaling species but are
unable to track single cells. Thus cytometry experiments provide detailed time
stamped snapshots of single cell signaling kinetics. Is it possible to use the
time stamped cytometry data to reconstruct single cell signaling trajectories?
Borrowing concepts of conserved and slow variables from non-equilibrium
statistical physics we develop an approach to reconstruct signaling
trajectories using snapshot data by creating new variables that remain
invariant or vary slowly during the signaling kinetics. We apply this approach
to reconstruct trajectories using snapshot data obtained from in silico
simulations and live-cell imaging measurements. The use of invariants and slow
variables to reconstruct trajectories provides a radically different way to
track object using snapshot data. The approach is likely to have implications
for solving matching problems in a wide range of disciplines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09417</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09417</id><created>2016-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Sobol</keyname><forenames>O. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supercritical instability of Dirac electrons in the field of two
  oppositely charged nuclei</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ukrainian Journal of Physics, 2016. Vol. 61, No. 9</journal-ref><doi>10.15407/ujpe61.09.0759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dirac equation for an electron in a finite dipole potential has been
studied within the method of linear combination of atomic orbitals (LCAO). The
Coulomb potential of the nuclei that compose a dipole is regularized, by
considering the finite nuclear size. It is shown that if the dipole momentum
reaches a certain critical value, the novel type of supercriticality occurs;
namely, the wave function of the highest occupied electron bound state changes
its localization from the negatively charged nucleus to the positively charged
one. This phenomenon can be interpreted as a spontaneous creation of an
electron-positron pair in vacuum, with each of the created particles being in
the bound state with the corresponding nucleus and partially screening it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00978</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mamatsashvili</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonmodal analysis of helical and azimuthal magnetorotational
  instabilities</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.SR physics.flu-dyn physics.space-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, extended proceedings paper for the PAMIR 2016
  conference</comments><journal-ref>Magnetohydrodynamics, 53, 2017, p.107</journal-ref><doi>10.22364/mhd</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Helical and azimuthal magnetorotational instabilities operate in rotating
magnetized flows with relatively steep negative or extremely steep positive
shear. The corresponding lower and upper Liu limits of the shear, which
determine the threshold of modal growth of these instabilities, are
continuously connected when some axial electrical current is allowed to pass
through the rotating fluid. We investigate the nonmodal dynamics of these
instabilities arising from the non-normality of shear flow in the local
approximation, generalizing the results of the modal approach. It is
demonstrated that moderate transient/nonmodal amplification of both types of
magnetorotational instability occurs within the Liu limits, where the system is
stable according to modal analysis. We show that for the helical
magnetorotational instability this magnetohydrodynamic behavior is closely
connected with the nonmodal growth of the underlying purely hydrodynamic
problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02927</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smidman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steglich</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>H. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible Weyl fermions in the magnetic Kondo system CeSb</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, Supplementary Information available from journal
  link (open access)</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Materials 2, 39 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41535-017-0038-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Materials where the electronic bands have unusual topologies allow for the
realization of novel physics and have a wide range of potential applications.
When two electronic bands with linear dispersions intersect at a point, the
excitations could be described as Weyl fermions which are massless particles
with a particular chirality. Here we report evidence for the presence of Weyl
fermions in the ferromagnetic state of the low-carrier density, strongly
correlated Kondo lattice system CeSb, from electronic structure calculations
and angle-dependent magnetoresistance measurements. When the applied magnetic
field is parallel to the electric current, a pronounced negative
magnetoresistance is observed within the ferromagnetic state, which is
destroyed upon slightly rotating the field away. These results give evidence
for CeSb belonging to a new class of Kondo lattice materials with Weyl fermions
in the ferromagnetic state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05887</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Juan</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grushin</keyname><forenames>Adolfo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morimoto</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Joel E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantized circular photogalvanic effect in Weyl semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4+5 pages, 3 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15995 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15995</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The circular photogalvanic effect (CPGE) is the part of a photocurrent that
switches depending on the sense of circular polarization of the incident light.
It has been consistently observed in systems without inversion symmetry and
depends on non-universal material details. Here we find that in a class of Weyl
semimetals (e.g. SrSi$_2$) and three-dimensional Rashba materials (e.g. doped
Te) without inversion and mirror symmetries, the injection contribution to the
CPGE trace is effectively quantized in terms of the fundamental constants $e,
h, c$ and $\epsilon_0$ with no material-dependent parameters. This is so
because the CPGE directly measures the topological charge of Weyl points, and
non-quantized corrections from disorder and additional bands can be small over
a significant range of incident frequencies. Moreover, the magnitude of the
CPGE induced by a Weyl node is relatively large, which enables the direct
detection of the monopole charge with current techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06554</id><created>2016-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Muduli</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-polarized quasiparticle control in a double spin-filter tunnel
  junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Unpublished data set</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024514 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024514</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin-polarized quasiparticles can be easily created during spin-filtering
through a ferromagnetic insulator (FI) in contact with a superconductor due to
pair breaking effects at the interface. A combination FI-N-FI sandwiched
between two superconductors can be used to create and analyze such
spin-polarized quasiparticles through their nonequilibrium accumulation in the
middle metallic (N) layer. We report spin-polarized quasiparticle regulation in
a double spin-filter tunnel junction in the configuration NbN-GdN1-Ti-GdN2-NbN.
The middle Ti layer provides magnetic decoupling between two ferromagnetic GdN
and a place for nonequilibrium quasiparticle accumulation. The two GdN(1,2)
layers were deposited under different conditions to introduce coercive
contrast. The quasiparticle tunneling spectra has been measured at different
temperatures to understand the tunneling mechanism in these double spin-filter
junctions. The conductance spectra were found to be comparable to an asymmetric
SINI'S-type tunnel junction. A hysteretic R-H loop with higher resistance for
the antiparallel configuration compared to parallel state was observed
asserting the spin-polarized nature of quasiparticles. The hysteresis in the
R-H loop was found to disappear for sub-gap bias current. This difference can
be understood by considering suppression of the interlayer coupling due to
nonequilibrium spin-polarized quasiparticle accumulation in the Ti layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08414</id><created>2016-11-25</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lindenfelser</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Negnevitsky</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ragg</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Home</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooling atomic ions with visible and infra-red light</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New journal of physics, 19: 06304 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa7150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the ability to load, cool and detect singly-charged calcium
ions in a surface electrode trap using only visible and infrared lasers for the
trapped-ion control. As opposed to the standard methods of cooling using
dipole-allowed transitions, we combine power broadening of a quadrupole
transition at 729 nm with quenching of the upper level using a dipole allowed
transition at 854 nm. By observing the resulting 393 nm fluorescence we are
able to perform background-free detection of the ion. We show that this system
can be used to smoothly transition between the Doppler cooling and sideband
cooling regimes, and verify theoretical predictions throughout this range. We
achieve scattering rates which reliably allow recooling after collision events
and allow ions to be loaded from a thermal atomic beam. This work is compatible
with recent advances in optical waveguides, and thus opens a path in current
technologies for large-scale quantum information processing. In situations
where dielectric materials are placed close to trapped ions, it carries the
additional advantage of using wavelengths which do not lead to significant
charging, which should facilitate high rate optical interfaces between remotely
held ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10261</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magierski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekizawa</keyname><forenames>Kazuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wlaz&#x142;owski</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel Role of Superfluidity in Low-Energy Nuclear Reactions</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>Manuscript with included Supplemental online material, published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 042501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.042501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate, within symmetry unrestricted time-dependent density
functional theory, the existence of new effects in low-energy nuclear reactions
which originate from superfluidity. The dynamics of the pairing field induces
solitonic excitations in the colliding nuclear systems, leading to qualitative
changes in the reaction dynamics. The solitonic excitation prevents collective
energy dissipation and effectively suppresses fusion cross section. We
demonstrate how the variations of the total kinetic energy of the fragments can
be traced back to the energy stored in the superfluid junction of colliding
nuclei. Both contact time and scattering angle in non-central collisions are
significantly affected. The modification of the fusion cross section and
possibilities for its experimental detection are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01920</id><created>2016-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sapienza</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Jin Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falt</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegscheider</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badolato</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author></authors><title>Combined atomic force microscopy and photoluminescence imaging to select
  single InAs/GaAs quantum dots for quantum photonic devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 6205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-06566-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a combined photoluminescence imaging and atomic force microscopy
study of single, isolated self-assembled InAs quantum dots (density &lt;0.01
um^(-2) capped by a 95 nm GaAs layer, and emitting around 950 nm. By combining
optical and scanning probe characterization techniques, we determine the
position of single quantum dots with respect to comparatively large (100 nm to
1000 nm in-plane dimension) topographic features. We find that quantum dots
often appear (&gt;25% of the time) in the vicinity of these features, but
generally do not exhibit significant differences in their non-resonantly pumped
emission spectra in comparison to quantum dots appearing in defect-free
regions. This behavior is observed across multiple wafers produced in different
growth chambers. Our characterization approach is relevant to applications in
which single quantum dots are embedded within nanofabricated photonic devices,
where such large surface features can affect the interaction with confined
optical fields and the quality of the single-photon emission. In particular, we
anticipate using this approach to screen quantum dots not only based on their
optical properties, but also their surrounding surface topographies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03090</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Rossatto</keyname><forenames>Daniel Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villas-B&#xf4;as</keyname><forenames>Celso J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>Mikel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral Classification of Coupling Regimes in the Quantum Rabi Model</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013849 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013849</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum Rabi model is in the scientific spotlight due to the recent
theoretical and experimental progress. Nevertheless, a full-fledged
classification of its coupling regimes remains as a relevant open question. We
propose a spectral classification dividing the coupling regimes into three
regions based on the validity of perturbative criteria on the quantum Rabi
model, which allows us the use of exactly solvable effective Hamiltonians.
These coupling regimes are i) the perturbative ultrastrong coupling regime
which comprises the Jaynes-Cummings model, ii) a region where non-perturbative
ultrastrong and non-perturbative deep strong coupling regimes coexist, and iii)
the perturbative deep strong coupling regime. We show that this spectral
classification depends not only on the ratio between the coupling strength and
the natural frequencies of the unperturbed parts, but also on the energy to
which the system can access. These regimes additionally discriminate the
completely different behaviors of several static physical properties, namely
the total number of excitations, the photon statistics of the field, and the
cavity-qubit entanglement. Finally, we explain the dynamical properties which
are traditionally associated to the deep strong coupling regime, such as the
collapses and revivals of the state population, in the frame of the proposed
spectral classification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03234</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-01-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Appleby</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stacey</keyname><forenames>Blake C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Huangjun</forenames></author></authors><title>Introducing the Qplex: A Novel Arena for Quantum Theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 4 figures, 3 appendices; v2: typos and notational glitches
  corrected</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. D (2017) 71: 197</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2017-80024-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reconstruct quantum theory starting from the premise that, as Asher Peres
remarked, &quot;Unperformed experiments have no results.&quot; The tools of modern
quantum information theory, and in particular the symmetric informationally
complete (SIC) measurements, provide a concise expression of how exactly
Peres's dictum holds true. That expression is a constraint on how the
probability distributions for outcomes of different, mutually exclusive
experiments mesh together, a type of constraint not foreseen in classical
thinking. Taking this as our foundational principle, we show how to reconstruct
the formalism of quantum theory in finite-dimensional Hilbert spaces. Along the
way, we derive a condition for the existence of a d-dimensional SIC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04828</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Mark E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Earl T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kok</keyname><forenames>Pieter</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal Quantum Metrology of Distant Black Bodies</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum, Vol. 1, 21 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-07-26-21</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of an object's temperature are important in many disciplines,
from astronomy to engineering, as are estimates of an object's spatial
configuration. We present the quantum optimal estimator for the temperature of
a distant body based on the black body radiation received in the far-field. We
also show how to perform separable quantum optimal estimates of the spatial
configuration of a distant object, i.e. imaging. In doing so we necessarily
deal with multi-parameter quantum estimation of incompatible observables, a
problem that is poorly understood. We compare our optimal observables to the
two mode analogue of lensed imaging and find that the latter is far from
optimal, even when compared to measurements which are separable. To prove the
optimality of the estimators we show that they minimise the cost function
weighted by the quantum Fisher information---this is equivalent to maximising
the average fidelity between the actual state and the estimated one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00263</id><created>2017-01-01</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Callaham</keyname><forenames>Jared</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machta</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author></authors><title>Population Annealing Simulations of a Binary Hard Sphere Mixture</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 063315 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.063315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Population annealing is a sequential Monte Carlo scheme well-suited to
simulating equilibrium states of systems with rough free energy landscapes.
Here we use population annealing to study a binary mixture of hard spheres.
Population annealing is a parallel version of simulated annealing with an extra
resampling step that ensures that a population of replicas of the system
represents the equilibrium ensemble at every packing fraction in an annealing
schedule. The algorithm and its equilibration properties are described and
results are presented for a glass-forming fluid composed of a 50/50 mixture of
hard spheres with diameter ratio of 1.4:1. For this system, we obtain precise
results for the equation of state in the glassy regime up to packing fractions
$\varphi \approx 0.60$ and study deviations from the BMCSL equation of state.
For higher packing fractions, the algorithm falls out of equilibrium and a free
volume fit predicts jamming at packing fraction $\varphi \approx 0.667$. We
conclude that population annealing is an effective tool for studying
equilibrium glassy fluids and the jamming transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00784</id><created>2017-01-03</created><updated>2017-01-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Fuyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Bowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Classification and surface anomaly of glide symmetry protected
  topological phases in three dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables, references updated</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19,073002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa769b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study glide protected topological (GSPT) phases of interacting bosons and
fermions in three spatial dimensions certain on-site symmetries. They are
crystalline SPT phases, which are distinguished from a trivial product state
only in the presence of non-symmorphic glide symmetry. We classify these GSPT
phases with various on-site symmetries such as $U(1)$ and time reversal, and
show that they can all be understood by stacking and coupling two-dimensional
short-range-entangled phases in a glide-invariant way. Using such a coupled
layer construction we study the anomalous surface topological orders of these
GSPT phases, which gap out the two-dimensional surface states without breaking
any symmetries. This framework is demonstrated in many examples, including the
non-symmorphic topological insulator with &quot;hourglass fermion&quot; surface states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03792</id><created>2017-01-13</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garrison-Kimmel</keyname><forenames>Shea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wetzel</keyname><forenames>Andrew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bullock</keyname><forenames>James S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Philip F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boylan-Kolchin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faucher-Giguere</keyname><forenames>Claude-Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keres</keyname><forenames>Dusan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanderson</keyname><forenames>Robyn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graus</keyname><forenames>Andrew S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelley</keyname><forenames>Tyler</forenames></author></authors><title>Not so lumpy after all: modeling the depletion of dark matter subhalos
  by Milky Way-like galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables. Accepted into MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Among the most important goals in cosmology is detecting and quantifying
small ($M_{\rm halo}\simeq10^{6-9}~\mathrm{M}_\odot$) dark matter (DM)
subhalos. Current probes around the Milky Way (MW) are most sensitive to such
substructure within $\sim20$ kpc of the halo center, where the galaxy
contributes significantly to the potential. We explore the effects of baryons
on subhalo populations in $\Lambda$CDM using cosmological zoom-in baryonic
simulations of MW-mass halos from the Latte simulation suite, part of the
Feedback In Realistic Environments (FIRE) project. Specifically, we compare
simulations of the same two halos run using (1) DM-only (DMO), (2) full
baryonic physics, and (3) DM with an embedded disk potential grown to match the
FIRE simulation. Relative to baryonic simulations, DMO simulations contain
$\sim2\times$ as many subhalos within 100 kpc of the halo center; this excess
is $\gtrsim5\times$ within 25 kpc. At $z=0$, the baryonic simulations are
completely devoid of subhalos down to $3\times10^6~\mathrm{M}_\odot$ within
$15$ kpc of the MW-mass galaxy, and fewer than 20 surviving subhalos have
orbital pericenters &lt;20 kpc. Despite the complexities of baryonic physics, the
simple addition of an embedded central disk potential to DMO simulations
reproduces this subhalo depletion, including trends with radius, remarkably
well. Thus, the additional tidal field from the central galaxy is the primary
cause of subhalo depletion. Subhalos on radial orbits that pass close to the
central galaxy are preferentially destroyed, causing the surviving subhalo
population to have tangentially biased orbits compared to DMO predictions. Our
method of embedding a disk potential in DMO simulations provides a fast and
accurate alternative to full baryonic simulations, thus enabling suites of
cosmological simulations that can provide accurate and statistical predictions
of substructure populations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05786</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>G&#xfc;gercino&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>Erbil</forenames></author></authors><title>Postglitch exponential relaxation of radio pulsars and magnetars in
  terms of vortex creep across flux tubes</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To appear on MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (2): 2313-2322</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Timing observations of rapidly rotating neutron stars revealed a great number
of glitches, observed both from canonical radio pulsars and magnetars. Among
them, 76 glitches have shown exponential relaxation(s) with characteristic
decay times ranging from several days to a few months, followed by a more
gradual recovery. Glitches displaying exponential relaxation with single or
multiple decay time constants are analysed in terms of a model based on the
interaction of the vortex lines with the toroidal arrangement of flux tubes in
the outer core of the neutron star. Model results agree with the observed
timescales in general. Thus, the glitch phenomenon can be used to deduce
valuable information about neutron star structure, in particular on the
interior magnetic field configuration which is unaccessible from surface
observations. One immediate conclusion is that the magnetar glitch data are
best explained with a much cooler core and therefore require that direct Urca
type fast cooling mechanisms should be effective for magnetars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06627</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Nerovny</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorchuk</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golubev</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author></authors><title>Representation of light pressure resultant force and moment as a tensor
  series</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>36 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nerovny, N., Zimin, V., Fedorchuk, S. et al. Celest Mech Dyn Astr
  (2017) 128: 483</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10569-017-9758-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we address a problem of determination of light pressure upon
space structures of the complex geometric shape. For the surface element, we
wrote a condition that this element can interact with light only from the front
side, not from the back side. This condition To in the form of series of
Chebyshev polynomials of the first kind. Chebyshev expansion lets us move to
the series of tensors of increasing rank for the problem of determination of
force and moment. We obtained expressions for the fiber method for
determination of light pressure on space structures of complex geometry taking
into account self--shadowing and reflections within the structure. We also give
the expressions for tensor parametrization by the specularity coefficient in
case of specular-diffuse reflection. For these expressions we calculated the
principal moment and force upon two-sided flat solar sail, spherical and
cylindrical bodies, and approximated light pressure upon a perspective space
observatory Millimetron. The proposed expressions can be used in the ballistic
analysis of solar sails and other space objects, which are significantly
affected by the radiation pressure. Also, these results can be used to analyze
the dynamics of movement of large-scale space structures around the center of
gravity under the light pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06764</id><created>2017-01-24</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prado</keyname><forenames>Raul R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author></authors><title>A new air-shower observable to constrain hadronic interaction models</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE hep-ex</categories><journal-ref>Astroparticle Physics 93 (2017) 28-37</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2017.05.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy spectrum of muons at ground level in air showers are studied and a
new observable is proposed to constrain hadronic interaction models used in air
shower simulations. An asymmetric Gaussian function is proposed to describe the
muon ground energy spectrum and its parameters are studied regarding primary
particle, energy and hadronic interaction models. Based on two realistic
measurements of the muon density at a given distance from the shower axis, a
new observable (\rmu) is defined. Considering realistic values of detector
resolutions and number of measured events, it is also shown \rmu can be
successfully used to constrain low and high hadronic interaction models. The
study is focused in the energy range between $10^{17.5}$ and $10^{18.0}$ eV
because of the importance of this interval for particle physics and
astrophysical models. The constraining power of the new observable is shown to
be large within current experimental capabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00078</id><created>2017-01-31</created><authors><author><keyname>&#x141;odyga</keyname><forenames>Justyna</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#x142;obus</keyname><forenames>Waldemar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramanathan</keyname><forenames>Ravishankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grudka</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horodecki</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horodecki</keyname><forenames>Ryszard</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement uncertainty from no-signaling and non-locality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages main + 8 pages appendix; 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 012124 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the formulations of Heisenberg uncertainty principle, concerning
so-called measurement uncertainty, states that the measurement of one
observable modifies the statistics of the other. Here, we derive such a
measurement uncertainty principle from two comprehensible assumptions:
impossibility of instantaneous messaging at a distance (no-signaling), and
violation of Bell inequalities (non-locality). The uncertainty is established
for a pair of observables of one of two spatially separated systems that
exhibit non-local correlations. To this end, we introduce a gentle form of
measurement which acquires partial information about one of the observables. We
then bound disturbance of the remaining observables by the amount of
information gained from the gentle measurement, minus a correction depending on
the degree of non-locality. The obtained quantitative expression resembles the
quantum mechanical formulations, yet it is derived without the quantum
formalism and complements the known qualitative effect of disturbance implied
by non-locality and no-signaling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00840</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tannenbaum</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of $\hat{q}$ in Relativistic Heavy Ion Collisions using
  di-hadron correlations</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B771(2017)553-557</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The azimuthal width of the di-hadron correlations in p$+$p collisons, beyond
the fragmentation transverse momentum, $j_T$, is dominated by $k_T$, the
so-called intrinsic transverse momentum of a parton in a nucleon, which can be
measured. The predicted azimuthal broadening in A$+$A collisions should produce
a larger $k_T$ than in p$+$p collisions. The present work introduces the
observation that the $k_T$ measured in p$+$p collisions for di-hadrons with
$p_{Tt}$ and $p_{Ta}$ must be reduced to compensate for the energy loss of both
the trigger and away parent partons when comparing to the $k_T$ measured with
the same di-hadron $p_{Tt}$ and $p_{Ta}$ in Au$+$Au collisions. This idea is
applied to a recent STAR di-hadron measurement, with result
$\langle{\hat{q}L}\rangle=2.1\pm 0.6$ GeV$^2$. This is more precise but in
agreement with a theoretical calulation of
$\langle{\hat{q}L}\rangle=14^{+42}_{-14}$ GeV$^2$ using the same data. Assuming
a length $\langle{L}\rangle\approx 7$ fm for central Au$+$Au collisions the
present result gives $\hat{q}=0.30\pm 0.09$ GeV$^2$/fm, in fair agreement with
the JET collaboration result of $\hat{q}\approx 1.2\pm 0.3$ GeV$^2$/fm at
initial time $\tau_0=0.6$ fm/c in Au+Au collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}=200$ GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02410</id><created>2017-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Savelainen</keyname><forenames>Matti</forenames></author></authors><title>Four-form field versus fundamental scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>JETP Lett. 105 (2017) no.10, 682-685</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364017100034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A modified-gravity theory with a four-form field strength $F$, a variable
gravitational coupling parameter $G(F)$, and a standard matter action is
considered here. Maxwell and Einstein equations are now derived when including
to action also derivates of $F$. The energy momentum tensor of the 4-form field
contains both the part, which is typical for the fundamental (pseudo)scalar,
and the part, which cancels the divergent contribution of the zero-point
energies of quantum fields to the vacuum energy and thus leads to the natural
nullification of the cosmological constant in Minkowski vacuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02565</id><created>2017-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Caiming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Jianhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Songsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yujuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Xianzhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Chlorine and Bromine Isotope Fractionation of Halogenated Organic
  Pollutants on Gas Chromatography Columns</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chromatography A, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chroma.2017.07.058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Compound-specific chlorine/bromine isotope analysis (CSIA-Cl/Br) has become a
useful approach for degradation pathway investigation and source appointment of
halogenated organic pollutants (HOPs). CSIA-Cl/Br is usually conducted by gas
chromatography-mass spectrometry (GC-MS), which could be negatively impacted by
chlorine and bromine isotope fractionation of HOPs on GC columns. In this
study, 31 organochlorines and 4 organobromines were systematically investigated
in terms of Cl/Br isotope fractionation on GC columns using GC-double focus
magnetic-sector high resolution MS (GC-DFS-HRMS). On-column chlorine/bromine
isotope fractionation behaviors of the HOPs were explored, presenting various
isotope fractionation modes and extents. Twenty-nine HOPs exhibited inverse
isotope fractionation, and only polychlorinated biphenyl-138 (PCB-138) and
PCB-153 presented normal isotope fractionation. And no observable isotope
fractionation was found for the rest four HOPs, i.e., PCB-101,
1,2,3,7,8-pentachlorodibenzofuran, PCB-180 and 2,3,7,8-tetrachlorodibenzofuran.
The isotope fractionation extents of different HOPs varied from below the
observable threshold (0.50%) to 7.31% (PCB-18). The mechanisms of the on-column
chlorine/bromine isotope fractionation were tentatively interpreted with the
Craig-Gordon model and a modified two-film model. Inverse isotope effects and
normal isotope effects might contribute to the total isotope effects together
and thus determine the isotope fractionation directions and extents. Proposals
derived from the main results of this study for CSIA-Cl/Br research were
provided for improving the precision and accuracy of CSIA-Cl/Br results. The
findings of this study will shed light on the development of CSIA-Cl/Br methods
using GC-MS techniques, and help to implement the research using CSIA-Cl/Br to
investigate the environmental behaviors and pollution sources of HOPs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02774</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-02-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vilchinskii</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobol</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbar</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudenok</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetogenesis during inflation and preheating in the Starobinsky model</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 083509 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.083509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By assuming the kinetic coupling $f^{2}(\phi)FF$ of the effective inflaton
field $\phi$ with the electromagnetic field, we explore magnetogenesis during
the inflation and preheating stages in the Starobinsky model. We consider the
case of the exponential coupling function $f(\phi)=\exp(\alpha\phi/M_{p})$ and
show that for $\alpha \sim 12-15$ it is possible to generate the large scale
magnetic fields with strength $\gtrsim 10^{-15}$ Gauss at the present epoch.
The spectrum of generated magnetic fields is blue with the spectral index
$n=1+s$, $s&gt;0$. We have found that for the relevant values of the coupling
parameter, $\alpha=12-15$, model avoids the back-reaction problem for all
relevant modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04160</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saemann</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric Yang-Mills Theory as Higher Chern-Simons Theory</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2: 25 pages, conventions improved, typos fixed, published version</comments><report-no>EMPG-17-02, DMUS-MP-17/02</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 07 (2017) 111</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We observe that the string field theory actions for the topological sigma
models describe higher or categorified Chern-Simons theories. These theories
yield dynamical equations for connective structures on higher principal
bundles. As a special case, we consider holomorphic higher Chern-Simons theory
on the ambitwistor space of four-dimensional space-time. In particular, we
propose a higher ambitwistor space action functional for maximally
supersymmetric Yang-Mills theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04350</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>del Campo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina-Vilaplana</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonner</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scrambling the spectral form factor: unitarity constraints and exact
  results</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 6 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 126008 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.126008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum speed limits set an upper bound to the rate at which a quantum system
can evolve and as such can be used to analyze the scrambling of information. To
this end, we consider the survival probability of a thermofield double state
under unitary time-evolution which is related to the analytic continuation of
the partition function. We provide an exponential lower bound to the survival
probability with a rate governed by the inverse of the energy fluctuations of
the initial state. Further, we elucidate universal features of the
non-exponential behavior at short and long times of evolution that follow from
the analytic properties of the survival probability and its Fourier transform,
both for systems with a continuous and a discrete energy spectrum. We find the
spectral form factor in a number of illustrative models, notably we obtain the
exact answer in the Gaussian unitary ensemble for any $N$ with excellent
agreement with recent numerical studies. We also discuss the relationship of
our findings to models of black hole information loss, such as the
Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model dual to AdS$_2$ as well as higher-dimensional versions
of AdS/CFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04444</id><created>2017-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Shun-Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chang-An</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral anomaly and anomalous finite-size conductivity in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4, 035014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa77b9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene is a monolayer of carbon atoms packed into a hexagon lattice to host
two pairs of massless two-dimensional Dirac fermions in the absence of or with
negligible spin-orbit coupling. It is known that the existence of non-zero
electric polarization in reduced momentum space which is associated with a
hidden chiral symmetry will lead to the zero-energy flat band of zigzag
nanoribbon. The Adler-Bell-Jackiw chiral anomaly or non-conservation of chiral
charges at different valleys can be realized in a confined ribbon of finite
width. In the laterally diffusive regime, the finite-size correction to
conductivity is always positive and goes inversely with the square of the
lateral dimension W, which is different from the finite-size correction
inversely with W from boundary modes. This anomalous finite-size conductivity
reveals the signature of the chiral anomaly in graphene, and is measurable
experimentally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08512</id><created>2017-02-21</created><updated>2017-07-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Cheng-shi</forenames></author></authors><title>The renormalization method from continuous to discrete dynamical
  systems: asymptotic solutions, reductions and invariant manifolds</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages.arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1605.02888</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The renormalization method based on the Taylor expansion for asymptotic
analysis of differential equations is generalized to difference equations. The
proposed renormalization method is based on the Newton-Maclaurin expansion.
Several basic theorems on the renormalization method are proven. Some
interesting applications are given, including asymptotic solutions of quantum
anharmonic oscillator and discrete boundary layer, the reductions and invariant
manifolds of some discrete dynamics systems. Furthermore, the homotopy
renormalization method based on the Newton-Maclaurin expansion is proposed and
applied to those difference equations including no a small parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00382</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shor</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>polylog-LDPC Capacity Achieving Codes for the Noisy Quantum Erasure
  Channel</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide $poly\log$ sparse quantum codes for correcting the erasure channel
arbitrarily close to the capacity. Specifically, we provide $[[n, k, d]]$
quantum stabilizer codes that correct for the erasure channel arbitrarily close
to the capacity if the erasure probability is at least $0.33$, and with a
generating set $\langle S_1, S_2, ... S_{n-k} \rangle$ such that $|S_i|\leq
\log^{2+\zeta}(n)$ for all $i$ and for any $\zeta &gt; 0$ with high probability.
In this work we show that the result of Delfosse et al. is tight: one can
construct capacity approaching codes with weight almost $O(1)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01808</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silant'ev</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alekseeva</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The generalized Milne problem in gas-dusty atmosphere</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 Tables, 5 figures. Has gone into production by
  Astrophysics and Space Science</comments><doi>10.1007/s10509-017-3137-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the generalized Milne problem in non-conservative plane-parallel
optically thick atmosphere consisting of two components - the free electrons
and small dust particles. Recall, that the traditional Milne problem describes
the propagation of radiation through the conservative (without absorption)
optically thick atmosphere when the source of thermal radiation located far
below the surface. In such case, the flux of propagating light is the same at
every distance in an atmosphere. In the generalized Milne problem, the flux
changes inside the atmosphere. The solutions of the both Milne problems give
the angular distribution and polarization degree of emerging radiation. The
considered problem depends on two dimensionless parameters W and (a+b), which
depend on three parameters: $\eta$ - the ratio of optical depth due to free
electrons to optical depth due to small dust grains; the absorption factor
$\varepsilon$ of dust grains and two coefficients - $\bar b_1$ and $\bar b_2$,
describing the averaged anisotropic dust grains. These coefficients obey the
relation $\bar b_1+3\bar b_2=1$. The goal of the paper is to study the
dependence of the radiation angular distribution and degree of polarization of
emerging light on these parameters. Here we consider only continuum radiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02966</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Christou</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schadschneider</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Condensation in continuous stochastic mass transport models</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of condensation for a stochastic continuous mass
transport process defined on a one-dimensional lattice. Specifically we
introduce three different variations of the truncated random average process.
We generalize hereby the regular truncated process by introducing a new
parameter $\gamma$ and derive a rich phase diagram in the $\rho-\gamma$ plane
where several new phases next to the condensate or fluid phase can be observed.
Lastly we use an extreme value approach in order to describe the conditions of
a condensation transition in the thermodynamic limit. This leads us to a
possible explanation of the broken ergodicity property expected for truncation
processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03576</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>Anu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petri</keyname><forenames>Jerome</forenames></author></authors><title>Pulsed emission from a rotating off-centred magnetic dipole in vacuum</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1711</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topology of the electromagnetic field around neutron stars severely
impacts pulsar physics. While most of the works assume a standard centred
dipolar magnetic field model, recently some efforts have been made to explain
how inclusion of higher multipolar components could drastically change our
understanding of these objects. Also, for simplicity, it has always been
assumed that the magnetic moment coincides with the geometrical centre of the
star. However, lately, a more general picture has been put forward in which the
magnetic dipole moment is shifted off from the centre of the star. It has been
demonstrated that the rotating off-centred dipole can be expanded into
multipolar components. We study the effects of an off-centred rotating dipole
on various characteristic emission features of pulsars in vacuum. The
reliability of the off-centred case and its consequences on the magnetic field
line structure, shape of the polar caps, high energy and radio emission phase
plots and corresponding light curves along with a comparison with the standard
centred case are discussed. It has been seen that an off-centred dipole breaks
the north-south symmetry and allows for more flexibility in radio and
high-energy light-curves fitting and phase lag.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08095</id><created>2017-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Battista</keyname><forenames>Emmanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tartaglia</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucchesi</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruggiero</keyname><forenames>Matteo Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valko</keyname><forenames>Pavol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agnello</keyname><forenames>Simone Dell'</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Fiore</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simo</keyname><forenames>Jules</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grado</keyname><forenames>Aniello</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum time delay in the gravitational field of a rotating mass</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa7f11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine quantum corrections of time delay arising in the gravitational
field of a spinning oblate source. Low-energy quantum effects occurring in Kerr
geometry are derived within a framework where general relativity is fully seen
as an effective field theory. By employing such a pattern, gravitational
radiative modifications of Kerr metric are derived from the energy-momentum
tensor of the source, which at lowest order in the fields is modelled as a
point mass. Therefore, in order to describe a quantum corrected version of time
delay in the case in which the source body has a finite extension, we introduce
a hybrid scheme where quantum fluctuations affect only the monopole term
occurring in the multipole expansion of the Newtonian potential. The predicted
quantum deviation from the corresponding classical value turns out to be too
small to be detected in the next future, showing that new models should be
examined in order to test low-energy quantum gravity within the solar system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08446</id><created>2017-03-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Tomczak</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toschi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kresse</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Merging GW with DMFT and non-local correlations beyond</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>tutorial review submitted to EPJ-ST (scientific report of research
  unit FOR 1346); 11 figures 27 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Special Topics 226, 2565 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2017-70053-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review recent developments in electronic structure calculations that go
beyond state-of-the-art methods such as density functional theory (DFT) and
dynamical mean field theory (DMFT). Specifically, we discuss the following
methods: GW as implemented in the Vienna {\it ab initio} simulation package
(VASP) with the self energy on the imaginary frequency axis, GW+DMFT, and ab
initio dynamical vertex approximation (D$\Gamma$A). The latter includes the
physics of GW, DMFT and non-local correlations beyond, and allows for
calculating (quantum) critical exponents. We present results obtained by the
three methods with a focus on the benchmark material SrVO$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08565</id><created>2017-03-24</created><updated>2017-04-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Jin-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bang-Gui</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic ferromagnetism and quantum anomalous Hall effect in CoBr2
  monolayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 19 (2017) 13432</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7CP02158E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic, magnetic, and topological properties of CoBr2 monolayer are
studied in the frame-work of the density-functional theory (DFT) combined with
tight-binding (TB) modeling in terms of Wannier basis. Our DFT investigation
and Monte Carlo simulation show that there exists intrinsic two-dimensional
ferromagnetism in the CoBr2 monolayer thanks to large out-of-plane
magnetocrystalline anisotropic energy. Our further study shows that the
spin-orbits coupling makes it become a topologically nontrivial insulator with
quantum anomalous Hall effect and topological Chern number C=4, and its edge
states can be manipulated by changing the width of its nanoribbons and applying
strains. The CoBr2 monolayer can be exfoliated from the layered CoBr2 bulk
material because its exfoliation energy is between those of graphene and MoS2
monolayer and it is dynamically stable. These results make us believe that the
CoBr2 monolayer can make a promising spintronic material for future
high-performance devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09247</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alok</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Bhubanjyoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Dinesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Jacky</forenames></author><author><keyname>London</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sankar</keyname><forenames>S. Uma</forenames></author></authors><title>New Physics in $b \rightarrow s \mu^+ \mu^-$: Distinguishing Models
  through CP-Violating Effects</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 figures; references updated; published in Physical Review
  D</comments><report-no>UdeM-GPP-TH-17-255; WSU-HEP-1703</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 015034 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.015034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At present, there are several measurements of $B$ decays that exhibit
discrepancies with the predictions of the SM, and suggest the presence of new
physics (NP) in $b \to s \mu^+ \mu^-$ transitions. Many NP models have been
proposed as explanations. These involve the tree-level exchange of a leptoquark
(LQ) or a flavor-changing $Z'$ boson. In this paper we examine whether it is
possible to distinguish the various models via CP-violating effects in $B \to
K^{(*)} \mu^+ \mu^-$. Using fits to the data, we find the following results. Of
all possible LQ models, only three can explain the data, and these are all
equivalent as far as $b \to s \mu^+ \mu^-$ processes are concerned. In this
single LQ model, the weak phase of the coupling can be large, leading to some
sizeable CP asymmetries in $B \to K^{(*)} \mu^+ \mu^-$. There is a spectrum of
$Z'$ models; the key parameter is $g_L^{\mu\mu}$, which describes the strength
of the $Z'$ coupling to $\mu^+\mu^-$. If $g_L^{\mu\mu}$ is small (large), the
constraints from $B^0_s$-${\bar B}^0_s$ mixing are stringent (weak), leading to
a small (large) value of the NP weak phase, and corresponding small (large) CP
asymmetries. We therefore find that the measurement of CP-violating asymmetries
in $B \to K^{(*)} \mu^+ \mu^-$ can indeed distinguish among NP $b \to s \mu^+
\mu^-$ models
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10291</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cinti</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boninsegni</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical and quantum filaments in the ground state of trapped dipolar
  Bose gases</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Replaced with published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013627 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013627</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study by quantum Monte Carlo simulations the ground state of a
harmonically confined dipolar Bose gas with aligned dipole moments, and with
the inclusion of a repulsive two-body potential of varying range. Two different
limits can be clearly identified, namely a classical one in which the
attractive part of the dipolar interaction dominates and the system forms an
ordered array of parallel filaments, and a quantum-mechanical one, wherein
filaments are destabilized by zero-point motion, and eventually the ground
state becomes a uniform cloud. The physical character of the system smoothly
evolves from classical to quantum mechanical as the range of the repulsive
two-body potential increases. An intermediate regime is observed, in which
ordered filaments are still present, albeit forming different structures from
the ones predicted classically; quantum-mechanical exchanges of
indistinguishable particles across different filaments allow phase coherence to
be established, underlying a global superfluid response.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00129</id><created>2017-04-01</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsirkin</keyname><forenames>Stepan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Ivo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanderbilt</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Composite Weyl nodes stabilized by screw symmetry with and without time
  reversal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 045102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.045102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We classify the band degeneracies in 3D crystals with screw symmetry $n_m$
and broken $\mathcal P*\mathcal T$ symmetry, where $\mathcal P$ stands for
spatial inversion and $\mathcal T$ for time reversal. The generic degeneracies
along symmetry lines are Weyl nodes: Chiral contact points between pairs of
bands. They can be single nodes with a chiral charge of magnitude $|\chi|=1$ or
composite nodes with $|\chi|=2$ or $3$, and the possible $\chi$ values only
depend on the order $n$ of the axis, not on the pitch $m/n$ of the screw.
Double Weyl nodes require $n=4$ or 6, and triple nodes require $n=6$. In all
cases the bands split linearly along the axis, and for composite nodes the
splitting is quadratic on the orthogonal plane. This is true for triple as well
as double nodes, due to the presence in the effective two-band Hamiltonian of a
nonchiral quadratic term that masks the chiral cubic dispersion. If $\mathcal
T$ symmetry is present and $\mathcal P$ is broken there may exist on some
symmetry lines Weyl nodes pinned to $\mathcal T$-invariant momenta, which in
some cases are unavoidable. In the absence of other symmetries their
classification depends on $n$, $m$, and the type of $\mathcal T$ symmetry. With
spinless $\mathcal T$ such $\mathcal T$-invariant Weyl nodes are always double
nodes, while with spinful $\mathcal T$ they can be single or triple nodes.
$\mathcal T$-invariant triples nodes can occur not only on 6-fold axes but also
on 3-fold ones, and their in-plane band splitting is cubic, not quadratic as in
the case of generic triple nodes. These rules are illustrated by means of
first-principles calculations for hcp cobalt, a $\mathcal T$-broken, $\mathcal
P$-invariant crystal with $6_3$ symmetry, and for trigonal tellurium and
hexagonal NbSi$_2$, which are $\mathcal T$-invariant, $\mathcal P$-broken
crystals with 3-fold and 6-fold screw symmetry respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00219</id><created>2017-04-01</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsumura</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Masatoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Yuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational wave from dark sector with dark pion</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>47 pages, 9 figures, references added; version published in JCAP</comments><report-no>KUNS-2669, EPHOU-17-004</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP07(2017)044</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we investigate the spectra of gravitational waves produced by
chiral symmetry breaking in dark quantum chromodynamics (dQCD) sector. The dark
pion ($\pi$) can be a dark matter candidate as weakly interacting massive
particle (WIMP) or strongly interacting massive particle (SIMP). For a WIMP
scenario, we introduce the dQCD sector coupled to the standard model (SM)
sector with classical scale invariance and investigate the annihilation process
of the dark pion via the $2\pi \to 2\,\text{SM}$ process. For a SIMP scenario,
we investigate the $3\pi \to 2\pi$ annihilation process of the dark pion as a
SIMP using chiral perturbation theory. We find that in the WIMP scenario the
gravitational wave background spectra can be observed by future space
gravitational wave antennas. On the other hand, when the dark pion is the SIMP
dark matter with the constraints for the chiral perturbative limit and
pion-pion scattering cross section, the chiral phase transition becomes
crossover and then the gravitational waves are not produced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00550</id><created>2017-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Namouni</keyname><forenames>Fathi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morais</keyname><forenames>Helena</forenames></author></authors><title>Coorbital capture at arbitrary inclination</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>8 pages. 2 figures. Submitted to Journal of Computational and Applied
  Mathematics</comments><doi>10.1007/s40314-017-0489-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The process of capture in the coorbital region of a solar system planet is
studied. Absolute capture likelihood in the 1:1 resonance is determined by
randomly constructed statistical ensembles numbering $7.24\times 10^5$ of
massless asteroids that are set to migrate radially from the outer to the inner
boundaries of the coorbital region of a Jupiter-mass planet. Orbital states
include coorbital capture, ejection, collisions with the Sun and the planet and
free-crossing of the coorbital region. The relative efficiency of retrograde
capture with respect to prograde capture is confirmed as an intrinsic property
of the coorbital resonance. Half the asteroids cross the coorbital region
regardless of eccentricity and for any inclination less than $120^\circ$. We
also find that the recently discovered retrograde coorbital of Jupiter,
asteroid 2015 BZ509, lies almost exactly at the capture efficiency peak
associated with its orbital parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00864</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blunt</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Booth</keyname><forenames>George H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alavi</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Density matrices in full configuration interaction quantum Monte Carlo:
  Excited states, transition dipole moments and parallel distribution</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4986963</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present developments in the calculation of reduced density matrices (RDMs)
in the full configuration interaction quantum Monte Carlo (FCIQMC) method. An
efficient scheme is described to allow storage of RDMs across distributed
memory, thereby allowing their calculation and storage in large basis sets. We
demonstrate the calculation of RDMs for general states by using the
recently-introduced excited-state FCIQMC approach [J. Chem. Phys. 143, 134117
(2015)] and further introduce calculation of transition density matrices (TDMs)
in the method. These approaches are combined to calculate excited-state dipole
and transition dipole moments for heteronuclear diatomic molecules, including
LiH, BH and MgO, and initiator error is investigated in these quantities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01831</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Dharm Veer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Naveen K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anti-Evaporation of Bardeen de-Sitter Black Holes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Extensively revised</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics, Vol 383 (2017) 600-609</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we discuss the possibility of the anti-evaporation of
degenerate Bardeen de-Sitter black hole. We solve the perturbation equations
around the Nariai space-time. The solution of one of the perturbations related
to the horizon size demonstrates that horizon of such black hole is constant.
The other perturbation is also found to be stable. We further study
thermodynamical properties of such black holes. We observe double phase
transition at the Nariai limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06727</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Huibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Guixin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benavides</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCandless</keyname><forenames>Gregory T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Julia Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelton</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DiTusa</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Density wave instability in a ferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages with 4 figures. Supplemental Materials Included</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ferromagnetic (FM) and incommensurate spin-density wave (ISDW) states are an
unusual set of competing magnetic orders that are seldom observed in the same
material without application of a polarizing magnetic field. We report, for the
first time, the discovery of an ISDW state that is derived from a FM ground
state through a Fermi surface (FS) instability in Fe$_3$Ga$_4$. This was
achieved by combining neutron scattering experiments with first principles
simulations. Neutron diffraction demonstrates that Fe$_3$Ga$_4$ is in an ISDW
state at intermediate temperatures and that there is a conspicuous re-emergence
of ferromagnetism above 360 K. First principles calculations show that the ISDW
ordering wavevector is in excellent agreement with a prominent nesting
condition in the spin-majority FS demonstrating the discovery of a novel
instability for FM metals; ISDW formation due to Fermi surface nesting in a
spin-polarized Fermi surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07074</id><created>2017-04-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Woojun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyosub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Jaewook</forenames></author></authors><title>Defect-free atomic array formation using Hungarian matching algorithm</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deterministic loading of single atoms onto arbitrary two-dimensional lattice
points has recently been demonstrated, where by dynamically controlling the
optical-dipole potential, atoms from a probabilistically loaded lattice were
relocated to target lattice points to form a zero-entropy atomic lattice. In
this atom rearrangement, how to pair atoms with the target sites is a
combinatorial optimization problem: brute-force methods search all possible
combinations so the process is slow, while heuristic methods are time-efficient
but optimal solutions are not guaranteed. Here, we use the Hungarian matching
algorithm as a fast and rigorous alternative to this problem of defect-free
atomic lattice formation. Our approach utilizes an optimization cost function
that restricts collision-free guiding paths so that atom loss due to collision
is minimized during rearrangement. Experiments were performed with cold
rubidium atoms that were trapped and guided with holographically controlled
optical-dipole traps. The result of atom relocation from a partially filled
7-by-7 lattice to a 3-by-3 target lattice strongly agrees with the theoretical
analysis: using the Hungarian algorithm minimizes the collisional and
trespassing paths and results in improved performance, with over 50\% higher
success probability than the heuristic shortest-move method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07640</id><created>2017-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Trojak</keyname><forenames>Oliver J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Suk In</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Jin Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapienza</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Metallic nanorings for broadband, enhanced extraction of light from
  solid-state emitters</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 111, 021109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993774</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the increased extraction of light emitted by solid-state sources
embedded within high refractive index materials. This is achieved by making use
of a local lensing effect by sub-micron metallic rings deposited on the sample
surface and centered around single emitters. We show enhancements in the
intensity of the light emitted by InAs/GaAs single quantum dot lines into free
space as high as a factor 20. Such a device is intrinsically broadband and
therefore compatible with any kind of solid-state light source. We foresee the
fabrication of metallic rings via scalable techniques, like nano-imprint, and
their implementation to improve the emission of classical and quantum light
from solid-state sources. Furthermore, while increasing the brightness of the
devices, the metallic rings can also act as top contacts for the local
application of electric fields for carrier injection or wavelength tuning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08642</id><created>2017-04-27</created><updated>2017-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Choudhuri</keyname><forenames>Samir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bharadwaj</keyname><forenames>Somnath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Sk. Saiyad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Intema</keyname><forenames>H. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Abhik</forenames></author></authors><title>The angular power spectrum measurement of the Galactic synchrotron
  emission in two fields of the TGSS survey</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 table, 3 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS
  Letters. The definitive version will be available at
  http://mnrasl.oxfordjournals.org/</comments><journal-ref>2017, MNRAS, 470, L11</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Characterizing the diffuse Galactic synchrotron emission at arcminute angular
scales is needed to reliably remove foregrounds in cosmological 21-cm
measurements. The study of this emission is also interesting in its own right.
Here, we quantify the fluctuations of the diffuse Galactic synchrotron emission
using visibility data for two of the fields observed by the TIFR GMRT Sky
Survey (TGSS). We have used the 2D Tapered Gridded Estimator (TGE) to estimate
the angular power spectrum $(C_{\ell})$ from the visibilities. We find that the
sky signal, after subtracting the point sources, is likely dominated by the
diffuse Galactic synchrotron radiation across the angular multipole range $240
\le \ell \lesssim 500$. We present a power law fit,
$C_{\ell}=A\times\big(\frac{1000}{l}\big)^{\beta}$, to the measured $C_{\ell}$
over this $\ell$ range. We find that $(A,\beta)$ have values $(356\pm109~{\rm
mK^2},2.8\pm0.3)$ and $(54\pm26~{\rm mK^2},2.2\pm0.4)$ in the two fields. For
the second field, however, there is indication of a significant residual point
source contribution, and for this field we interpret the measured $C_{\ell}$ as
an upper limit for the diffuse Galactic synchrotron emission. While in both
fields the slopes are consistent with earlier measurements, the second field
appears to have an amplitude which is considerably smaller compared to similar
measurements in other parts of the sky.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02769</id><created>2017-05-08</created><updated>2017-07-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larsson</keyname><forenames>Henrik R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tannor</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical pruning of the multiconfiguration time-dependent Hartree
  method (DP-MCTDH): An efficient approach for multidimensional quantum
  dynamics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics, 147, 044103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993219</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present two strategies for combining dynamical pruning with the
multiconfiguration time-dependent Hartree method (DP-MCTDH), where dynamical
pruning means on-the-fly selection of relevant basis functions. The first
strategy prunes the primitive basis that represents the single-particle
functions (SPFs). This is useful for smaller systems that require many
primitive basis functions per degree of freedom, as we will illustrate for
NO$_2$. Furthermore, this allows for higher-dimensional mode combination and
partially lifts the sum-of-product-form requirement onto the structure of the
Hamiltonian, as we illustrate for nonadiabatic 24-dimensional pyrazine. The
second strategy prunes the set of configurations of SPF at each time step. We
show that this strategy yields significant speed-ups with factors between 5 and
50 in computing time, making it competitive with the multilayer MCTDH method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04234</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miao</keyname><forenames>Jiayuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsige</keyname><forenames>Mesfin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Philip L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized model for the diffusion of solvents in glassy polymers: From
  Fickian to super Case II</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>15 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics 147 (2017) 044904</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4994924</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The diffusion of small solvent molecules in glassy polymers may take on a
variety of different forms. Fickian, anomalous, Case II, and super Case II
diffusion have all been observed, and theoretical models exist that describe
each specific type of behavior. Here we present a single generalized kinetic
model capable of yielding all these different types of diffusion on the basis
of just two parameters. The principal determinant of the type of diffusion is
observed to be a dimensionless parameter, $\gamma$, that describes the
influence of solvent-induced swelling in lowering the potential barriers
separating available solvent sites. A second parameter, $\eta$, which
characterizes the effect of the solvent in reducing the potential energy of a
solvent molecule when at rest at an available site, only influences the type of
diffusion to a lesser extent. The theoretical analysis does not include any
effects that are explicitly non-local in time, an example of which is the
inclusion of polymer viscosity in the Thomas-Windle model; it thus represents a
variant of Fick's second law utilizing a concentration-dependent diffusivity
when $\eta$ is small. To check the significance of time-delayed swelling, a
simulation was performed of a modified model that contained a history-dependent
term. The results were found to be very similar to those in the time-local
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06329</id><created>2017-05-17</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Wei</forenames><affiliation>AIfA, Bonn University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stancliffe</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames><affiliation>AIfA, Bonn University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Can the Helium-Enriched Main-Sequence Donor Scenario Hide Enough
  Hydrogen to Explain Type Ia Supernovae?</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages,2 figures, 1 table, Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical
  Society: Letters, Volume 470, Issue 1, p.L72-L76</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx080</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrodynamical simulations predict that a large amount of hydrogen (&gt;0.1
solar masses) is removed from a hydrogen-rich companion star by the SN
explosion in the single-degenerate scenario of Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia).
However, non-detection of hydrogen-rich material in the late-time spectra of
SNe Ia suggests that the hydrogen mass stripped from the progenitor system is
&lt;0.001-0.058 solar masses. In this letter we include thermohaline mixing into
self-consistent binary evolution calculations for the helium-enriched
main-sequence (HEMS) donor channel of SNe Ia for the first time. We find that
the swept-up hydrogen masses expected in this channel are around 0.10-0.17
solar masses, which is higher than the observational limits, although the
companion star is strongly helium-enriched when the SN explodes. This presents
a serious challenge to the HEMS donor channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07905</id><created>2017-05-22</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berton</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio astronomico di Brera</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Foschini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio astronomico di Brera</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Caccianiga</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio astronomico di Brera</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ciroi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Congiu</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio astronomico di Brera</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cracco</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frezzato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>La Mura</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rafanelli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Dipartimento di Fisica e Astronomia &quot;G. Galilei&quot;, Universit&#xe0; di Padova</affiliation></author></authors><title>An orientation-based unification of young jetted AGN: the case of 3C 286</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures. Proceeding of the conference &quot;Quasars at all
  cosmic epochs&quot;, held in Padova, April 2-7, 2017, published on Frontiers in
  Astronomy and Space Sciences</comments><doi>10.3389/fspas.2017.00008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, the old paradigm according to which only high-mass black
holes can launch powerful relativistic jets in active galactic nuclei (AGN) has
begun to crumble. The discovery of $\gamma$-rays coming from narrow-line
Seyfert 1 galaxies (NLS1s), usually considered young and growing AGN harboring
a central black hole with mass typically lower than 10$^8$ M$_\odot$, indicated
that also these low-mass AGN can produce powerful relativistic jets. The search
for parent population of $\gamma$-ray emitting NLS1s revealed their connection
with compact steep-spectrum sources (CSS). In this proceeding we present a
review of the current knowledge of these sources, we present the new important
case of 3C 286, classified here for the fist time as NLS1, and we finally
provide a tentative orientation based unification of NLS1s and CSS sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08899</id><created>2017-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Martinez-Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xfc;nsch</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palou&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Can Dust Injected by SNe Explain the NIR-MIR Excess in Young Massive
  Stellar Clusters?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, Accepted for publication in The Astrophysical
  Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 843, Issue 2, article id. 95, 12
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a physically-motivated model involving the different processes
affecting supernova dust grains as they are incorporated into the thermalized
medium within young massive star clusters. The model is used to explain the
near- to mid-infrared (NIR-MIR) excess found in such clusters and usually
modeled as a blackbody with temperature $\sim (400-1000)$ K. In our approach,
dust grains are efficiently produced in the clumpy ejecta of core-collapse
supernovae, fragmented into small pieces ($\lesssim 0.05$ $\mu$m) as they are
incorporated into the hot and dense ISM, heated via frequent collisions with
electrons and the absorption of energetic photons. Grains with small sizes can
more easily acquire the high temperatures ($\sim 1000$ K) required to produce a
NIR-MIR excess with respect to the emission of foreground PAHs and starlight.
However, the extreme conditions inside young massive clusters make difficult
for these small grains to have a persistent manifestation at NIR-MIR
wavelengths as they are destroyed by efficient thermal sputtering.
Nevertheless, the chances for a persistent manifestation are increased by
taking into account that small grains become increasingly transparent to their
impinging ions as their size decreases. For an individual SN event, we find
that the NIR-MIR excess last longer if the time required to incorporate all the
grains into the thermalized medium is also longer, and in some cases,
comparable to the characteristic interval between supernova explosions. Our
models, can successfully explain the near-infrared excesses found in the star
clusters observed in M33 (Rela\~no et al. 2016) assuming a low heating
efficiency and mass-loading. In this scenario, the presence of the NIR-MIR
excess is an indication of efficient dust production in SNe and its subsequent
destruction
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10477</id><created>2017-05-30</created><updated>2017-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsukamoto</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogasawara</keyname><forenames>Kota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Yungui</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle collision with an arbitrarily high center-of-mass energy near a
  Ba\~nados-Teitelboim-Zanelli black hole</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 figures, minor correction, accepted for publication in
  Physical Review D</comments><report-no>RUP-17-10</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 024042 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.024042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a particle collision with a high center-of-mass energy near a
Ba\~nados-Teitelboim-Zanelli (BTZ) black hole. We obtain the center-of-mass
energy of two general colliding geodesic particles in the BTZ black hole
spacetime. We show that the center-of-mass energy of two ingoing particles can
be arbitrarily large on an event horizon if either of the two particles has a
critical angular momentum and the other has a non-critical angular momentum. We
also show that the motion of a particle with a subcritical angular momentum is
allowed near an extremal rotating BTZ black hole and that a center-of-mass
energy for a tail-on collision at a point can be arbitrarily large in a
critical angular momentum limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01514</id><created>2017-06-05</created><updated>2017-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krapivsky</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent Network Modularity</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.PR</categories><comments>21 pages, 10 figures, 2 appendices. Minor corrections in version2.
  For publication in JSTAT</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 073405 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa7a3f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a network growth model based on complete redirection: a new node
randomly selects an existing target node, but attaches to a random neighbor of
this target. For undirected networks, this simple growth rule generates
unusual, highly modular networks. Individual network realizations typically
contain multiple macrohubs---nodes whose degree scales linearly with the number
of nodes $N$. The size of the network &quot;nucleus&quot;---the set of nodes of degree
greater than one---grows sublinearly with $N$ and thus constitutes a
vanishingly small fraction of the network. The network therefore consists
almost entirely of leaves (nodes of degree one) as $N\to\infty$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02716</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Suarez</keyname><forenames>Teresita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pontzen</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-scale fluctuations in the cosmic ionising background: the impact
  of beamed source emission</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When modelling the ionisation of gas in the intergalactic medium after
reionisation, it is standard practice to assume a uniform radiation background.
This assumption is not always appropriate; models with radiative transfer show
that large-scale ionisation rate fluctuations can have an observable impact on
statistics of the Lyman-alpha forest. We extend such calculations to include
beaming of sources, which has previously been neglected but which is expected
to be important if quasars dominate the ionising photon budget. Beaming has two
effects: first, the physical number density of ionising sources is enhanced
relative to that directly observed; and second, the radiative transfer itself
is altered. We calculate both effects in a hard-edged beaming model where each
source has a random orientation, using an equilibrium Boltzmann hierarchy in
terms of spherical harmonics. By studying the statistical properties of the
resulting ionisation rate and HI density fields at redshift $z\sim 2.3$, we
find that the two effects partially cancel each other; combined, they
constitute a maximum $5\%$ correction to the power spectrum
$P_{\mathrm{HI}}(k)$ at $k=0.04 \, h/\mathrm{Mpc}$. On very large scales
($k&lt;0.01\, h/\mathrm{Mpc}$) the source density renormalisation dominates; it
can reduce, by an order of magnitude, the contribution of ionising shot-noise
to the intergalactic HI power spectrum. The effects of beaming should be
considered when interpreting future observational datasets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02782</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caram&#xea;s</keyname><forenames>Thiago R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabris</keyname><forenames>J&#xfa;lio C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Mello</keyname><forenames>E. R. Bezerra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belich</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>$f(R)$ global monopole revisited</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 1 figure and 1 table. Minor changes to match published
  version in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 496</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5057-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the $f(R)$ global monopole is reexamined. We provide an exact
solution for the modified field equations in the presence of a global monopole
for regions outside its core, generalizing previous results. Additionally, we
discuss some particular cases obtained from this solution. We consider a setup
consisting of a possible Schwarzschild black hole that absorbs the topological
defect, giving rise to a static black hole endowed with a monopole's charge.
Besides, we demonstrate how the asymptotic behavior of the Higgs field far from
the monopole's core is shaped by a class of spacetime metrics which includes
those ones analyzed here. In order to assess the gravitational properties of
this system, we analyse the geodesic motion of both massive and massless test
particles moving in the vicinity of such configuration. For the material
particles we set the requirements they have to obey in order to experience
stable orbits. On the other hand, for the photons we investigate how their
trajectories are affected by the gravitational field of this black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03068</id><created>2017-06-09</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alioli</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pappadopulo</keyname><forenames>Duccio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruderman</keyname><forenames>Joshua T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision Probes of QCD at High Energies</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>40 pages, 13 figures, 8 tables. Minor changes. Accepted on JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1707 (2017) 097</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)097</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New physics, that is too heavy to be produced directly, can leave measurable
imprints on the tails of kinematic distributions at the LHC. We use energetic
QCD processes to perform novel measurements of the Standard Model (SM)
Effective Field Theory. We show that the dijet invariant mass spectrum, and the
inclusive jet transverse momentum spectrum, are sensitive to a dimension 6
operator that modifies the gluon propagator at high energies. The dominant
effect is constructive or destructive interference with SM jet production. We
compare differential next-to-leading order predictions from POWHEG to public 7
TeV jet data, including scale, PDF, and experimental uncertainties and their
respective correlations. We constrain a New Physics (NP) scale of 3.5 TeV with
current data. We project the reach of future 13 and 100 TeV measurements, which
we estimate to be sensitive to NP scales of 8 and 60 TeV, respectively. As an
application, we apply our bounds to constrain heavy vector octet colorons that
couple to the QCD current. We project that effective operators will surpass
bump hunts, in terms of coloron mass reach, even for sequential couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03518</id><created>2017-06-12</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takesue</keyname><forenames>Koki</forenames></author></authors><title>ADHM Construction of (Anti-)Self-dual Instantons in $4n$ Dimensions</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>23 pages, published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 07 (2017) 110</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ADHM construction is a very strong scheme to construct the instantons in
four dimensions. We study an ADHM construction of instantons in $4n~(n\geq2)$
dimensions by generalizing this scheme. The higher-dimensional ADHM
construction generates the $4n$-dimensional (anti-)self-dual instantons which
satisfy the (anti-)self-dual equation in $4n$ dimensions:
$F(n)=\pm\ast_{4n}F(n)$. Here $F(n)$ is the $n$th wedge products of the gauge
field strength 2-form $F$. We also show that our scheme reproduces the known
$4n$-dimensional one-instantons and there are multi-instanton solutions of the
't Hooft type in the dilute instanton gas limit. Moreover we discuss a
Harrington-Shepard type caloron in $4n$ dimensions and this monopole limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04611</id><created>2017-06-14</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>On the origin of the hard X-Ray excess of high-synchrotron-peaked BL Lac
  object Mrk 421</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, 3 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>2017, ApJ, 842, 129</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7744</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the first time, Kataoka \&amp; Stawarz reported a clear detection of a hard
X-ray excess, above $\gtrsim$20 keV, in the high-synchrotron-peaked BL Lac
object Mrk 421. We find that this feature may not be produced by the low-energy
part of the same electron population that produced the Fermi/LAT $\gamma$-ray.
Because of that it is required that the power-law electron energy go down to
$\gamma_{\rm min}\approx19$, which predicts a very strong radio emission (radio
flux larger than the observed) even considering the synchrotron self-absorption
effect. We investigate the possibility of this excess being produced from the
spine/layer jet structure, which has been clearly detected in Mrk 421. We find
that (1) similar to one-zone modeling, the spine emissions provide good
modeling of the broadband spectral energy distribution, except for the hard
X-ray excess; and (2) the hard X-ray excess can be well represented by the
synchrotron photons (from the layer) being inverse Compton scattered by the
spine electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06092</id><created>2017-06-17</created><updated>2017-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Qing-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiang-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ruo-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of an Internal Dissipation Origin for the High-energy Prompt
  Emission of GRB 170214A</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 844, 56 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa7a58</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the prompt high-energy ($&gt;100$MeV) emission of Gamma-ray Bursts
(GRBs), detected by the Large Area Telescope (LAT) on board the Fermi Gamma-ray
Space Telescope, is still under debate, for which both the external shock
origin and internal dissipation origin have been suggested. In the internal
dissipation scenario, the high energy emission is expected to exhibit
significant temporal variability, tracking the keV/MeV fast variable behavior.
Here, we report a detailed analysis on the Fermi data of GRB~170214A, which is
sufficiently bright in the high energy to enable a quantitative analysis of the
correlation between high-energy emission and keV/MeV emission with high
statistics. Our result shows a clear temporal correlation between high-energy
and keV/MeV emission in the whole prompt emission phase as well as in two
decomposed short time intervals. Such correlation behavior is also found in
some other bright LAT GRBs, i.e., GRB 080916C, 090902B and 090926A. For these
GRBs as well as GRB 090510, we also find the rapid temporal variability in the
high-energy emission. We thus conclude that the prompt high-energy emission in
these bright LAT GRBs should be due to internal origin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06567</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oliva-Leyva</keyname><forenames>Maurice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chumin</forenames></author></authors><title>Magneto-optical conductivity of anisotropic two-dimensional Dirac-Weyl
  materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Revised Version</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 384, 61-70 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the presence of an external magnetic field, the optical response of
two-dimensional materials, whose charge carriers behave as massless Dirac
fermions with arbitrary anisotropic Fermi velocity, is investigated. Using Kubo
formalism, we obtain the magneto-optical conductivity tensor for these
materials, which allows to address the magneto-optical response of anisotropic
Dirac fermions from the well known magneto-optical conductivity of isotropic
Dirac fermions. As an application, we analyse the combined effects of
strain-induced anisotropy and magnetic field on the transmittance, as well as
on the Faraday rotation, of linearly polarized light after passing strained
graphene. The reported analytical expressions can be a useful tool to predict
the absorption and the Faraday angle of strained graphene under magnetic field.
Finally, our study is extended to anisotropic two-dimensional materials with
Dirac fermions of arbitrary pseudospin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06586</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>McQuinn</keyname><forenames>Kristen B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skillman</keyname><forenames>Evan D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolphin</keyname><forenames>Andrew E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Danielle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennicutt</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate Distances to Important Spiral Galaxies: M63, M74, NGC 1291, NGC
  4559, NGC 4625, NGC 5398</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures, 8 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate distances are fundamental to interpreting many measured properties
of galaxies. Surprisingly, many of the best-studied spiral galaxies in the
Local Volume have distance uncertainties that are much larger than can be
achieved with modern observations. Using Hubble Space Telescope optical
imaging, we use the tip of the red giant branch method to measure the distances
to six galaxies that are included in the Spitzer Infrared Nearby Galaxies
Survey (SINGS) program and its offspring surveys. The sample includes M63, M74,
NGC 1291, NGC 4559, NGC 4625, and NGC 5398. We compare our results with
distances reported to these galaxies based on a variety of methods. Depending
on the technique, there can be a wide range in published distances,
particularly from the Tully-Fisher relation. In addition, differences between
the Planetary Nebula Luminosity Function and Surface Brightness Fluctuation
techniques can vary between galaxies suggesting inaccuracies that cannot be
explained by systematics in the calibrations. Our distances improve upon
previous results as we use a well-calibrated, stable distance indicator,
precision photometry in an optimally selected field of view, and a Bayesian
Maximum Likelihood technique that reduces measurement uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08983</id><created>2017-06-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Rappazzo</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthaeus</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruffolo</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Servidio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coronal Heating Topology: the Interplay of Current Sheets and Magnetic
  Field Lines</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph physics.space-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 Figures, ApJ (in press)</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 844, 87 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa79f2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetic topology and field line random walk properties of a
nanoflare-heated and magnetically confined corona are investigated in the
reduced magnetohydrodynamic regime. Field lines originating from current sheets
form coherent structures, called Current Sheet Connected (CSC) regions,
extended around them. CSC field line random walk is strongly anisotropic, with
preferential diffusion along the current sheets' in-plane length. CSC field
line random walk properties remain similar to those of the entire ensemble but
exhibit enhanced mean square displacements and separations due to the stronger
magnetic field intensities in CSC regions. The implications for particle
acceleration and heat transport in the solar corona and wind, and for solar
moss formation are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09033</id><created>2017-06-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Choudhuri</keyname><forenames>Samir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bharadwaj</keyname><forenames>Somnath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Sk. Saiyad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Abhik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Prasun</forenames></author></authors><title>Validating a novel angular power spectrum estimator using simulated low
  frequency radio-interferometric data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 1 table, 9 figures, Accepted for publication in New
  Astronomy</comments><journal-ref>2017, New Astronomy, 57, 94</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.newast.2017.06.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The &quot;Tapered Gridded Estimator&quot; (TGE) is a novel way to directly estimate the
angular power spectrum from radio-interferometric visibility data that reduces
the computation by efficiently gridding the data, consistently removes the
noise bias, and suppresses the foreground contamination to a large extent by
tapering the primary beam response through an appropriate convolution in the
visibility domain. Here we demonstrate the effectiveness of TGE in recovering
the diffuse emission power spectrum through numerical simulations. We present
details of the simulation used to generate low frequency visibility data for
sky model with extragalactic compact radio sources and diffuse Galactic
synchrotron emission. We then use different imaging strategies to identify the
most effective option of point source subtraction and to study the underlying
diffuse emission. Finally, we apply TGE to the residual data to measure the
angular power spectrum, and assess the impact of incomplete point source
subtraction in recovering the input power spectrum $C_{\ell}$ of the
synchrotron emission. This estimator is found to successfully recovers the
$C_{\ell}$ of input model from the residual visibility data. These results are
relevant for measuring the diffuse emission like the Galactic synchrotron
emission. It is also an important step towards characterizing and removing both
diffuse and compact foreground emission in order to detect the redshifted $21\,
{\rm cm}$ signal from the Epoch of Reionization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09710</id><created>2017-06-28</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bolotin</keyname><forenames>Yu. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konchatnyi</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemets</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zazunov</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmography of Cardassian model</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>3 figures. corrected some errors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The parameters of any model that satisfies the cosmological principle (the
universe is homogeneous and isotropic on large scale), can be expressed through
cosmographic parameters. In this paper, we perform this procedure for the
Cardassian model. We demonstrate a number of advantages of the approach used
before traditional methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00586</id><created>2017-07-03</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borgo</keyname><forenames>Martina Dal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hovhannisyan</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouault</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic results in solvable two-charge models</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><msc-class>60B20, 82B05, 15B52, 15A15 (Primary), 60F05, 60F10, 62H10
  (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rider, Sinclair and Xu (2013) introduced a solvable two charge ensemble of
interacting charged particles on the real line in the presence of the harmonic
oscillator potential. It can be seen as a special form of a grand canonical
ensemble with the total charge being fixed and unit charge particles being
random. Moreover, it serves as an interpolation between the Gaussian orthogonal
and the Gaussian symplectic ensembles and maintains the Pfaffian structure of
the eigenvalues. A similar solvable ensemble of charged particles on the unit
circle was studied by Shum and Sinclair (2014) and Forrester (2010). In this
paper we explore the sharp asymptotic behavior of the number of unit charge
particles on the line and on the circle, as the total charge goes to infinity.
We establish extended central limit theorems, Berry-Esseen estimates and
precise moderate deviations using the machinery of the mod-Gaussian
convergence. Also a large deviation principle is derived using the
G\&quot;artner-Ellis theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01094</id><created>2017-07-04</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>Sedona H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kriek</keyname><forenames>Mariska</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feldmann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Philip F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faucher-Gigu&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Claude-Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kere&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Du&#x161;an</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barro</keyname><forenames>Guillermo</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the Recovery of Intrinsic Galaxy Sizes and Masses of z~2 Massive
  Galaxies Using Cosmological Simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in the Astrophysical Journal Letters (7 pages, 5 figures;
  updated to match published version)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate measurements of galaxy masses and sizes are key to tracing galaxy
evolution over time. Cosmological zoom-in simulations provide an ideal test bed
for assessing the recovery of galaxy properties from observations. Here, we
utilize galaxies with $M_*\sim10^{10}-10^{11.5}M_{\odot}$ at z~1.7-2 from the
MassiveFIRE cosmological simulation suite, part of the Feedback in Realistic
Environments (FIRE) project. Using mock multi-band images, we compare intrinsic
galaxy masses and sizes to observational estimates. We find that observations
accurately recover stellar masses, with a slight average underestimate of ~0.06
dex and a ~0.15 dex scatter. Recovered half-light radii agree well with
intrinsic half-mass radii when averaged over all viewing angles, with a
systematic offset of ~0.1 dex (with the half-light radii being larger) and a
scatter of ~0.2 dex. When using color gradients to account for mass-to-light
variations, recovered half-mass radii also exceed the intrinsic half-mass radii
by ~0.1 dex. However, if not properly accounted for, aperture effects can bias
size estimates by ~0.1 dex. No differences are found between the mass and size
offsets for star-forming and quiescent galaxies. Variations in viewing angle
are responsible for ~25% of the scatter in the recovered masses and sizes. Our
results thus suggest that the intrinsic scatter in the mass-size relation may
have previously been overestimated by ~25%. Moreover, orientation-driven
scatter causes the number density of very massive galaxies to be overestimated
by ~0.5 dex at $M_*\sim10^{11.5}M_{\odot}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01802</id><created>2017-07-06</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanafy</keyname><forenames>W. El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nashed</keyname><forenames>G. G. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorenz Gauge Fixing of $f(T)$ Teleparallel Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Minor modifications, some references added to match the published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D, Vol. 26 (2017) 1750154</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817501541</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In teleparallel gravity, we apply Lorenz type gauge fixing to cope with
redundant degrees of freedom in the vierbein field. This condition is mainly to
restore the Lorentz symmetry of the teleparallel torsion scalar. In
cosmological application, this technique provides standard cosmology,
turnaround, bounce or $\Lambda$CDM as separate scenarios. We reconstruct the
$f(T)$ gravity which generates these models. We study the stability of the
solutions by analyzing the corresponding phase portraits. Also, we investigate
Lorenz gauge in the unimodular coordinates, it leads to unify a nonsingular
bounce and standard model cosmology in a single model, where crossing the
phantom divide line is achievable through a finite-time singularity of Type IV
associated with a de Sitter fixed point. We reconstruct the unimodular $f(T)$
gravity which generates the unified cosmic evolution showing the role of the
torsion gravity to establish a healthy bounce scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03075</id><created>2017-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Cifuentes-Quintal</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Pe&#xf1;a-Seaman</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Coss</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Electron-phonon coupling in two-dimensional silicene and
  germanene&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Physical Review B (7 July 2017)</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 96, 047401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.047401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In their work, Yan et al. [Phys. Rev. B 88, 121403 (2013)] employing density
functional perturbation theory (DFPT) calculations, demonstrate that silicene
and germanene show weaker Kohn anomalies in the $\Gamma$-$E_g$ and $K$-$A_1$
phonon modes, compared to graphene. Furthermore, they compute the electron
phonon (e-ph) coupling matrix elements using the frozen phonon approach and
found that in silicene the average e-ph coupling matrix-element square over the
Fermi surface, $\langle g_{{\bf q}\nu}^2\rangle_{F}$, is about 50 % of those in
graphene, but in germanene is weaker and nearly negligible. However, Yan et al.
argues that the smaller Fermi velocity in silicene compensates the reduced
$\langle g_{{\bf q}\nu}^2\rangle_{F}$, leading to phonon linewidths
($\gamma_{{\bf q}\nu}$) slightly larger than those in graphene. In this
Comment, we show that the DFPT and the frozen phonon results of Yan et al. for
silicene are inconsistent. Additionally, we have evaluated the e-ph coupling
using direct DFPT calculations, analytical relations, and frozen phonon
calculations, and we found systematically that $\langle g_{{\bf
q}\nu}^2\rangle_{F}$ and $\gamma_{{\bf q}\nu}$ in silicene are one order of
magnitude smaller than in graphene, in contrast to the conclusions of Yan et
al.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03726</id><created>2017-07-12</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pashitskii</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pentegov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the nature of the Newton's gravitational constant and the possible
  quantum-field theory of gravitation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the basis of the coincidence of the physical dimensions (in natural units
$\hbar = c = 1$) of the Newton's gravitational constant $G_{N} $ and the
phenomenological Fermi constant $G_{F} $ for weak interaction, it is suggested
that there is a certain similarity between weak forces, which are caused by the
exchange of massive intermediate vector bosons with spin $S=1$, and &quot;superweak&quot;
gravitational forces that can be caused by the exchange of &quot;supermassive&quot;
hypothetical tensor bosons with spin $S=2$. By analogy with how the masses of
intermediate bosons in the theory of electroweak interaction arise as a result
of spontaneous breaking of the gauge symmetry of the electromagnetic field due
to its interaction with the nonlinear scalar Higgs field, the masses of
hypothetical tensor bosons carrying gravitational interaction can also arise as
a result of spontaneous breaking of gauge symmetry of the massless gravitons
when they interact with a fundamental nonlinear scalar field in a flat
4-dimensional space-time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04012</id><created>2017-07-13</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Montanaro</keyname><forenames>Ashley</forenames></author></authors><title>Learning stabilizer states by Bell sampling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>2+eps pages; first presented at Coogee'13 workshop, Sydney, January
  2013. v2: reference added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that measuring pairs of qubits in the Bell basis can be used to
obtain a simple quantum algorithm for efficiently identifying an unknown
stabilizer state of n qubits. The algorithm uses O(n) copies of the input state
and fails with exponentially small probability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04920</id><created>2017-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Trivedi</keyname><forenames>Tanuj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movva</keyname><forenames>Hema C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Emily S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bank</keyname><forenames>Seth R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neikirk</keyname><forenames>Dean P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sanjay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Versatile Large-Area Custom-Feature van der Waals Epitaxy of Topological
  Insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph</categories><comments>26 pages including Supporting Information: 15 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano 11 (7), pp 7457-7467 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.7b03894</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As the focus of applied research in topological insulators (TI) evolves, the
need to synthesize large-area TI films for practical device applications takes
center stage. However, constructing scalable and adaptable processes for
high-quality TI compounds remains a challenge. To this end, a versatile van der
Waals epitaxy (vdWE) process for custom-feature Bismuth Telluro-Sulfide TI
growth and fabrication is presented, achieved through selective-area
fluorination and modification of surface free-energy on mica. The TI features
grow epitaxially in large single-crystal trigonal domains, exhibiting armchair
or zigzag crystalline edges highly oriented with the underlying mica lattice
and only two preferred domain orientations mirrored at $180^\circ$. As-grown
feature thickness dependence on lateral dimensions and denuded zones at
boundaries are observed, as explained by a semi-empirical two-species surface
migration model with robust estimates of growth parameters and elucidating the
role of selective-area surface modification. Topological surface states
contribute up to 60% of device conductance at room-temperature, indicating
excellent electronic quality. High-yield microfabrication and the adaptable
vdWE growth mechanism with readily alterable precursor and substrate
combinations, lend the process versatility to realize crystalline TI synthesis
in arbitrary shapes and arrays suitable for facile integration with processes
ranging from rapid prototyping to scalable manufacturing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04938</id><created>2017-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Barreto</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Mueller</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fixed mesh refinement in the characteristic formulation of General
  Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 papes, 7 figures. To appear in General Relativity and Gravitation</comments><journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravitation 49: 107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2273-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We implement a spatially fixed mesh refinement under spherical symmetry for
the characteristic formulation of General Relativity. The
Courant-Friedrich-Levy (CFL) condition lets us deploy an adaptive resolution in
(retarded-like) time, even for the nonlinear regime. As test cases, we
replicate the main features of the gravitational critical behavior and the
spacetime structure at null infinity using the Bondi mass and the News
function. Additionally, we obtain the global energy conservation for an extreme
situation, i.e. in the threshold of the black hole formation. In principle, the
calibrated code can be used in conjunction with an ADM 3+1 code to confirm the
critical behavior recently reported in the gravitational collapse of a massless
scalar field in an asymptotic anti-de Sitter spacetime. For the scenarios
studied, the fixed mesh refinement offers improved runtime and results
comparable to code without mesh refinement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06405</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohkuwa</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ezawa</keyname><forenames>Yasuo</forenames></author></authors><title>Virtual Black Holes in a Third Quantized Formalism</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>15pages, no figures, Accepted in Annals of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Annals Phys. 384, 105 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we will analyse virtual black holes using the third
quantization formalism. As the virtual black hole model depends critically on
the assumption that the quantum fluctuations dominate the geometry of spacetime
at Planck scale, we will analyse the quantum fluctuations for a black hole
using third quantization. We will demonstrate that these quantum fluctuations
depend on the factor ordering chosen. So, we will show that only certain values
of the factor ordering parameter are consistent with virtual black holes model
of spacetime foam.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06995</id><created>2017-07-21</created><updated>2017-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramakrishna</keyname><forenames>Satish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narayan</keyname><forenames>Onuttom</forenames></author></authors><title>The curious case of the double-slit experiment and a black hole</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This experiment was conceived of as a method of transmitting information from
inside a black hole to the outside. As it turns out, it doesn't work in the
form described (and possibly not in any form), but the way in which Nature
prevents quantum-mechanical effects from transmitting usable information using
quantum correlations is illuminating. In the process, one can learn some
quantum theory, as well as quantum optics.
  The proposed scheme uses a double-slit experiment, in the manner of the
Delayed Choice set up (see Kim et. al.), where the region where the
interference takes place (between &quot;signal&quot; photons) is spatially separated from
the region where the Delayed Choice (with &quot;idler&quot; photons) is made. Indeed,
this Double-Delayed Choice, which is this thought experiment, has one of the
idler photons slip inside the event horizon and serves as the method to attempt
to communicate from the inside to the outside.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08119</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Deng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin-He</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological forecasts from current observations of LIGO</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the simulated gravitational-wave data to explore the evolution of the
universe in light of current observations of the Laser Interferometer
Gravitational-Wave Observatory (LIGO). Taking advantage of state-of-the-art
Markov Chain Monte Carlo technique to constrain the basic cosmological
parameters, the Hubble constant, present matter density parameter and equation
of state of dark energy, we find that LIGO needs about, at least 5-year data
accumulation, namely about 1000 events, to achieve the accuracy comparable to
the Planck result. We also find that, from a new information channel, the
constrained value of the Hubble constant from 1000 simulated events is more
consistent with the direct local observation by Riess et al. than the indirect
global measurement by the Planck Collaboration at the $2\sigma$ confidence
level. The combination of gravitational waves and electromagnetic signals is
very prospective to reveal the underlying physics of the universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08153</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Merkel</keyname><forenames>Philipp M.</forenames><affiliation>ZAH/Heidelberg</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schaefer</keyname><forenames>Bjoern Malte</forenames><affiliation>ZAH/Heidelberg</affiliation></author></authors><title>Parameter constraints from weak lensing tomography of galaxy shapes and
  cosmic microwave background fluctuations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, it has been shown that cross-correlating CMB lensing and 3D cosmic
shear allows to considerably tighten cosmological parameter constraints. We
investigate whether similar improvement can be achieved in a conventional
tomographic setup. We present Fisher parameter forecasts for a Euclid-like
galaxy survey in combination with different ongoing and forthcoming CMB
experiments. In contrast to a fully three-dimensional analysis we find only
marginal improvement. Assuming Planck-like CMB data we show that including the
full covariance of the combined CMB and cosmic shear data improves the dark
energy figure of merit by only three per cent. The marginalized error on the
sum of neutrino masses is reduced at the same level. For a next generation CMB
satellite mission such as Prism the predicted improvement of the dark energy
figure of merit amounts to approximately 25 per cent. Furthermore, we show that
the small improvement is contrasted by an increased bias in the dark energy
parameters when the intrinsic alignment of galaxies is not correctly accounted
for in the full covariance matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08154</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Takenaka</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco-Casado</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>Mikio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitamura</keyname><forenames>Mitsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Masahide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toyoshima</keyname><forenames>Morio</forenames></author></authors><title>Satellite-to-ground quantum communication using a 50-kg-class
  micro-satellite</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures. Published in Nature Photonics (2017),
  http://www.nature.com/nphoton/journal/vaop/ncurrent/full/nphoton.2017.107.html</comments><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2017.107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent rapid growth in the number of satellite-constellation programs for
remote sensing and communications, thanks to the availability of small-size and
low-cost satellites, provides impetus for high capacity laser communication
(lasercom) in space. Quantum communication can enhance the overall performance
of lasercom, and also enables intrinsically hack-proof secure communication
known as Quantum Key Distribution (QKD). Here, we report a quantum
communication experiment between a micro-satellite (48 kg and 50 cm cube) in a
low earth orbit and a ground station with single-photon counters.
Non-orthogonal polarization states were transmitted from the satellite at a
10-MHz repetition rate. On the ground, by post-processing the received quantum
states at an average of 0.14 photons/pulse, clock data recovery and
polarization reference-frame synchronization were successfully done even under
remarkable Doppler shifts. A quantum bit error rate below 5% was measured,
demonstrating the feasibility of quantum communication in a real scenario from
space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08163</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dhurandhar</keyname><forenames>Sanjeev</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krishnan</keyname><forenames>Badri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willis</keyname><forenames>Joshua L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Marginalizing the likelihood function for modeled gravitational wave
  searches</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>26 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Matched filtering is a commonly used technique in gravitational wave searches
for signals from compact binary systems and from rapidly rotating neutron
stars. A common issue in these searches is dealing with four extrinsic
parameters which do not affect the phase evolution of the system: the overall
amplitude, initial phase, and two angles determining the overall orientation of
the system. The F-statistic maximizes the likelihood function analytically over
these parameters, while the B-statistic marginalizes over them. The
B-statistic, while potentially more powerful and capable of incorporating
astrophysical priors, is not as widely used because of the computational
difficulty of performing the marginalization. In this paper we address this
difficulty and show how the marginalization can be done analytically by
combining the four parameters into a set of complex amplitudes. The results of
this paper are applicable to both transient non-precessing binary coalescence
events, and to long lived signals from rapidly rotating neutron stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08165</id><created>2017-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Lian</keyname><forenames>D. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Heisenberg equation for a nonrelativistic particle on a hypersurface:
  from the centripetal force to a curvature induced force</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In classical mechanics, a nonrelativistic particle constrained on an $N-1$
curved hypersurface embedded in $N$ flat space experiences the centripetal
force only. In quantum mechanics, the situation is totally different for the
presence of the geometric potential. We demonstrate that the motion of the
quantum particle is &quot;driven&quot; by not only the the centripetal force, but also a
curvature induced force proportional to the Laplacian of the mean curvature,
which is fundamental in the interface physics, causing curvature driven
interface evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08166</id><created>2017-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Druecke</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parks</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosoi</keyname><forenames>Anette E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of compressibility and aspect ratio on performance of long
  elastic seals</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments show no statistical impact of seal length on the
performance of long elastomeric seals in relatively smooth test fixtures.
Motivated by these results, we analytically and computationally investigate the
combined effects of seal length and compressibility on the maximum differential
pressure a seal can support. We present a Saint-Venant type analytic shear lag
solution for slightly compressible seals with large aspect ratios, which
compares well with nonlinear finite element simulations in regions far from the
ends of the seal. However, at the high- and low-pressure ends, where fracture
is observed experimentally, the analytic solution is in poor agreement with
detailed finite element calculations. Nevertheless, we show that the analytic
solution provides far-field stress measures that correlate, over a range of
aspect ratios and bulk moduli, the calculated energy release rates for the
growth of small cracks at the two ends of the seal. Thus a single finite
element simulation coupled with the analytic solution can be used to determine
tendencies for fracture at the two ends of the seal over a wide range of
geometry and compressibility. Finally, using a hypothetical critical energy
release rate, predictions for whether a crack on the high-pressure end will
begin to grow before or after a crack on the low-pressure end begins to grow
are made using the analytic solution and compared with finite element
simulations for finite deformation, hyperelastic seals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08168</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Anferov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derenchuck</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Ron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreuder</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating proton beam energy spread using Bragg peak measurement</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures; Presented at PTCOG-54 conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  230 MeV proton beam out of a cyclotron was delivered into a Zebra multi
layered IC detector (IBA) calibrated in terms of penetration range in water.
The analysis of the measured Bragg peak determines penetration range in water
which can be subsequently converted into proton beam energy using Range-Energy
tables. We extended this analysis to obtain an estimate of the beam energy
spread out of the cyclotron. Using Monte Carlo simulations we established the
correlation between Bragg peak shape parameters (width at 50% and 80% dose
levels, distal falloff) and penetration range for a monoenergetic proton beam.
Then we studied how this correlation changes when the shape of Bragg peak is
distorted by the beam focusing conditions. We found that small field size or
diverging beam cause Bragg peak deformation predominantly in the proximal
region. The distal shape of the renormalized Bragg peaks stays nearly constant.
This excludes usage of Bragg peak width parameters for energy spread estimates.
The measured Bragg peaks had an average distal falloff of 4.86mm, which
corresponds to an effective range of 35.5cm for a monoenergetic beam. The
32.7cm measured penetration range is 2.8cm less. Passage of a 230 MeV proton
beam through a 2.8cm thick slab of water results in a 0.56 MeV energy spread.
As a final check, we confirmed agreement between shapes of the measured Bragg
peak and one generated by Monte-Carlo code for proton beam with 0.56 MeV energy
spread.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08193</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Appourchaux</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auch&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonucci</keyname><forenames>Ester</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gizon</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacDonald</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hara</keyname><forenames>Hirohisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekii</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moses</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vourlidas</keyname><forenames>Angelos</forenames></author></authors><title>SOLARIS: Solar Sail Investigation of the Sun</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>Macdonald M. (eds) Advances in Solar Sailing, pp 259-268, Feb 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-34907-2_18</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we detail the scientific objectives and outline a strawman
payload of the SOLAR sail Investigation of the Sun (SOLARIS). The science
objectives are to study the 3D structure of the solar magnetic and velocity
field, the variation of total solar irradiance with latitude, and the structure
of the corona. We show how we can meet these science objective using solar-sail
technologies currently under development. We provide a tentative mission
profile considering several trade-off approaches. We also provide a tentative
mass budget breakdown and a perspective for a programmatic implementation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08217</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Verena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frohnapfel</keyname><forenames>Bettina</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Numerical Simulation of Turbulent Channel Flow with Riblets at
  Low Reynolds Number</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this report we briefly summarize the set-up and results for direct
numerical simulations (DNS) of turbulent channel flows with riblets. The DNS
are carried out with OpenFOAM which allows the use of an unstructured mesh. The
present results were presented at the European Drag Reduction and Flow Control
Meeting in 2015.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08221</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Cockburn</keyname><forenames>James D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Subleading Corrections to Hadronic Cross-Sections at High Energies</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Large Hadron Collider (LHC) has provided, and will continue to provide,
data for collisions at the highest energies ever seen in a particle
accelerator. A strong knowledge of the properties of amplitudes for Quantum
Chromodynamics in the High Energy Limit is therefore important to interpret
this data. We study this limit in the context of the High Energy Jets (HEJ)
formalism. This formalism resums terms in the perturbative expansion of the
cross-section that behave like $\alpha_s^n \log
\left(\frac{s}{-t}\right)^{n-1}$, which are enhanced in this limit.
Understanding this region is particularly important in certain key analyses at
the LHC: for example, Higgs-boson-plus-dijet analyses where cuts are applied to
pick out events with a large $m_{jj}$ and in many searches for new physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08228</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Drzazga</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Domagalska</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarosik</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szcz&#x229;&#x15b;niak</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalaga</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characteristics of superconducting state in vanadium: the Eliashberg
  equations and semi-analytical formulas</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconducting state in vanadium characterizes with the critical
temperature ($T_{c}$) equal to $5.3$~K. The Coulomb pseudopotential, calculated
with the help of the Eliashberg equations, possesses anomalously high value
$\mu^{\star}\left(3\Omega_{\rm max}\right)=0.259$ or
$\mu^{\star}\left(10\Omega_{\rm max}\right)=0.368$ ($\Omega_{\rm max}$ denotes
the maximum phonon frequency). Despite the relatively large electron-phonon
coupling constant ($\lambda=0.91$), the quantities such as: the order parameter
($\Delta$), the specific heat ($C$), and the thermodynamic critical field
($H_{c}$) determine the values of the dimensionless ratios not deviating much
from the predictions of the BCS theory: $R_{\Delta}=2\Delta\left(0\right)/
k_{B}T_{c}=3.68$, $R_{C}=\Delta C\left(T_{c}\right)/
C^{N}\left(T_{c}\right)=1.69$, and $R_{H}=T_{c}C^{N}\left(T_{c}\right)/
H^{2}_{c}\left(0\right)=0.171$. This result is associated with the reduction of
the strong-coupling and the retardation effects by the high value of the
Coulomb pseudopotential. It has been shown that the results of the Eliashberg
formalism can be relatively precisely reproduced with the help of the
semi-analytical formulas, if the value of $\mu^{\star}$ is determined on the
basis of the $T_{c}$-Allen-Dynes expression ($\mu^{\star}_{AD}=0.198$). The
attention should be paid to the fact that in the numerical and in the
semi-analytical approach the comparable values of the thermodynamic parameters
for the same $\mu^{\star}$ have been obtained only in the vicinity of the point
$\mu^{\star}=0.1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08231</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Janiszewski</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-relativistic entanglement entropy from Horava gravity</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an analogue of the Ryu-Takayanagi formula for holographic
entanglement entropy applicable to non-relativistic holographic dualities
involving Horava gravity. This is a powerful tool for the duality to have, as
topological order quantified by entanglement entropy is a robust notion in
condensed matter systems. Our derivation makes use of examining on-shell
gravitational actions on conical spacetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08239</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Valishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effect of Electron Lens as Landau Damping Device on Single Particle
  Dynamics in HL-LHC</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><report-no>FERMILAB-TM-2659-AD-APC FERMILAB-TM-2659-AD-APC
  FERMILAB-TM-2659-AD-APC</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An electron lens can serve as an effective mechanism for suppressing coherent
instabilities in high intensity storage rings through nonlinear amplitude
dependent betatron tune shift. However, the addition of a strong localized
nonlinear focusing element to the accelerator lattice may lead to undesired
effects in particle dynamics. We evaluate the effect of a Gaussian electron
lens on single particle motion in HL-LHC using numerical tracking simulations,
and compare the results to the case when an equal tune spread is generated by
conventional octupole magnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08246</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kinsman</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asher</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of Eta Aquariid Outbursts Recorded in the Classic Maya
  Hieroglyphic Script Using Orbital Integrations</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Planet. Space Sci., 144, 112-125 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2017.04.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  No firm evidence has existed that the ancient Maya civilization recorded
specific occurrences of meteor showers or outbursts in the corpus of Maya
hieroglyphic inscriptions. In fact, there has been no evidence of any
pre-Hispanic civilization in the Western Hemisphere recording any observations
of any meteor showers on any specific dates.
  The authors numerically integrated meteoroid-sized particles released by
Comet Halley as early as 1404 BC to identify years within the Maya Classic
Period, AD 250-909, when Eta Aquariid outbursts might have occurred. Outbursts
determined by computer model were then compared to specific events in the Maya
record to see if any correlation existed between the date of the event and the
date of the outburst. The model was validated by successfully explaining
several outbursts around the same epoch in the Chinese record. Some outbursts
observed by the Maya were due to recent revolutions of Comet Halley, within a
few centuries, and some to resonant behavior in older Halley trails, of the
order of a thousand years. Examples were found of several different Jovian mean
motion resonances as well as the 1:3 Saturnian resonance that have controlled
the dynamical evolution of meteoroids in apparently observed outbursts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08247</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Debojyoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorf</keyname><forenames>Mikhail A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorr</keyname><forenames>Milo R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hittinger</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey A. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic Simulation of Collisional Magnetized Plasmas with Semi-Implicit
  Time Integration</title><categories>cs.CE physics.comp-ph</categories><msc-class>65M06, 86A10, 76N15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasmas with varying collisionalities occur in many applications, such as
tokamak edge regions, where the flows are characterized by significant
variations in density and temperature. While a kinetic model is necessary for
weakly-collisional high-temperature plasmas, high collisionality in colder
regions render the equations numerically stiff due to disparate time scales. In
this paper, we propose an implicit-explicit algorithm for such cases, where the
collisional term is integrated implicitly in time, while the advective term is
integrated explicitly in time, thus allowing time step sizes that are
comparable to the advective time scales. This partitioning results in a more
efficient algorithm than those using explicit time integrators, where the time
step sizes are constrained by the stiff collisional time scales. We implement
semi-implicit additive Runge-Kutta methods in COGENT, a finite-volume
gyrokinetic code for mapped, multiblock grids and test the accuracy,
convergence, and computational cost of these semi-implicit methods for test
cases with highly-collisional plasmas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08248</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Bitan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muralidharan</keyname><forenames>Bhaskaran</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric cooling and thermal switching via the non-linear phonon
  Peltier effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigating the non-linear transport regime in a quantum dot heat engine
described by the Anderson-Holstein model, it is shown that a finite
electron-phonon interaction leads to a charge induced phonon generation that
stimulates a phonon current even in the absence of a thermal gradient. This
gives rise to the non-linear phonon Peltier effect which shows a non-trivial
dependence on varying the electron-phonon interaction. Utilizing the reversal
of phonon currents via charge induced phonon accumulation, we demonstrate that
the heat engine surprisingly can be cooled when coupled to a hot reservoir. In
further exploring possibilities that can arise from this effect, we propose a
charge-induced phonon switching mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08251</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kova&#x10d;evi&#x107;-Doj&#x10d;inovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Jelena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mar&#x10d;eta-Mandi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Sladjana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Luka &#x10c;.</forenames></author></authors><title>Black Hole Mass Estimation in Type 1 AGN: H$\beta$ vs. Mg II lines and
  the role of Balmer continuum</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, Accepted for publication in Frontiers in
  Astronomy and Space Sciences</comments><journal-ref>Front. Astron. Space Sci. 4:7 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3389/fspas.2017.00007</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Here we investigate the H$\beta$ and Mg II spectral line parameters used for
the black hole mass (M$_{\rm BH}$) estimation for a sample of Type 1 Active
Galactic Nuclei (AGN) spectra selected from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS)
database. We have analyzed and compared the virialization of the H$\beta$ and
Mg II emission lines, and found that the H$\beta$ line is more confident virial
estimator than Mg II. We have investigated the influence of the Balmer
continuum emission to the M$_{\rm BH}$ estimation from the UV parameters, and
found that the Balmer continuum emission can contribute to the overestimation
of the M$_{\rm BH}$ on average for ~ 5% (up to 10%).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08252</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Colman</keyname><forenames>Ewan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spies</keyname><forenames>Kristen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bansal</keyname><forenames>Shweta</forenames></author></authors><title>The reachability of contagion in temporal contact networks: how disease
  latency can exploit the rhythm of human behavior</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>9 Pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The symptoms of many infectious diseases influence their host to withdraw
from social activity limiting their own potential to spread. Successful
transmission therefore requires the onset of infectiousness to coincide with a
time when its host is socially active. Since social activity and infectiousness
are both temporal phenomena, we hypothesize that diseases are most pervasive
when these two processes are synchronized. We consider disease dynamics that
incorporate a behavioral response that effectively shortens the infectious
period of the disease. We apply this model to data collected from face-to-face
social interactions and look specifically at how the duration of the latent
period effects the reachability of the disease. We then simulate the spread of
the model disease on the network to test the robustness of our results.
Diseases with latent periods that synchronize with the temporal social behavior
of people, i.e. latent periods of 24 hours or 7 days, correspond to peaks in
the number of individuals who are potentially at risk of becoming infected. The
effect of this synchronization is present for a range of disease models with
realistic parameters. The relationship between the latent period of an
infectious disease and its pervasiveness is non-linear and depends strongly on
the social context in which the disease is spreading.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08304</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakkeeran</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutz</keyname><forenames>J. Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jinhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xianting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wai</keyname><forenames>P. K. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Eckhaus Instability in the Fourier-Domain Mode Locked Fiber Laser Cavity</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High frequency fluctuation in the optical signal generated in Fourier-Domain
Mode Locked fiber laser (FDML-FL), which is the major problem and degrades the
laser performance, is not yet fully analyzed or studied. The basic theory which
is causing this high frequency fluctuation is required to clearly understand
its dynamics and to control it for various applications. In this letter, by
analyzing the signal and system dynamics of FDML-FL, we theoretically
demonstrate that the high frequency fluctuation is induced by the intrinsic
instability of frequency offset of the signal in cavity with nonlinear gain and
spectral filter. Unlike the instabilities observed in other laser cavities this
instability is very unique to FDML-FL as the central frequency of the optical
signal continuously shifts away from the center frequency of the filter due to
the effects like dispersion and/or nonlinearity. This instability is none other
than the Eckhaus instability reported and well studied in fluid dynamics
governed by real Ginzburg-Landau equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08324</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiri</keyname><forenames>Daryoush</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio Study of Nonlinear Optical Susceptibilities in Silicon
  Nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 tables. 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using Time Independent Density Functional Theory (TIDFT) it is shown that the
2nd order optical susceptibilities of narrow (1nm-2nm) Silicon Nanowires (SiNW)
are enhanced due to surface termination. The value of $\chi^{(2)}$ is enhanced
up to 200 pm/V which is promising a strong Second Harmonic Generation (SHG) in
SiNWs. For [100], [110] and [111] SiNWs, yxx component of $\chi^{(2)}$ tensor
is 81, 225 and 81 pm/V, respectively. These are in close agreement with
$\chi^{(2)}$ values reported for strained silicon waveguides in experiments.
The 3rd order susceptibility, $\chi^{(3)}$, is within the range of
(0.1-12)x$10^{-18} \frac{m^{2}}{V^{2}}$ which is close to the experimental
values of bulk silicon (0.1-0.2)x$10^{-18} \frac{m^{2}}{V^{2}}$ for [110] and
[100] SiNWs and it is 100 times better for [111] SiNW. This study suggests
possibilities of enhancing SHG in SiNWs through symmetry breaking via strain
and surface termination/reconstruction as well as suitability of this DFT-based
method in predicting nonlinear optical susceptibilities of nano structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08333</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;ler</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barthel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehling</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karolak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangiovanni</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Realistic theory of electronic correlations in nanoscopic systems</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>tutorial review submitted to EPJ-ST (scientific report of research
  unit FOR 1346); 14 figures, 26 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Special Topics 226, 2615 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2017-70049-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanostructures with open shell transition metal or molecular constituents
host often strong electronic correlations and are highly sensitive to atomistic
material details. This tutorial review discusses method developments and
applications of theoretical approaches for the realistic description of the
electronic and magnetic properties of nanostructures with correlated electrons.
First, the implementation of a flexible interface between density functional
theory and a variant of dynamical mean field theory (DMFT) highly suitable for
the simulation of complex correlated structures is explained and illustrated.
On the DMFT side, this interface is largely based on recent developments of
quantum Monte Carlo and exact diagonalization techniques allowing for efficient
descriptions of general four fermion Coulomb interactions, reduced symmetries
and spin-orbit coupling, which are explained here. With the examples of the Cr
(001) surfaces, magnetic adatoms, and molecular systems it is shown how the
interplay of Hubbard U and Hund's J determines charge and spin fluctuations and
how these interactions drive different sorts of correlation effects in
nanosystems. Non-local interactions and correlations present a particular
challenge for the theory of low dimensional systems. We present our method
developments addressing these two challenges, i.e., advancements of the
dynamical vertex approximation and a combination of the constrained random
phase approximation with continuum medium theories. We demonstrate how
non-local interaction and correlation phenomena are controlled not only by
dimensionality but also by coupling to the environment which is typically
important for determining the physics of nanosystems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08343</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08343</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nordmark</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varkonyi</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Champneys</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics beyond dynamic jam; unfolding the Painlev\'e paradox
  singularity</title><categories>math.DS physics.class-ph</categories><msc-class>70F40, 37N05, 70H45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper analyses in detail the dynamics in a neighbourhood of a
G\'enot-Brogliato point, colloquially termed the G-spot, which physically
represents so-called dynamic jam in rigid body mechanics with unilateral
contact and Coulomb friction. Such singular points arise in planar rigid body
problems with slipping point contacts at the intersection between the
conditions for onset of lift-off and for the Painlev\'e paradox. The G-spot can
be approached in finite time by an open set of initial conditions in a general
class of problems. The key question addressed is what happens next. In
principle trajectories could, at least instantaneously, lift off, continue in
slip, or undergo a so-called impact without collision. Such impacts are
non-local in momentum space and depend on properties evaluated away from the
G-spot. The results are illustrated on a particular physical example, namely
the a frictional impact oscillator first studied by Leine et al.
  The answer is obtained via an analysis that involves a consistent contact
regularisation with a stiffness proportional to $1/\varepsilon^2$. Taking a
singular limit as $\varepsilon \to 0$, one finds an inner and an outer
asymptotic zone in the neighbourhood of the G-spot. Two distinct cases are
found according to whether the contact force becomes infinite or remains finite
as the G-spot is approached. In the former case it is argued that there can be
no such canards and so an impact without collision must occur. In the latter
case, the canard trajectory acts as a dividing surface between trajectories
that momentarily lift off and those that do not before taking the impact. The
orientation of the initial condition set leading to each eventuality is shown
to change each time a certain positive parameter $\beta$ passes through an
integer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08351</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nakas</keyname><forenames>Theodoros</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for Localized Black-Hole solutions in Brane-World models</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of this thesis, the question that is going to occupy us, is
the existence of a 5-dimensional braneworld black hole solution that is
localized close to the 3-brane and has the properties of a regular
4-dimensional one. For this purpose, the 4-dimensional part of the complete
5-dimensional spacetime is considered to be a generalized Vaidya metric, in the
context of which, the mass parameter $m$ is allowed to vary with respect to
time, while it is also allowed to have both $y$ and $r$ dependence. The
dependence on the $r$-coordinate essentially means that our black hole solution
can deviate from the conventional Schwarzschild solution. Additionally, the
dependence on the $y$-coordinate leads to a non-trivial profile of the black
hole along the extra dimension. In order to justify physically the existence of
such general mass parameter, we consider the case of two scalar fields
$\phi(v,r,y)$, $\chi(v,r,y)$ which interact with each other and they are also
non-minimally coupled to gravity via a general coupling function
$f(\phi,\chi)$. In all the cases that were investigated in the context of this
particular scenario, the result for the existence of a viable 5-dimensional
localized black hole solution was negative, a result that causes concern about
the compatibility of brane-world models with basic predictions of General
Theory of Relativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08382</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Verhelst</keyname><forenames>Nick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichmoukhamedov</keyname><forenames>Timour</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tempere</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author></authors><title>Radial vortex core oscillations in Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>EPJ-ST 226, 2829-2836 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60374-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dilute ultracold quantum gases form an ideal and highly tunable system in
which superuidity can be studied. Recently quantum turbulence in Bose-Einstein
condensates was reported [PRL 103, 045310 (2009)], opening up a new
experimental system that can be used to study quantum turbulence. A novel
feature of this system is that vortex cores now have a finite size. This means
that the vortices are no longer one dimensional features in the condensate, but
that the radial behaviour and excitations might also play an important role in
the study of quantum turbulence in Bose-Einstein condensates. In this paper we
investigate these radial modes using a simplified variational model for the
vortex core. This study results in the frequencies of the radial modes, which
can be compared with the frequencies of the thoroughly studied Kelvin modes.
From this comparison we find that the lowest (l=0) radial mode has a frequency
in the same order of magnitude as the Kelvin modes. However the radial modes
still have a larger energy than the Kelvin modes, meaning that the Kelvin modes
will still constitute the preferred channel for energy decay in quantum
turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08406</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Maryenko</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCollam</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozuka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeitler</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transition from a composite fermion liquid to a Wigner solid in
  the lowest Landau level of ZnO</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, Supplementary Information available upon request</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interactions between the constituents of a condensed matter system can drive
it through a plethora of different phases due to many-body effects. A prominent
platform for this type of behavior is a two-dimensional electron system in a
magnetic field, which evolves intricately through various gaseous, liquid and
solids phases governed by Coulomb interaction. Here we report on the
experimental observation of a phase transition between the Laughlin liquid of
composite fermions and the adjacent insulating phase of a magnetic
field-induced Wigner solid. The experiments are performed in the lowest Landau
level of a MgZnO/ZnO two-dimensional electron system with attributes of both a
liquid and a solid. An in-plane magnetic field component applied on top of the
perpendicular magnetic field extends the Wigner phase further into the liquid
phase region. Our observations indicate the direct competition between a Wigner
solid and a Laughlin liquid both formed by composite particles rather than bare
electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08424</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Krivoruchenko</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superfluid neutron matter in the s-channel exchange nucleon-nucleon
  interaction models</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages, REVTeX. Presented as a part of invited talks at Conference
  on Isospin, Structure, Reactions and Energy of Symmetry (ISTROS), Casta -
  Papiernicka, Casta, Slovakia, May 14 - 19, 2017 and Workshop on Spectroscopy
  and Reactions of Exotic Nuclei (Huzhou-CUSTIPEN), Huzhou, China, July 3 - 9,
  2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superfluid pairing gap of neutron matter is calculated in the framework
of Quark Compound Bag model with nucleon-nucleon interactions generated by the
s-channel exchange of Jaffe-Low primitives (6-quark states).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08425</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Trambak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cleymans</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-extensive Fokker-Planck transport coefficients of heavy quarks</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In presence of the non-ideal plasma effects, Heavy Quarks (HQs) carry out non
linear random walk inside Quark-Gluon Plasma (QGP) and in the small momentum
transfer limit, the evolution of the HQ distribution is dictated by the Non
Linear Fokker-Planck Equation (NLFPE). Using the NLFPE, we calculate the
transport coefficients (drag and diffusion) of heavy quarks travelling through
QGP. We observe substantial modification in the momentum and temperature
variation of the transport coefficients; and this will modify the physical
picture we are having about the transport of heavy quarks inside QGP, and
hence, about the characterisation of the plasma.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08428</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Grytsay</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musatenko</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The structure of a chaos of strange attractors within a mathematical
  model of the metabolism of a cell</title><categories>nlin.CD q-bio.CB</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ukrainian journal of physics. - 2013. - V. 58, n 7. - pp. 677-686</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work continues the study of the earlier constructed mathematical model
of the metabolic process running in a cell.
  We will consider auto-oscillations arising on the level of enzyme-substrate
interactions in the nutrient and respiratory chains, which leads to the
self-organization in autocatalysis of the integral metabolic process in cells.
The auto-oscillations organize themselves in the total metabolic process of
cells at autocatalysis.
  The behavior of the phase-parametric characteristic under the high
dissipation of a kinetic membrane potentialis analyzed. All possible
oscillatory modes of the system and the scenario of formation and destruction
of regular and strange attractors are studied. The bifurcations of the
transitions &quot;order-chaos&quot;, &quot;chaos-order&quot;, &quot;chaos-chaos&quot; and &quot;order-order&quot; are
calculated. The total spectra of Lyapunov indices and the divergences for all
types of attractors on a part of the phase-parametric characteristic under
consideration are determined. For various types of strange attractors, their
Lyapunov dimensions, KS-entropies, and &quot;predictability horizons&quot; are
calculated. Some conclusions about the structure of the chaos of strange
attractors and its influence on the stability of the metabolic process in a
cell are drawn.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08434</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amans</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dujardin</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ledoux</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allouche</keyname><forenames>Abdul-Rahman</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomistic Mechanisms for the Nucleation of Aluminium Oxide Nanoparticles</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.atm-clus physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. A, 2015, 119, 33, 8944</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpca.5b05829</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A predictive model for nanoparticle nucleation has not yet been successfully
achieved. Classical nucleation theory fails because the atomistic nature of the
seed has to be considered since geometrical structure as well as stoichiometry
do not always match the bulk values. We present a fully microscopic approach
based on a first-principle study of aluminium oxide clusters. We have
calculated stable structures of AlxOy} and their associated thermodynamic
properties. From these data, the chemical composition of a gas composed of
aluminium and oxygen atoms can be calculated as a function of temperature,
pressure, and aluminium to oxygen ratio. We demonstrate the accuracy of this
approach in reproducing experimental results obtained with time resolved
spectroscopy of a laser induced plasma from an Al2O3} target. We thus extended
the calculation to lower temperatures, i.e. longer time scales, to propose a
scenario of composition gas evolution leading to the first alumina seeds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08441</id><created>2017-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mchedlov-Petrosyan</keyname><forenames>Petro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davydov</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact travelling wave solutions for the Penrose-Fife Phase Field Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Penrose-Fife Phase Field Model is now a well-established model in the
theory of phase transitions. In the course of study of this model both the
rigorous mathematical results and approximate solutions were obtained. However,
to the best of our knowledge, no exact solutions were given in the literature.
In the present paper we give exact traveling wave solutions for this system.
While the functional form of the solutions is rather simple, the dependence of
solutions on the parameters of the model is quite complicated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08442</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishi</keyname><forenames>Binaya K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk viscous cosmological model in Brans Dicke theory with new form of
  time varying deceleration parameter</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 24 figures, Accepted in Advances in high energy physics,
  2017</comments><msc-class>83F05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we have presented FRW cosmological model in the framework of
Brans-Dicke theory. This paper deals with a new proposed form of deceleration
parameter and cosmological constant. The effect of bulk viscosity is also
studied in the presence of modified Chaplygin gas equation of state. Further,
we have discussed the physical behaviors of the models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08444</id><created>2017-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Adrian J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Circular Polarization and Coherent Backscattering</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the work of Mishchenko et al. (2000) regarding the exact results of
the polarization effect, using the theory of Amic et al. (1997) to derive a
model prediction for the polarization coherent opposition effect at small
angles. Our extension is to assess the effect of circular polarized light, thus
completing exact derivation of the full M\&quot;uller matrix for the semi infinite
slab of Rayleigh sized particles. We find the circular polarization peak is
narrower than the coherent backscattering intensity peak, and weaker in
intensity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08452</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Borcea</keyname><forenames>Liliana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnier</keyname><forenames>Josselin</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser beam imaging from the speckle pattern of the off-axis scattered
  intensity</title><categories>physics.data-an math.AP physics.optics</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the inverse problem of localization (imaging) of a laser beam from
measurements of the intensity of light scattered off-axis by a Poisson cloud of
small particles. Starting from the wave equation, we analyze the microscopic
coherence of the scattered intensity and show that it is possible to determine
the laser beam from the speckle pattern captured by a group of CCD cameras. Two
groups of cameras are sufficient when the particles are either small or large
with respect to the wavelength. For general particle sizes the accuracy of the
laser localization with two groups of cameras is subject to knowing the
scattering properties of the cloud. However, three or more groups of cameras
allow accurate localization that is robust to uncertainty of the type, size,
shape and concentration of the particles in the cloud. We introduce a novel
laser beam localization algorithm and give some numerical illustrations in a
regime relevant to the application of imaging high energy lasers in a maritime
atmosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08455</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bisio</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Ariano</keyname><forenames>Giacomo Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perinotti</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Walks, Weyl equation and the Lorentz group</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, Volume 47, Issue 8, pp 1065-1076 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-017-0086-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum cellular automata and quantum walks provide a framework for the
foundations of quantum field theory, since the equations of motion of free
relativistic quantum fields can be derived as the small wave-vector limit of
quantum automata and walks starting from very general principles. The intrinsic
discreteness of this framework is reconciled with the continuous Lorentz
symmetry by reformulating the notion of inertial reference frame in terms of
the constants of motion of the quantum walk dynamics. In particular, among the
symmetries of the quantum walk which recovers the Weyl equation--the so called
Weyl walk--one finds a non linear realisation of the Poincar\'e group, which
recovers the usual linear representation in the small wave-vector limit. In
this paper we characterise the full symmetry group of the Weyl walk which is
shown to be a non linear realization of a group which is the semidirect product
of the Poincar\'e group and the group of dilations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08457</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sihi</keyname><forenames>Antik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying the effect of different exchange correlation functionals on the
  structural and electronic properties of a half-Heusler NaAuS compound</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretically, NaAuS is predicted as topological insulator, while no detail
electronic structure study has been done for this compound. Here, we report the
structural and electronic properties of NaAuS by using LDA, PBEsol, PBE and
revPBE exchange correlation functionals. The calculated values of equilibrium
lattice constant for LDA, PBEsol, PBE and revPBE exchange correlation
functionals are found to be $\sim$6.128 {\AA}, $\sim$6.219 {\AA}, $\sim$6.353
{\AA} and $\sim$6.442 {\AA}, respectively. The bulk modulus predicted by LDA,
PBEsol, PBE and revPBE exchange correlation functionals is $\sim$66.6,
$\sim$56.4, $\sim$46.5 and $\sim$39.3 GPa, respectively. Hence, the order of
calculated values of bulk modulus is consistent with the order of calculated
values of equilibrium lattice parameters for these exchange correlation
functionals. The spread of total density of states below the Fermi level
decreases as the exchange correlation functional changes from LDA to PBEsol to
PBE to revPBE, which is also found to be consistent with the order of bulk
modulus for these exchange correlation functionals. In presence of spin-orbit
coupling, a direct band gap is observed in NaAuS compound, which is found to be
$\sim$0.26, $\sim$0.25, $\sim$0.24 and $\sim$0.23 eV for LDA, PBEsol, PBE and
revPBE exchange correlation functionals, respectively. Here, NaAuS is found to
be topological insulator as it shows band inversion at $\Gamma$ point. The
calculated values of band inversion strength for LDA (PBEsol) and PBE (revPBE)
exchange correlation functionals are $\sim$1.58 eV ($\sim$1.57 eV) and
$\sim$1.50 eV ($\sim$1.47 eV), respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08467</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Hammerschmidt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiser</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>X. Garcia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zschiedrich</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodermann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying parameter uncertainties in optical scatterometry using
  Bayesian inversion</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Proceedings article, SPIE conference &quot;Modeling Aspects in Optical
  Metrology VI&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 10330 (2017) 1033004</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2270596</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Newton-like method to solve inverse problems and to quantify
parameter uncertainties. We apply the method to parameter reconstruction in
optical scatterometry, where we take into account a priori information and
measurement uncertainties using a Bayesian approach. Further, we discuss the
influence of numerical accuracy on the reconstruction result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08473</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaggero</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>GRAPPA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grasso</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>INFN and Universit&#xe1; Pisa</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>INFN and Universit&#xe1; Pisa</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Taoso</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>IFT</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Urbano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>CERN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ventura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>INFN and Universit&#xe1; Pisa</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hard Cosmic Ray Sea in the Galactic Center: a consistent interpretation
  of H.E.S.S. and Fermi-LAT $\gamma$-ray data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Oral contribution to the International Cosmic Ray Conference (ICRC
  2017), 12-20 July 2017, Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel interpretation of the gamma-ray diffuse emission measured
by H.E.S.S. in the Galactic Center (GC) region and the Galactic ridge. Our
starting base is an updated analysis of PASS8 Fermi-LAT data, which allows to
extend down to few GeV the spectra measured by H.E.S.S. and to infer the
primary CR radial distribution above 100 GeV. We compare those results with a
CR transport model assuming a harder scaling of the diffusion coefficient with
rigidity in the inner Galaxy. Such a behavior reproduces the radial dependence
of the CR spectral index recently inferred from Fermi-LAT measurements in the
inner GP. We find that, in this scenario, the bulk of the Galactic ridge
emission can be naturally explained by the interaction of the diffuse,
steady-state Galactic CR sea interacting with the gas present in the Central
molecular zone. The evidence of a GC PeVatron is significantly weaker than that
inferred adopting a conventional (softer) CR sea.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08478</id><created>2017-07-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Slutsker</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsman</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaidar</keyname><forenames>Mr. Avner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Even-Tzur</keyname><forenames>Dr. Gilad</forenames></author></authors><title>GNSS Differential Interferometer</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Baseline azimuth calculation using GPS carrier phase data can be achieved in
a classic way by using two or more geodetic synchronized GPS receivers. Such
system includes dedicated expensive components and thus is not applicable to
many uses. The development of low cost GPS receivers have come to a point where
good quality carrier phase measurements are available and double differencing
systems utilizing these receivers have proven feasible. Inexpensive receivers
like this, combined with attitude determination algorithm, can make accurate
attitude determination using GPS accessible to everyone.
  Our project consisted of developing a low cost attitude determination system
utilizing 2 Fastrax off-the-shelf receivers. Phase and code data from the
receivers is processed, filtered and used for attitude determination using
double-difference algorithm. Possible applications for such systems are for
example: * Civilian - search and rescue equipment * Industrial - low cost
geodetic measurement * Military - inexpensive weapon guidance system
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08479</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>P. -I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>X. Garcia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rockstuhl</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Global optimization of complex optical structures using Baysian
  optimization based on Gaussian processes</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Proceedings article, SPIE conference &quot;Digital Optical Technologies
  2017&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 10335 (2017) 103350O</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2270609</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical simulation of complex optical structures enables their optimization
with respect to specific objectives. Often, optimization is done by multiple
successive parameter scans, which are time consuming and computationally
expensive. We employ here Bayesian optimization with Gaussian processes in
order to automatize and speed up the optimization process. As a toy example, we
demonstrate optimization of the shape of a free-form reflective meta surface
such that it diffracts light into a specific diffraction order. For this
example, we compare the performance of six different Bayesian optimization
approaches with various acquisition functions and various kernels of the
Gaussian process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08508</id><created>2017-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Sbitnev</keyname><forenames>Valeriy I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamics of Superfluid Quantum Space: de Broglie interpretation of
  the quantum mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, Quantum Studies: Mathematics and Foundations,
  2017, available on URL: http://rdcu.be/un41</comments><doi>10.1007/s40509-017-0116-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ubiquitous ether coming from the ancient times up to middle of the twenty
century is replaced by a superfluid quantum space. It represents by itself a
Bose-Einstein condensate consisting of enormous amount of virtual
particle-antiparticle pairs emerging and disappearing in an infinitely ongoing
dance. Flowing of this medium in the non-relativistic limit is described by the
modified Navier-Stokes equation along with the continuity equation. The first
equation admits the splitting on to two coupled equations. They are the quantum
Hamilton-Jacobi equation and the equation for vorticity. The quantum
Hamilton-Jacoby equation paired with the continuity equation can be reduced to
the \Schrodinger equation. These two equations representing the kernel of the
Bohmian mechanics give finding bundle of the Bohmian trajectories. Whereas the
vorticity equation gives solutions for vortices moving along such trajectories.
As the result we come to the de Broglie's interpretation of quantum mechanics
according to which there is a pilot-wave guiding the particle (in our case it
is a vortex clot) from a source up to its detection along an optimal path that
is the Bohmian trajectory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08527</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Andre M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rap&#x10d;an</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsallis</keyname><forenames>Constantino</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement can preserve the compact nature of the phase-space
  occupancy</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the one-dimensional transverse-field spin-1/2 Ising ferromagnet at
its critical point. We consider an $L$-sized subsystem of a $N$-sized ring, and
trace over the states of $(N-L)$ spins, with $N\to\infty$. The full $N$-system
is in a pure state, but the $L$-system is in a statistical mixture. As well
known, for $L &gt;&gt;1$, the Boltzmann-Gibbs-von Neumann entropy violates
thermodynamical extensivity, namely $S_{BG}(L) \propto \log L$, whereas the
nonadditive entropy $S_q$ is extensive for $q=q_c=\sqrt{37}-6 $, namely
$S_{q_c}(L) \propto L$. When this problem is expressed in terms of independent
fermions, we show that the usual thermostatistical sums emerging within
Fermi-Dirac statistics can, for $L&gt;&gt;1$, be indistinctively taken up to $L$
terms or up to $\log L$ terms. This is interpreted as a compact occupancy of
phase-space of the $L$-system, hence standard BG quantities with an effective
length $V \equiv \log L$ are appropriate and are explicitly calculated. In
other words, the calculations are to be done in a phase-space whose effective
dimension is $2^{\log L}$ instead of $2^L$. The whole scenario is strongly
reminiscent of a usual phase transition of a spin-1/2 $d$-dimensional system,
where the phase-space dimension is $2^{L^d}$ in the disordered phase, and
effectively $2^{L^d/2}$ in the ordered one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08557</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shindnes</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karve</keyname><forenames>Vaibhav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yager</keyname><forenames>Derrek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Work</keyname><forenames>Daniel B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sowers</keyname><forenames>Richard B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Congestion Barcodes: Exploring the Topology of Urban Congestion Using
  Persistent Homology</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DS math.AT physics.data-an</categories><comments>9 pages, 15 figures, Accepted to IEEE 20th International Conference
  on Intelligent Transportation Systems 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work presents a new method to quantify connectivity in transportation
networks. Inspired by the field of topological data analysis, we propose a
novel approach to explore the robustness of road network connectivity in the
presence of congestion on the roadway. The robustness of the pattern is
summarized in a congestion barcode, which can be constructed directly from
traffic datasets commonly used for navigation. As an initial demonstration, we
illustrate the main technique on a publicly available traffic dataset in a
neighborhood in New York City.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
