<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:13:26Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-19" from="2016-09-19" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0905.4054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0905.4054</id><created>2009-05-25</created><updated>2009-05-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lorenzoni</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedroni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raimondo</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>$F$-manifolds and integrable systems of hydrodynamic type</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>LaTeX, 21 pages; Sections 5 and 6 completely rewritten</comments><journal-ref>Archivum Mathematicum, vol. 47 (2011), issue 3, pp. 163-180</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the role of Hertling-Manin condition on the structure
constants of an associative commutative algebra in the theory of integrable
systems of hydrodynamic type. In such a framework we introduce the notion of
F-manifold with compatible connection generalizing a structure introduced by
Manin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1111.6098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1111.6098</id><created>2011-11-25</created><updated>2012-03-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalinowski</keyname><forenames>Artur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazana</keyname><forenames>Malgorzata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roszkowski</keyname><forenames>Leszek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Yue-Lin Sming</forenames></author></authors><title>Bayesian Implications of Current LHC and XENON100 Search Limits for the
  Constrained MSSM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Accepted by PRD. Added discussions on prior dependence and the
  p-value. Main conclusions unchanged. 21 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D85 (2012) 075012</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.85.075012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CMS Collaboration has released the results of its search for
supersymmetry, by applying an alphaT method to 1.1/fb of data at 7 TeV. The
null result excludes (at 95% CL) a low-mass region of the Constrained MSSM's
parameter space that was previously favored by other experiments. Additionally,
the negative result of the XENON100 dark matter search has excluded (at 90% CL)
values of the spin-independent scattering cross sections sigma^SI_p as low as
10^-8 pb. We incorporate these improved experimental constraints into a global
Bayesian fit of the Constrained MSSM by constructing approximate likelihood
functions. In the case of the alphaT limit, we simulate detector efficiency for
the CMS alphaT 1.1/fb and validate our method against the official 95% CL
contour. We identify the 68% and 95% credible posterior regions of the CMSSM
parameters, and also find the best-fit point. We find that the credible regions
change considerably once a likelihood from alphaT is included, in particular
the narrow light Higgs resonance region becomes excluded, but the focus
point/horizontal branch region remains allowed at the 1sigma level. Adding the
limit from XENON100 has a weaker additional effect, in part due to large
uncertainties in evaluating sigma^SI_p, which we include in a conservative way,
although we find that it reduces the posterior probability of the focus point
region to the 2sigma level. The new regions of high posterior favor squarks
lighter than the gluino and all but one Higgs bosons heavy. The dark matter
neutralino mass is found in the range 250 GeV &lt;~ m_Chi1 &lt;~ 343 GeV (at 1sigma)
while, as the result of improved limits from the LHC, the favored range of
sigma^SI_p is pushed down to values below 10^{-9} pb. We highlight tension
between (g-2)_mu and BR(b-&gt;sg), which is exacerbated by including the alphaT
limit; each constraint favors a different region of the CMSSM's mass
parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1309.2308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1309.2308</id><created>2013-09-09</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eisert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Worm</keyname><forenames>M. van den</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manmana</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kastner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Breakdown of quasilocality in long-range quantum lattice models</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures; Fixed another typo in equations (3) and (4) and
  added a footnote</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 111, 260401 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.111.260401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the non-equilibrium dynamics of correlations in quantum lattice
models in the presence of long-range interactions decaying asymptotically as a
power law. For exponents larger than the lattice dimensionality, a
Lieb-Robinson-type bound effectively restricts the spreading of correlations to
a causal region, but allows supersonic propagation. We show that this decay is
not only sufficient but also necessary. Using tools of quantum metrology, for
any exponents smaller than the lattice dimension, we construct Hamiltonians
giving rise to quantum channels with capacities not restricted to a causal
region. An analytical analysis of long-range Ising models illustrates the
disappearance of the causal region and the creation of correlations becoming
distance-independent. Numerical results obtained using matrix product state
methods for the XXZ spin chain reveal the presence of a sound cone for large
exponents, and supersonic propagation for small ones. In all models we analyzed
the fast spreading of correlations follows a power law, but not the exponential
increase of the long-range Lieb-Robinson bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.2090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.2090</id><created>2013-10-08</created><updated>2013-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cividini</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilhorst</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Appert-Rolland</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact domain wall theory for deterministic TASEP with parallel update</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 47 (2014) 222001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/47/22/222001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Domain wall theory (DWT) has proved to be a powerful tool for the analysis of
one-dimensional transport processes. A simple version of it was found very
accurate for the Totally Asymmetric Simple Exclusion Process (TASEP) with
random sequential update. However, a general implementation of DWT is still
missing in the case of updates with less fluctuations, which are often more
relevant for applications. Here we develop an exact DWT for TASEP with parallel
update and deterministic (p=1) bulk motion. Remarkably, the dynamics of this
system can be described by the motion of a domain wall not only on the
coarse-grained level but also exactly on the microscopic scale for arbitrary
system size. All properties of this TASEP, time-dependent and stationary, are
shown to follow from the solution of a bivariate master equation whose
variables are not only the position but also the velocity of the domain wall.
In the continuum limit this exactly soluble model then allows us to perform a
first principle derivation of a Fokker-Planck equation for the position of the
wall. The diffusion constant appearing in this equation differs from the one
obtained with the traditional `simple' DWT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.0152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.0152</id><created>2013-12-31</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haber</keyname><forenames>Howard E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Higgs data and the Decoupling Limit</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures. Talk given at the &quot;Toyama International Workshop
  on Higgs as a Probe of New Physics 2013&quot;, 13-16 February 2013, Toyama, Japan
  (v2: two typographical errors in Table I have been corrected)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Higgs data analyzed by the ATLAS and CMS Collaborations suggest that the
scalar state discovered in 2012 is a Standard Model (SM)--like Higgs boson.
Nevertheless, there is still significant room for Higgs physics beyond the
Standard Model. Many approaches to electroweak symmetry breaking possess a
decoupling limit in which the properties of the lightest CP-even Higgs scalar
approach those of the SM Higgs boson. In some cases, an apparent SM-like Higgs
signal can also arise in a regime that may not be governed by the decoupling
limit. One such scenario can be realized if the observed Higgs signal is a
result of two unresolved nearly-mass-degenerate scalar states. The general
two-Higgs doublet model provides a useful framework for studying the decoupling
limit and possible departures from SM-like Higgs behavior. The implications for
current and future Higgs data are briefly considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.5419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.5419</id><created>2014-02-21</created><updated>2014-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raidal</keyname><forenames>Martti</forenames></author></authors><title>Prospects for constrained supersymmetry at $\sqrt{s}=33$ TeV and
  $\sqrt{s}=100$ TeV proton-proton super-colliders</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures. Matches version published in Eur.Phys.J. C.
  Results and conclusions unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C74 (2014) 2948</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-014-2948-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discussions are underway for a high-energy proton-proton collider. Two
preliminary ideas are the $\sqrt{s}=33$ TeV HE-LHC and the $\sqrt{s}=100$ TeV
VLHC. With Bayesian statistics, we calculate the probabilities that the LHC,
HE-LHC and VLHC discover SUSY in the future, assuming that nature is described
by the CMSSM and given the experimental data from the LHC, LUX and Planck. We
find that the LHC with $300$/fb at $\sqrt{s}=14$ TeV has a $15$-$75%$
probability of discovering SUSY. Should that run fail to discover SUSY, the
probability of discovering SUSY with $3000$/fb is merely $1$-$10%$. Were SUSY
to remain undetected at the LHC, the HE-LHC would have a $35$-$85%$ probability
of discovering SUSY with $3000$/fb. The VLHC, on the other hand, ought to be
definitive; the probability of it discovering SUSY, assuming that the CMSSM is
the correct model, is $100%$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.5646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.5646</id><created>2014-04-22</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vadapoo</keyname><forenames>Rajasekarakumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallal</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Hongxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chshiev</keyname><forenames>Mairbek</forenames></author></authors><title>First principles investigation of magnetocrystalline anisotropy at the
  L2$_1$ Full Heusler|MgO interfaces and tunnel junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104418 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetocrystalline anisotropy at Heusler alloy$|$MgO interfaces have been
studied using first principles calculations. It is found that Co terminated
Co$_{2}$FeAl$|$MgO interfaces show perpendicular magnetic anisotropy up to 1.31
mJ/m$^2$, while those with FeAl termination exhibit in-plane magnetic
anisotropy. Atomic layer resolved analysis indicates that the origin of
perpendicular magnetic anisotropy in Co$_{2}$FeAl$|$MgO interfaces can be
attributed to the out-of-plane orbital contributions of interfacial Co atoms.
At the same time, Co$_{2}$MnGe and Co$_{2}$MnSi interfaced with MgO tend to
favor in-plane magnetic anisotropy for all terminations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.5394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.5394</id><created>2014-06-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Cividini</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilhorst</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stripe formation instability in crossing traffic flows</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 47 (2014) 445002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/47/44/445002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At the intersection of two unidirectional traffic flows a stripe formation
instability is known to occur. In this paper we consider coupled time evolution
equations for the densities of the two flows in their intersection area. We
show analytically how the instability arises from the randomness of the traffic
entering the area. The Green function of the linearized equations is shown to
form a Gaussian wave packet whose oscillations correspond to the stripes.
Explicit formulas are obtained for various characteristic quantities in terms
of the traffic density and comparison is made with the much simpler calculation
on a torus and with numerical solution of the evolution equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.7534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.7534</id><created>2014-07-28</created><updated>2014-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the CNMSSM more credible than the CMSSM?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 color figures. Closely matches version published in
  Eur.Phys.J. C. Minor changes to title and abstract, and additional
  information about scanning settings. Conclusions unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C74 (2014) no.10, 3105</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-014-3105-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With Bayesian statistics, we investigate the full parameter space of the
constrained &quot;next-to-minimal&quot; supersymmetric Standard Model (CNMSSM) with
naturalness priors, which were derived in a previous work. In the past, most
Bayesian analyses of the CNMSSM ignored naturalness of the electroweak (EW)
scale by making prejudicial assumptions for parameters defined at the EW scale.
We test the CNMSSM against the CMSSM with Bayesian evidence, which, with
naturalness priors, incorporates a penalty for fine-tuning of the EW scale.
With the evidence, we measure credibility with respect to all measurements,
including the EW scale and LHC direct searches. We find that the evidence in
favor of the CNMSSM versus the CMSSM is &quot;positive&quot; to &quot;strong&quot; but that if one
ignores the $\mu$-problem, the evidence is &quot;barely worth mentioning&quot; to
&quot;positive.&quot; The $\mu$-problem significantly influences our findings. Unless one
considers the $\mu$-problem, the evidence in favor of the CNMSSM versus the
CMSSM is at best &quot;positive,&quot; which is two grades below &quot;very strong.&quot; We,
furthermore, identify the most probable regions of the CMSSM and CNMSSM
parameter spaces and examine prospects for future discovery at hadron
colliders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.6699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.6699</id><created>2014-08-28</created><updated>2014-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzola</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing quark mixing in minimal left-right symmetric models with
  $b$-tags at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures. Matches version published in Nucl.Phys. B.
  Expanded descriptions of figures but conclusions unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B889 (2014) 36-45</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2014.10.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by a hint in a CMS search for right-handed $W$-bosons in $eejj$
final states, we propose an experimental test of quark-mixing matrices in a
general left-right symmetric model, based on counting the numbers of $b$-tags
from right-handed $W$-boson hadronic decays. We find that, with our test,
differences between left- and right-handed quark-mixing matrices could be
detected at the LHC with $\sqrt{s}=14$ TeV. With an integrated luminosity of
about $20/\textrm{fb}$, our test is sensitive to right-handed quark-mixing
angles as small as about $30^\circ$ and with $3000/\textrm{fb}$, our test's
sensitivity improves to right-handed mixing angles as small as about
$7.5^\circ$. Our test's sensitivity might be further enhanced by tuning
$b$-tagging efficiency against purity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.2427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.2427</id><created>2014-10-09</created><updated>2015-05-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>Sashikumaar</forenames></author></authors><title>Computation of impinging droplet with soluble surfactants and dynamic
  contact angle</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 figures and 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Comp. Phy. 301 (2015) 178-200</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2015.08.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An arbitrary Lagrangian--Eulerian (ALE) finite element scheme for
computations of soluble surfactant droplet impingement on a horizontal surface
is presented. The numerical scheme solves the time-dependent Navier--Stokes
equations for the fluid flow, scalar convection-diffusion equation for the
surfactant transport in the bulk phase, and simultaneously, surface evolution
equations for the surfactants on the free surface and on the liquid-solid
interface. The effects of surfactants on the flow dynamics are included into
the model through the surfactant-dependent surface tension and dynamic contact
angle. In particular, the dynamic contact angle $(\theta_d)$ of the droplet is
defined in terms of the surfactant concentration at the contact line and the
equilibrium contact angle $(\theta_e^0)$ of the clean surface using the
nonlinear equation of state for surface tension. Further, the surface forces
are included in the model as the surface divergence of the surface stress
tensor that allows to incorporate the Marangoni effects without calculating the
surface gradient of the surfactant concentration on the free surface. In
addition to a mesh convergence study and validation of the numerical results
with experiments, the effects of adsorption and desorption surfactant
coefficients on the flow dynamics in wetting, partially wetting and non-wetting
droplets are studied in detail. It is observed that the effect of surfactants
are more in wetting droplets than in the non-wetting droplets. Further, the
presence of surfactants at the contact line reduces the equilibrium contact
angle further when $ \theta_e^0 $ is less than $90^\circ$, and increases it
further when $ \theta_e^0 $ is greater than $90^\circ$. The presence of
surfactants has no effect on the contact angle, when $\theta_e^0 =90^\circ$.
The numerical study clearly demonstrates that the surfactant-dependent contact
angle ...
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.7589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.7589</id><created>2014-10-28</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>X. X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preparation of edge states by shaking boundaries</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 373, 286297 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.07.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Preparing topological states of quantum matter, such as edge states, is one
of the most important directions in condensed matter physics. In this work, we
present a proposal to prepare edge states in
Aubry-Andr$\acute{\textrm{e}}$-Harper (AAH) model with open boundaries, which
takes advantage of Lyapunov control to design operations. We show that edge
states can be obtained with almost arbitrary initial states. A numerical
optimalization for the control is performed and the dependence of control
process on the system size is discussed. The merit of this proposal is that the
shaking exerts only on the boundaries of the model. As a by-product, a
topological entangled state is achieved by elaborately designing the shaking
scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.5587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.5587</id><created>2014-12-17</created><updated>2015-03-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzola</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Examining a right-handed quark mixing matrix with $b$-tags at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures, matches version to appear in Nuclear Physics B</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B894 (2015) 588-601</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2015.03.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Encouraged by a hint in a search for right-handed $W$ bosons at the LHC, we
investigate whether the unitarity of a right-handed quark mixing matrix and the
equality of the left- and right-handed quark mixing matrices could be tested at
the LHC. We propose a particular test, involving counting the numbers of
$b$-tags in the final state, and simulate the test at the event level with
Monte-Carlo tools for the forthcoming $\sqrt{s}=13$ TeV LHC run. We find that
testing unitarity with 20/fb will be challenging; our test successfully rejects
unitarity if the right-handed quark mixing matrix is non-unitary, but only in
particular cases. On the other hand, our test may provide the first opportunity
to test the unitarity of a right-handed quark mixing matrix and with 3000/fb
severely constrains possible departures from unitarity in the latter. We refine
our previous work, testing the equality of quark mixing matrices, with full
collider simulation. With 20/fb, we are sensitive to mixing angles as small as
$30^\circ$, and with 3000/fb, angles as small as $7.5^\circ$, confirming our
preliminary analysis. We briefly investigate testing the unitarity of the SM
CKM matrix with a similar method by studying semileptonic $t\bar t$ production,
concluding that systematics make it particularly difficult.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02137</id><created>2015-01-09</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nanni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>A Discussion on the Heisenberg Uncertainty Principle from the
  Perspective of Special Relativity</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Article published on Physics Essays</comments><journal-ref>Physics Essays, 29, 309-312 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.4006/0836-1398-29.3.309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note, we consider the implications of the Heisenberg uncertainty
principle (HUP) when computing uncertainties that affect the main dynamical
quantities, from the perspective of special relativity. Using the well-known
formula for propagating statistical errors, we prove that the uncertainty
relations between the moduli of conjugate observables are not relativistically
invariant. The new relationships show that, in experiments involving
relativistic particles, limitations of the precision of a quantity obtained by
indirect calculations may affect the final result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06960</id><created>2015-01-27</created><updated>2016-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Changjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>You-Gen</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic evolution of scalar fields with multiple vacua: generalized DBI
  and quintessence</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures, accepted by IJTP. A number of typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Theor. Phys (2016) 55: 4532</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-016-3076-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find a method to rewrite the equations of motion of scalar fields,
generalized DBI field and quintessence, in the autonomous form
for\emph{arbitrary} scalar potentials. With the aid of this method, we explore
the cosmic evolution of generalized DBI field and quintessence with the
potential of multiple vacua. Then we find that the scalars are always frozen in
the false or true vacuum in the end. Compared to the evolution of quintessence,
the generalized DBI field has more times of oscillations around the vacuum of
the potential. The reason for this point is that, with the increasing of speed
$\dot{\phi}$, the friction term of generalized DBI field is greatly decreased.
Thus the generalized DBI field acquires more times of oscillations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.04884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.04884</id><created>2015-02-17</created><updated>2015-10-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Venkatesan</keyname><forenames>Jagannath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>Sashikumaar</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Navier-slip boundary condition for computations of impinging
  droplets</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 Pages</comments><doi>10.1109/HiPCW.2015.10</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mesh-dependent relation for the slip number in the Navier-slip with
friction boundary condition for computations of impinging droplets with sharp
interface methods is proposed. The relation is obtained as a function of
Reynolds number, Weber number and the mesh size. The proposed relation is
validated for several test cases by comparing the numerically obtained wetting
diameter with the experimental results. Further, the computationally obtained
maximum wetting diameter using the proposed slip relation is verified with the
theoretical predictions. The relative error between the computationally
obtained maximum wetting diameter and the theoretical predictions is less than
10 % for impinging droplet on a hydrophilic surface, and the error increases in
the case of hydrophobic surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04118</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2015-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parniak</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#x119;cak</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wasilewski</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Multimode Raman light-atom interface in warm atomic ensemble as multiple
  three-mode quantum operations</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures (corrected version, some results changed)</comments><journal-ref>J. Mod. Opt. 63(20), 2039-2047 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2015.1125538</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the properties of a Raman quantum light-atom interface in long
atomic ensemble and its applications as a quantum memory or two-mode squeezed
state generator. We consider the weak-coupling regime and include both Stokes
and anti-Stokes scattering and the effects of Doppler broadening in buffer gas
assuming frequent velocity-averaging collisions. We find the Green functions
describing multimode transformation from input to output fields of photons and
atomic excitations. Proper mode basis is found via singular value decomposition
for short interaction times. It reveals that triples of modes are coupled by a
transformation equivalent to a combination of two beamsplitters and a two-mode
squeezing operation. We analyze the possible transformations on an example of
warm rubidium-87 vapor. The model we present bridges the gap between the Stokes
only and anti-Stokes only interactions providing simple, universal description
in a temporally and longitudinally multimode situation. Our results also
provide an easy way to find an evolution of the states in a Schr\&quot;odinger
picture thus facilitating understanding and design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04863</id><created>2015-05-18</created><updated>2015-09-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>X. X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum gates by periodic driving</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports, 6, 22077 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep22077</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological quantum computation has been extensively studied due to its
robustness against decoherence. A conventional way to realize it is by
adiabatic operations---it requires relatively long time to accomplish so that
the speed of quantum computation slows down. In this work, we present a method
to realize topological quantum computation by periodic driving. Compared to the
adiabatic evolution, the total operation time can be regulated arbitrarily by
the amplitude and frequency of the periodic driving. For the sinusoidal
driving, we give an expression for the total operation time in the
high-frequency limit. For the square wave driving, we derive an exact
analytical expression for the evolution operator without any approximations,
and show that the amplitude and frequency of driving field depend on its period
and total operation time. This could provide a new direction in regulations of
the operation time in topological quantum computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01889</id><created>2015-06-05</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tannous</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langlois</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical noise, Quantum noise and Secure communication</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures. Published as a Review paper in European Journal
  of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Eur.J. Phys. 37 (2016) 013001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0143-0807/37/1/013001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Secure communication based on message encryption might be performed by
combining the message with controlled noise (called pseudo-noise) as performed
in Spread-Spectrum communication used presently in Wi-Fi and Smartphone
Telecommunication systems. Quantum communication based on entanglement is
another route for securing communications as demonstrated by several important
experiments described in this work. The central role played by the photon in
unifying the description of Classical and Quantum noise as major ingredients of
secure communication systems is highlighted and described on the basis of the
classical and quantum fluctuation dissipation theorems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00277</id><created>2015-08-02</created><updated>2016-09-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sagiyama</keyname><forenames>Koki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudraraju</keyname><forenames>Shiva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garikipati</keyname><forenames>Krishna</forenames></author></authors><title>Unconditionally stable, second-order accurate schemes for solid state
  phase transformations driven by mechano-chemical spinodal decomposition</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>added more comments on reduced formulations and updated figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cma.2016.09.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider solid state phase transformations that are caused by free energy
densities with domains of non-convexity in strain-composition space; we refer
to the non-convex domains as mechano-chemical spinodals. The non-convexity with
respect to composition and strain causes segregation into phases with different
crystal structures. We work on an existing model that couples the classical
Cahn-Hilliard model with Toupin's theory of gradient elasticity at finite
strains. Both systems are represented by fourth-order, nonlinear, partial
differential equations. The goal of this work is to develop unconditionally
stable, second-order accurate time-integration schemes, motivated by the need
to carry out large scale computations of dynamically evolving microstructures
in three dimensions. We also introduce reduced formulations naturally derived
from these proposed schemes for faster computations that are still second-order
accurate. Although our method is developed and analyzed here for a specific
class of mechano-chemical problems, one can readily apply the same method to
develop unconditionally stable, second-order accurate schemes for any problems
for which free energy density functions are multivariate polynomials of
solution components and component gradients. Apart from an analysis and
construction of methods, we present a suite of numerical results that
demonstrate the schemes in action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04377</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04377</id><created>2015-07-13</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kalaydzhyan</keyname><forenames>Tigran</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational mass of positron from LEP synchrotron losses</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages. Version accepted for publication in Sci. Rep. [Nature
  Publishing Group]</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 30461 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30461</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  General relativity (GR) is the current description of gravity in modern
physics. One of the cornerstones of GR, as well as Newton's theory of gravity,
is the weak equivalence principle (WEP), stating that the trajectory of a
freely falling test body is independent of its internal structure and
composition. WEP is known to be valid for the normal matter with a high
precision. However, due to the rarity of antimatter and weakness of the
gravitational forces, the WEP has never been confirmed for antimatter. The
current direct bounds on the ratio between the gravitational and inertial
masses of the antihydrogen do not rule out a repulsive nature for the
antimatter gravity. Here we establish an indirect bound of 0.13% on the
difference between the gravitational and inertial masses of the positron
(antielectron) from the analysis of synchrotron losses at the Large
Electron-Positron collider (LEP). This serves as a confirmation of the
conventional gravitational properties of antimatter without common assumptions
such as, e.g., coupling of gravity to virtual particles, dynamics of distant
astrophysical sources and the nature of absolute gravitational potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03851</id><created>2015-09-13</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Mikolaj K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esteban</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Tudela</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giedke</keyname><forenames>Geza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aizpurua</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>QED description of Raman scattering from molecules in plasmonic cavities</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>We add the discussion of the quantum noise treatment to the main
  text, correct equations in the SI and amend the discussion of the processes
  yield strong Stokes/anti-Stokes correlations</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano 10 (6), pp 6291-6298 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b02484</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasmon-enhanced Raman scattering can push single-molecule vibrational
spectroscopy beyond a regime addressable by classical electrodynamics. We
employ a quantum electrodynamics (QED) description of the coherent interaction
of plasmons and molecular vibrations that reveal the emergence of
nonlinearities in the inelastic response of the system. For realistic
situations, we predict the onset of \textit{phonon-stimulated Raman scattering}
and an counter-intuitive dependence of the anti-Stokes emission on the
frequency of excitation. We further show that this novel QED framework opens a
venue to analyze the correlations of photons emitted at a plasmonic cavity
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05145</id><created>2015-09-17</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordbar</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>B. Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahiyan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified TOV in gravity's rainbow: properties of neutron stars and
  dynamical stability conditions</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 tables, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 09 (2016) 013</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/09/013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider a spherical symmetric metric to extract the
hydrostatic equilibrium equation of stars in $(3+1)-$dimensional gravity's
rainbow in the presence of cosmological constant. Then, we generalize the
hydrostatic equilibrium equation to $d$-dimensions and obtain the hydrostatic
equilibrium equation for this gravity. Also, we obtain the maximum mass of
neutron star using the modern equations of state of neutron star matter derived
from the microscopic calculations. It is notable that, in this paper, we
consider the effects of rainbow functions on the diagrams related to the
mass-central mass density ($M$-$\rho _{c}$) relation and also the mass-radius
($M$-$R$) relation of neutron star. We also study the effects of rainbow
functions on the other properties of neutron star such as the Schwarzschild
radius, average density, strength of gravity and gravitational redshift. Then,
we apply the cosmological constant to this theory to obtain the diagrams of
$M$-$\rho _{c}$ (or $M$-$R$) and other properties of these stars. Next, we
investigate the dynamical stability condition for these stars in gravity's
rainbow and show that these stars have dynamical stability. We also obtain a
relation between mass of neutron stars and Planck mass. In addition, we compare
obtained results of this theory with the observational data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08878</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2016-09-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abbasi</keyname><forenames>Navid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davody</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hejazi</keyname><forenames>Kasra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rezaei</keyname><forenames>Zahra</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamic Waves in an Anomalous Charged Fluid</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 fig, 2 tables; references added; finite density
  computations added (PLB published version)</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B 762 (2016) 23-32</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.09.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the collective excitations in a relativistic fluid with an anomalous
$U(1)$ current. In $3+1$ dimensions at zero chemical potential, in addition to
ordinary sound modes we find two propagating modes in presence of an external
magnetic field. The first one which is a transverse degenerate mode, propagates
with a velocity proportional to the coefficient of gravitational anomaly; this
is in fact the Chiral Alfv\'en wave recently found in \cite{Yamamoto:2015ria}.
Another one is a wave of density perturbation, namely a chiral magnetic wave
(CMW). The velocity dependence of CMW on the chiral anomaly coefficient is well
known. We compute the dependence of CMW's velocity on the coefficient of
gravitational anomaly as well. We also show that the dissipation splits the
degeneracy of CAW. At finite chiral charge density we show that in general
there may exist five chiral hydrodynamic waves. Of these five waves, one is the
CMW while the other four are mixed Modified Sound-Alfv\'en waves. It turns out
that in propagation transverse to the magnetic field no anomaly effect appear
while in parallel to the magnetic field we find sound waves become dispersive
due to anomaly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03059</id><created>2015-10-11</created><updated>2015-11-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fontanari</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Francisco A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of network topology on cooperative problem-solving systems</title><categories>cs.SI nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Theory in Biosciences 135 (2016) 101-110</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12064-015-0219-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The idea of a collective intelligence behind the complex natural structures
built by organisms suggests that the organization of social networks is
selected so as to optimize problem-solving competence at the group-level. Here
we study the influence of the social network topology on the performance of a
group of agents whose task is to locate the global maxima of NK fitness
landscapes. Agents cooperate by broadcasting messages informing on their
fitness and use this information to imitate the fittest agent in their
influence networks. In the case those messages convey accurate information on
the proximity of the solution (i.e., for smooth fitness landscapes) we find
that high connectivity as well as centralization boost the group performance.
For rugged landscapes, however, these characteristics are beneficial for small
groups only. For large groups, it is advantageous to slow down the information
transmission through the network to avoid local maximum traps. Long-range links
and modularity have marginal effects on the performance of the group, except
for a very narrow region of the model parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07080</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2016-02-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Xudong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Feiyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Shengqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Creasing of an everted elastomer tube</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1039/C6SM01381C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A cylindrical elastomer tube can stay in an everted state without any applied
external forces. If the thickness of the tube is small, the everted tube,
except for the regions close to the two ends of the tube, is cylindrical, if
the thickness is larger than a critical value, the cross-section of the everted
tube becomes noncircular, which is due to mechanical instability. Although the
eversion-induced mechanical instability in an elastomer tube has been reported
several decades ago, a satisfying explanation of the phenomenon is still
unavailable. In all previous studies, linear stability analyses have been
commonly adopted to predict the critical thickness of the tube for the
eversion-induced instability. The discrepancy between the prediction and
experiment is significant and well known. In this letter, based on the
experiments and theoretical analyses, we show that crease formation on the
inner surface of an everted tube is the mechanical instability mode, which
cannot be captured by linear stability analyses. Instead, a combination of
energetic analyses and numerical simulation of highly nonlinear deformation
enables us to correctly predict both the critical thickness of the tube for the
onset of creases and the profile of the cross-section of an everted tube with
multiple creases on its inner surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08881</id><created>2015-11-28</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>Stephen D. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>The measure problem in no-collapse (many worlds) quantum mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 1 figure. To appear in International Journal of Modern
  Physics D. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1110.0549</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explain the measure problem (cf. origin of the Born probability rule) in
no-collapse quantum mechanics. Everett defined maverick branches of the state
vector as those on which the usual Born probability rule fails to hold -- these
branches exhibit highly improbable behaviors, including possibly the breakdown
of decoherence or even the absence of an emergent semi-classical reality.
Derivations of the Born rule which originate in decision theory or subjective
probability (i.e., the reasoning of individual observers) do not resolve this
problem, because they are circular: they assume, a priori, that the observer
occupies a non-maverick branch. An ab initio probability measure is sometimes
assumed to explain why we do not occupy a maverick branch. This measure is
constrained by, e.g., Gleason's Theorem or envariance to be the usual Hilbert
measure. However, this ab initio measure ultimately governs the allocation of a
self or a consciousness to a particular branch of the wavefunction, and hence
invokes primitives which lie beyond the Everett wavefunction and beyond what we
usually think of as physics. The significance of this leap has been largely
overlooked, but requires serious scrutiny.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09225</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martone</keyname><forenames>Giovanni I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pepe</keyname><forenames>Francesco V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Facchi</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascazio</keyname><forenames>Saverio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stringari</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Tricriticalities and Quantum Phases in Spin-Orbit-Coupled Spin-$1$ Bose
  Gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures + Supplemental Material. Revised version,
  published in PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 125301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.125301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the zero-temperature phase diagram of a spin-orbit-coupled
Bose-Einstein condensate of spin $1$, with equally weighted Rashba and
Dresselhaus couplings. Depending on the antiferromagnetic or ferromagnetic
nature of the interactions, we find three kinds of striped phases with
qualitatively different behaviors in the modulations of the density profiles.
Phase transitions to the zero-momentum and the plane-wave phases can be induced
in experiments by independently varying the Raman coupling strength and the
quadratic Zeeman field. The properties of these transitions are investigated in
detail, and the emergence of tricritical points, which are the direct
consequence of the spin-dependent interactions, is explicitly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03055</id><created>2015-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Blaszczyk</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oehlmann</keyname><forenames>Paul-Konstantin</forenames></author></authors><title>Tracing symmetries and their breakdown through phases of heterotic (2,2)
  compactifications</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>35 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1604 (2016) 068</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are considering the class of heterotic $\mathcal{N}=(2,2)$ Landau-Ginzburg
orbifolds with 9 fields corresponding to $A_1^9$ Gepner models. We classify all
of its Abelian discrete quotients and obtain 152 inequivalent models closed
under mirror symmetry with $\mathcal{N}=1,2$ and $4$ supersymmetry in 4D. We
compute the full massless matter spectrum at the Fermat locus and find a
universal relation satisfied by all models. In addition we give prescriptions
of how to compute all quantum numbers of the 4D states including their discrete
R-symmetries. Using mirror symmetry of rigid geometries we describe orbifold
and smooth Calabi-Yau phases as deformations away from the Landau-Ginzburg
Fermat locus in two explicit examples. We match the non-Fermat deformations to
the 4D Higgs mechanism and study the conservation of R-symmetries. The first
example is a $\mathbb{Z}_3$ orbifold on an E$_6$ lattice where the R-symmetry
is preserved. Due to a permutation symmetry of blow-up and torus K\&quot;{a}hler
parameters the R-symmetry stays conserved also smooth Calabi-Yau phase. In the
second example the R-symmetry gets broken once we deform to the geometric
$\mathbb{Z}_3 \times \mathbb{Z}_{3,\text{free}}$ orbifold regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03507</id><created>2015-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hongquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author></authors><title>Reproducible Ultrahigh Electromagnetic SERS Enhancement in
  Nanosphere-Plane Junctions</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/srep33218</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) in nanoscale hotspots has been
placed great hopes upon for identification of minimum chemical traces and
in-situ investigation of single molecule structures and dynamics. However,
previous work consists of either irreproducible enhancement factors (EF) from
random aggregates, or moderate EFs despite better reproducibility.
Consequently, systematic study of SERS at the single and few molecules level is
still very limited, and the promised applications are far from being realized.
Here we report EFs as high as the most intense hotspots in previous work yet
achieved in a reproducible and well controlled manner, that is, electromagnetic
EFs (EMEF) of 10^9~10 with an error down to 10^+/-0.08 from gold nanospheres on
atomically flat gold planes under radially polarized (RP) laser excitation. In
addition, our experiment reveals the EF's unexpected nonlinearity under as low
as hundreds of nanowatts of laser power.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04058</id><created>2015-12-13</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Babichev</keyname><forenames>Eugeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear stability of nonbidiagonal black holes in massive gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures; v2: References added; v3: matches published
  version; v4: acknowledgement added</comments><report-no>LPT-Orsay-16-06</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 044041 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.044041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider generic linear perturbations of a nonbidiagonal class of static
black-hole solutions in massive (bi)gravity. We show that the quasinormal
spectrum of these solutions coincides with that of a Schwarzschild black hole
in general relativity, thus proving that these solutions are mode stable. This
is in contrast to the case of bidiagonal black-hole solutions which are
affected by a radial instability. On the other hand, the full set of
perturbation equations is generically richer than that of a Schwarzschild black
hole in general relativity, and this affects the linear response of the black
hole to external perturbations. Finally, we argue that the generalization of
these solutions to the spinning case does not suffer from the superradiant
instability, despite the fact that the theory describes a massive graviton.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05259</id><created>2015-12-16</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villani</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filisetti</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical criticality: overview and open questions</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><comments>Added references, rephrased some sentences and corrected typos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Systems that exhibit complex behaviours are often found in a particular
dynamical condition, poised between order and disorder. This observation is at
the core of the so-called criticality hypothesis, which states that systems in
a dynamical regime between order and disorder attain the highest level of
computational capabilities and achieve an optimal trade-off between robustness
and flexibility. Recent results in cellular and evolutionary biology,
neuroscience and computer science have revitalised the interest in the
criticality hypothesis, emphasising its role as a viable candidate general law
in adaptive complex systems. In this paper we provide an overview of the works
on dynamical criticality that are -to the best of our knowledge- particularly
relevant for the criticality hypothesis. We review the main contributions
concerning dynamics and information processing at the edge of chaos, and we
illustrate the main achievements in the study of critical dynamics in
biological systems. Finally, we discuss open questions and propose an agenda
for future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05519</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abert</keyname><forenames>Claas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruggeri</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruckner</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogler</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manchon</keyname><forenames>Aurelien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Praetorius</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suess</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author></authors><title>A self-consistent spin-diffusion model for micromagnetics</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a three-dimensional micromagnetic model that dynamically solves
the Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation coupled to the full spin-diffusion
equation. In contrast to previous methods, we solve for the magnetization
dynamics and the electric potential in a self-consistent fashion. This
treatment allows for an accurate description of magnetization dependent
resistance changes. Moreover, the presented algorithm describes both spin
accumulation due to smooth magnetization transitions and due to material
interfaces as in multilayer structures. The model and its finite-element
implementation are validated by current driven motion of a magnetic vortex
structure. In a second experiment, the resistivity of a magnetic multilayer
structure in dependence of the tilting angle of the magnetization in the
different layers is investigated. Both examples show good agreement with
reference simulations and experiments respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05818</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-09-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coh</keyname><forenames>Sinisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Marvin L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louie</keyname><forenames>Steven G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antiferromagnetism enables electron-phonon coupling in iron-based
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, with a supplement</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that a generic form of an antiferromagnetic wave function opens
strong electron-phonon coupling channels in the iron-based superconductors. In
the nonmagnetic state these channels exist locally on a single iron atom, but
are canceled out between the two iron atoms in the primitive unit cell. Our
findings are based on symmetry and the presence of an xz/yz Fermi surface near
the M point and thus should be relevant for the known iron-based pnictide or
chalcogenide superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06646</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okazaki</keyname><forenames>Tadashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Douglas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological M-Strings and Supergroup WZW Models</title><categories>hep-th math.GT</categories><comments>36 pages, 2 figures; v4: published version in Physical Review D</comments><report-no>DCPT-15/69, NCTS-TH/1508</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 065016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.065016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the boundary conditions in the topologically twisted Chern-Simons
matter theories with the Lie 3-algebraic structure. We find that the
supersymmetric boundary conditions and the gauge invariant boundary conditions
can be unified as the complexified gauge invariant boundary conditions which
lead to the supergroup WZW models. We propose that the low-energy effective
field theories on the two-dimensional intersection of multiple M2-branes on a
holomorphic curve inside K3 with two non-parallel M5-branes on the K3 are
supergroup WZW models from the topologically twisted BLG-model and the
ABJM-model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09230</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Yan-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Ruidan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneeloch</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lili</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Shuai-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xing-Jiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Can-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xu-Cun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Qi-Kun</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure of the ingredient planes of cuprate superconductor
  Bi2Sr2CuO6+{\delta}: a comparison study with Bi2Sr2CaCu2O8+{\delta}</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 140504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.140504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of low-temperature scanning tunneling microscopy, we report on the
electronic structures of BiO and SrO planes of Bi2Sr2CuO6+{\delta} (Bi-2201)
superconductor prepared by argon-ion bombardment and annealing. Depending on
post annealing conditions, the BiO planes exhibit either pseudogap (PG) with
sharp coherence peaks and an anomalously large gap of 49 meV or van Hove
singularity (VHS) near the Fermi level, while the SrO is always characteristic
of a PG-like feature. This contrasts with Bi2Sr2CaCu2O8+{\delta} (Bi-2212)
superconductor where VHS occurs solely on the SrO plane. We disclose the
interstitial oxygen dopants ({\delta} in the formulas) as a primary cause for
the occurrence of VHS, which are located dominantly around the BiO and SrO
planes, respectively, in Bi-2201 and Bi-2212. This is supported by the
contrasting structural buckling amplitude of BiO and SrO planes in the two
superconductors. Our findings provide solid evidence for the irrelevance of PG
to the superconductivity in the two superconductors, as well as insights into
why Bi-2212 can achieve a higher superconducting transition temperature than
Bi-2201, and by implication, the mechanism of cuprate superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02344</id><created>2016-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Titchener</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solntsev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhorukov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-photon tomography using on-chip quantum walks</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 41, 4079-4082 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.004079</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a conceptual approach to quantum tomography based on first
expanding a quantum state across extra degrees of freedom and then exploiting
the introduced sparsity to perform reconstruction. We formulate its application
to photonic circuits, and show that measured spatial photon correlations at the
output of a specially tailored discrete-continuous quantum-walk can enable full
reconstruction of any two-photon spatially entangled and mixed state at the
input. This approach does not require any tunable elements, so is well suited
for integration with on-chip superconducting photon detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08093</id><created>2016-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Poddubny</keyname><forenames>Alexander N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iorsh</keyname><forenames>Ivan V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhorukov</keyname><forenames>Andrey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of photon-plasmon quantum states in nonlinear hyperbolic
  metamaterials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 123901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.123901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a general theoretical framework of integrated paired
photon-plasmon generation through spontaneous wave mixing in nonlinear
plasmonic and metamaterial nanostructures, rigorously accounting for material
dispersion and losses in quantum regime through the electromagnetic Green
function. We identify photon-plasmon correlations in layered metal-dielectric
structures with 70% internal heralding quantum efficiency, and reveal novel
mechanism of broadband generation enhancement due to topological transition in
hyperbolic metamaterials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04610</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guedezounme</keyname><forenames>S&#xea;cloka Lazare</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanfon</keyname><forenames>Antonin Danvid&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samary</keyname><forenames>Dine Ousmane</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherically symmetric potential in noncommutative spacetime with a
  compactified extra dimensions</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:505</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4359-3</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Schr\&quot;odinger equation of the spherical symmetry quantum models such as
the hydrogen atom problem seems to be analytically non-solvable in higher
dimensions. When we try to compactifying one or several dimensions this
question can maybe solved. This paper stands for the study of the spherical
symmetry quantum models on noncommutative spacetime with compactified extra
dimensions. We provide analytically the resulting spectrum of the hydrogen atom
and Yukawa problem in $4+1$ dimensional noncommutative spacetime in the first
order approximation of noncommutative parameter. The case of higher dimensions
$D\geq 4$ is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04636</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kechkin</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosharev</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Singularity-free interaction in dilaton-Maxwell electrodynamics</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501698</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An effective potential is created for the dynamics of a test particle, which
preserves dilatation symmetry for nonlinear static dilaton-Maxwell background.
It is found that the central interaction in this theory is regular everywhere,
and that the theory is asymptotically free at short distances and that it has a
Coulomb properties at great distances from the source. It is shown that static
and spherically symmetric source, behaves like a soliton: it has the finite
energy characteristics that are inversely proportional to the dilaton-Maxwell
coupling constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07279</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Torrico</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas</keyname><forenames>Onofre</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero temperature non-plateau magnetization and magnetocaloric effect in
  an Ising-XYZ diamond chain structure</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.08.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zero temperature non-plateau magnetization is a peculiar property of a
quantum spin chain and it sometimes appears due to different gyromagnetic
factors. In this study, we illustrate a quite unusual nonplateau magnetization
property driven by XY-anisotropy in an Ising-XYZ diamond chain. Two particles
with spin-1/2 are bonded by XYZ coupling and they are responsible for the
emergence of non-plateau magnetization. These two quantum operator spins are
bonded to two nodal Ising spins and this process is repeated infinitely to
yield a diamond chain structure. Due to the non-plateau magnetization property,
we focus our discussion on the magnetocaloric effect of this model by
presenting the isentropic curves and the Gruneisen parameters, as well as
showing the regions where the model exhibits an efficient magnetocaloric
effect. Due to the existence of two phases located very close to each other,
the strong XY-anisotropy exhibits a particular behavior with a magnetocaloric
effect, with a wider interval in the magnetic field, where the magnetocaloric
effect is efficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07317</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sayad</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rausch</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potthoff</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation of a classical spin coupled to a strongly correlated electron
  system</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5+3 pages, 5 figures, v2 as published in PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 127201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.127201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A classical spin which is antiferromagnetically coupled to a system of
strongly correlated conduction electrons is shown to exhibit unconventional
real-time dynamics which cannot be described by Gilbert damping. Depending on
the strength of the local Coulomb interaction, the two main electronic
dissipation channels, transport of excitations via correlated hopping and via
excitations of correlation-induced magnetic moments, become active on largely
different time scales. We demonstrate that this can lead to a prethermalization
scenario which so far has been observed in purely electronic systems only and
which is governed here by proximity to the divergent magnetic time scale in the
infinite-U limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01636</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Punsly</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balsara</keyname><forenames>Dinshaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jinho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garain</keyname><forenames>Sudip</forenames></author></authors><title>Riemann Solvers and Alfven Waves in Black Hole Magnetospheres</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Published in Computational Astrophysics and Cosmology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the magnetosphere of a rotating black hole, an inner Alfven critical
surface (IACS) must be crossed by inflowing plasma. Inside the IACS, Alfven
waves are inward directed toward the black hole. The majority of the proper
volume of the active region of spacetime (the ergosphere) is inside of the
IACS. The charge and the totally transverse momentum flux (the momentum flux
transverse to both the wave normal and the unperturbed magnetic field) are both
determined exclusively by the Alfven polarization. Thus, it is important for
numerical simulations of black hole magnetospheres to minimize the dissipation
of Alfven waves. Elements of the dissipated wave emerge in adjacent cells
regardless of the IACS, there is no mechanism to prevent Alfvenic information
from crossing outward. Thus, numerical dissipation can affect how simulated
magnetospheres attain the substantial Goldreich-Julian charge density
associated with the rotating magnetic field. In order to help minimize
dissipation of Alfven waves in relativistic numerical simulations we have
formulated a one-dimensional Riemann solver, called HLLI, which incorporates
the Alfven discontinuity and the contact discontinuity. We have also formulated
a multidimensional Riemann solver, called MuSIC, that enables low dissipation
propagation of Alfven waves in multiple dimensions. The importance of higher
order schemes in lowering the numerical dissipation of Alfven waves is also
catalogued.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01881</id><created>2016-03-06</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ronke</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Estarellas</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Amico</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiller</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyadera</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anderson localisation in spin chains for perfect state transfer</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. D (2016) 70: 189</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2016-60665-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anderson localisation is an important phenomenon arising in many areas of
physics, and here we explore it in the context of quantum information devices.
Finite dimensional spin chains have been demonstrated to be important devices
for quantum information transport, and in particular can be engineered to allow
for &quot;perfect state transfer&quot; (PST). Here we present extensive investigations of
disordered PST spin chains, demonstrating spatial localisation and transport
retardation effects, and relate these effects to conventional Anderson
localisation. We provide thresholds for Anderson localisation in these finite
quantum information systems for both the spatial and the transport domains.
Finally, we consider the effect of disorder on the eigenstate and energy
spectrum of our Hamiltonian, where results support our conclusions on the
presence of Anderson localisation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05167</id><created>2016-03-16</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ettinger</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindblad</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author></authors><title>A sharp counterexample to local existence of low regularity solutions to
  Einstein's equations in wave coordinates</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are concerned with how regular initial data have to be to ensure local
existence for Einstein's equations in wave coordinates. Klainerman-Rodnianski
and Smith-Tataru showed that there in general is local existence for data in
Sobolev spaces H^s with regularity s&gt;2. We give an example of data in Sobolev
spaces with regularity s=2 for which there is no local solution in this space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08781</id><created>2016-03-29</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Latychevskaia</keyname><forenames>Tatiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wicki</keyname><forenames>Flavio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longchamp</keyname><forenames>Jean-Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escher</keyname><forenames>Conrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Hans-Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct observation of individual charges and their dynamics on graphene
  by low-energy electron holography</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano Letters, Volume 16, Issue 9, pages 5469-5474, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b01881</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Visualizing individual charges confined to molecules and observing their
dynamics with high spatial resolution is a challenge for advancing various
fields in science, ranging from mesoscopic physics to electron transfer events
in biological molecules. We show here, that the high sensitivity of low-energy
electrons to local electric fields can be employed to directly visualize
individual charged adsorbates and to study their behaviour in a quantitative
way. This makes electron holography a unique probing tool for directly
visualising charge distributions with a sensitivity of a fraction of an
elementary charge. Moreover, spatial resolution in the nanometer range and fast
data acquisition inherent to lens-less low-energy electron holography allows
for direct visual inspection of charge transfer processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05893</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05893</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Z. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>X. X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Population transfer driven by far-off-resonant fields</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1011.4423 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>Optics EXPRESS 24, 21971 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.021971</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a two-level system, it is believed that a far-off-resonant driving can
not help coherent population transfer between the states. In this work, we
propose a scheme to implement the coherent transfer with far-off-resonant
driving. The scheme works well with both constant driving and Gaussian driving.
The total time to finish population transfer is also minimized by optimizing
the detuning and coupling constants. We find that the scheme is sensitive to
spontaneous emission much more than dephasing. It might find potential
applications in X-ray quantum optics and population transfer in Rydberg atoms
as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06131</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-08-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farutin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>W. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thi&#xe9;baud</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rafa&#xef;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peyla</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misbah</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Amoeboid swimming in a channel</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn q-bio.CB</categories><comments>Advance Article, Soft Matter (2016), 16 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 12, 7470-7484 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM00934D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several micro-organisms, such as bacteria, algae, or spermatozoa, use
flagella or cilia to swim in a fluid, while many other micro-organisms instead
use ample shape deformation, described as amoeboid, to propel themselves by
either crawling on a substrate or swimming. Many eukaryotic cells were believed
to require an underlying substratum to migrate (crawl) by using membrane
deformation (like blebbing or generation of lamellipodia) but there is now
increasing evidence that a large variety of cells (including those of the
immune system) can migrate without the assistance of focal adhesion, allowing
them to swim as efficiently as they can crawl. This paper details the analysis
of amoeboid swimming in a confined fluid by modeling the swimmer as an
inextensible membrane deploying local active forces. The swimmer displays a
rich behavior: it may settle into a straight trajectory in the channel or
navigate from one wall to the other depending on its confinement. The nature of
the swimmer is also found to be affected by confinement: the swimmer can
behave, on the average over one swimming cycle, as a pusher at low confinement,
and becomes a puller at higher confinement. The swimmer's nature is thus not an
intrinsic property. The scaling of the swimmer velocity V with the force
amplitude A is analyzed in detail showing that at small enough A, $V\sim
A^2/\eta^2$, whereas at large enough A, V is independent of the force and is
determined solely by the stroke frequency and swimmer size. This finding
starkly contrasts with currently known results found from swimming models where
motion is based on flagellar or ciliary activity, where $V\sim A/\eta$. To
conclude, two definitions of efficiency as put forward in the literature are
analyzed with distinct outcomes. We find that one type of efficiency has an
optimum as a function of confinement while the other does not. Future
perspectives are outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07720</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Thomas L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedder</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Helical gaps in interacting Rashba wires at low electron densities</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages main text, 6 pages appendix, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125420 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125420</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rashba spin-orbit coupling and a magnetic field perpendicular to the Rashba
axis have been predicted to open a partial gap (&quot;helical gap&quot;) in the energy
spectrum of noninteracting or weakly interacting one-dimensional quantum wires.
By comparing kinetic energy and Coulomb energy we show that this gap opening
typically occurs at low electron densities where the Coulomb energy dominates.
To address this strongly correlated limit, we investigate Rashba wires using
Wigner crystal theory. We find that the helical gap exists even in the limit of
strong interactions but its dependence on electron density differs
significantly from the weakly interacting case. In particular, we find that the
critical magnetic field for opening the gap becomes an oscillatory function of
electron density. This changes strongly the expected signature of the helical
gap in conductance measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02403</id><created>2016-05-08</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Lixin</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the Neutrino Mass through the Cross Correlation between the
  Rees-Sciama Effect and Weak Lensing</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, to appear in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)059</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmology plays a fundamental role to determine the neutrino mass, therefore
also to determine its mass hierarchy, since the massive neutrino contributes to
the total matter density in the Universe at the background and perturbation
levels, once it becomes non-relativistic. After the non-relativistic transition
the fluctuations are smashed out at the scales $k\gg k_{fs}$. Therefore, the
missing fluctuation in the total matter is imprinted on the large scale
structure, say the suppression of the matter power spectrum $\Delta P/P\approx
-8f_{\nu}$ at the scales $k\gg k_{fs}$. In this paper, instead of considering
the linear perturbation theory, which is well understood in the presence of
neutrino, we propose to use the cross correlation between the Rees-Sciama
effect and weak lensing to probe the neutrino mass. At the small scales, the
density contrast grows faster than the background scale factor $\delta\sim a$,
that makes a sign flipping on $\Phi' \propto \mathcal{H}\delta d\ln
(\delta/a)/d\ln a$, which happens only in the non-linear regime. We show that
the flipping scale in the cross power spectrum between the Rees-Sciama effect
and weak lensing depends on the neutrino mass by assuming the shallow and deep
weak lensing surveys. Our analysis shows that the Deep survey has larger
signal-to-noise ratio $S/N\sim 160$. Finally, we use the Fisher information
matrix to forecast constraint on the neutrino mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02782</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sherafati</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Principi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignale</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Hall viscosity and electromagnetic response of electrons in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages including one Appendix, one figure. As main modifications,
  in this version the result for the Hall viscosity and Hall conductivity of
  graphene reflect the expected electron-hole symmetry and a detailed
  discussion section has been added to compare our results with those obtained
  earlier in the literature</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125427 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125427</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive an analytic expression for the geometric Hall viscosity of
non-interacting electrons in a single graphene layer in the presence of a
perpendicular magnetic field. We show that a recently-derived formula in [C.
Hoyos and D. T. Son, Phys. Rev. Lett. {\bf 108}, 066805 (2012)], which connects
the coefficient of $q^2$ in the wave vector expansion of the Hall conductivity
$\sigma_{xy}(q)$ of the two-dimensional electron gas (2DEG) to the Hall
viscosity and the orbital diamagnetic susceptibility of that system, continues
to hold for graphene -- in spite of the lack of Galilean invariance -- with a
suitable definition of the effective mass. We also show that, for a
sufficiently large number of occupied Landau levels in the positive energy
sector, the Hall conductivity of electrons in graphene reduces to that of a
Galilean-invariant 2DEG with an effective mass given by $\hbar k_F/v_F$
(cyclotron mass). Even in the most demanding case, i.e. when the chemical
potential falls between the zero-th and the first Landau level, the cyclotron
mass formula gives results accurate to better than 1$\%$. The connection
between the Hall conductivity and the viscosity provides a possible avenue to
measure the Hall viscosity in graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02803</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marolf</keyname><forenames>Donald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wien</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author></authors><title>Adiabatic corrections to holographic entanglement in thermofield doubles
  and confining ground states</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>32 pages, 16 figures, typos fixed and reg. procedure refined</comments><journal-ref>J. J. High Energ. Phys. (2016) 2016: 58</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study entanglement in states of holographic CFTs defined by Euclidean path
integrals over geometries with slowly varying metrics. In particular, our CFT
spacetimes have $S^1$ fibers whose size $b$ varies along one direction ($x$) of
an ${\mathbb R}^{d-1}$ base. Such examples respect an ${\mathbb R}^{d-2}$
Euclidean symmetry. Treating the $S^1$ direction as time leads to a thermofield
double state on a spacetime with adiabatically varying redshift, while treating
another direction as time leads to a confining ground state with slowly varying
confinement scale. In both contexts the entropy of slab-shaped regions defined
by $|x - x_0| \le L$ exhibits well-known phase transitions at length scales $L=
L_{crit}$ characterizing the CFT entanglements. For the thermofield double, the
numerical coefficients governing the effect of variations in $b(x)$ on the
transition are surprisingly small and exhibit an interesting change of sign:
gradients reduce $L_{crit}$ for $d \le 3$ but increase $L_{crit}$ for $d\ge4$.
This means that, while for general $L &gt; L_{crit}$ they significantly increase
the mutual information of opposing slabs as one would expect, for $d\ge 4$
gradients cause a small decrease near the phase transition. In contrast, for
the confining ground states gradients always decrease $L_{crit}$, with the
effect becoming more pronounced in higher dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04395</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karpov</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brazovskii</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions in ensembles of solitons induced by an optical pumping
  or a strong electric field</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The latest trend in studies of modern electronically and/or optically active
materials is to provoke phase transformations induced by high electric fields
or by short (femtosecond) powerful optical pulses. The systems of choice are
cooperative electronic states whose broken symmetries give rise to topological
defects. For typical quasi-one-dimensional architectures, those are the
microscopic solitons taking from electrons the major roles as carriers of
charge or spin. Because of the long-range ordering, the solitons experience
unusual super-long-range forces leading to a sequence of phase transitions in
their ensembles: the higher-temperature transition of the confinement and the
lower one of aggregation into macroscopic walls. Here we present results of an
extensive numerical modeling for ensembles of both neutral and charged solitons
in both two- and three-dimensional systems. We suggest a specific Monte Carlo
algorithm preserving the number of solitons, which substantially facilitates
the calculations, allows to extend them to the three-dimensional case and to
include the important long-range Coulomb interactions. The results confirm the
first confinement transition, except for a very strong Coulomb repulsion, and
demonstrate a pattern formation at the second transition of aggregation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04964</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bisset</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baillie</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blakie</keyname><forenames>P. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ground-state phase diagram of a dipolar condensate with quantum
  fluctuations</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>11 pages and 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 033619 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.033619</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the ground state properties of a trapped dipolar condensate under
the influence of quantum fluctuations. We show that this system can undergo a
phase transition from a low density condensate state to a high density droplet
state, which is stabilized by quantum fluctuations. The energetically favored
state depends on the geometry of the confining potential, the number of atoms
and the two-body interactions. We develop a simple variational ansatz and
validate it against full numerical solutions. We produce a phase diagram for
the system and present results relevant to current experiments with dysprosium
and erbium condensates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05940</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gieles</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames><affiliation>University of Surrey</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Renaud</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames><affiliation>University of Surrey</affiliation></author></authors><title>If it does not kill them, it makes them stronger: collisional evolution
  of star clusters with tidal shocks</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, updated to match journal style</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. R. Astron. Soc. 463, L103-L107 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw163</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radii of young (&lt;100 Myr) star clusters correlate only weakly with their
masses. This shallow relation has been used to argue that impulsive tidal
perturbations, or `shocks', by passing giant molecular clouds (GMCs)
preferentially disrupt low-mass clusters. We show that this mass-radius
relation is in fact the result of the combined effect of two-body relaxation
and repeated tidal shocks. Clusters in a broad range of environments including
those like the solar neighbourhood evolve towards a typical radius of a few
parsecs, as observed, independent of the initial radius. This equilibrium
mass-radius relation is the result of a competition between expansion by
relaxation and shrinking due to shocks. Interactions with GMCs are more
disruptive for low-mass clusters, which helps to evolve the globular cluster
mass function (GCMF). However, the properties of the interstellar medium in
high-redshift galaxies required to establish a universal GCMF shape are more
extreme than previously derived, challenging the idea that all GCs formed with
the same power-law mass function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06089</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Karlsen</keyname><forenames>Jonas T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augustsson</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruus</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author></authors><title>The acoustic force density acting on inhomogeneous fluids in acoustic
  fields</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>RevTex, 5 pages, 3 eps figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 117, 114504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.114504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theory for the acoustic force density acting on inhomogeneous
fluids in acoustic fields on time scales that are slow compared to the acoustic
oscillation period. The acoustic force density depends on gradients in the
density and compressibility of the fluid. For microfluidic systems, the theory
predicts a relocation of the inhomogeneities into stable field-dependent
configurations, which are qualitatively different from the horizontally layered
configurations due to gravity. Experimental validation is obtained by confocal
imaging of aqueous solutions in a glass-silicon microchip.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06161</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fitzgerald</keyname><forenames>Michael P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graham</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalas</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Eve J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiang</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duchene</keyname><forenames>Gaspard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millar-Blanchaer</keyname><forenames>Maxwell A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ammons</keyname><forenames>S. Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruzzone</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Rosa</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draper</keyname><forenames>Zachary H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macintosh</keyname><forenames>Bruce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchis</keyname><forenames>Franck</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metchev</keyname><forenames>Stanimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrin</keyname><forenames>Marshall</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pueyo</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajan</keyname><forenames>Abhijith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rantakyro</keyname><forenames>Fredrik T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vega</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Schuyler</forenames></author></authors><title>Bringing &quot;The Moth&quot; to Light: A Planet-Sculpting Scenario for the HD
  61005 Debris Disk</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted to AJ; added Figure 5 and minor text edits</comments><journal-ref>The Astronomical Journal 152 (2016) 85</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-6256/152/4/85</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The HD 61005 debris disk (&quot;The Moth&quot;) stands out from the growing collection
of spatially resolved circumstellar disks by virtue of its unusual swept-back
morphology, brightness asymmetries, and dust ring offset. Despite several
suggestions for the physical mechanisms creating these features, no definitive
answer has been found. In this work, we demonstrate the plausibility of a
scenario in which the disk material is shaped dynamically by an eccentric,
inclined planet. We present new Keck NIRC2 scattered-light angular differential
imaging of the disk at 1.2-2.3 microns that further constrains its outer
morphology (projected separations of 27-135 AU). We also present complementary
Gemini Planet Imager 1.6 micron total intensity and polarized light detections
that probe down to projected separations less than 10 AU. To test our
planet-sculpting hypothesis, we employed secular perturbation theory to
construct parent body and dust distributions that informed scattered-light
models. We found that this method produced models with morphological and
photometric features similar to those seen in the data, supporting the premise
of a planet-perturbed disk. Briefly, our results indicate a disk parent body
population with a semimajor axis of 40-52 AU and an interior planet with an
eccentricity of at least 0.2. Many permutations of planet mass and semimajor
axis are allowed, ranging from an Earth mass at 35 AU to a Jupiter mass at 5
AU.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06347</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coletta</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf3;th</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penc</keyname><forenames>Karlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mila</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Semiclassical theory of the magnetization process of the triangular
  lattice Heisenberg model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages - 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075136 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the numerous examples of 1/3 magnetization plateaux in the
triangular lattice Heisenberg an- tiferromagnet with spins ranging from 1/2 to
5/2, we revisit the semiclassical calculation of the magnetization curve of
that model, with the aim of coming up with a simple method that allows one to
calculate the full mag- netization curve, and not just the critical fields of
the 1/3 plateau. We show that it is actually possible to calculate the
magnetization curve including the first quantum corrections and the appearance
of the 1/3 plateau entirely within linear spin-wave theory, with predictions
for the critical fields that agree to order 1/S with those derived a long-time
ago on the basis of arguments that required to go beyond linear spin-wave
theory. This calculation relies on the central observation that there is a kink
in the semiclassical energy at the field where the classical ground state is
the collinear up-up-down structure, and that this kink gives rise to a locally
linear behavior of the energy with the field when all semiclassical ground
states are compared to each other for all fields. The magnetization curves
calculated in this way for spin 1/2, 1 and 5/2 are shown to be in good
agreement with available experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07209</id><created>2016-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Dustin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grutter</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arenholz</keyname><forenames>Elke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirby</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borchers</keyname><forenames>Julie A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maranville</keyname><forenames>Brian B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond the Interface Limit: Structural and Magnetic Depth Profiles of
  Voltage-Controlled Magneto-Ionic Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 7, 12264 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12264</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electric-field control of magnetism provides a promising route towards
ultralow power information storage and sensor technologies. The effects of
magneto-ionic motion have so far been prominently featured in the direct
modification of interface chemical and physical characteristics. Here we
demonstrate magnetoelectric coupling moderated by voltage-driven oxygen
migration beyond the interface limit in relatively thick AlOx/GdOx/Co (15 nm)
films. Oxygen migration and its ramifications on the Co magnetization are
quantitatively mapped with polarized neutron reflectometry under thermal and
electro-thermal conditionings. The depth-resolved profiles uniquely identify
interfacial and bulk behaviors and a semi-reversible suppression and recovery
of the magnetization. Magnetometry measurements show that the conditioning
changes the microstructure so as to disrupt long-range ferromagnetic ordering,
resulting in an additional magnetically soft phase. X-ray spectroscopy confirms
electric field induced changes in the Co oxidation state but not in the Gd,
suggesting that the GdOx transmits oxygen but does not source or sink it. These
results together provide crucial insight into controlling magnetic
heterostructures via magneto-ionic motion, not only at the interface, but also
throughout the bulk of the films.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08059</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Brito</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Junior</keyname><forenames>J. T. Guaitolini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kroff</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malta</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz violation in simple QED processes</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Final version, includind suggestions of the referee. Published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 056005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.056005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the effect of a CPT-even and Lorentz violating non-minimal
coupling on the differential cross sections for some of the most important
tree-level processes in QED, namely, Compton and Bhabha scatterings, as well as
electron-positron annihilation. Experimental limits constraining the allowed
deviation of the differential cross sections relative to pure QED allow us to
place upper bounds on the Lorentz violating parameters. A constraint based on
the decay rate of para-positronium is also obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01044</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cropp</keyname><forenames>Bethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liberati</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turcati</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author></authors><title>Analogue black holes in relativistic BECs: Mimicking Killing and
  universal horizons</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages, 2 figures. Final version matching the published one in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 063003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.063003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Relativistic Bose-Einstein condensates (rBECs) have recently become a
well-established system for analogue gravity. Indeed, while such relativistic
systems cannot be yet realized experimentally, they provide an interesting
framework for mimicking metrics for which no analogue is yet available, so
paving the way for further theoretical and numerical explorations. In this
vein, we here discuss black holes in rBECs and explore how their features
relate to the bulk properties of the system. We then propose the coupling of
external fields to the rBEC as a way to mimic non-metric features. In
particular, we use a Proca field to simulate an aether field, as found in
Einstein-Aether or Horava-Lifshitz gravity. This allows us to mimic a universal
horizon, the causal barrier relevant for superluminal modes in these modified
gravitational theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01574</id><created>2016-06-05</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ryabov</keyname><forenames>Artem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holubec</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yaghoubi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Hassan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varga</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foulaadvand</keyname><forenames>M. Ebrahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chvosta</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport coefficients for a confined Brownian ratchet operating between
  two heat reservoirs</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 093202</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/09/093202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss two-dimensional diffusion of a Brownian particle confined to a
periodic asymmetric channel with soft walls modeled by a parabolic potential.
In the channel, the particle experiences different noise intensities, or
temperatures, in the transversal and longitudinal directions. The model is
inspired by the famous Feynman's ratchet and pawl. Using ideas of the
Fick-Jacobs approximation we derive the mean velocity of the particle, the
effective diffusion coefficient, and the stationary probability density in the
potential unit cell. The derived results are exact for small channel width.
Yet, we check by exact numerical calculation that they qualitatively describe
the ratchet effect observed for an arbitrary width of the channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01915</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pagani</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsinikos</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaro</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>The impact of the photon PDF and electroweak corrections on $t \bar t$
  distributions</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>20 pages, 18 figures; it matches the version published in EPJ C</comments><report-no>CP3-16-28</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76: 479</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4318-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the impact of EW corrections on differential distributions in
top-quark pair production at the LHC and future hadron colliders, focusing on
the effects of initial-state photons. Performing a calculation at
Next-to-Leading Order QCD+EW accuracy, we investigate in detail the impact of
photon-initiated channels on central values as well as PDF and scale
uncertainties, both at order $\alpha_s\alpha$ and $\alpha_s^2\alpha$. We
present predictions at 13 and 100 TeV, and provide results for the 8 TeV
differential measurements performed by ATLAS and CMS. A thorough comparison of
results obtained with the NNPDF2.3QED and CT14QED PDF sets is performed. While
contributions due to the photon PDF are negligible with CT14QED, this is not
the case for NNPDF2.3QED, where such contributions are sizeable and show large
PDF uncertainties. On the one hand, we show that differential observables in
top-pair production, in particular top-quark and $t\bar t$ rapidities, can be
used to improve the determination of the photon PDF within the NNPDF approach.
On the other hand, with current PDF sets, we demonstrate the necessity of
including EW corrections and photon-induced contributions for a correct
determination of both the central value and the uncertainties of theoretical
predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06525</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barbado</keyname><forenames>Luis C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barcel&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garay</keyname><forenames>Luis J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jannes</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author></authors><title>A tensorial description of particle perception in black-hole physics</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Minor corrections to match the published version. 11 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In quantum field theory in curved backgrounds, one typically distinguishes
between objective, tensorial, quantities such as the Renormalized Stress-Energy
Tensor (RSET) and subjective, non-tensorial, quantities such as Bogoliubov
coefficients which encode perception effects associated with the specific
trajectory of a detector. In this work we propose a way to treat both objective
and subjective notions on an equal tensorial footing. For that purpose, we
define a new tensor which we will call the Perception Renormalized
Stress-Energy Tensor (PeRSET). The PeRSET is defined as the subtraction of the
RSET corresponding to two different vacuum states. Based on this tensor we can
define perceived energy densities and fluxes. The PeRSET helps to have a more
organized and systematic understanding of various results in the literature
regarding quantum field theory in black hole spacetimes. We illustrate the
physics encoded in this tensor by working out various examples of special
relevance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09032</id><created>2016-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Yost</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>B. F. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>HERWIRI2.1: Electroweak Corrections for Hadron Scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 12 figures. Presented by S. Yost at Loops and Legs in
  Quantum Field Theory, 24-29 April 2016, Leipzig, Germany</comments><report-no>IFJPAN-IV-2016-16, BU-HEPP-16-03</report-no><journal-ref>Proc. Loops and Legs in Quantum Field Theory 2016, PoS(LL2016) 062</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the program HERWIRI2.1, which implements order alpha-squared
photonic radiative corrections exponentiated at the amplitude level (initial
state, final state, and initial-final interference) and electroweak corrections
to the matrix element by generating events using the KK Monte Carlo to generate
the hard process, with quark initial states generated according to PDFs via an
LHAPDF interface. The events can be showered internally using HERWIG6.5 or
exported and showered using any desired external showering program. Some early
results are shown, including comparisons to HERWIG6.5 and HORACE 3.1.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02686</id><created>2016-07-09</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pereyra</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved optical transitions theory for superlattices and periodic
  systems; new selection rules</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 27 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the superlattice (SL) eigenvalues $E_{\mu ,\nu }^{c,v}$ and
eigenfunctions $\varphi_{\mu\nu}^{c,v}(z) $, obtained within the theory of
finite periodic systems, where $\mu$ indicates the subbands and $\nu$ the
intra-subband levels, we calculate optical transitions in SLs and periodic
systems. Based on the eigenfunction parity symmetries, studied in the previous
paper, new symmetry selection rules (SSR) are derived and photoluminescence and
infrared spectra for different types of SLs are calculated. The narrow peaks
clustered in groups that couldn't be explained before in Nakamura's et al. for
blue emitting devices, are now fully understood. Among the various properties
and differences that we discuss in the paper, we notice that many transitions
that were experimentally observed but theoretically forbidden, are now
perfectly possible. Since the number of matrix-elements allowed by the SSR is
generally too large, we devote the second part of this paper to show that one
can obtain the same spectra when, besides the SSR, other leading order
selection rules closely related to intra-subband symmetries are introduced.
These rules reduce the number of matrix evaluations from $\sim n^2$$n_cn_v/2$
to $\sim n$$n_cn_v/2$, i.e., depending on the SL, from about 1000 to 100. We
comment also on a third rule, that picks up the contributions of the surface
and edge states, and show that it reduces further the number of transitions to
$N_s\leq n_cn_v$. With these rules, the main peaks are conserved and their
number practically matches with that of the actual spectrum. Excellent
agreements with experimental results are found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03383</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03383</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>B. Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahiyan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momennia</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>F(R) gravity's rainbow and its Einstein counterpart</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 12 figures. matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Adv. High Energy Phys. 2016, 9813582 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/9813582</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by UV completion of general relativity with a modification of a
geometry at high energy scale, it is expected to have an energy dependent
geometry. In this paper, we introduce charged black hole solutions with power
Maxwell invariant source in the context of gravity's rainbow. In addition, we
investigate two classes of $F(R)$ gravity's rainbow solutions. At first, we
study energy dependent $F(R)$ gravity without energy momentum tensor, and then
we obtain $F(R)$ gravity's rainbow in the presence of conformally invariant
Maxwell source. We study geometrical properties of the mentioned solutions and
compare their results. We also give some related comments regarding to
thermodynamical behavior of the obtained solutions and discuss thermal
stability of the solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04126</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zeidler</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebel</keyname><forenames>Eva K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nota</keyname><forenames>Antonella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabbi</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquali</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tosi</keyname><forenames>Monica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonanos</keyname><forenames>Alceste Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christian</keyname><forenames>Carol</forenames></author></authors><title>A High-Resolution Multiband Survey of Westerlund 2 With the Hubble Space
  Telescope. II. Mass accretion in the Pre-Main Sequence Population</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>21 pages, 17 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>2016 AJ, 152, 4</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-6256/152/4/84</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed analysis of the pre-main-sequence (PMS) population of
the young star cluster Westerlund~2 (Wd2), the central ionizing cluster of the
HII region RCW 49, using data from a high resolution multi-band survey with the
Hubble Space Telescope. The data were acquired with the Advanced Camera for
Surveys in the F555W, F814W, and F658N filters and with the Wide Field Camera 3
in the F125W, F160W, and F128N filters. We find a mean age of the region of
1.04+-0.72 Myr. The combination of dereddened F555W and F814W photometry in
combination with F658N photometry allows us to study and identify stars with
H_alpha excess emission. With a careful selection of 240 bona-fide PMS H_alpha
excess emitters we were able to determine their H_alpha luminosity, which has a
mean value L(H_alpha)=1.67 x 10^{-31} erg s^{-1}. Using the PARSEC 1.2S
isochrones to obtain the stellar parameters of the PMS stars we determined a
mean mass accretion rate \dot M_acc=4.43 x 10^{-8} M_sun yr^{-1} per star. A
careful analysis of the spatial dependence of the mass-accretion rate suggests
that this rate is ~25% lower in center of the two density peaks of Wd2 in close
proximity to the luminous OB stars, compared to the Wd2 average. This rate is
higher with increasing distance from the OB stars, indicating that the PMS
accretion disks are being rapidly destroyed by the far-ultra-violet radiation
emitted by the OB population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04213</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sekera</keyname><forenames>Tibor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruder</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belzig</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectricity in a junction between interacting cold atomic Fermi
  gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 033618 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.033618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A gas of interacting ultracold fermions can be tuned into a strongly
interacting regime using a Feshbach resonance. Here we theoretically study
quasiparticle transport in a system of two reservoirs of interacting ultracold
fermions on the BCS side of the BCS-BEC crossover coupled weakly via a tunnel
junction. Using the generalized BCS theory we calculate the time evolution of
the system that is assumed to be initially prepared in a non-equilibrium state
characterized by a particle number imbalance or a temperature imbalance. A
number of characteristic features like sharp peaks in quasiparticle currents,
or transitions between the normal and superconducting states are found. We
discuss signatures of the Seebeck and the Peltier effect and the resulting
temperature difference of the two reservoirs as a function of the interaction
parameter $(k_Fa)^{-1}$. The Peltier effect may lead to an additional cooling
mechanism for ultracold fermionic atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05060</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Peronio</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giessibl</keyname><forenames>Franz J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Attempts to test an alternative electrodynamic theory of superconductors
  by low-temperature scanning tunneling and atomic force microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures. Minor amendments</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94 (2016) 094503</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform an experiment to test between two theories of the electrodynamics
of superconductors: the standard London theory and an alternative proposed by
J. E. Hirsch [Phys. Rev. B 69, 214515 (2004)]. The two alternatives give
different predictions with respect to the screening of an electric field by a
superconductor, and we try to detect this effect using atomic force microscopy
on a niobium sample. We also perform the reverse experiment, where we
demonstrate a superconductive tip mounted on a qPlus force sensor. Due to
limited accuracy, we are able neither to prove nor to disprove Hirsch's
hypothesis. Within our accuracy of 0.17 N/m, the superconductive transition
does not alter the atomic-scale interaction between tip and sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06505</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Filonov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Yotam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlov</keyname><forenames>Vitali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ginzburg</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant Meta-atoms with Nonlinearities on Demand</title><categories>cond-mat.other physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 111904 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962838</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear light-matter interactions and their applications are constrained by
properties of available materials. The use of metamaterials opens the way to
achieve precise control over electromagnetic properties at a microscopic level,
providing new tools for experimental studies of complex nonlinear phenomena in
photonics. Here a doubly resonant nonlinear meta-atom is proposed, analyzed and
characterized in the GHz spectral range. The underlying structure is composed
of a pair of split rings, resonant at both fundamental and nonlinear
frequencies. The rings share a varactor diode, which serves as a microscopic
source of nonlinearity. Flexible control over the coupling and near- and
far-field patterns are reported, favoring the doubly resonant structure over
other realizations. Relative efficiencies of the second and third harmonics,
generated by the diode, are tailored by dint of the double-ring geometry,
providing a guideline for selecting one frequency against another, using the
design of the auxiliary structures. The on-demand control over the microscopic
nonlinear properties enables developing a toolbox for experimental emulation of
complex nonlinear phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07874</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07874</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-09-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gourgouliatos</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollerbach</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>Resistive Tearing Instability in Electron-MHD: Application to Neutron
  Star Crusts</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Accepted by MNRAS, 10 pages, 10 Figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a resistive tearing instability developing in a system evolving
through the combined effect of Hall drift in the Electron-MHD limit and Ohmic
dissipation. We explore first the exponential growth of the instability in the
linear case and we find the fastest growing mode, the corresponding eigenvalues
and dispersion relation. The instability growth rate scales as $\gamma \propto
B^{2/3} \sigma^{-1/3}$ where $B$ is the magnetic field and $\sigma$ the
electrical conductivity. We confirm the development of the tearing resistive
instability in the fully non-linear case, in a plane parallel configuration
where the magnetic field polarity reverses, through simulations of systems
initiating in Hall equilibrium with some superimposed perturbation. Following a
transient phase, during which there is some minor rearrangement of the magnetic
field, the perturbation grows exponentially. Once the instability is fully
developed the magnetic field forms the characteristic islands and X-type
reconnection points, where Ohmic decay is enhanced. We discuss the implications
of this instability for the local magnetic field evolution in neutron stars'
crusts, proposing that it can contribute to heating near the surface of the
star, as suggested by models of magnetar post-burst cooling. In particular, we
find that a current sheet a few meters thick, covering as little as $1\%$ of
the total surface can provide $10^{42}~$erg in thermal energy within a few
days. We briefly discuss applications of this instability in other systems
where the Hall effect operates such as protoplanetary discs and space plasmas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00035</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Modrzejewski</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hapka</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chalasinski</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczesniak</keyname><forenames>Malgorzata M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Employing Range Separation on the meta-GGA Rung: New Functional Suitable
  for Both Covalent and Noncovalent Interactions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Theory Comput. 12, 3662 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We devise a scheme for converting an existing exchange functional into its
range-separated hybrid variant. The underlying exchange hole of the
Becke-Roussel type has the exact second-order expansion in the interelectron
distance. The short-range part of the resulting range-separated exchange energy
depends on the kinetic energy density and the Laplacian even if the base
functional lacks the dependence on these variables. The most successful
practical realization of the scheme, named LC-PBETPSS, combines the
range-separated PBE exchange lifted to the hybrid meta-GGA rung and the TPSS
correlation. The value of the range-separation parameter is estimated
theoretically and confirmed by empirical optimization. The D3 dispersion
correction is recommended for all energy computations employing the presented
functional. Numerical tests show remarkably robust performance of the method
for noncovalent interaction energies, barrier heights, main-group
thermochemistry, and excitation energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01320</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Ipsita</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting instability in non-Fermi liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con hep-th</categories><comments>minor typos corrected; journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115138 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115138</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use renormalization group (RG) analysis and dimensional regularization
techniques to study potential superconductivity-inducing four-fermion
interactions in systems with critical Fermi surfaces of general dimensions
($m$) and co-dimensions ($d-m$), arising as a result of quasiparticle
interaction with a gapless Ising-nematic order parameter. These are examples of
non-Fermi liquid states in $d$ spatial dimensions. Our formalism allows us to
treat the corresponding zero-temperature low-energy effective theory in a
controlled approximation close to the upper critical dimension $d=d_c(m)$. The
fixed points are identified from the RG flow equations, as functions of $d$ and
$m$. We find that the flow towards the non-Fermi liquid fixed point is
preempted by Cooper pair formation for both the physical cases of $(d=3, m=2)$
and $(d=2, m=1)$. In fact, there is a strong enhancement of superconductivity
by the order parameter fluctuations at the quantum critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03378</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Fangfang</forenames></author><author><keyname>White.</keyname><forenames>B. E.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author></authors><title>Hall measurement of ultra thin vanadium dioxide thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to a sign error in
  equation 5</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present the investigation of temperature dependent hall
measurement of the ultra thin VO$_2$ films grown on Si/SiO$_2$ substrate.
Experimental results suggest that electrons are the predominant carrier both in
the semiconducting and metallic phases. The decrease of the resistivity with
increasing temperature is mainly caused by the increase in the number density
of charge carriers. The temperature dependence of the carrier concentration
indicates the VO$_2$ films has a band gap of 0.40$\pm$0.09 $ev$ in the
semiconducting phase. Analysis of hall effect data based on a composite cube
model suggests that the sample has some untransitional phase with a length that
is 1/4 of the grains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04316</id><created>2016-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Middey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>A. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuo</keyname><forenames>C. -T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyers</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kareev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tung</keyname><forenames>I. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fadley</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakhalian</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeland</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductor to Mott insulator transition in
  YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_7$/LaCaMnO$_3$ heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Accepted in Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports, 6, 33184 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep33184</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The superconductor-to-insulator transition (SIT) induced by means such as
external magnetic fields, disorder or spatial confinement is a vivid
illustration of a quantum phase transition dramatically affecting the
superconducting order parameter. In pursuit of a new realization of the SIT by
interfacial charge transfer, we developed extremely thin superlattices composed
of high $T_c$ superconductor YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_7$ (YBCO) and colossal
magnetoresistance ferromagnet La$_{0.67}$Ca$_{0.33}$MnO$_3$ (LCMO). By using
linearly polarized resonant X-ray absorption spectroscopy and magnetic circular
dichroism, combined with hard X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy, we derived a
complete picture of the interfacial carrier doping in cuprate and manganite
atomic layers, leading to the transition from superconducting to an unusual
Mott insulating state emerging with the increase of LCMO layer thickness. In
addition, contrary to the common perception that only transition metal ions may
response to the charge transfer process, we found that charge is also actively
compensated by rare-earth and alkaline-earth metal ions of the interface. Such
deterministic control of $T_c$ by pure electronic doping without any hindering
effects of chemical substitution is another promising route to disentangle the
role of disorder on the pseudo-gap and charge density wave phases of underdoped
cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04630</id><created>2016-08-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Dustin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Jung-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirby</keyname><forenames>Brian J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winklhofer</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Chih-Huang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Yoking and Tunable Interactions in FePt-Based Hard/Soft
  Bilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures, plus 3-page supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 32842 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep32842</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assessing and controlling magnetic interactions in magnetic nanostructures
are critical to nanomagnetic and spintronic explorations, such as magnetic
recording media, permanent magnets, magnetic memory and logic devices, etc.
Here we demonstrate an extremely sensitive magnetic yoking effect and tunable
interactions in FePt based hard/soft bilayers mediated by the soft layer. Below
the exchange length, a thin soft layer strongly exchange couples to the
perpendicular moments of the hard layer; above the exchange length, just a few
nanometers thicker, the soft layer moments turn in-plane and act to yoke the
dipolar fields from the adjacent hard layer perpendicular domains. The
evolution from exchange to dipolar-dominated interactions is experimentally
captured by first-order reversal curves, the delta-M method, and polarized
neutron reflectometry, and confirmed by micromagnetic simulations. These
findings demonstrate an effective yoking approach to design and control
magnetic interactions in wide varieties of magnetic nanostructures and devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00335</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Guangfu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forghani</keyname><forenames>Kamran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuech</keyname><forenames>Thomas F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Dane</forenames></author></authors><title>First-principles Predictions of Electronic Properties of GaAs1-x-yPyBix
  and GaAs1-x-yPyBix-based Heterojunctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 112104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962729</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Significant efficiency droop is a major concern for light-emitting diodes and
laser diodes operating at high current density. Recent study has suggested that
heavily Bi-alloyed GaAs can decrease the non-radiative Auger recombination and
therefore alleviate the efficiency droop. Using density functional theory, we
studied a newly fabricated quaternary alloy, GaAs1-x-yPyBix, which can host
significant amounts of Bi, through calculations of its band gap, spin-orbit
splitting, and band offsets with GaAs. We found that the band gap changes of
GaAs1-x-yPyBix relative to GaAs are determined mainly by the local structural
changes around P and Bi atoms rather than their electronic structure
differences. To obtain alloy with lower Auger recombination than GaAs bulk, we
identified the necessary constraints on the compositions of P and Bi. Finally,
we demonstrated that GaAs/GaAs1-x-yPyBix heterojunctions with potentially low
Auger recombination can exhibit small lattice mismatch and large enough band
offsets for strong carrier confinement. This work shows that the electronic
properties of GaAs1-x-yPyBix are potentially suitable for high-energy infrared
light-emitting diodes and laser diodes with improved efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00822</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00822</id><created>2016-09-03</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pavicic</keyname><forenames>Mladen</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical and Quantum Logics with Multiple and a Common Lattice Models</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.LO math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages; Typos corrected, presentation improved, language polished.
  There are inconsequential stylistic differences between the present and the
  published versions introduced by the editorial office. Any betoken overlaps
  between this paper and some previous ones of ours are directly
  anti-correlated with IQ of AI employed to hunt for them</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics, Volume 2016, Article ID 6830685
  (2016); 12 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/6830685</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a proper propositional quantum logic and show that it has
multiple disjoint lattice models, only one of which is an orthomodular lattice
(algebra) underlying Hilbert (quantum) space. We give an equivalent proof for
the classical logic which turns out to have disjoint distributive and
non-distributive ortholattices as its models. In particular, we prove that both
classical and quantum logics are sound and complete with respect to each of
these lattices. We also show that there is one common non-orthomodular lattice
that is a model of both quantum and classical logics. In technical terms, that
enables us to run the same classical logic on both a digital (standard, two
subset, 0-1 bit) computer and on a non-digital (say, a six subset) computer
(with appropriate chips and circuits). With quantum logic, the same six element
common lattice can serve us as a benchmark for an efficient evaluation of
equations of bigger lattice models or theorems of the logic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00851</id><created>2016-09-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Lindquist</keyname><forenames>Beth A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jadrich</keyname><forenames>Ryan B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truskett</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse Design for Self Assembly via On-the-Fly Optimization</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics 145, 111101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962754</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inverse methods of statistical mechanics have facilitated the discovery of
pair potentials that stabilize a wide variety of targeted lattices at zero
temperature. However, such methods are complicated by the need to compare,
within the optimization framework, the energy of the desired lattice to all
possibly relevant competing structures, which are not generally known in
advance. Furthermore, ground-state stability does not guarantee that the target
will readily assemble from the fluid upon cooling from higher temperature.
Here, we introduce a molecular dynamics simulation-based, optimization design
strategy that iteratively and systematically refines the pair interaction
according to the fluid and crystalline structural ensembles encountered during
the assembly process. We successfully apply this probabilistic,
machine-learning approach to the design of repulsive, isotropic pair potentials
that assemble into honeycomb, kagome, square, rectangular, truncated square and
truncated hexagonal lattices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00928</id><created>2016-09-04</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>C M N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Y</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>H S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voigt</keyname><forenames>J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitz</keyname><forenames>B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterji</keyname><forenames>T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jalarvo</keyname><forenames>N H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xfc;ckel</keyname><forenames>Th</forenames></author></authors><title>Hyperfine and crystal field interactions in multiferroic HoCrO${_3}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures, published in J. Phys.: Condens. Matter</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Condensed Matter, vol. 28, 47, 476001, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/47/476001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a comprehensive specific heat and inelastic neutron scattering
study to explore the possible origin of multiferroicity in HoCrO$_3$. We have
performed specific heat measurements in the temperature range 100 mK - 290 K
and inelastic neutron scattering measurements were performed in the temperature
range 1.5 - 200 K. From the specific heat data we determined hyperfine
splitting at 22.5(2) $\mu$eV and crystal field transitions at 1.379(5) meV,
10.37(4) meV, 15.49(9) meV and 23.44(9) meV, indicating the existence of strong
hyperfine and crystal field interactions in HoCrO$_3$. Further, an effective
hyperfine field is determined to be 600(3) T. The quasielastic scattering
observed in the inelastic scattering data and a large linear term
$\gamma=6.3(8)$ mJmol$^{-1}$K$^{-2}$ in the specific heat is attributed to the
presence of short range exchange interactions, which is understood to be
contributing to the observed ferroelectricity. Further the nuclear and magnetic
entropies were computed to be, $\sim$$17.2$ Jmol$^{-1}$K$^{-1}$ and $\sim$34
Jmol$^{-1}$K$^{-1}$, respectively. The entropy values are in excellent
agreement with the limiting theoretical values. An anomaly is observed in peak
position of the temperature dependent crystal field spectra around 60 K, at the
same temperature an anomaly in the pyroelectric current is reported. From this
we could elucidate a direct correlation between the crystal electric field
excitations of Ho$^{3+}$ and ferroelectricity in HoCrO$_3$. Our present study
along with recent reports confirm that HoCrO$_3$, and $R$CrO$_3$ ($R=$ Rare
earth) in general, possess more than one driving force for the ferroelectricity
and multiferroicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00998</id><created>2016-09-04</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tortello</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colonna</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernal</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novara</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giorgis</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggio</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerra</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saracco</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonnelli</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fina</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of thermal annealing on the heat transfer properties of reduced
  graphite oxide flakes: a nanoscale characterization via scanning thermal
  microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Carbon volume 109, November 2016, 390-401</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2016.08.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper reports on the thermal properties of reduced graphite oxide (RGO)
flakes, studied by means of scanning thermal microscopy (SThM). This technique
was demonstrated to allow thermal characterization of the flakes with a spatial
resolution of the order of a few tens of nanometers, while recording nanoscale
topography at the same time. Several individual RGO flakes were analyzed by
SThM, both as obtained after conventional thermal reduction and after a
subsequent annealing at 1700{\deg}C. Significant differences in the thermal
maps were observed between pristine and annealed flakes, reflecting higher heat
dissipation on annealed RGO flakes compared with pristine ones. This result was
correlated with the reduction of RGO structure defectiveness. In particular, a
substantial reduction of oxidized groups and sp3 carbons upon annealing was
proven by X-ray photoelectron and Raman spectroscopies, while the increase of
crystalline order was demonstrated by X-ray diffraction, in terms of higher
correlation lengths both along and perpendicular to the graphene planes.
Results presented in this paper provide experimental evidence for the
qualitative correlation between the defectiveness of graphene-related materials
and their thermal conductivity, which is clearly crucial for the exploitation
of these materials into thermally conductive nanocomposites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03650</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aghamohammadi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahoney</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crutchfield</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extreme Quantum Advantage when Simulating Strongly Coupled Classical
  Systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.CC cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures;
  http://csc.ucdavis.edu/~cmg/compmech/pubs/isingcql.htm; Correct algebraic
  error</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical stochastic processes can be generated by quantum simulators instead
of the more standard classical ones, such as hidden Markov models. One reason
for using quantum simulators is that they generally require less memory than
their classical counterparts. Here, we examine this quantum advantage for
strongly coupled spin systems---the Dyson-like one-dimensional Ising spin chain
with variable interaction length. We find that the advantage scales with both
interaction range and temperature, growing without bound as interaction
increases. Thus, quantum systems can very efficiently simulate strongly coupled
classical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04047</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sablikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukhanov</keyname><forenames>Aleksei A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical transitions in two-dimensional topological insulators with point
  defects</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica B: Condensed Matter, v. 503, pp. 1-6 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2016.09.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nontrivial properties of electronic states in topological insulators are
inherent not only to the surface and boundary states, but to bound states
localized at structure defects as well. We clarify how the unusual properties
of the defect-induced bound states are manifested in optical absorption spectra
in two-dimensional topological insulators. The calculations are carried out for
defects with short-range potential. We find that the defects give rise to the
appearance of specific features in the absorption spectrum, which are an
inherent property of topological insulators. They have the form of two or three
absorption peaks that are due to intracenter transitions between electron-like
and hole-like bound states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04119</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpov</keyname><forenames>Evgueni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pilyavets</keyname><forenames>Oleg V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerf</keyname><forenames>Nicolas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical capacity of phase-sensitive Gaussian quantum channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The full solution of the optimization problem giving the Gaussian capacity of
the single-mode fiducial Gaussian quantum channel is provided. Since it was
shown that the Gaussian capacity of an arbitrary (phase-sensitive or
insensitive) single-mode Gaussian quantum channel is equal to the Gaussian
capacity of this fiducial channel, the solution presented in this work can be
regarded as universal. The analytical study of this solution, below and above
the energy threshold, shows that the dependence of the Gaussian capacity on the
environment noise squeezing is not monotonic. In particular, the capacity may
have a saddle point, one or two extrema at finite squeezing, or be a
monotonically increasing function of the squeezing parameter. The exact
dependence is defined by the determinant of the noise covariance matrix and by
the transmissivity (or gain) of the fiducial Gaussian channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04756</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Egeland</keyname><forenames>Ricky</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soon</keyname><forenames>Willie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baliunas</keyname><forenames>Sallie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pevtsov</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henry</keyname><forenames>Gregory W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamo Sensitivity in Solar Analogs with 50 Years of Ca II H &amp; K
  Activity</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. To appear in the proceedings of &quot;The 19th
  Cambridge Workshop on Cool Stars, Stellar Systems, and the Sun&quot; (ed. G. A.
  Feiden), Uppsala, Sweden, 06-10 June 2016</comments><doi>10.5281/zenodo.154118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Sun has a steady 11-year cycle in magnetic activity most well-known by
the rising and falling in the occurrence of dark sunspots on the solar disk in
visible bandpasses. The 11-year cycle is also manifest in the variations of
emission in the Ca II H &amp; K line cores, due to non-thermal (i.e. magnetic)
heating in the lower chromosphere. The large variation in Ca II H &amp; K emission
allows for study of the patterns of long-term variability in other stars thanks
to synoptic monitoring with the Mount Wilson Observatory HK photometers
(1966-2003) and Lowell Observatory Solar-Stellar Spectrograph (1994-present).
Overlapping measurements for a set of 27 nearby solar-analog (spectral types
G0-G5) stars were used to calibrate the two instruments and construct time
series of magnetic activity up to 50 years in length. Precise properties of
fundamental importance to the dynamo are available from Hipparcos, the
Geneva-Copenhagen Survey, and CHARA interferometry. Using these long time
series and measurements of fundamental properties, we do a comparative study of
stellar &quot;twins&quot; to explore the sensitivity of the stellar dynamo to small
changes to structure, rotation, and composition. We also compare this sample to
the Sun and find hints that the regular periodic variability of the solar cycle
may be rare among its nearest neighbors in parameter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04829</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Crespo</keyname><forenames>N. &#xc1;lvarez</forenames><affiliation>UniTO-INFN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Masetti</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>INAF-IASF-BO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UniRomaTRE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Landoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>INAF</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pati&#xf1;o-&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>INAOE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Massaro</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UniTO-INFN-TO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>D'Abrusco</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paggi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chavushyan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>INAOE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jim&#xe9;nez-Bail&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>UNAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Torrealba</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>INAOE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Latronico</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>INFN-TO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>La Franca</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UniRomaTRE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Howard A.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tosti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>UniPG</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical Spectroscopic Observations of Gamma-ray Blazar Candidates. V.
  TNG, KPNO, and OAN Observations of Blazar Candidates of Uncertain Type in the
  Northern Hemisphere</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>21 pages, 26 figures, 3 tables, pre-proof version, published on the
  Astronomical Journal. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1503.04202</comments><journal-ref>2016 AJ, 151, 32</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-6256/151/2/32</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extragalactic $\gamma$-ray sky is dominated by emission from blazars, a
peculiar class of active galactic nuclei (AGNs). Many of the $\gamma$-ray
sources included in Fermi -Large Area Telescope Third Source catalog (3FGL) are
classified as a blazar candidate of uncertain type (BCU) because there is no
optical spectra available in the literature to confirm their nature. In 2013 we
started a spectroscopic campaign to look for the optical counterparts of the
BCUs and of the Unidentified $\gamma$-ray Sources. The main goal of our
investigation is to confirm the blazar nature of these sources having peculiar
properties as compact radio emission and/or selected on the basis of their
infrared (IR) colors. Whenever possible we also determine their redshifts. Here
we present the results of the observations carried out in the Northern
hemisphere in 2013 and 2014 at Telescopio Nazionale Galilleo (TNG), Kitt Peak
National Observatory (KPNO) and Observatorio Astron\'omico Nacional (OAN) in
San Pedro M\'artir. In this paper we describe the optical spectra of 25
sources. We confirmed that all the 15 BCUs observed in our campaign and
included in our sample are blazars and we estimated the redshift for 3 of them.
In addition, we present the spectra for 3 sources classified as BL Lacs in the
literature but with no optical spectra available to date. We found that one of
them is a quasar (QSO) at a redshift $z$ = 0.208 and the other 2 are BL Lacs.
Moreover, we also present 7 new spectra for known blazars listed in the
Roma-BZCAT having an uncertain redshift or being classified as BL Lac
candidates. We found that one of them, 5BZB J0724+2621 is a `changing look'
blazar. According to the spectrum available in the literature it was classified
as a BL Lac but in our observation we clearly detected a broad emission line
that lead to classify this source as a QSO at $z$=1.17.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04850</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Csete</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szenes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maraczi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banhelyi</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csendes</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic structure integrated single-photon detectors optimized to
  maximize polarization contrast</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical optimization was performed via COMSOL Multiphysics to maximize the
polarization contrast of superconducting nanowire single photon detectors
(SNSPDs). SNSPDs were integrated with four different types of one-dimensional
periodic plasmonic structures capable of mediating p-polarized photon
selectivity to the niobium-nitride superconducting nanowire pattern.
Optimization with two different criteria regarding the maximal tilting resulted
in wavelength-scaled periodic integrated structures, which have different
geometrical parameters, and exhibit different polar angle dependent optical
response and dispersion characteristics, as well as accompanying near-field
phenomena at the extrema. Polarization contrast of 6.37*10^2 and 3.28*10^2 -
6.86*10^11 and 1.42*10^11 - 1.81*10^13 and 7.87*10^12 - 1.90*10^3 and 1.15*10^5
can be achieved in nanocavity-, nanocavity-deflector-,
nanocavity-double-deflector-, nanocavity-trench-array-integrated P-SNSPDs
optimized with 85 degree and 80 degree criterion regarding the maximal tilting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04859</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Caceres</keyname><forenames>Rajmonda S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiner</keyname><forenames>Leah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Matthew C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>William M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Model Selection Framework for Graph-based data</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphs are powerful abstractions for capturing complex relationships in
diverse application settings. An active area of research focuses on theoretical
models that define the generative mechanism of a graph. Yet given the
complexity and inherent noise in real datasets, it is still very challenging to
identify the best model for a given observed graph. We discuss a framework for
graph model selection that leverages a long list of graph topological
properties and a random forest classifier to learn and classify different graph
instances. We fully characterize the discriminative power of our approach as we
sweep through the parameter space of two generative models, the Erdos-Renyi and
the stochastic block model. We show that our approach gets very close to known
theoretical bounds and we provide insight on which topological features play a
critical discriminating role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04881</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Akbar</keyname><forenames>Fathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>Mikrajuddin</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical Solutions for Bending Of Fireworks and Similarities with the
  Solution of Electromagnetic Wave Diffraction</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we examine more deeply about the bending mechanism of
rod-shaped fireworks which burned from the free end. We derived new analytic
equations. Surprisingly, we obtained the bending patterns are similar to the
cornu spiral. With a few simple steps we proved that positions of points
throughout the fireworks are given by Fresnel integrals, C(x) and S(x), which
are generally found in phenomena of electromagnetic wave diffraction. Although
we deeply discussed bending of fireworks rods, however the proposed method is
likely to explain any phenomena in nature related to an evolving length scale
associated with some material that becomes progressively stiff or dry, such as
the growth of resin exuded from trees.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04882</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Vaquero</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svalgaard</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>V. M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clette</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lef&#xe8;vre</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallego</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arlt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aparicio</keyname><forenames>A. J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>J. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howe</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Revised Collection of Sunspot Group Numbers</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>27 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in Solar Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-0982-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a revised collection of the number of sunspot groups from 1610 to
the present. This new collection is based on the work of Hoyt and Schatten
(Solar Phys. 179, 189, 1998). The main changes are the elimination of a
considerable number of observations during the Maunder Minimum (hereafter, MM)
and the inclusion of several long series of observations. Numerous minor
changes are also described. Moreover, we have calculated the active-day
percentage during the MM from this new collection as a reliable index of the
solar activity. Thus, the level of solar activity obtained in this work is
greater than the level obtained using the original Hoyt and Schatten data,
although it remains compatible with a grand minimum of solar activity. The new
collection is available in digital format.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04903</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Tanmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Noseong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subrahmanian</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ensemble-Based Algorithms to Detect Disjoint and Overlapping Communities
  in Networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>5 figures, 5 tables, 8 pages, 2016 IEEE/ACM International Conference
  on Advances in Social Networks Analysis (ASONAM), San Fransisco, USA</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given a set ${\cal AL}$ of community detection algorithms and a graph $G$ as
inputs, we propose two ensemble methods $\mathtt{EnDisCO}$ and $\mathtt{MeDOC}$
that (respectively) identify disjoint and overlapping communities in $G$.
$\mathtt{EnDisCO}$ transforms a graph into a latent feature space by leveraging
multiple base solutions and discovers disjoint community structure.
$\mathtt{MeDOC}$ groups similar base communities into a meta-community and
detects both disjoint and overlapping community structures. Experiments are
conducted at different scales on both synthetically generated networks as well
as on several real-world networks for which the underlying ground-truth
community structure is available. Our extensive experiments show that both
algorithms outperform state-of-the-art non-ensemble algorithms by a significant
margin. Moreover, we compare $\mathtt{EnDisCO}$ and $\mathtt{MeDOC}$ with a
recent ensemble method for disjoint community detection and show that our
approaches achieve superior performance. To the best of our knowledge,
$\mathtt{MeDOC}$ is the first ensemble approach for overlapping community
detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04915</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Monier</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gebran</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Royer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>HR8844: A new hot Am star ?</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>3 pages, SF2A 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using one archival high dispersion high quality spectrum of HR8844 (A0V)
obtained with the echelle spectrograph SOPHIE at Observatoire de Haute
Provence, we show that this star is not a superficially normal A0V star as
hitherto thought. The model atmosphere and spectrum synthesis modeling of the
spectrum of HR8844 reveals large departures of its abundances from the solar
composition. We report here on our first determinations of the elemental
abundances of 41 elements in the atmosphere of HR8844. Most of the light
elements are underabundant whereas the very heavy elements are overabundant in
HR8844.This interesting new chemically peculiar star could be a hybrid object
between the HgMn stars and the Am stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04925</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zelekson</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of antitropic electron beams by self-generated electric
  field. Kinetic description</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper makes use of a one-dimensional kinetic model to investigate the
nonlinear longitudinal dynamics of electron beams generated in the plasma under
the influence of a self-generated electric field. It is expressed as where is a
wave potential, , and charge particle distribution functions satisfy the Vlasov
equation. It is proved that its correct solution is characterized by sudden
change in the resonant part of the distribution function. Hence, in particular,
the incorrectness of the established in the literature point of view follows
that the fast, with velocities over V, and slow, with velocities under V,
trapped particles are described by the same distribution function. Also for the
first time it is shown that the self-generated strong electric field always
produces antitropic electron beams with the velocities much larger than the
value V, including the cold plasma limit. The possibility of implementing a new
class of self-consistent wave structures with a nonzero average potential is
shown. Maximum possible amplitude of a self-generated electric field in a
stationary collisionless plasma is determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04930</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Sebastian K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gold Photoluminescence Wavelength and Polarization Engineering</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate engineering of the spectral content and polarization of
photoluminescence (PL) from arrayed gold nanoparticles atop a
subwavelength-thin dielectric spacer and optically-thick gold film, a
configuration that supports gap-surface plasmon resonances (GSPRs). Choice of
shapes and dimensions of gold nanoparticles influences the GSPR wavelength and
polarization characteristics, thereby allowing us to enhance and spectrally
mold the plasmon-assisted PL while simultaneously controlling its polarization.
In order to understand the underlying physics behind the plasmon-enhanced PL,
we develop a simple model that faithfully reproduces all features observed in
our experiments showing also good quantitative agreement for the PL enhancement
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04934</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozkan</keyname><forenames>A</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>T</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Britun</keyname><forenames>N</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Snyders</keyname><forenames>R</forenames><affiliation>ChIPS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogaerts</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author></authors><title>DBD in burst mode: solution for more efficient CO2 conversion?</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology, IOP Publishing, 2016, 25
  (5), pp.055005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0963-0252/25/5/055005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CO2 conversion into value-added products has gained significant interest over
the few last years, as the greenhouse gas concentrations constantly increase
due to anthropogenic activities. Here we report on experiments for CO2
conversion by means of a cold atmospheric plasma using a cylindrical flowing
dielectric barrier discharge (DBD) reactor. A detailed comparison of this DBD
ignited in a so-called burst mode (i.e. where an AC voltage is applied during a
limited amount of time) and pure AC mode is carried out to evaluate their
effect on the conversion of CO2 as well as on the energy efficiency. Decreasing
the duty cycle in the burst mode from 100% (i.e. corresponding to pure AC mode)
to 40% leads to a rise in the conversion from 16--26% and to a rise in the
energy efficiency from 15 to 23%. Based on a detailed electrical analysis, we
show that the conversion correlates with the features of the microfilaments.
Moreover, the root-mean-square voltage in the burst mode remains constant as a
function of the process time for the duty cycles \textless{}70%, while a higher
duty cycle or the usual pure AC mode leads to a clear voltage decay by more
than 500 V, over approximately 90 s, before reaching a steady state regime. The
higher plasma voltage in the burst mode yields a higher electric field. This
causes the increasing the electron energy, and therefore their involvement in
the CO2 dissociation process, which is an additional explanation for the higher
CO2 conversion and energy efficiency in the burst mode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04935</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozkan</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogaerts</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>How do the barrier thickness and dielectric material influence the
  filamentary mode and CO2 conversion in a flowing DBD?</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology, IOP Publishing, 2016, 25
  (4), pp.045016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0963-0252/25/4/045016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dielectric barrier discharges (DBDs) are commonly used to generate cold
plasmas at atmospheric pressure. Whatever their configuration (tubular or
planar), the presence of a dielectric barrier is mandatory to prevent too much
charge build up in the plasma and the formation of a thermal arc. In this
article, the role of the barrier thickness (2.0, 2.4 and 2.8 mm) and of the
kind of dielectric material (alumina, mullite, pyrex, quartz) is investigated
on the filamentary behavior in the plasma and on the CO2 conversion in a
tubular flowing DBD, by means of mass spectrometry measurements correlated with
electrical characterization and IR imaging. Increasing the barrier thickness
decreases the capacitance, while preserving the electrical charge. As a result,
the voltage over the dielectric increases and a larger number of
microdischarges is generated, which enhances the CO2 conversion. Furthermore,
changing the dielectric material of the barrier, while keeping the same
geometry and dimensions, also affects the CO2 conversion. The highest CO2
conversion and energy efficiency are obtained for quartz and alumina, thus not
following the trend of the relative permittivity. From the electrical
characterization, we clearly demonstrate that the most important parameters are
the somewhat higher effective plasma voltage (yielding a somewhat higher
electric field and electron energy in the plasma) for quartz, as well as the
higher plasma current (and thus larger electron density) and the larger number
of microdischarge filaments (mainly for alumina, but also for quartz). The
latter could be correlated to the higher surface roughness for alumina and to
the higher voltage over the dielectric for quartz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04936</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Collette</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author></authors><title>Reactivity of water vapor in an atmospheric argon flowing post-discharge
  plasma torch</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Plasma Sources Science and Technology, IOP Publishing, 2016, 25
  (2), pp.025014</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0963-0252/25/2/025014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reactivity of water vapor introduced in the flowing post-discharge of an
RF atmospheric plasma torch is investigated through electrical
characterization, optical emission spectroscopy and mass spectrometry
measurements. Due to the technical features of the plasma torch, the
post-discharge can be considered as divided into two regions: an inner region
(inside the plasma torch device) where the water vapor is injected and an outer
region which directly interacts with the ambient air. The main reactions
induced by the injection of water vapor are identified as well as those
indicative of the influence of the ambient air. Plausible pathways allowing the
production of H, OH, O radicals and H2O2 are discussed as well as reactions
potentially responsible for inhomogeneities and for a low DC current measured
in the flowing post-discharge. Keywords: atmospheric post-discharge, H2O plasma
reactivity, RF plasma torch
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04942</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Poenaru</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gherghescu</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Linearly increasing radius of the light fragment during the spontaneous
  fission of $^{282}$Cn</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures and 2 tables. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1609.00847</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous article published in Phys. Rev. C 94 (2016) 014309 we have
shown for the first time that the best dynamical trajectory during the
deformation toward fission of the superheavy nucleus $^{286}$Fl is a linearly
increasing radius of the light fragment, $R_2$. This macroscopic-microscopic
result reminds us about the $\alpha $ or cluster preformation at the nuclear
surface, assumed already in 1928, and proved microscopically many times. This
time we give more detailed arguments for the neighboring nucleus $^{282}$Cn.
Also similar figures are presented for heavy nuclei $^{240}$Pu and $^{252}$Cf.
The deep minimum of total deformation energy near the surface is shown for the
first time as a strong argument for cluster preformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04966</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Chao</keyname><forenames>Jingyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Mei</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon polarization tensor in a magnetized plasma system</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the photon polarization tensor at finite temperature in the
presence of a static and homogeneous external magnetic field. In our scheme,
the Matsubara frequency summation is performed after Poisson summation, which
will be taken easily and convergent quickly in the frame of proper time
representation. Moreover, the dependence of Landau levels is expressed
explicitly. It demonstrates the convergence of summing Landau levels as it has
to be. Consequently, there is no necessary to truncate the Landau level in a
numerical estimation. At zero temperature, the Lowest Landau Level (LLL)
approximation is analytically satisfied for the imaginary parts of the vacuum
photon polarization tensor. Our results examine that, the LLL approximation is
not enough for the thermal photon polarization tensor, it gains the
contribution not only from the lowest Landau level but also up to the
finite-$n$ levels. Such large imaginary ones only show up at finite
temperatures, which is the so called Landau damping. It originates from the
absorption of soft fields by hard plasma constituents, which is a universal
feature of plasma systems. Finally, it was argued that the summation of
Matsubara frequency is not commuted with Landau level ones, such conjecture is
excluded in our calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04969</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Maccarrone</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paffuti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Some comments on the electrostatic forces between circular electrodes</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the force between two circular electrodes in different
configurations. A formula analogous to Kelvin's formula for the spheres is
given in the case of equal disks held at the same potential and when one plate
is earthed. An expression for the force at short distance between two
arbitrarily charged disks is found: the generic case shows a logarithmic
repulsive force, also for disks carrying charges of opposite sign. Some
numerical computations support the results. A classification for the possible
behaviors of the force is proposed on the basis of a decomposition of the
capacitance matrix. It is shown that the forces depend strongly on the
dimensionality of the contact zone between the conductors. The analysis is
supported by a numerical computation carried for the case of two disks of
different radii.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04976</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Boschker</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhaoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huijben</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koster</keyname><forenames>Gertjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rijnders</keyname><forenames>Guus</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface Engineering in La0.67Sr0.33MnO3-SrTiO3 Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>This will be published as a chapter in the upcoming book Oxide
  interfaces - charge and spin transport - Fundamentals and Applications. 29
  pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interface engineering is an extremely useful tool for systematically
investigating materials and the various ways materials interact with each
other. We describe different interface engineering strategies designed to
reveal the origin of the electric and magnetic dead-layer at La0.67Sr0.33MnO3
interfaces. La0.67Sr0.33MnO3 is a key example of a strongly correlated
peroskite oxide material in which a subtle balance of competing interactions
gives rise to a ferromagnetic metallic groundstate. This balance, however, is
easily disrupted at interfaces. We systematically vary the dopant profile, the
disorder and the oxygen octahedra rotations at the interface to investigate
which mechanism is responsible for the dead layer. We find that the magnetic
dead layer can be completely eliminated by compositional interface engineering
such that the polar discontinuity at the interface is removed. This, however,
leaves the electrical dead-layer largely intact. We find that deformations in
the oxygen octahedra network at the interface are the dominant cause for the
electrical dead layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04996</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>del Rosso</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grazzi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Celli</keyname><forenames>Milva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colognesi</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Sakai</keyname><forenames>Victoria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulivi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Refined Structure of Metastable Ice XVII from Neutron Diffraction
  Measurements</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structure of the recently identified metastable ice XVII, obtained by
release of hydrogen from the C$_0$ D$_2$O-H$_2$ compound (filled ice), has been
accurately measured by neutron powder diffraction. The diffraction pattern is
indexed with a hexagonal cell and can be refined with space group $P6_122$ so
to obtain accurate values of the oxygen and deuterium positions. The values of
the lattice constants at three temperatures between 25 to 100 K are reported,
and their behavior is compared with that of ice Ih. Ice XVII is a porous solid
that, if exposed to H$_2$ gas, may adsorb a substantial amount of it.
Monitoring this effect at a constant temperature of 50 K, we have observed that
the two lattice constants show opposite behavior, $a$ increases and $c$
decreases, with the volume showing a linear increase. At temperatures higher
than 130 K the metastability of this form of porous ice is lost and the sample
transforms into ice Ih.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04998</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Harz</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klasen</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kova&#x159;&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>Karol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steppeler</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting the neutralino relic density in the MSSM more precisely</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages. Contribution to the proceedings of the 38th International
  Conference of High Energy Physics (ICHEP), Chicago, Aug. 3-10, 2016</comments><report-no>MS-TP-16-25, LAPTH-Conf-037/16</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dark matter relic density being a powerful observable to constrain models
of new physics, the recent experimental progress calls for more precise
theoretical predictions. On the particle physics side, improvements are to be
made in the calculation of the (co)annihilation cross-section of the dark
matter particle. We present the project DM@NLO which aims at calculating the
neutralino (co)annihilation cross-section in the MSSM including radiative
corrections in QCD. In the present document, we briefly review selected results
for different (co)annihilation processes. We then discuss the estimation of the
associated theory uncertainty obtained by varying the renormalization scale.
Finally, perspectives are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04999</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Buha</keyname><forenames>Joka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaspari</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>Antonio Esau Del Rio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonaccorso</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manna</keyname><forenames>Liberato</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Stability and Anisotropic Sublimation of Two-Dimensional
  Colloidal Bi2Te3 and Bi2Se3 Nanocrystals</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures, May 27, 2016 Letter pubs.acs.org/NanoLett Nano
  Letters, May 27, 2016</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b01116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The structural and compositional stabilities of two dimensional 2D Bi2Te3 and
Bi2Se3 nanocrystals, produced by both colloidal synthesis and by liquid phase
exfoliation, were studied by in situ transmission electron microscopy TEM
during annealing at temperatures between 350 and 500 C. The sublimation process
induced by annealing is structurally and chemically anisotropic and takes place
through the preferential dismantling of the prismatic 011-0 type planes, and
through the preferential sublimation of Te or Se.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05012</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Laib</keyname><forenames>Mohamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanevski</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial Patterns of Wind Speed Distributions in Switzerland</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents an initial exploration of high frequency records of
extreme wind speed in two steps. The first consists in finding the suitable
extreme distribution for $120$ measuring stations in Switzerland, by comparing
three known distributions: Weibull, Gamma, and Generalized extreme value. This
comparison serves as a basis for the second step which applies a spatial
modelling by using Extreme Learning Machine. The aim is to model distribution
parameters by employing a high dimensional input space of topographical
information. The knowledge of probability distribution gives a comprehensive
information and a global overview of wind phenomena. Through this study, a
flexible and a simple modelling approach is presented, which can be generalized
to almost extreme environmental data for risk assessment and to model renewable
energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05018</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lionni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivasseau</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Intermediate Field Representation for Positive Matrix and Tensor
  Interactions</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 21 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce an intermediate field representation for random
matrices and random tensors with positive (stable) interactions of degree
higher than 4. This representation respects the symmetry axis responsible for
positivity. It is non-perturbative and allows to prove that such models are
Borel-Le Roy summable of the appropriate order in their coupling constant.
However we have not been able yet to associate a convergent Loop Vertex
Expansion to this representation, hence our Borel summability result is not of
the optimal expected form when the size N of the matrix or of the tensor tends
to infinity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05027</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zaccone</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terentjev</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herling</keyname><forenames>T. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knowles</keyname><forenames>T. P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aleksandrova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terentjev</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetics of fragmentation and dissociation of two-strand protein
  filaments: Coarse-grained simulations and experiments</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 105101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962366</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While a significant body of investigations have been focused on the process
of protein self-assembly, much less is understood about the reverse process of
a filament breaking due to thermal motion into smaller fragments, or
depolymerization of subunits from the filament ends. Indirect evidence for
actin and amyloid filament fragmentation has been reported, although the
phenomenon has never been directly observed either experimentally or in
simulations. Here we report the direct observation of filament depolymerization
and breakup in a minimal, calibrated model of coarse-grained molecular
simulation. We quantify the orders of magnitude by which the depolymerization
rate from the filament ends $k_\mathrm{off}$ is larger than fragmentation rate
$k_{-}$ and establish the law $k_\mathrm{off}/k_- = \exp [( \varepsilon_\| -
\varepsilon_\bot) / k_\mathrm{B}T ] = \exp [0.5 \varepsilon / k_\mathrm{B}T ]$,
which accounts for the topology and energy of bonds holding the filament
together. This mechanism and the order-of-magnitude predictions are well
supported by direct experimental measurements of depolymerization of insulin
amyloid filaments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05041</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Aharonov</keyname><forenames>Yakir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popescu</keyname><forenames>Sandu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rohrlich</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>On conservation laws in quantum mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We raise fundamental questions about the very meaning of conservation laws in
quantum mechanics and we argue that the standard way of defining conservation
laws, while perfectly valid as far as it goes, misses essential features of
nature and has to be revisited and extended.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05066</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Zenin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andryieuski</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malureanu</keyname><forenames>Radu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radko</keyname><forenames>Ilya P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Valentyn S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramotnev</keyname><forenames>Dmitri K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrinenko</keyname><forenames>Andrei V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Boosting local field enhancement by on-chip nanofocusing and
  impedance-matched plasmonic antennas</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b03593</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strongly confined surface plasmon-polariton modes can be used for efficiently
delivering the electromagnetic energy to nano-sized volumes by reducing the
cross sections of propagating modes far beyond the diffraction limit, i.e., by
nanofocusing. This process results in significant local-field enhancement that
can advantageously be exploited in modern optical nanotechnologies, including
signal processing, biochemical sensing, imaging and spectroscopy. Here, we
propose, analyze, and experimentally demonstrate on-chip nanofocusing followed
by impedance-matched nanowire antenna excitation in the end-fire geometry at
telecom wavelengths. Numerical and experimental evidences of the efficient
excitation of dipole and quadrupole (dark) antenna modes are provided,
revealing underlying physical mechanisms and analogies with the operation of
plane-wave Fabry-P\'erot interferometers. The unique combination of efficient
nanofocusing and nanoantenna resonant excitation realized in our experiments
offers a major boost to the field intensity enhancement up to $\sim 12000$,
with the enhanced field being evenly distributed over the gap volume of
$30\times 30\times 10\ {\rm nm}^3$, and promises thereby a variety of useful
on-chip functionalities within sensing, nonlinear spectroscopy and signal
processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05069</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Grumitt</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sloan</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Measures in Mutlifield Inflation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the classical dynamics of multifield inflation models with
quadratic potentials. Such models are shown to have inflationary attractors in
phase space, consistent with the stretching of phase space trajectories along
the volume factor of the universe during inflation. Using the symplectic
structure associated with Hamiltonian systems we form a measure on the phase
space, as initially proposed by Gibbons, Hawking and Stewart. This is used to
calculate lower bounds on the probabilities of observational agreement (i.e.
the probability the model gives a value for the spectral index within the
region $n_{s}=0.968\pm{0.006}$) for equal mass two and three field models with
quadratic potentials, giving values of 0.982 and 0.997 respectively. We derive
the measure for a general $N$-field model and argue that as the number of
fields approaches infinity, the probability of observational agreement
approaches one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05072</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bagnaschi</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author></authors><title>Matching uncertainties in the prediction of the Higgs boson transverse
  momentum in the SM and beyond</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of LHCP2016</comments><report-no>DESY 16-173</report-no><journal-ref>PoS(LHCP2016)077</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of our recent study (arXiv:1510.08850) of the
theoretical uncertainties that affect the predictions for the Higgs-boson
transverse-momentum in gluon fusion when fixed- and all-order results are
matched. Our investigation consists of a twofold analysis: first we present a
detailed comparison of two recently introduced prescriptions for the
determination of the matching scale (arXiv:1409.0531, arXiv:1505.00735), then
we apply the results of these methods to three widely used matching frameworks,
namely the aMC@NLO and POWHEG Monte Carlo approaches and analytic resummation.
The results of our study are applied to the production of the SM Higgs boson
and of the neutral Higgs bosons of the Two-Higgs-Doublet Model in a variety of
scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05073</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>McKemmish</keyname><forenames>Laura K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurchenko</keyname><forenames>Sergei N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennyson</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio calculations to support accurate modelling of the rovibronic
  spectroscopy calculations of vanadium monoxide (VO)</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Molecular Physics, 2016</comments><doi>10.1080/00268976.2016.1225994</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate knowledge of the rovibronic near-infrared and visible spectra of
vanadium monoxide (VO) is very important for studies of cool stellar and hot
planetary atmospheres. Here, the required ab initio dipole moment and
spin-orbit coupling curves for VO are produced. This data forms the basis of a
new VO line list considering 13 different electronic states and containing over
277 million transitions. Open shell transition, metal diatomics are challenging
species to model through ab initio quantum mechanics due to the large number of
low-lying electronic states, significant spin-orbit coupling and strong static
and dynamic electron correlation. Multi-reference configuration interaction
methodologies using orbitals from a complete active space self-consistent-field
(CASSCF) calculation are the standard technique for these systems. We use
different state-specific or minimal-state CASSCF orbitals for each electronic
state to maximise the calculation accuracy. The off-diagonal dipole moment
controls the intensity of electronic transitions. We test finite-field
off-diagonal dipole moments, but found that (1) the accuracy of the excitation
energies were not sufficient to allow accurate dipole moments to be evaluated
and (2) computer time requirements for perpendicular transitions were
prohibitive. The best off-diagonal dipole moments are calculated using
wavefunctions with different CASSCF orbitals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05076</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avellini</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kriegel</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaspari</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almeida</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertoni</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scotognella</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pellegrino</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manna</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Colloidal CuFeS2 Nanocrystals: Intermediate Fe d-Band Leads to High
  Photothermal Conversion Efficiency</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, Chemistry of Materials, 31-May-2016</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.chemmater.6b02192</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the colloidal hot-injection synthesis of phase-pure nanocrystals
(NCs) of a highly abundant mineral, chalcopyrite (CuFeS2). Absorption bands
centered at around 480 and 950 nm, spanning almost the entire visible and near
infrared regions, encompass their optical extinction characteristics. These
peaks are ascribable to electronic transitions from the valence band (VB) to
the empty intermediate band (IB), located in the fundamental gap and mainly
composed of Fe 3d orbitals. Laser-irradiation (at 808 nm) of an aqueous
suspension of CuFeS2 NCs exhibited significant heating, with a photothermal
conversion efficiency of 49%. Such efficient heating is ascribable to the
carrier relaxation within the broad IB band (owing to the indirect VB-IB gap),
as corroborated by transient absorption measurements. The intense absorption
and high photothermal transduction efficiency (PTE) of these NCs in the
so-called biological window (650-900 nm) makes them suitable for photothermal
therapy as demonstrated by tumor cell annihilation upon laser irradiation. The
otherwise harmless nature of these NCs in dark conditions was confirmed by in
vitro toxicity tests on two different cell lines. The presence of the deep Fe
levels constituting the IB is the origin of such enhanced PTE, which can be
used to design other high performing NC photothermal agents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05098</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Louchet</keyname><forenames>Francois</forenames></author></authors><title>Weather instabilities as a warning sign for a nearby climatic tipping
  point?</title><categories>physics.ao-ph nlin.AO</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure. Original paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using in a simple way the theory of non linear dynamical systems, we show
that increasing climatic instabilities may be a qualitative warning sign for
the occurrence of a nearby bifurcation, yielding a discontinuous and sudden
climate tipping towards an unknown and unpredictable state. The possibility of
an accurate prediction of the occurrence time of such a transition is also
discussed in terms of the approach of a critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05099</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cameron</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dormy</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>A systematic method to enforce conservativity on semi-Lagrangian schemes</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Semi-Lagrangian schemes have proven to be very efficient to model advection
problems. However most semi-Lagrangian schemes are not conservative. Here, a
systematic method is introduced in order to enforce the conservative property
on a semi-Lagrangian advection scheme. This method is shown to generate
conservative schemes with the same linear stability range and the same order of
accuracy as the initial advection scheme from which they are derived. We used a
criterion based on the column-balance property of the schemes to assess their
conservativity property. We show that this approach can be used with large CFL
numbers and third order schemes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05100</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Wai-shing</forenames></author></authors><title>Schmidt number of bipartite and multipartite states under local
  projections</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Schmidt number is a fundamental parameter characterizing the properties
of quantum states, and the local projections are a fundamental operation in
quantum physics. We investigate the relation between the Schmidt numbers of
bipartite states and their projected states. We show that there exist bipartite
positive-partial-transpose (PPT) entangled states of any given Schmidt number.
We further construct the notion of joint Schmidt number for multipartite
states, and its relation with the Schmidt number of bipartite reduced density
operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05102</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>The STAR Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>The CBM Collaboration eTOF Group</keyname></author></authors><title>Physics Program for the STAR/CBM eTOF Upgrade</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 19 figures, detector upgrade proposal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The STAR Collaboration and the CBM Collaboration institutions: Heidelberg,
Darmstadt, CCNU, Tsinghua, and USTC propose to install an end-cap
time-of-flight upgrade (eTOF) to the STAR detector for the RHIC beam energy
scan phase II (BES-II) program in 2019 and 2020. BES-II will cover the
collision energy range 3.0 to 19.6 GeV. This is the region of interest in the
search for a critical point and first-order phase transition, identified by the
results from BES-I and by model calculations. For the collider-mode portion of
the energy scan, 7.7 to 19.6 GeV, eTOF will extend particle identification
(PID) for pions, kaons, and protons to a rapidity of 1.2, complementing the
inner Time Projection Chamber (iTPC) upgrade to the forward tracking. The
rapidity coverage for PID would extend to only 0.8 without the eTOF upgrade.
The eTOF upgrade will enable precision studies of the key bulk property
observables, essential to the BES-II search. An internal fixed-target program
will allow the energy scan to cover 3.0 to 7.7 GeV. The eTOF upgrade will
provide essential mid-rapidity PID for the 4.5 to 7.7 GeV portion of the scan
in fixed-target mode. Otherwise there would be a large energy gap in the middle
of the BES-II program. A full description of the physics provided by the eTOF
upgrade to STAR is presented in this note.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05105</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferretti</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>STAX. An Axion-like Particle Search with Microwave Photons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Contributed to the 12th Patras Workshop on Axions, WIMPs and WISPs,
  Jeju Island, South Korea, June 20 to 26, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss an improved detection scheme for a light-shining-through-wall
(LSW) experiment for axion-like particle searches. We propose to use: gyrotrons
or klystrons, which can provide extremely intense photon fluxes at frequencies
around 30 GHz; transition-edge-sensors (TES) single photon detectors in this
frequency domain, with efficiency $\approx1$; high quality factor Fabry-Perot
cavities in the microwave domain, both on the photon-axion conversion and
photon regeneration sides. We compute that present laboratory exclusion limits
on axion-like particles might be improved by at least four orders of magnitude
for axion masses $\lesssim 0.02$ meV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05109</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Gustavsson</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biferale</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Preferential sampling of helicity by isotropic helicoids</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.CD</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Fluids , vol. 1, 054201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.1.054201}</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical and numerical study on the motion of isotropic
helicoids in complex flows. These are particles whose motion is invariant under
rotations but not under mirror reflections of the particle. This is the
simplest, yet unexplored, extension of the much studied case of small spherical
particles. We show that heavy isotropic helicoids, due to the coupling between
translational and rotational degrees of freedom, preferentially sample
different helical regions in laminar or chaotic advecting flows. This opens the
way to control and engineer particles able to track complex flow structures
with potential applications to microfluidics and turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05144</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Boussarie</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pire</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallon</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoproduction of a large invariant mass $\gamma \rho$ pair at small
  momentum transfer</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, to appear in the proceedings of XXIV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subject - DIS
  2016, 11-15 April 2016, DESY Hamburg, Germany</comments><report-no>CPHT-PC039.072016, LPT-Orsay-16-59</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The collinear factorization framework allows to describe the exclusive
photoproduction of a $\gamma\,\rho$ pair in the generalized Bjorken regime in
terms of a perturbatively calculable coefficient function and universal
generalized parton distributions. The kinematics are defined by a large
invariant mass of the $\gamma \rho$ pair and a small transverse momentum of the
final nucleon. We calculate the scattering amplitude at leading order in
$\alpha_s$ and the differential cross sections for the process where the
$\rho-$meson is either longitudinally or transversely polarized, in the
kinematics of the near future Jlab experiments. Our estimate of the cross
section demonstrates that this process is measurable at JLab 12-GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05159</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Naumkin</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames><affiliation>Joint Institute of High Temperatures, Russian Academy of Sciences, Izhorskaya 13, Bd. 2, 125412 Moscow, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhukhovitskii</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames><affiliation>Joint Institute of High Temperatures, Russian Academy of Sciences, Izhorskaya 13, Bd. 2, 125412 Moscow, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Molotkov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames><affiliation>Joint Institute of High Temperatures, Russian Academy of Sciences, Izhorskaya 13, Bd. 2, 125412 Moscow, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lipaev</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames><affiliation>Joint Institute of High Temperatures, Russian Academy of Sciences, Izhorskaya 13, Bd. 2, 125412 Moscow, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fortov</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames><affiliation>Joint Institute of High Temperatures, Russian Academy of Sciences, Izhorskaya 13, Bd. 2, 125412 Moscow, Russia</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames><affiliation>Research Group Complex Plasma, DLR, Oberpfaffenhofen, 82234 Wessling, Germany, and</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Research Group Complex Plasma, DLR, Oberpfaffenhofen, 82234 Wessling, Germany, and</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morfill</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institute for Extraterrestrial Physics, D-85748 Garching, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Density distribution of a dust cloud in three-dimensional complex
  plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>37 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E, 2016, vol. 94, no. 3. p. 033204</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.033204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel method of determination of the dust particle spatial
distribution in dust clouds that form in three-dimensional (3D) complex plasmas
under microgravity conditions. The method utilizes the data obtained during the
3D scanning of a cloud and provides a reasonably good accuracy. Based on this
method, we investigate the particle density in a dust cloud realized in gas
discharge plasma in the PK-3 Plus setup onboard the International Space
Station. We find that the treated dust clouds are both anisotropic and
inhomogeneous. One can isolate two regimes, in which a stationary dust cloud
can be observed. At low pressures, the particle density decreases monotonically
with the increase of the distance from the discharge center; at higher
pressures, the density distribution has a shallow minimum. Regardless of the
regime, we detect a cusp of the distribution at the void boundary and a slowly
varying density at larger distances (in the foot region). A theoretical
interpretation of obtained results is developed that leads to reasonable
estimates of the densities for both the cusp and foot. The modified ionization
equation of state, which allows for violation of the local quasineutrality in
the cusp region, predicts the spatial distributions of ion and electron
densities to be measured in future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05168</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Chandrasekar</keyname><forenames>Rohith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhuoxian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xiangeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shalaginov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagutchev</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Young L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kildishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boltasseva</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shalaev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lasing Action with Gold Nanorod Hyperbolic Metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coherent nanoscale photon sources are of paramount importance to achieving
all-optical communication. Several nanolasers smaller than the diffraction
limit have been theoretically proposed and experimentally demonstrated using
plasmonic cavities to confine optical fields. Such compact cavities exhibit
large Purcell factors, thereby enhancing spontaneous emission, which feeds into
the lasing mode. However, most plasmonic nanolasers reported so far have
employed resonant nanostructures and therefore had the lasing restricted to the
proximity of the resonance wavelength. Here, we report on an approach based on
gold nanorod hyperbolic metamaterials for lasing. Hyperbolic metamaterials
provide broadband Purcell enhancement due to large photonic density of optical
states, while also supporting surface plasmon modes to deliver optical feedback
for lasing due to nonlocal effects in nanorod media. We experimentally
demonstrate the advantage of hyperbolic metamaterials in achieving lasing
action by its comparison with that obtained in a metamaterial with elliptic
dispersion. The conclusions from the experimental results are supported with
numerical simulations comparing the Purcell factors and surface plasmon modes
for the metamaterials with different dispersions. We show that although the
metamaterials of both types support lasing, emission with hyperbolic samples is
about twice as strong with 35% lower threshold vs. the elliptic ones. Hence,
hyperbolic metamaterials can serve as a convenient platform of choice for
nanoscale coherent photon sources in a broad wavelength range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05172</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calatayud</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cassinelli</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ibarra</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goya</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long term stability and reproducibility of magnetic colloids are key
  issues for steady values of Specific Power Absorption through time</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>European Journal of Inorganic Chemistry, 2015, 4524; 4531</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/ejic.201500303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Virtually all clinical applications of magnetic nanoparticles (MNPs) require
the formulation of biocompatible, water-based magnetic colloids. For magnetic
hyperthermia, the requirements also include a high colloidal stability against
precipitation and agglomeration of the constituent MNPs, in order to keep the
heating efficiency of the ferrofluid in the long term. The specific power
absorption (SPA) of single-domain MNPs depends critically on the average
particle size and size distribution width, therefore first-rate reproducibility
among different batches regarding these parameters are also needed. We have
studied the evolution of the SPA of highly reproducible and stable water-based
colloid composed of polymer coated $Fe_{3}O_{4}$ magnetic nanoparticles. By
measuring the specific power absorption (SPA) values along one year as a
function of field amplitude and frequencies ($H \leq 24 kA/m$; $260 \leq f \leq
830 kHz$), we demonstrated that SPA in these samples can be made reproducible
between successive synthesis, and stable along several months, due to the in
situ polymer coating that provides colloidal stability and keeps dipolar
interactions negligible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05183</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Lebedev</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lake</keyname><forenames>Kayll</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic Aberration and the Cosmological Constant in Gravitational
  Lensing I: Introduction</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>revtex with 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An analysis of null geodesics in Schwarzschild de Sitter space is presented
with special attention to their global `bending angles', local measurable
angles, and the involvement of the cosmological constant. We make use of a
general technique which allows for finding observable intersection angles of
null trajectories analytically. A general relativistic aberration relationship
is established as one of its applications. The question of whether or not the
cosmological constant, $\Lambda$, contributes to orbits of light and to related
observable quantities is addressed in detail. We also discuss the ongoing
debate on this issue and respond to some recent papers on the topic. The
dependence of measurable quantities on the motion of observers is stressed
throughout. Exact formulas for measurable intersection angles, as well as
gravitational lens equations for observers in the Schwarzschild de Sitter
background are provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05187</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Van-Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saint-Martin</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dollfus</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volz</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing isotope and vacancy engineering in graphene ribbons to
  enhance the thermoelectric performance without degrading the electronic
  properties</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The enhancement of thermoelectric figure of merit ZT requires to either
increase the power factor or reduce the phonon conductance, or even both. In
graphene, the high phonon thermal conductivity is the main factor limiting the
thermoelectric conversion. The common strategy to enhance ZT is therefore to
introduce phonon scatterers to suppress the phonon conductance while retaining
high electrical conductance and Seebeck coefficient. Although thermoelectric
performance is eventually enhanced, all studies based on this strategy show a
significant reduction of the electrical conductance, most often leading to a
lower electronic performance. In this study we show that appropriate sources of
disorder, including isotopes and vacancies at lowest electron density
positions, can be used as phonon scatterers to reduce the phonon conductance in
graphene ribbons without degrading the electrical conductance, particularly in
the low-energy region which is the most important range for device operation.
By means of atomistic calculations using semi-empirical Tight-Binding and Force
Constant models in combination with Non-Equilibrium Green function formalism,
we show that the natural electronic properties of graphene ribbons can be fully
preserved while their thermoelectric efficiency is strongly enhanced. For
ribbons of width M = 5 dimer lines, room-temperature ZT is enhanced from less
than 0.26 for defect-free ribbons to more than 2.5. This study is likely to set
the milestones of a new generation of nano-devices with dual electronic,
thermoelectric functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05190</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Brod</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory News Higgs</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures. Proceedings of BEAUTY 2016: 16th International
  Conference on B-Physics at Frontier Machines, Marseille, France</comments><journal-ref>PoS (BEAUTY2016) 026</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I review new developments in Higgs physics, with a focus on Yukawa couplings
in and beyond the standard model. In particular, I discuss different methods of
measuring the light Yukawas, new sources of CP violation in the Higgs sector,
and lepton flavor violation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
