<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:12:33Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-15" from="2016-09-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.0457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.0457</id><created>2010-01-04</created><updated>2010-09-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Homological Type of Geometric Transitions</title><categories>math.AG hep-th</categories><comments>36 pages. Minor changes: A reference and a related comment in Remark
  3.2 were added. This is the final version accepted for publication in the
  journal Geometriae Dedicata</comments><msc-class>14J32, 32S30, 32S45, 81T30</msc-class><journal-ref>Geom. Dedicata 151 (2011), 323-359</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10711-010-9537-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present paper gives an account and quantifies the change in topology
induced by small and type II geometric transitions, by introducing the notion
of the \emph{homological type} of a geometric transition. The obtained results
agree with, and go further than, most results and estimates, given to date by
several authors, both in mathematical and physical literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1103.2930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1103.2930</id><created>2011-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zahiri-Abyaneh</keyname><forenames>Mehran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farhoudi</keyname><forenames>Mehrdad</forenames></author></authors><title>Zitterbewegung in External Magnetic Field: Classic versus Quantum
  Approach</title><categories>quant-ph hep-ph hep-th physics.class-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Foud. Phys. 41 (No. 8) (2011), 1355-1374</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-011-9553-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate variations of the Zitterbewegung frequency of electron due to
an external static and uniform magnetic field employing the expectation value
quantum approach, and compare our results with the classical model of spinning
particles. We demonstrate that these two so far compatible approaches are not
in agreement in the presence of an external uniform static magnetic field, in
which the classical approach breaks the usual symmetry of free particles and
antiparticles states, i.e. it leads to CP violation. Hence, regarding the
Zitterbewegung frequency of electron, the classical approach in the presence of
an external magnetic field is unlikely to correctly describe the spin of
electron, while the quantum approach does, as expected. We also show that the
results obtained via the expectation value are in close agreement with the
quantum approach of the Heisenberg picture derived in the literature. However,
the method we use is capable of being compared with the classical approach
regarding the spin aspects. The classical interpretation of spin produced by
the altered Zitterbewegung frequency, in the presence of an external magnetic
field, are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.0817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.0817</id><created>2013-07-02</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bargigli</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lionetto</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viaggiu</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>A Statistical Test of Walrasian Equilibrium by Means of Complex Networks
  Theory</title><categories>q-fin.GN cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Title modified. Version published on J. Stat. Phys</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1599-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We represent an exchange economy in terms of statistical ensembles for
complex networks by introducing the concept of market configuration. This is
defined as a sequence of nonnegative discrete random variables $\{w_{ij}\}$
describing the flow of a given commodity from agent $i$ to agent $j$. This
sequence can be arranged in a nonnegative matrix $W$ which we can regard as the
representation of a weighted and directed network or digraph $G$. Our main
result consists in showing that general equilibrium theory imposes highly
restrictive conditions upon market configurations, which are in most cases not
fulfilled by real markets. An explicit example with reference to the e-MID
interbank credit market is provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.4839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.4839</id><created>2013-11-19</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galanis</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefankovic</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vigoda</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Linji</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic Potts Model: Refined #BIS-hardness and Related Results</title><categories>cs.CC math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>To appear in SIAM J. Computing</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent results establish for 2-spin antiferromagnetic systems that the
computational complexity of approximating the partition function on graphs of
maximum degree D undergoes a phase transition that coincides with the
uniqueness phase transition on the infinite D-regular tree. For the
ferromagnetic Potts model we investigate whether analogous hardness results
hold. Goldberg and Jerrum showed that approximating the partition function of
the ferromagnetic Potts model is at least as hard as approximating the number
of independent sets in bipartite graphs (#BIS-hardness). We improve this
hardness result by establishing it for bipartite graphs of maximum degree D. We
first present a detailed picture for the phase diagram for the infinite
D-regular tree, giving a refined picture of its first-order phase transition
and establishing the critical temperature for the coexistence of the disordered
and ordered phases. We then prove for all temperatures below this critical
temperature that it is #BIS-hard to approximate the partition function on
bipartite graphs of maximum degree D. As a corollary, it is #BIS-hard to
approximate the number of k-colorings on bipartite graphs of maximum degree D
when k &lt;= D/(2 ln D).
  The #BIS-hardness result for the ferromagnetic Potts model uses random
bipartite regular graphs as a gadget in the reduction. The analysis of these
random graphs relies on recent connections between the maxima of the
expectation of their partition function, attractive fixpoints of the associated
tree recursions, and induced matrix norms. We extend these connections to
random regular graphs for all ferromagnetic models and establish the Bethe
prediction for every ferromagnetic spin system on random regular graphs. We
also prove for the ferromagnetic Potts model that the Swendsen-Wang algorithm
is torpidly mixing on random D-regular graphs at the critical temperature for
large q.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.4648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.4648</id><created>2014-03-18</created><updated>2015-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salfi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mol</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimeck</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simmons</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollenberg</keyname><forenames>L. C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogge</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatially Resolving Valley Quantum Interference of a Donor in Silicon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures. Supplementary Information: 10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Materials 13, 605, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat3941</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron and nuclear spins of donor ensembles in isotopically pure silicon
experience a vacuum-like environment, giving them extraordinary coherence.
However, in contrast to a real vacuum, electrons in silicon occupy quantum
superpositions of valleys in momentum space. Addressable single-qubit and
two-qubit operations in silicon require that qubits are placed near interfaces,
modifying the valley degrees of freedom associated with these quantum
superpositions and strongly influencing qubit relaxation and exchange
processes. Yet to date, spectroscopic measurements only indirectly probe
wavefunctions, preventing direct experimental access to valley population,
donor position, and environment. Here we directly probe the probability density
of single quantum states of individual subsurface donors, in real space and
reciprocal space, using scanning tunneling spectroscopy. We directly observe
quantum mechanical valley interference patterns associated with linear
superpositions of valleys in the donor ground state. The valley population is
found to be within $5 \%$ of a bulk donor when $2.85\pm0.45$ nm from the
interface, indicating that valley perturbation-induced enhancement of spin
relaxation will be negligible for depths $&gt;3$ nm. The observed valley
interference will render two-qubit exchange gates sensitive to atomic-scale
variations in positions of subsurface donors. Moreover, these results will also
be of interest to emerging schemes proposing to encode information directly in
valley polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.2548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.2548</id><created>2014-04-09</created><updated>2014-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrier-Barbut</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delehaye</keyname><forenames>Marion</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurent</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grier</keyname><forenames>Andrew T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierce</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rem</keyname><forenames>Benno S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevy</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salomon</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>A Mixture of Bose and Fermi Superfluids</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Science 345, 1035 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.1255380</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconductivity and superfluidity of fermionic and bosonic systems are
remarkable many-body quantum phenomena. In liquid helium and dilute gases, Bose
and Fermi superfluidity has been observed separately, but producing a mixture
in which both the fermionic and the bosonic components are superfluid is
challenging. Here we report on the observation of such a mixture with dilute
gases of two Lithium isotopes, 6Li and 7Li. We probe the collective dynamics of
this system by exciting center-of-mass oscillations that exhibit extremely low
damping below a certain critical velocity. Using high precision spectroscopy of
these modes we observe coherent energy exchange and measure the coupling
between the two superfluids. Our observations can be captured theoretically
using a sum-rule approach that we interpret in terms of two coupled
oscillators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.4551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.4551</id><created>2014-04-17</created><updated>2014-04-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dappiaggi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murro</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative observables for linearized gravity on asymptotically flat
  spacetimes and their boundary induced states</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, added references</comments><msc-class>81T30</msc-class><doi>10.1063/1.4890581</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the quantization of linearized gravity on globally hyperbolic,
asymptotically flat, vacuum spacetimes and the construction of distinguished
states which are both of Hadamard form and invariant under the action of all
bulk isometries. The procedure, we follow, consists of looking for a
realization of the observables of the theory as a sub-algebra of an auxiliary,
non-dynamical algebra constructed on future null infinity $\Im^+$. The
applicability of this scheme is tantamount to proving that a solution of the
equations of motion for linearized gravity can be extended smoothly to $\Im^+$.
This has been claimed to be possible provided that a suitable gauge fixing
condition, first written by Geroch and Xanthopoulos, is imposed. We review its
definition critically showing that there exists a previously unnoticed
obstruction in its implementation leading us to introducing the concept of
radiative observables. These constitute an algebra for which a Hadamard state
induced from null infinity and invariant under the action of all spacetime
isometries exists and it is explicitly constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.4578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.4578</id><created>2014-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>McMillen</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellouard</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>On the anisotropy of stress-distribution induced in glasses and crystals
  by non-ablative femtosecond laser exposure</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 23, 86-100 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.23.000086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Femtosecond laser exposure in the non-ablative regime induces a variety of
bulk structural modifications, in which anisotropy may depend on the
polarization of the writing beam. In this work, we investigate the correlation
between polarization state and stress anisotropy. In particular, we introduce a
methodology that allows for rapid analysis and visualization of laser-induced
stress anisotropy in glasses and crystals. Using radial and azimuthal
polarization, we also demonstrate stress states that are nearly isotropic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.2950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.2950</id><created>2014-10-11</created><updated>2014-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deb</keyname><forenames>Bimalendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Creation and manipulation of bound states in continuum with lasers:
  Applications to cold atoms and molecules</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>26 pages 3 figures, typographical and other minor errors are
  corrected in version-2</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 90, 063417 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.90.063417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show theoretically that it is possible to create and manipulate a pair of
bound states in continuum in ultracold atoms by two lasers in the presence of a
magnetically tunable Feshbach resonance. These bound states are formed due to
coherent superposition of two electronically excited molecular bound states and
a quasi-bound state in ground-state potential. These superposition states are
decoupled from the continuum of two-atom collisional states. Hence, in the
absence of other damping processes they are non-decaying. We analyze in detail
the physical conditions that can lead to the formation of such states in cold
collisions between atoms, and discuss the possible experimental signatures of
such states. An extremely narrow and asymmetric shape with a distinct minimum
of photoassociative absorption spectrum or scattering cross section as a
function of collision energy will indicate the occurrence of a bound state in
continuum (BIC). We prove that the minimum will occur at an energy at which the
BIC is formed. We discuss how a BIC will be useful for efficient creation of
Feshbach molecules and manipulation of cold collisions. Experimental
realizations of BIC will pave the way for a new kind of bound-bound
spectroscopy in ultracold atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4689</id><created>2014-11-17</created><updated>2015-03-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunzinger</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinbauer</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stojkovic</keyname><forenames>Milena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vickers</keyname><forenames>James A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking's singularity theorem for $C^{1,1}$-metrics</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages, LaTeX; v2: corrected Lemma 4.2; v3: typos corrected, final
  version</comments><msc-class>83C75, 53B30</msc-class><journal-ref>Classical Quantum Gravity 32 (2015), no. 7, 075012, 19 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/32/7/075012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a detailed proof of Hawking's singularity theorem in the
regularity class $C^{1,1}$, i.e., for spacetime metrics possessing locally
Lipschitz continuous first derivatives. The proof uses recent results in
$C^{1,1}$-causality theory and is based on regularisation techniques adapted to
the causal structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00287</id><created>2015-02-01</created><updated>2015-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunzinger</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinbauer</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vickers</keyname><forenames>James A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Penrose singularity theorem in regularity $C^{1,1}$</title><categories>gr-qc math.DG</categories><comments>13 pages. Final version</comments><msc-class>83C75, 53B30</msc-class><journal-ref>Classical Quantum Gravity 32 (2015), no. 15, 155010, 12 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/32/15/155010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the validity of the Penrose singularity theorem to spacetime
metrics of regularity $C^{1,1}$. The proof is based on regularisation
techniques, combined with recent results in low regularity causality theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.08042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.08042</id><created>2015-02-27</created><updated>2016-02-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>J. D. Querales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ventura</keyname><forenames>C. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Citro</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature and doping dependence of normal state spectral properties in
  a two-orbital model for ferropnictides</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Manuscript accepted in Physics Letters A on Feb. 25, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 380, 1648 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.02.042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a second-order perturbative Green's functions approach we determined
the normal state single-particle spectral function $A(\vec{k},\omega)$
employing a minimal effective model for iron-based superconductors. The
microscopic model, used before to study magnetic fluctuations and
superconducting properties, includes the two effective tight-binding bands
proposed by S.Raghu et al. [Phys. Rev. B 77, 220503 (R) (2008)], and intra- and
inter-orbital local electronic correlations, related to the Fe-3d orbitals.
Here, we focus on the study of normal state electronic properties, in
particular the temperature and doping dependence of the total density of
states, $A(\omega)$, and of $A(\vec{k},\omega)$ in different Brillouin zone
regions, and compare them to the existing angle resolved photoemission
spectroscopy (ARPES) and previous theoretical results in ferropnictides. We
obtain an asymmetric effect of electron and hole doping, quantitative agreement
with the experimental chemical potential shifts as a function of doping, as
well as spectral weight redistributions near the Fermi level as a function of
temperature consistent with the available experimental data. In addition, we
predict a non-trivial dependence of the total density of states with the
temperature, exhibiting clear renormalization effects by correlations.
Interestingly, investigating the origin of this predicted behaviour by
analyzing the evolution with temperature of the k-dependent self-energy
obtained in our approach, we could identify a number of specific Brillouin zone
points, none of them probed by ARPES experiments yet, where the largest
non-trivial effects of temperature on the renormalization are present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02233</id><created>2015-03-07</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stickley</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aragon-Calvo</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>NebulOS: A Big Data Framework for Astrophysics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cs.DC</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures</comments><acm-class>C.2.4</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce NebulOS, a Big Data platform that allows a cluster of Linux
machines to be treated as a single computer. With NebulOS, the process of
writing a massively parallel program for a datacenter is no more complicated
than writing a Python script for a desktop computer. The platform enables most
pre-existing data analysis software to be used, as scale, in a datacenter
without modification. The shallow learning curve and compatibility with
existing software greatly reduces the time required to develop distributed data
analysis pipelines. The platform is built upon industry-standard, open-source
Big Data technologies, from which it inherits several fault tolerance features.
NebulOS enhances these technologies by adding an intuitive user interface,
automated task monitoring, and other usability features. We present a summary
of the architecture, provide usage examples, and discuss the system's
performance scaling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08183</id><created>2015-03-27</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chanda</keyname><forenames>Sumanto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roychowdhury</keyname><forenames>Raju</forenames></author></authors><title>Taub-NUT as Bertrand spacetime with magnetic fields</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages, contents and reference section modified, presentation
  improved, version to appear in JGSP, 35 pages</comments><msc-class>37J35, 70H06, 81R12</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Geometry and Symmetry in Physics Vol.41 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7546/jgsp-41-2016-33-67</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on symmetries Taub-NUT shares with Bertrand spacetime, we cast it as
the latter with magnetic fields. Its nature as a Bianchi-IX gravitational
instanton and other related geometrical properties are reviewed. We provide an
easy derivation and comparison between the spatial Killing-Yano tensors deduced
from first-integrals and the corresponding hyperk\&quot;ahler structures and finally
verify the existence of a graded Lie-algebra structure via Schouten-Nijenhuis
brackets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03336</id><created>2015-05-13</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jamali</keyname><forenames>Tayeb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jafari</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farahani</keyname><forenames>S. Vasheghani</forenames></author></authors><title>Patterns for the waiting time in the context of discrete-time stochastic
  processes</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this study is to extend the scope and applicability of the
level-crossing method to discrete-time stochastic processes and generalize it
to enable us to study multiple discrete-time stochastic processes. In previous
versions of the level-crossing method, problems with it correspond to the fact
that this method had been developed for analyzing a continuous-time process or
at most a multiple continuous-time process in an individual manner. However,
since all empirical processes are discrete in time, the already-established
level-crossing method may not prove adequate for studying empirical processes.
Beyond this, due to the fact that most empirical processes are coupled; their
individual study could lead to vague results. To achieve the objectives of this
study, we first find an analytical expression for the average frequency of
crossing a level in a discrete-time process, giving the measure of the time
experienced for two consecutive crossings named as the &quot;waiting time&quot;. We then
introduce the generalized level-crossing method by which the consideration of
coupling between the components of a multiple process becomes possible.
Finally, we provide an analytic solution when the components of a multiple
stochastic process are independent Gaussian white noises. The comparison of the
results obtained for coupled and uncoupled processes measures the strength and
efficiency of the coupling, justifying our model and analysis. The advantage of
the proposed method is its sensitivity to the slightest coupling and shortest
correlation length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04001</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haber</keyname><forenames>Howard E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Preserving the validity of the Two-Higgs Doublet Model up to the Planck
  scale</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 4 figures, 4 tables (Version 3: typographical error in eq.
  (A.28) corrected)</comments><report-no>SCIPP-15/07</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 033003 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.033003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the constraints on the two Higgs doublet model (2HDM) due to the
stability of the scalar potential and absence of Landau poles at energy scales
below the Planck scale. We employ the most general 2HDM that incorporates an
approximately Standard Model (SM) Higgs boson with a flavor aligned Yukawa
sector to eliminate potential tree-level Higgs-mediated flavor changing neutral
currents. Using basis independent techniques, we exhibit robust regimes of the
2HDM parameter space with a 125 GeV SM-like Higgs boson that is stable and
perturbative up to the Planck scale. Implications for the heavy scalar spectrum
are exhibited.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07674</id><created>2015-05-28</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tessore</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellagamba</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metcalf</keyname><forenames>R. Benton</forenames></author></authors><title>Lensed: a code for the forward reconstruction of lenses and sources from
  strong lensing observations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>v2: major revision; accepted by MNRAS; lens reconstruction code
  available at http://glenco.github.io/lensed/</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2212</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Robust modelling of strong lensing systems is fundamental to exploit the
information they contain about the distribution of matter in galaxies and
clusters. In this work, we present Lensed, a new code which performs forward
parametric modelling of strong lenses. Lensed takes advantage of a massively
parallel ray-tracing kernel to perform the necessary calculations on a modern
graphics processing unit (GPU). This makes the precise rendering of the
background lensed sources much faster, and allows the simultaneous optimisation
of tens of parameters for the selected model. With a single run, the code is
able to obtain the full posterior probability distribution for the lens light,
the mass distribution and the background source at the same time. Lensed is
first tested on mock images which reproduce realistic space-based observations
of lensing systems. In this way, we show that it is able to recover unbiased
estimates of the lens parameters, even when the sources do not follow exactly
the assumed model. Then, we apply it to a subsample of the SLACS lenses, in
order to demonstrate its use on real data. The results generally agree with the
literature, and highlight the flexibility and robustness of the algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01036</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01036</id><created>2015-06-02</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Metwally</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eleuch</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Obada</keyname><forenames>A. -S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sudden death and rebirth of Entanglement for Different Dimensional
  Systems driven by a Classical Random External Field</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Published in Laser Physics Letter 13 (2016) 105206 (8pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1612-2011/13/10/105206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The entangled behavior of different dimensional systems driven by classical
external random field is investigated. The amount of the survival entanglement
between the components of each system is quantified. There are different
behaviors of entanglement that come into view decay, sudden death, sudden birth
and long-lived entanglement. The maximum entangled states which can be
generated from any of theses suggested systems are much fragile than the
partially entangled ones. The systems of larger dimensions are more robust than
those of smaller dimensions systems, where the entanglement decay smoothly,
gradually and may vanish for a very short time. For the class of $2\times 3$
dimensional system, the one parameter family is found to be more robust than
the two parameters family. Although the entanglement of driven $ 2 \times 3$
dimensional system is very sensitive to the classical external random field,
one can use them to generate a long-lived entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01321</id><created>2015-06-03</created><updated>2015-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gentile</keyname><forenames>Martin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horsley</keyname><forenames>Simon A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>William L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localized exciton-polariton modes in dye-doped nanospheres: a quantum
  approach</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optics, 18, 015001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/1/015001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We model a dye-doped polymeric nanosphere as an ensemble of quantum emitters
and use it to investigate the localized exciton-polaritons supported by such a
nanosphere. By determining the time evolution of the density matrix of the
collective system, we explore how an incident laser field may cause transient
optical field enhancement close to the surface of such nanoparticles. Our
results provide further evidence that excitonic materials can be used to good
effect in nanophotonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03109</id><created>2015-06-09</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arici</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landi</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Pimsner algebras and circle bundles</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages. v3: Updated title. No changes in the scientific content and
  results</comments><msc-class>19K35, 55R25, 46L08</msc-class><journal-ref>Operator Theory: Advances and Applications, Vol. 252, 1--25, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-29116-1_1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the connections between noncommutative principal circle bundles,
Pimsner algebras and strongly graded algebras. We illustrate several results
with the examples of quantum weighted projective and lens spaces and
theta-deformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04942</id><created>2015-07-17</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lees</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence of N\'eel order in the S=1 bilinear-biquadratic Heisenberg
  model via random loops</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2656-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the general spin-1 SU(2) invariant Heisenberg model with a
two-body interaction. A random loop model is introduced and relations to
quantum spin systems is proved. Using this relation it is shown that for
dimensions 3 and above N\'eel order occurs for a large range of values of the
relative strength of the bilinear ($-J_1$) and biquadratic ($-J_2$) interaction
terms. The proof uses the method of reflection positivity and infrared bounds.
Links between spin correlations and loop correlations are proved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00026</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00026</id><created>2015-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Karlovets</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotkin</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serbo</keyname><forenames>V. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Born approximation for scattering of wave packets on atoms. I.
  Theoretical background for scattering of a wave packet on a potential field</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 92, 052703 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.052703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Laser photons carrying non-zero orbital angular momentum are known and
exploited during the last twenty years. Recently it has been demonstrated
experimentally that such (twisted) electrons can be produced and even focused
to a subnanometer scale. Thus, twisted electrons emerge as a new tool in atomic
physics. The state of a twisted electron can be considered as a specific wave
packet of plane waves. In the present paper-I we consider elastic scattering of
the wave packets of fast non-relativistic particles on a potential field. We
obtain simple and convenient formulae for a number of events in such a
scattering. The equations derived represent, in fact, generalization of the
well-known Born approximation for the case when finite sizes and inhomogeneity
of the initial packet should be taken into account. To illustrate the obtained
results, we consider two simple models corresponding to scattering of a
Gaussian wave packet on the Gaussian potential and on the hydrogen atom. The
scattering of twisted electrons on atoms will be considered in the next
paper-II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04653</id><created>2015-09-15</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finkelstein-Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calatayud</keyname><forenames>Monica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atabek</keyname><forenames>Osman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mujica</keyname><forenames>Vladimiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear Fano Interferences in Open Quantum Systems: an Exactly
  Solvable Model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>appendix added, corrected some typos</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 063414 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.063414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain an explicit solution for the stationary state populations of a
dissipative Fano model, where a discrete excited state is coupled to a
continumm set of states; both excited set of states are reachable by
photo-excitation from the ground state. The dissipative dynamic is described by
a Liouville equation in Lindblad form and the field intensity can take
arbitrary values within the model. We show that the continuum states population
as a function of laser frequency can always be expressed as a Fano profile plus
a Lorentzian function with effective parameters whose explicit expressions are
given in the case of a closed system coupled to a bath as well as for the
original Fano scattering framework. Although the solution is intricate, it can
be elegantly expressed as a linear transformation of the kernel of a $4\times
4$ matrix which has the meaning of an effective Liouvillian. We unveil key
notable processes related to the optical nonlinearity and which had not been
reported to date: electromagnetic induced-transparency, population inversions,
power narrowing and broadening, as well as an effective reduction of the Fano
asymmetry parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08403</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alho</keyname><forenames>Timo</forenames></author></authors><title>Coordinate free integrals in Geometric Calculus</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP math.RA</categories><comments>20 pages, 1 figure. Add details on orientation of subspaces, and
  mention a more systematic method</comments><journal-ref>Alho, T. Adv. Appl. Clifford Algebras (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00006-016-0655-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a method for evaluating integrals in geometric calculus without
introducing coordinates, based on using the fundamental theorem of calculus
repeatedly and cutting the resulting manifolds so as to create a boundary and
allow for the existence of an antiderivative at each step. The method is a
direct generalization of the usual method of integration on function of a real
variable. It may lead to both practical applications and help unveil new
connections to various fields of mathematics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08129</id><created>2015-10-27</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Quintela</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Fabris</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Harmonic Oscillator in the Classical Limit of a Minimal-Length
  Scenario</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Brazilian Journal of Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s13538-016-0457-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we explicitly solve the problem of the harmonic oscillator in
the classical limit of a minimal-length scenario. We show that (i) the motion
equation of the oscillator is not linear anymore because the presence of a
minimal length introduces an anarmonic term and (ii) its motion is described by
a Jacobi sine elliptic function. Therefore the motion is periodic with the same
amplitude and with the new period depending on the minimal length. This result
(the change in the period of oscillation) is very important since it enables us
to find in a quite simple way the most relevant effect of the presence of a
minimal length and consequently traces of the Planck-scale physics. We show
applications of our results in spectroscopy and gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01842</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pershoguba</keyname><forenames>Sergey S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakosai</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balatsky</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Skyrmion-induced bound states in a superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures; Corresponds to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064513 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064513</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a superconductor proximity coupled to a two-dimensional
ferromagnetic film with a skyrmion texture. Using the T-matrix calculations and
numerical modeling we calculate the spin-polarized local density of states in
the superconductor in the vicinity of the skyrmion. We predict the skyrmion
bound states (SBS) that are induced in the superconductor, similar to the
well-known Yu-Shiba-Rusinov (YSR) states. The SBS wavefunctions have spatial
power law decay. Presence of the SBS suggests the mechanism by which
superconductivity could facilitate an effective long-range interaction between
skyrmions when their SBS wavefunctions overlap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02748</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smotlacha</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pincak</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analogies in electronic properties of graphene wormhole and perturbed
  nanocylinder</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2013) 86: 480</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2013-40594-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic properties of the wormhole and the perturbed nanocylinder will
be investigated using two different methods: the continuum gauge field-theory
model which deals with the contin- uum approximation of the surface and the
Haydock recursion method which transforms the surface into simplier structure
and deals with the nearest-neighbor interactions. Furthermore, the changes of
the electronic properties will be investigated for the case of enclosing the
appropriate structure and possible substitutes for the encloser will be
derived. Finally, possible character of the electron flux will be derived from
the model based on the multiwalled nanotubes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03652</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>D. J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giomi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear response to leadership, effective temperature and decision making
  in flocks</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages (incl. supplementary information), 8 figures, Supplementary
  movies can be found at
  http://wwwhome.lorentz.leidenuniv.nl/~giomi/sup_mat/20151108/</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 022612 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022612</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large collections of autonomously moving agents, such as animals or
micro-organisms, are able to 'flock' coherently in space even in the absence of
a central control mechanism. While the direction of the flock resulting from
this critical behavior is random, this can be controlled by a small subset of
informed individuals acting as leaders of the group. In this article we use the
Vicsek model to investigate how flocks respond to leadership and make
decisions. Using a combination of numerical simulations and continuous modeling
we demonstrate that flocks display a linear response to leadership that can be
cast in the framework of the fluctuation-dissipation theorem, identifying an
'effective temperature' reflecting how promptly the flock reacts to the
initiative of the leaders. The linear response to leadership also holds in the
presence of two groups of informed individuals with competing interests,
indicating that the flock's behavioral decision is determined by both the
number of leaders and their degree of influence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04279</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04279</id><created>2015-11-13</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bunatian</keyname><forenames>Gevorg G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effective description of non-strange hadrons low-energy electro-weak
  transitions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>My artikle contains 27 pages. There are two Feynman-diagrams</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting with the general principles of global and local symmetries, the
effective pion-nucleon lagrangian, essentially non-linear in pion field, to
describe the non-strange hadrons low-energy electro-weak transitions is
developed. We encounter no divergence summarizing properly all the infinite
power series in pion field which occur in the course of treatment. Our
consistent approach proves to be relevant in considering P-parity violation in
pion-nucleon interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09445</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gorniaczyk</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tresp</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bienias</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris-Mandoki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirgorodskiy</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xfc;chler</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesanovsky</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofferberth</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancement of Rydberg-mediated single-photon nonlinearities by
  electrically tuned F\&quot;orster Resonances</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>7 pages main text, 3 figures, 2 pages supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 7, 12480 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12480</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mapping the strong interaction between Rydberg atoms onto single photons via
electromagnetically induced transparency enables manipulation of light on the
single photon level and novel few-photon devices such as all-optical switches
and transistors operated by individual photons. Here, we demonstrate
experimentally that Stark-tuned F\&quot;orster resonances can substantially increase
this effective interaction between individual photons. This technique boosts
the gain of a single-photon transistor to over 100, enhances the
non-destructive detection of single Rydberg atoms to a fidelity beyond 0.8, and
enables high precision spectroscopy on Rydberg pair states. On top, we achieve
a gain larger than 2 with gate photon read-out after the transistor operation.
Theory models for Rydberg polariton propagation on F\&quot;orster resonance and for
the projection of the stored spin-wave yield excellent agreement to our data
and successfully identify the main decoherence mechanism of the Rydberg
transistor, paving the way towards photonic quantum gates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00382</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-02-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>J. D. Querales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ventura</keyname><forenames>C. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Citro</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-N&#xfa;&#xf1;ez</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Normal state electronic properties of LaO$_{1-x}$F$_{x}$BiS$_{2}$
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 figures. Manuscript accepted in Physica B: Condensed Matter on Jan.
  25, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Physica B: Condensed Matter, 488, 32 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2016.01.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A good description of the electronic structure of BiS$_{2}$-based
superconductors is essential to understand their phase diagram, normal state
and superconducting properties. To describe the first reports of normal state
electronic structure features from angle resolved photoemission spectroscopy
(ARPES) in LaO$_{1-x}$F$_{x}$BiS$_{2}$, we used a minimal microscopic model to
study their low energy properties. It includes the two effective tight-binding
bands proposed by Usui et al [Phys.Rev.B 86, 220501(R)(2012)], and we added
moderate intra- and inter-orbital electron correlations related to Bi-($p_{Y}$,
$p_{X}$) and S-($p_{Y}$, $p_{X}$) orbitals. We calculated the electron Green's
functions using their equations of motion, which we decoupled in second-order
of perturbations on the correlations. We determined the normal state spectral
density function and total density of states for LaO$_{1-x}$F$_{x}$BiS$_{2}$,
focusing on the description of the k-dependence, effect of doping, and the
prediction of the temperature dependence of spectral properties. Including
moderate electron correlations, improves the description of the few
experimental ARPES and soft X-ray photoemission data available for
LaO$_{1-x}$F$_{x}$BiS$_{2}$. Our analytical approximation enabled us to
calculate the spectral density around the conduction band minimum at
$\vec{k}_{0}=(0.45\pi,0.45\pi)$, and to predict the temperature dependence of
the spectral properties at different BZ points, which might be verified by
temperature dependent ARPES.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03957</id><created>2015-12-12</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guillot</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaspi</keyname><forenames>Victoria M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Archibald</keyname><forenames>Robert F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bachetti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flynn</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jankowski</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailes</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boggs</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>Finn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hailey</keyname><forenames>Charles A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Fiona A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Willam W.</forenames></author></authors><title>The NuSTAR view of the non-thermal emission from PSR J0437-4715</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS. 12 pages, 8 figures, 3 table</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2194</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a hard X-ray NuSTAR observation of PSR J0437-4715, the nearest
millisecond pulsar. The known pulsations at the apparent pulse period ~5.76 ms
are detected at energies up to 20 keV. We measure a photon index $\Gamma=
1.65\pm0.24$ (90% confidence) for the power law fit to the non-thermal
emission. It had been shown that spectral models with two or three thermal
components fit the XMM-Newton spectrum of PSR J0437-4715, depending on the
slope of the power-law component, and the amount of absorption of soft X-rays.
The new constraint on the high-energy emission provided by NuSTAR removes
ambiguities regarding the thermal components of the emission below 3 keV. We
performed a simultaneous spectral analysis of the XMM-Newton and NuSTAR data to
confirm that three thermal components and a power law are required to fit the
0.3-20 keV emission of PSR J0437-4715. Adding a ROSAT-PSPC spectrum further
confirmed this result and allowed us to better constrain the temperatures of
the three thermal components. A phase-resolved analysis of the NuSTAR data
revealed no significant change in the photon index of the high-energy emission.
This NuSTAR observation provides further impetus for future observations with
the NICER mission (Neutron Star Interior Composition Explorer) whose
sensitivity will provide much stricter constraints on the equation of state of
nuclear matter by combining model fits to the pulsar's phase-folded lightcurve
with the pulsar's well-defined mass and distance from radio timing
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06553</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Manipulating charge-density-wave in $1T$-TaS$_{2}$ by charge carrier
  doping: A first-principles investigation</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transition metal dichalcogenide (TMD) $1T$-TaS$_{2}$ exhibits a rich set
of charge density wave (CDW) orders. Recent investigations suggested that using
light or electric field can manipulate the commensurate (C) CDW ground state.
Such manipulations are considered to be determined by the charge carrier
doping. Here we simulate by first-principles calculations the carrier doping
effect on CCDW in $1T$-TaS$_{2}$. We investigate the charge doping effects on
the electronic structures and phonon instabilities of $1T$ structure and
analyze the doping induced energy and distortion ratio variations in CCDW
structure. We found that both in bulk and monolayer $1T$-TaS$_{2}$, CCDW is
stable upon electron doping, while hole doping can significantly suppress the
CCDW, implying different mechanisms of such reported manipulations. Light or
positive perpendicular electric field induced hole doping increases the energy
of CCDW, so that the system transforms to NCCDW or similar metastable state. On
the other hand, even the CCDW distortion is more stable upon in-plain electric
field induced electron injection, some accompanied effects can drive the system
to cross over the energy barrier from CCDW to nearly commensurate (NC) CDW or
similar metastable state. We also estimate that hole doping can introduce
potential superconductivity with $T_{c}$ of $6\sim7$ K. Controllable switching
of different states such as CCDW/Mott insulating state, metallic state, and
even the superconducting state can be realized in $1T$-TaS$_{2}$, which makes
the novel material have very promising applications in the future electronic
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08117</id><created>2015-12-26</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Jong-Chul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Seong Chan</forenames></author></authors><title>Indirect signature of dark matter with the diphoton resonance at 750 GeV</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures, additional anaysis of smaller DM mass,
  references added, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Dark Univ. 14 (2016) 4-10</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the recently reported diphoton resonance at 750 GeV, we study a
new axion-like bosonic portal model of dark matter physics. When the resonance
particle is identified as the pseudo-scalar mediator, via which the standard
model sector would interact with the dark matter sector, the data from collider
physics would provide profound implications to dark matter phenomenology. In
this paper, we first identify the preferred parameter space of the suggested
portal model from the results of the LHC run with $\sqrt{s}=13$ TeV, and then
we examine the dark matter signature taking into account the data from
cosmic-ray experiments including Fermi-LAT dwarf galaxy $\gamma$-ray search,
HESS $\gamma$-line search, and future CTA diffuse $\gamma$-ray and
$\gamma$-line searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00898</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stahl</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Embr&#xe9;us</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papp</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landreman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xfc;l&#xf6;p</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic modelling of runaway electrons in dynamic scenarios</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Fusion, 56, 112009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0029-5515/56/11/112009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Improved understanding of runaway-electron formation and decay processes are
of prime interest for the safe operation of large tokamaks, and the dynamics of
the runaway electrons during dynamical scenarios such as disruptions are of
particular concern. In this paper, we present kinetic modelling of scenarios
with time-dependent plasma parameters; in particular, we investigate hot-tail
runaway generation during a rapid drop in plasma temperature. With the goal of
studying runaway-electron generation with a self-consistent electric-field
evolution, we also discuss the implementation of a collision operator that
conserves momentum and energy and demonstrate its properties. An operator for
avalanche runaway-electron generation, which takes the energy dependence of the
scattering cross section and the runaway distribution into account, is
investigated. We show that the simplified avalanche model of Rosenbluth &amp;
Putvinskii [Nucl. Fusion 1997 37 1355] can give inaccurate results for the
avalanche growth rate (either lower or higher) for many parameters, especially
when the average runaway energy is modest, such as during the initial phase of
the avalanche multiplication. The developments presented pave the way for
improved modelling of runaway-electron dynamics during disruptions or other
dynamic events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01311</id><created>2016-01-06</created><updated>2016-02-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Kueifu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Tzuhsuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bo</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anlage</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shvets</keyname><forenames>Gennady</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Realization of a Reflections-Free Compact Delay Line Based
  on a Photonic Topological Insulator</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>22 pages, 10 figures, typo corrected</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 28453 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep28453</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetic (EM) waves propagating through an inhomogeneous medium
inevitably scatter whenever electromagnetic properties of the medium change on
the scale of a single wavelength. This fundamental phenomenon constrains how
optical structures are designed and interfaced with each other. Recent
theoretical work indicates that electromagnetic structures collectively known
as photonic topological insulators (PTIs) can be employed to overcome this
fundamental limitation, thereby paving the way for ultra-compact photonic
structures that no longer have to be wavelength-scale smooth. Here we present
the first experimental demonstration of a photonic delay line based on
topologically protected surface electromagnetic waves (TPSWs) between two PTIs
which are the EM counterparts of the quantum spin-Hall topological insulators
in condensed matter. Unlike conventional guided EM waves that do not benefit
from topological protection, TPSWs are shown to experience multi-wavelength
reflection-free time delays when detoured around sharply-curved paths, thus
offering a unique paradigm for compact and efficient wave buffers and other
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03178</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Satya N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schehr</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vivo</keyname><forenames>Pierpaolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Number statistics for $\beta$-ensembles of random matrices: applications
  to trapped fermions at zero temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>34 pages, 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032115 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $\mathcal{P}_{\beta}^{(V)} (N_{\cal I})$ be the probability that a
$N\times N$ $\beta$-ensemble of random matrices with confining potential $V(x)$
has $N_{\cal I}$ eigenvalues inside an interval ${\cal I}=[a,b]$ of the real
line. We introduce a general formalism, based on the Coulomb gas technique and
the resolvent method, to compute analytically $\mathcal{P}_{\beta}^{(V)}
(N_{\cal I})$ for large $N$. We show that this probability scales for large $N$
as $\mathcal{P}_{\beta}^{(V)} (N_{\cal I})\approx \exp\left(-\beta N^2
\psi^{(V)}(N_{\cal I} /N)\right)$, where $\beta$ is the Dyson index of the
ensemble. The rate function $\psi^{(V)}(k_{\cal I})$, independent of $\beta$,
is computed in terms of single integrals that can be easily evaluated
numerically. The general formalism is then applied to the classical
$\beta$-Gaussian (${\cal I}=[-L,L]$), $\beta$-Wishart (${\cal I}=[1,L]$) and
$\beta$-Cauchy (${\cal I}=[-L,L]$) ensembles. Expanding the rate function
around its minimum, we find that generically the number variance ${\rm
Var}(N_{\cal I})$ exhibits a non-monotonic behavior as a function of the size
of the interval, with a maximum that can be precisely characterized. These
analytical results, corroborated by numerical simulations, provide the full
counting statistics of many systems where random matrix models apply. In
particular, we present results for the full counting statistics of zero
temperature one-dimensional spinless fermions in a harmonic trap.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06936</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The split property for quantum field theories in flat and curved
  spacetimes</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Based on a talk given at the German Mathematical Society annual
  meeting, Hamburg 2015. Expository article with some new results. v2 Minor
  changes, typos corrected. Version to appear in Abhandlungen aus dem
  Mathematischen Seminar der Universit\&quot;at Hamburg</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The split property expresses a strong form of independence of spacelike
separated regions in algebraic quantum field theory. In Minkowski spacetime, it
can be proved under hypotheses of nuclearity. An expository account is given of
nuclearity and the split property, and connections are drawn to the theory of
quantum energy inequalities. In addition, a recent proof of the split property
for quantum field theory in curved spacetimes is outlined, emphasising the
essential ideas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02453</id><created>2016-02-07</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Abhirup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Archisman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson-McDaniel</keyname><forenames>Nathan K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Chandra Kant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ajith</keyname><forenames>Parameswaran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Pozzo</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nichols</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yanbei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Alex B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berry</keyname><forenames>Christopher P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>London</keyname><forenames>Lionel</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing general relativity using golden black-hole binaries</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figs</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1500185-v11, ICTS/2016/1</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 021101(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.021101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The coalescences of stellar-mass black-hole binaries through their inspiral,
merger, and ringdown are among the most promising sources for ground-based
gravitational-wave (GW) detectors. If a GW signal is observed with sufficient
signal-to-noise ratio, the masses and spins of the black holes can be estimated
from just the inspiral part of the signal. Using these estimates of the initial
parameters of the binary, the mass and spin of the final black hole can be
uniquely predicted making use of general-relativistic numerical simulations. In
addition, the mass and spin of the final black hole can be independently
estimated from the merger--ringdown part of the signal. If the binary black
hole dynamics is correctly described by general relativity (GR), these
independent estimates have to be consistent with each other. We present a
Bayesian implementation of such a test of general relativity, which allows us
to combine the constraints from multiple observations. Using kludge modified GR
waveforms, we demonstrate that this test can detect sufficiently large
deviations from GR, and outline the expected constraints from upcoming GW
observations using the second-generation of ground-based GW detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03169</id><created>2016-02-09</created><updated>2016-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for direct pair production of scalar top quarks in the single-
  and dilepton channels in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SUS-14-015/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-SUS-14-015, CERN-PH-EP-2016-004</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 07 (2016) 027, Erratum: JHEP 09 (2016) 056</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Results are reported from a search for the top squark, the lighter of the two
supersymmetric partners of the top quark. The data sample corresponds to 19.7
inverse femtobarns of proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV collected
with the CMS detector at the LHC. The search targets top squark to b chi+/- and
top squark to t(*) chi0 decay modes, where chi+/- and chi0 are the lightest
chargino and neutralino, respectively. The reconstructed final state consists
of jets, b jets, missing transverse energy, and either one or two leptons.
Leading backgrounds are determined from data. No significant excess in data is
observed above the expectation from standard model processes. The results
exclude a region of the two-dimensional plane of possible top squark and chi0
masses. The highest excluded top squark and chi0 masses are about 700 GeV and
250 GeV, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03889</id><created>2016-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Fowlie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balazs</keyname><forenames>Csaba</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Graham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzola</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raidal</keyname><forenames>Martti</forenames></author></authors><title>Naturalness of the relaxion mechanism</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><report-no>CoEPP-MN-16-2</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 08 (2016) 100</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)100</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relaxion mechanism is a novel solution to the hierarchy problem. In this
first statistical analysis of the relaxion mechanism, we quantify the relative
plausibility of a QCD and a non-QCD relaxion model versus the Standard Model
with Bayesian statistics, which includes an automatic penalty for fine-tuning.
We find that in light of the hierarchy between the weak and Planck scales,
relaxion models are favoured by colossal Bayes-factors. Constraints upon \eg
the vacuum energy during relaxation, however, shrink the Bayes-factors such
that relaxion models are only slightly favoured. Including the bounds on
$\left|\theta_\text{QCD}\right|$ shatters the plausibility of the QCD relaxion
model as it typically yields $\left|\theta_\text{QCD}\right| \gg 0$. Finally,
we augment our models with scalar-field inflation and consider measurements of
inflationary observables from BICEP/Planck. We find that, all told, the
Standard Model is favoured by huge Bayes-factors as the relaxion models require
fine-tuning such that the Hubble parameter is less than the height of the
periodic barriers. Thus, whilst we confirm that relaxion models could solve the
hierarchy problem, we find that their unconventional cosmology demolishes their
plausibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04196</id><created>2016-02-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hecksher</keyname><forenames>Tina</forenames></author></authors><title>Linking the dielectric Debye process in 2-ethyl-1-hexanol to its density
  fluctuations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Main paper: 5 pages, 3 figures. Supplementary Material: 6 pages, 5
  figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4947470</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide the first evidence that the puzzling dielectric Debye process
observed in mono-alcohols is coupled to density fluctuations. The results open
up for an explanation of the Debye process within the framework of conventional
liquid-state theory. The spectral shape of dynamical bulk modulus of
2-ethyl-1-hexanol is nearly identical to that of the shear modulus, and thus
the supramolecular structures believed to be responsible for the slow
dielectric Debye process are manifested in the bulk modulus in the same way as
in the shear modulus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05606</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2016-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for single production of vector-like quarks decaying into $Wb$ in
  $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s} =$ 8 TeV with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>24 pages plus author list (40 pages total), 8 figures, 3 tables,
  published version, all figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/EXOT-2014-12/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-319</report-no><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4281-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search for singly produced vector-like $Q$ quarks, where $Q$ can be either
a $T$ quark with charge $+2/3$ or a $Y$ quark with charge $-4/3$, is performed
in proton-proton collisions recorded with the ATLAS detector at the LHC. The
dataset corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 20.3 fb$^{-1}$ and was
produced with a centre-of-mass energy of $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV. This analysis
targets $Q \to Wb$ decays where the $W$ boson decays leptonically. A veto on
massive large-radius jets is used to reject the dominant $t\bar{t}$ background.
The reconstructed $Q$-candidate mass, ranging from 0.4 to 1.2 TeV, is used in
the search to discriminate signal from background processes. No significant
deviation from the Standard Model expectation is observed, and limits are set
on the $Q \to Wb$ cross-section times branching ratio. The results are also
interpreted as limits on the $QWb$ coupling and the mixing with the Standard
Model sector for a singlet $T$ quark or a $Y$ quark from a doublet. $T$ quarks
with masses below 0.95 TeV are excluded at 95% confidence level, assuming a
unit coupling and a BR$(T\rightarrow Wb) = 0.5$, whereas the expected limit is
1.10 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05987</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-03-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aspden</keyname><forenames>Reuben S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padgett</keyname><forenames>Miles J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spalding</keyname><forenames>Gabriel C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Video recording true single-photon double-slit interference</title><categories>quant-ph physics.ed-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Am. J. Phys. 84, 671 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4955173</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As normally used, no commercially available camera has a low-enough dark
noise to directly produce video recordings of double-slit interference at the
photon-by-photon level, because readout noise significantly contaminates or
overwhelms the signal. In this work, noise levels are significantly reduced by
turning on the camera only when the presence of a photon has been heralded by
the arrival, at an independent detector, of a time-correlated photon produced
via parametric down-conversion. This triggering scheme provides the improvement
required for direct video imaging of Young's double-slit experiment with single
photons, allowing clarified versions of this foundational demonstration.
Further, we introduce variations on this experiment aimed at promoting
discussion of the role spatial coherence plays in such a measurement. We also
emphasize complementary aspects of single-photon measurement, where imaging
yields (transverse) position information, while diffraction yields the
transverse momentum, and highlight the roles of transverse position and
momentum correlations between down-converted photons, including examples of
&quot;ghost&quot; imaging and diffraction. The videos can be accessed at
http://sun.iwu.edu/~gspaldin/SinglePhotonVideos.html online.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08164</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-08-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Changjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>You-Gen</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solutions in f(R) theory of gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures,accepted by GRG</comments><journal-ref>General Relativity and Gravitation, 48(10), 1-15, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2128-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find a new method for looking for the static and spherically symmetric
solutions in $F(R)$ theory of gravity. With this method, a number of new
solutions in terms of the analytic functions are obtained. We hope this
investigation may be of some help in the searching for some other solutions in
$F(R)$ theory of gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00017</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Bitan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juricic</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Sankar Das</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal optical conductivity of a disordered Weyl semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5.5 Pages and 1 Figure (Supplementary: 7.5 Pages and 1 Figure:
  Published version, new references, added discussion</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 32446 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep32446</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological Weyl semimetals, besides manifesting chiral anomaly, can also
accommodate a disorder-driven unconventional quantum phase transition into a
metallic phase. A fundamentally and practically important question in this
regard concerns an experimentally measurable quantity that can clearly
distinguish these two phases. We show that the optical conductivity while
serving this purpose can also play the role of a bonafide order parameter
across such disorder-driven semimetal-metal quantum phase transition by virtue
of displaying distinct scaling behavior in semimetallic and metallic phases, as
well as inside the quantum critical fan supporting a non-Fermi liquid. We
demonstrate that the correction to dielectric constant and optical conductivity
in a dirty Weyl semimetal due to weak disorder is independent of the actual
nature of point-like impurity scatterers. Therefore, optical conductivity can
be used as an experimentally measurable quantity to study the critical
properties and to pin the universality class of the disorder-driven quantum
phase transition in Weyl semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03282</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bahari</keyname><forenames>Masoud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>Mir Vahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Zeeman-field-induced nontrivial topological phases in a one-dimensional
  spin-orbit-coupled dimerized lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125119 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study theoretically the interplay effect of Zeeman field and modulated
spin-orbit coupling on topological properties of a one-dimensional dimerized
lattice, known as Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model. We find that in the weak (strong)
modulated spin-orbit coupling regime, trivial regions or nontrivial ones with
two pairs of zero-energy states can be turned into nontrivial regions by
applying a uniform (staggered) perpendicular Zeeman field through a topological
phase transition. Furthermore, the resulting nontrivial phase hosting a pair of
zero-energy boundary states can survive within a certain range of the
perpendicular Zeeman field magnitude. Due to the effective time-reversal,
particle-hole, chiral, and inversion symmetries, in the presence of either
uniform or staggered perpendicular Zeeman field, the topological class of the
system is BDI which can be characterized by $\mathbbm{Z}$ index. We also
examine the robustness of the nontrivial phase by breaking the underlying
symmetries giving rise that inversion symmetry plays an important role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04802</id><created>2016-03-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Querales-Flores</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ventura</keyname><forenames>C. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuhr</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrio</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The two gap transitions in Ge$_{1-x}$Sn$_x$: effect of
  non-substitutional complex defects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 120, 105705 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962381</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of non-substitutional $\beta$-Sn defects in Ge$_{1-x}$Sn$_{x}$
was confirmed by emission channeling experiments [Decoster et al., Phys. Rev. B
81, 155204 (2010)], which established that although most Sn enters
substitutionally ($\alpha$-Sn) in the Ge lattice, a second significant fraction
corresponds to the Sn-vacancy defect complex in the split-vacancy configuration
( $\beta$-Sn ), in agreement with our previous theoretical study [Ventura et
al., Phys. Rev. B 79, 155202 (2009)]. Here, we present our electronic structure
calculation for Ge$_{1-x}$Sn$_{x}$, including substitutional $\alpha$-Sn as
well as non-substitutional $\beta$-Sn defects. To include the presence of
non-substitutional complex defects in the electronic structure calculation for
this multi-orbital alloy problem, we extended the approach for the purely
substitutional alloy by Jenkins and Dow [Jenkins and Dow, Phys. Rev. B 36, 7994
(1987)]. We employed an effective substitutional two-site cluster equivalent to
the real non-substitutional $\beta$-Sn defect, which was determined by a
Green's functions calculation. We then calculated the electronic structure of
the effective alloy purely in terms of substitutional defects, embedding the
effective substitutional clusters in the lattice. Our results describe the two
transitions of the fundamental gap of Ge$_{1-x}$Sn$_{x}$ as a function of the
total Sn-concentration: namely from an indirect to a direct gap, first, and the
metallization transition at higher $x$. They also highlight the role of
$\beta$-Sn in the reduction of the concentration range which corresponds to the
direct-gap phase of this alloy, of interest for optoelectronics applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00798</id><created>2016-04-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Urna</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Buyl</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maes</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto&#x10d;n&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>Karel</forenames></author></authors><title>Driving-induced stability with long-range effects</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><proxy>Pierre de Buyl</proxy><journal-ref>EPL 115 30007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/30007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a sufficient condition under which an applied rotation on medium
particles stabilizes a slow probe in the rotation center. The symmetric part of
the stiffness matrix thus gets a positive Lamb shift with respect to
equilibrium. For illustration we take diffusive medium particles with a
self-potential in the shape of a Mexican hat, high around the origin. There is
a short-range attraction between the medium particles and the heavier probe,
all immersed in an equilibrium thermal bath. For no or small rotation force on
the medium particles, the origin is an unstable fixed point for the probe and
the precise shape of the self-potential at large distances from the origin is
irrelevant for the statistical force there. Above a certain rotation threshold,
while the medium particles are still repelled from the origin, the probe
stabilizes there and more details of the medium-density at large distance start
to matter. The effect is robust around the quasi-static limit with rotation
threshold only weakly depending on the temperature but the stabilization gets
stronger at lower temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01318</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pimentel</keyname><forenames>Oscar M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Guillermo A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lora-Clavijo</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Energy-Momentum Tensor for a Dissipative Fluid in General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in General Relativity and Gravitation, 8
  pages, Minor changes</comments><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2121-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Considering the growing interest of the astrophysicist community in the study
of dissipative fluids with the aim of getting a more realistic description of
the universe, we present in this paper a physical analysis of the
energy-momentum tensor of a viscous fluid with heat flux. We introduce the
general form of this tensor and, using the approximation of small velocity
gradients, we relate the stresses of the fluid with the viscosity coefficients,
the shear tensor and the expansion factor. Exploiting these relations, we can
write the stresses in terms of the extrinsic curvature of the normal surface to
the 4-velocity vector of the fluid, and we can also establish a connection
between the perfect fluid and the symmetries of the spacetime. On the other
hand, we calculate the energy conditions for a dissipative fluid through
contractions of the energy-momentum tensor with the 4-velocity vector of an
arbitrary observer. This method is interesting because it allows us to compute
the conditions in a reasonable easy way and without considering any
approximation or restriction on the energy-momentum tensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04781</id><created>2016-04-16</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Shun-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jian-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagram and topological phases in the triangular lattice
  Kitaev-Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>published version, references updated</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125120 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the half-filled Hubbard model on the triangular lattice with
spin-dependent Kitaev-like hopping. Using the variational cluster approach, we
identify five phases: a metallic phase, a non-coplanar chiral magnetic order, a
$120^\circ$ magnetic order, a nonmagnetic insulator (NMI), and an interacting
Chern insulator (CI) with a nonzero Chern number. The transition from CI to NMI
is characterized by the change of the charge gap from an indirect band gap to a
direct Mott gap. Based on the slave-rotor mean-field theory, the NMI phase is
further suggested to be a gapless Mott insulator with a spinon Fermi surface or
a fractionalized CI with nontrivial spinon topology, depending on the strength
of Kitaev-like hopping. Our work highlights the rising field that interesting
phases emerge from the interplay of band topology and Mott physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08141</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piroli</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Essler</keyname><forenames>Fabian H. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum quenches to the attractive one-dimensional Bose gas: exact
  results</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>30 pages, 3 figures; v2: references added; v3: minor revision;
  submitted to SciPost Physics</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 1, 001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.1.1.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study quantum quenches to the one-dimensional Bose gas with attractive
interactions in the case when the initial state is an ideal one-dimensional
Bose condensate. We focus on properties of the stationary state reached at late
times after the quench. This displays a finite density of multi-particle bound
states, whose rapidity distribution is determined exactly by means of the
quench action method. We discuss the relevance of the multi-particle bound
states for the physical properties of the system, computing in particular the
stationary value of the local pair correlation function $g_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08282</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Zhong-Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Lu-Yao</forenames></author></authors><title>AdS and Lifshitz Scalar Hairy Black Holes in Gauss-Bonnet Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>28pages, no figures, minor corrections, references added,published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider Gauss-Bonnet (GB) gravity in general dimensions, which is
non-minimally coupled to a scalar field. By choosing the scalar potential of
the type $V(\phi)=2\Lambda_0+\fft 12m^2\phi^2+\gamma_4\phi^4$, we first obtain
large classes of scalar hairy black holes with spherical/hyperbolic/planar
topologies that are asymptotic to locally anti-de Sitter (AdS) space-times. We
derive the first law of black hole thermodynamics using Wald formalism. In
particular, for one class of the solutions, the scalar hair forms a
thermodynamic conjugate with the graviton and nontrivially contributes to the
thermodynamical first law. We observe that except for one class of the planar
black holes, all these solutions are constructed at the critical point of GB
gravity where there exists an unique AdS vacua. In fact, Lifshitz vacuum is
also allowed at the critical point. We then construct many new classes of
neutral and charged Lifshitz black hole solutions for a either minimally or
non-minimally coupled scalar and derive the thermodynamical first laws. We also
obtain new classes of exact dynamical AdS and Lifshitz solutions which describe
radiating white holes. The solutions eventually become an AdS or Lifshitz vacua
at late retarded times. However, for one class of the solutions the final state
is an AdS space-time with a globally naked singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00941</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Ya-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Liang-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Xing-Zhong</forenames></author></authors><title>e$^{+}$/e$^{-}$ Discrimination in Liquid Scintillator and Its Usage to
  Suppress $^{8}$He/$^{9}$Li Backgrounds</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages,8 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/1/016101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reactor neutrino experiments build large-scale detector systems to detect
neutrinos. In liquid scintillator, a neutral bound state of a positron and an
electron, named positronium, can be formed. The spin triplet state is called
ortho-positronium (o-Ps). In this article, an experiment is designed to measure
the lifetime of o-Ps, giving a result of 3.1 ns. A PSD parameter based on
photon emission time distribution (PETD) was constructed to discriminate
e$^+$/e$^-$. Finally, the application of e$^+$/e$^-$ discrimination in the JUNO
experiment is shown. It helps suppress $^{8}$He/$^{9}$Li backgrounds and
improves the sensitivity by 0.6 in $\chi^2$ analysis with an assumption of
$\sigma$=1 ns PMT Transit Time Spread, which will bring a smearing effect to
the PETD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00997</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Dipankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondal</keyname><forenames>Chandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Nucleon to $\Delta$ transition form factors and empirical transverse
  charge densities</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures; minor text modified, version to appear in Eur.
  Phys. J. A</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A 52, 285 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16285-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nucleon to $\Delta$ transition form factors in a soft-wall
AdS/QCD model and a light-front quark-diquark model inspired by AdS/QCD. From
the transition form factors we evaluate the transition charge densities which
influences the nucleon to $\Delta$ excitation. Here we consider both the
unpolarized and the transversely polarized cases. The AdS/QCD predictions are
compared with available experimental data and with the results of the global
parameterization, MAID2007.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02793</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lefranc</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panci</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamon</keyname><forenames>Gary A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prospects for annihilating Dark Matter towards Milky Way's dwarf
  galaxies by the Cherenkov Telescope Array</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages + references, 4 figures. v2: a few comments and references
  added, version published in JCAP</comments><report-no>IRFU-15-36</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP09(2016)021</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/09/021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA) sensitivity to dark matter (DM)
annihilation in several primary channels, over a broad range of DM masses.
These sensitivities are estimated when CTA is pointed towards a large sample of
Milky Way's dwarf spheroidal galaxies (dSphs) with promising $J$-factors and
small statistical uncertainties. This analysis neglects systematic
uncertainties, which we estimate at the level of at least 1 dex. We also
present sensitivities on the annihilation cross section from a combined
analysis of 4 dSphs. We assess the CTA sensitivity by: $i)$ using, for each
dSph, a recent determination of the $J$-factor and its statistical error; $ii)$
considering the most up-to-date cosmic ray background; and $iii)$ including
both spatial and spectral terms in the likelihood analysis. We find that a
joint spectral and spatial analysis improves the CTA sensitivity, in particular
for primary channels with sharp features in the $\gamma$-ray energy spectrum
and for dSphs with steep $J$-factor profiles, as deduced from the internal
kinematics. The greatest sensitivities are obtained for observations of Ursa
Minor among the classical dSphs and of Ursa Major II for ultra-faint dSphs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03946</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garaud</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babaev</keyname><forenames>Egor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bojesen</keyname><forenames>Troels Arnfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudb&#xf8;</keyname><forenames>Asle</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattices of double-quanta vortices and chirality inversion in $p_x+ip_y$
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Replaced with a version in print in Phys. Rev. B; Minor changes and
  references added; 12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the magnetization processes of a standard Ginzburg-Landau
model for chiral p-wave superconducting states in an applied magnetic field. We
find that the phase diagram is dominated by triangular lattices of doubly
quantized vortices. Only in close vicinity to the upper critical field, the
lattice starts to dissociate into a structure of single-quanta vortices. The
degeneracy between states with opposite chirality is broken in a nonzero field.
If the magnetization starts with an energetically unfavorable chirality, the
process of chirality-inversion induced by the external magnetic field results
in the formation of a sequence of metastable states with characteristic
magnetic signatures that can be probed by standard experimental techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07770</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sheftel</keyname><forenames>Mikhail B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yaz&#x131;c&#x131;</keyname><forenames>Devrim</forenames></author></authors><title>Recursion Operators and Tri-Hamiltonian Structure of the First Heavenly
  Equation of Pleba\'nski</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>Some text overlap with our paper arXiv:1510.03666 is caused by our
  use here of basically the same method for discovering the Hamiltonian and
  bi-Hamiltonian structures of the equation, but the equation considered here
  and the results are totally different from arXiv:1510.03666</comments><proxy>Sigma</proxy><msc-class>35Q75, 35L65, 83C15, 37K05, 37K10</msc-class><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 091, 17 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.091</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present first heavenly equation of Pleba\'nski in a two-component
evolutionary form and obtain Lagrangian and Hamiltonian representations of this
system. We study all point symmetries of the two-component system and, using
the inverse Noether theorem in the Hamiltonian form, obtain all the integrals
of motion corresponding to each variational (Noether) symmetry. We derive two
linearly independent recursion operators for symmetries of this system related
by a discrete symmetry of both the two-component system and its symmetry
condition. Acting by these operators on the first Hamiltonian operator $J_0$ we
obtain second and third Hamiltonian operators. However, we were not able to
find Hamiltonian densities corresponding to the latter two operators.
Therefore, we construct two recursion operators, which are either even or odd,
respectively, under the above-mentioned discrete symmetry. Acting with them on
$J_0$, we generate another two Hamiltonian operators $J_+$ and $J_-$ and find
the corresponding Hamiltonian densities, thus obtaining second and third
Hamiltonian representations for the first heavenly equation in a two-component
form. Using P. Olver's theory of the functional multi-vectors, we check that
the linear combination of $J_0$, $J_+$ and $J_-$ with arbitrary constant
coefficients satisfies Jacobi identities. Since their skew symmetry is obvious,
these three operators are compatible Hamiltonian operators and hence we obtain
a tri-Hamiltonian representation of the first heavenly equation. Our
well-founded conjecture applied here is that P. Olver's method works fine for
nonlocal operators and our proof of the Jacobi identities and bi-Hamiltonian
structures crucially depends on the validity of this conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07971</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Owerre</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chirality-induced magnon transport in AA-stacked bilayer honeycomb
  chiral magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages. 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 47LT02 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/47/47LT02</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Letter, we study the magnetic transport in AA-stacked bilayer
honeycomb chiral magnets coupled either ferromagnetically or
antiferromagnetically. For both couplings, we observe chirality-induced gaps,
chiral protected edge states, magnon Hall and magnon spin Nernst effects of
magnetic spin excitations. For ferromagnetically coupled layers, thermal Hall
and spin Nernst conductivities do not change sign as function of magnetic field
or temperature similar to single-layer honeycomb ferromagnetic insulator. In
contrast, for antiferromagnetically coupled layers, we observe a sign change in
the thermal Hall and spin Nernst conductivities as the magnetic field is
reversed. We discuss possible experimental accessible honeycomb bilayer quantum
materials in which these effects can be observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08876</id><created>2016-05-28</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keesman</keyname><forenames>Rick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamers</keyname><forenames>Jules</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duine</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barkema</keyname><forenames>G. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size scaling at infinite-order phase transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.SI</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, 1 table; v2: publication details added</comments><journal-ref>J Stat Mech: Theor Exp, vol 2016 (2016), pp 093201</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/09/093201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For systems with infinite-order phase transitions, in which an order
parameter smoothly becomes nonzero, a new observable for finite-size scaling
analysis is suggested. By construction this new observable has the favourable
property of diverging at the critical point. Focussing on the example of the
F-model we compare the analysis of this observable with that of another
observable, which is also derived from the order parameter but does not
diverge, as well as that of the associated susceptibility. We discuss the
difficulties that arise in the finite-size scaling analysis of such systems. In
particular we show that one may reach incorrect conclusions from large-system
size extrapolations of observables that are not known to diverge at the
critical point. Our work suggests that one should base finite-size scaling
analyses for infinite-order phase transitions only on observables that are
guaranteed to diverge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09385</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haim</keyname><forenames>Arbel</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xf6;lms</keyname><forenames>Konrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Erez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oreg</keyname><forenames>Yuval</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flensberg</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction-driven topological superconductivity in one dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Published version, 9 pages + appendices, 8 figures</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV CMT 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115124 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study one-dimensional topological superconductivity in the presence of
time-reversal symmetry. This phase is characterized by having a bulk gap, while
supporting a Kramers' pair of zero-energy Majorana bound states at each of its
ends. We present a general simple model which is driven into this topological
phase in the presence of repulsive electron-electron interactions. We further
propose two experimental setups and show that they realize this model at low
energies. The first setup is a narrow two-dimensional topological insulator
partially covered by a conventional s-wave superconductor, and the second is a
semiconductor wire in proximity to an s-wave superconductor. These systems can
therefore be used to realize and probe the time-reversal invariant topological
superconducting phase. The effect of interactions is studied using both a
mean-field approach and a renormalization group analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00633</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tomczyk</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paj&#x105;k</keyname><forenames>Grzegorz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longa</keyname><forenames>Lech</forenames></author></authors><title>Twist-bend nematic phases of bent-shaped biaxial molecules</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 7445 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01197G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How change in molecular structure can affect relative stability and
structural properties of the twist-bend nematic phase (N$_\text{TB}$)? Here we
extend the mean-field model [C. Greco et al., Soft Matter, 2014, 10, 9318] for
bent-shaped achiral molecules, to study the influence of arm molecular
biaxiality and the value of molecule's bend angle on relative stability of
N$_\text{TB}$. In particular we show that by controlling biaxiality of
molecule's arms up to four ordered phases can become stable. They involve
locally uniaxial and biaxial variants of N$_\text{TB}$, together with the
uniaxial and the biaxial nematic phases. However, the V-shaped molecule show
stronger ability to form stable N$_\text{TB}$ than a biaxial nematic phase,
where the latter phase appears in the phase diagram only for bend angles
greater than $140^\circ$ and for large biaxiality of the two arms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02151</id><created>2016-06-07</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ropo</keyname><forenames>Matti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blum</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldauf</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Trends for isolated amino acids and dipeptides: Conformation, divalent
  ion binding, and remarkable similarity of binding to calcium and lead</title><categories>q-bio.BM physics.atm-clus physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>submitted, underlying data can be found here:
  http://aminoaciddb.rz-berlin.mpg.de/</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive structural and binding energy trends for twenty amino acids, their
dipeptides, and their interactions with the divalent cations Ca$^{2+}$,
Ba$^{2+}$, Sr$^{2+}$, Cd$^{2+}$, Pb$^{2+}$, and Hg$^{2+}$. The underlying data
set consists of 45,892 first-principles predicted conformers with relative
energies up to about 4 eV (about 400kJ/mol). We show that only very few
distinct backbone structures of isolated amino acids and their dipeptides
emerge as lowest-energy conformers. The isolated amino acids predominantly
adopt structures that involve an acidic proton shared between the carboxy and
amino function. Dipeptides adopt one of two intramolecular-hydrogen bonded
conformations C$_5$ or equatorial C$_7$. Upon complexation with a divalent
cation, the accessible conformational space shrinks and intramolecular hydrogen
bonding is prevented due to strong electrostatic interaction of backbone and
side chain functional groups with cations. Clear correlations emerge from the
binding energies of the six divalent ions with amino acids and dipeptides.
Cd$^{2+}$ and Hg$^{2+}$ show the largest binding energies - a potential
correlation with their known high acute toxicities. Ca$^{2+}$ and Pb$^{2+}$
reveal almost identical binding energies across the entire series of amino
acids and dipeptides. This observation validates past indications that
ion-mimicry of calcium and lead should play an important role in a
toxicological context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07486</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karlsson</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial self-consistency and analyticity in many-body perturbation
  theory: particle number conservation and a generalized sum rule</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Minor changes, corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125124 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125124</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a general class of approximations which guarantees the
conservation of particle number in many-body perturbation theory. To do this we
extend the concept of $\Phi$-derivability for the self-energy $\Sigma$ to a
larger class of diagrammatic terms in which only some of the Green's function
lines contain the fully dressed Green's function $G$. We call the corresponding
approximations for $\Sigma$ partially $\Phi$-derivable. A special subclass of
such approximations, which are gauge-invariant, is obtained by dressing loops
in the diagrammatic expansion of $\Phi$ consistently with $G$. These
approximations are number conserving but do not have to fulfill other
conservation laws, such as the conservation of energy and momentum. From our
formalism we can easily deduce if commonly used approximations will fulfill the
continuity equation, which implies particle number conservation. We further
show how the concept of partial $\Phi$-derivability plays an important role in
the derivation of a generalized sum rule for the particle number, which reduces
to the Luttinger-Ward theorem in the case of a homogeneous electron gas, and
the Friedel sum rule in the case of the Anderson model. To do this we need to
ensure that the Green's function has certain complex analytic properties, which
can be guaranteed if the spectral function is positive semi-definite.The latter
property can be ensured for a subset of partially $\Phi$-derivable
approximations for the self-energy, namely those that can be constructed from
squares of so-called half-diagrams. In case the analytic requirements are not
fulfilled we highlight a number of subtle issues related to branch cuts, pole
structure and multi-valuedness. We also show that various schemes of computing
the particle number are consistent for particle number conserving
approximations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07856</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halimeh</keyname><forenames>Jad C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Punk</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin structure factors of chiral quantum spin liquids on the kagome
  lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, journal paper</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104413 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate dynamical spin structure factors for gapped chiral spin liquid
states in the spin-1/2 Heisenberg antiferromagnet on the kagome lattice using
Schwinger-boson mean-field theory. In contrast to static (equal-time) structure
factors, the dynamical structure factor shows clear signatures of time-reversal
symmetry breaking for chiral spin liquid states. In particular, momentum
inversion $\bm{k} \to -\bm{k}$ symmetry as well as the six-fold rotation
symmetry around the $\Gamma$-point are lost. We highlight other interesting
features, such as a relatively flat onset of the two-spinon continuum for the
\emph{cuboc1} state. Our work is based on the projective symmetry group
classification of time-reversal symmetry breaking Schwinger-boson mean-field
states by Messio, Lhuillier, and Misguich.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09213</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Braathen</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodsell</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slavich</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>Leading two-loop corrections to the Higgs boson masses in SUSY models
  with Dirac gauginos</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 5 figures; v2: version published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1609 (2016) 045</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the two-loop O(as*at) corrections to the Higgs boson masses in
supersymmetric extensions of the Standard Model with Dirac gaugino masses. We
rely on the effective-potential technique, allow for both Dirac and Majorana
mass terms for the gluinos, and compute the corrections in both the DRbar and
on-shell renormalisation schemes. We give detailed results for the MDGSSM and
the MRSSM, and simple approximate formulae valid in the decoupling limit for
all currently-studied variants of supersymmetric models with Dirac gluinos.
These results represent the first explicit two-loop calculation of Higgs boson
masses in supersymmetric models beyond the MSSM and the NMSSM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00398</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Artymowski</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>Endlessly flat scalar potentials and $\alpha$-attractors</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B761 (2016) 111-114</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a minimally-coupled inflationary theory with a general scalar
potential $V(f(\varphi))= V(\xi\sum_{k=1}^{n}\lambda_k \varphi^k)$ containing a
stationary point of maximal order $m$. We show that asymptotically flat
potentials can be associated to stationary points of infinite order and discuss
the relation of our approach to the theory of $\alpha$-attractors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00399</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sobreiro</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaz</keyname><forenames>Anderson A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting Planck scale and Newtonian constant from a Yang-Mills gauge
  theory: 1 and 2-loops estimates</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>22 pages and 8 figures. This new version contains some clarification
  points raised by the referee. To appear in Advances in High Energy Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, a model for an emergent gravity based on $SO(5)$ Yang-Mills action
in Euclidian 4-dimensional spacetime was proposed. In this work we provide some
1 and 2-loops computations and show that the model can accommodate suitable
predicting values for the Newtonian constant. Moreover, it is shown that the
typical scale of the expected transition between the quantum and the
geometrodynamical theory is consistent with Planck scale. We also provide a
discussion on the cosmological constant problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01771</id><created>2016-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Tianci</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faulkner</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fradkin</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy and Mutual Information of Circular Entangling
  Surfaces in 2 + 1-dimensional Quantum Lifshitz Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 2016(9):093101, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/09/093101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the entanglement entropy (EE) of circular entangling cuts in
the 2+1-dimensional quantum Lifshitz model, whose ground state wave function is
a spatially conformal invariant state of the Rokhsar-Kivelson type, whose
weight is the Gibbs weight of 2D Euclidean free boson. We show that the finite
subleading corrections of EE to the area-law term as well as the mutual
information are conformal invariants and calculate them for cylinder, disk-like
and spherical manifolds with various spatial cuts. The subtlety due to the
boson compactification in the replica trick is carefully addressed. We find
that in the geometry of a punctured plane with many small holes, the constant
piece of EE is proportional to the number of holes, indicating the ability of
entanglement to detect topological information of the configuration. Finally,
we compare the mutual information of two small distant disks with Cardy's
relativistic CFT scaling proposal. We find that in the quantum Lifshitz model,
the mutual information also scales at long distance with a power determined by
the lowest scaling dimension local operator in the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04714</id><created>2016-07-16</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oono</keyname><forenames>Shuhei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kariyado</keyname><forenames>Toshikaze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsugai</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Section Chern number for a 3D photonic crystal and the bulk-edge
  correspondence</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have characterized the robust propagation modes of electromagnetic waves
in helical structures by the section Chern number that is defined for a
two-dimensional (2D) section of the three- dimensional (3D) Brillouin zone. The
Weyl point in the photonic bands is associated with a dis- continuous jump of
the section Chern number. A spatially localized Gaussian basis set is used to
calculate the section Chern numbers where we have implemented the
divergence-free condition on each basis function in 3D. The validity of the
bulk-edge correspondence in a 3D photonic crystal is discussed in relation to
the broken inversion symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07652</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Steinkasserer</keyname><forenames>Lukas Eugen Marsoner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zarantonello</keyname><forenames>Alessandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paulus</keyname><forenames>Beate</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong 1D localization and highly anisotropic electron-hole masses in
  heavy-halogen functionalized graphenes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics, 2016, 18, 25629 - 25636</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP05188J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While halogenation of graphene presents a fascinating avenue to the
construction of a chemically and physically diverse class of systems, their
application in photovoltaics has been hindered by often prohibitively large
optical gaps. Herein we study the effects of partial bromination and
chlorination on the structure and optoelectronic properties of both graphane
and fluorographene. We find brominated and chlorinated fluorographene
derivatives to be as stable as graphane making them likely to be durable even
at elevated temperatures. A detailed investigation of the systems band
structure reveals significant 1D localization of the charge carriers as well as
strongly electron-hole asymmetric effective masses. Lastly using $G_0W_0$ and
BSE, we investigate the optical adsorption spectra of the aforementioned
materials whose first adsorption peak is shown to lie close to the optimal peak
position for photovoltaic applications ($\approx 1.5$ eV).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07759</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>Sumegha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuen</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhandry</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>New security notions and feasibility results for authentication of
  quantum data</title><categories>cs.CR quant-ph</categories><comments>50 pages, QCrypt 2016 - 6th International Conference on Quantum
  Cryptography, added a new lifting theorem that shows equivalence between a
  weak form of authentication security and a stronger notion that considers
  side information</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a new class of security definitions for authentication in the quantum
setting. These definitions capture and strengthen existing definitions of
security against quantum adversaries for both classical message authentication
codes (MACs) and well as full quantum state authentication schemes. The main
feature of our definitions is that they precisely characterize the effective
behavior of any adversary when the authentication protocol accepts, including
correlations with the key. Our definitions readily yield a host of desirable
properties and interesting consequences; for example, our security definition
for full quantum state authentication implies that the entire secret key can be
re-used if the authentication protocol succeeds.
  Next, we present several protocols satisfying our security definitions. We
show that the classical Wegman-Carter authentication scheme with 3-universal
hashing is secure against superposition attacks, as well as adversaries with
quantum side information. We then present conceptually simple constructions of
full quantum state authentication.
  Finally, we prove a lifting theorem which shows that, as long as a protocol
can securely authenticate the maximally entangled state, it can securely
authenticate any state, even those that are entangled with the adversary. Thus,
this shows that protocols satisfying a fairly weak form of authentication
security automatically satisfy a stronger notion of security (in particular,
the definition of Dupuis, et al (2012)).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00084</id><created>2016-07-30</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fuks</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Dong Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Seong Chan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>Min-Seok</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating the jet activity accompanying the production at the LHC of
  a massive scalar particle decaying into photons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 10 figures, accepted version to be published in PLB (V2)</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B761 (2016) 344-349</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the jet activity that accompanies the production by gluon fusion of
a new physics scalar particle decaying into photons at the LHC. In the
considered scenarios, both the production and decay mechanisms are governed by
loop-induced interactions involving a heavy colored state. We show that the
presence of large new physics contributions to the inclusive diphoton
invariant-mass spectrum always implies a significant production rate of
non-standard diphoton events containing extra hard jets. We investigate the
existence of possible handles that could provide a way to obtain information on
the underlying physics behind the scalar resonance, and this in a wide mass
window.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02560</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Bitan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juricic</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herbut</keyname><forenames>Igor F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on &quot;Quantum superconducting criticality in graphene and topological
  insulators&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>2 Pages, 1 Figure: Erratum published in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 119901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.119901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We correct our previous conclusion regarding the fate of a charged quantum
critical point across the superconducting transition for two dimensional
massless Dirac fermion. Within the leading order $\epsilon$ expansion, we now
find that the requisite number of four-component Dirac fermion flavors ($N_f$)
for the continuous phase transition through a charged critical point is
$N_f&gt;18.2699$. For $N_f\geq1/2$, the critical number of bosonic flavors for
this transition is significantly reduced as compared to the value determined in
the absence of the Dirac fermions in the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03212</id><created>2016-08-09</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Horndeski</keyname><forenames>Gregory W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lagrange Multipliers and Third Order Scalar-Tensor Field Theories</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>45 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a space of 4-dimensions, I will examine constrained variational problems
in which the Lagrangian, and constraint scalar density, are concomitants of a
(pseudo-Riemannian) metric tensor and its first two derivatives. The Lagrange
multiplier for these constrained extremal problems will be a scalar field. For
suitable choices of the Lagrangian, and constraint, we can obtain
Euler-Lagrange equations which are second order in the scalar field and third
order in the metric tensor. The effect of disformal transformations on the
constraint Lagrangians, and their generalizations, is examined. This will yield
other second order scalar-tensor Lagrangians which yield field equations which
are at most of third order. No attempt is made to construct all possible third
order scalar-tensor Euler-Lagrange equations in a 4-space, although nine
classes of such field equations are presented. Two of these classes admit
subclasses which yield conformally invariant field equations. A few remarks on
scalar-tensor-connection theories are also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03434</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mette</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fer</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Second-harmonic imaging microscopy for time-resolved investigations on
  transition metal dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heterostructures of two-dimensional transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDC)
have shown promise for various applications in optoelectronics and so-called
valleytronics. Their operation and performance strongly depend on the stacking
of individual layers. Here, optical second-harmonic generation (SHG) in imaging
mode is shown to be a versatile tool for systematic time-resolved
investigations of TMDC monolayers and heterostructures in consideration of the
material's structure. Large sample areas can be probed in a single shot without
the need of any mapping or scanning. By means of polarization dependent
measurements, the crystalline orientation of monolayers or the stacking angles
of heterostructures can be evaluated for the whole field of view. Pump-probe
experiments then allow to correlate observed transient changes of the second
harmonic response with the underlying structure. The corresponding
time-resolution is virtually limited by the pulse duration of the used laser.
As an example, polarization dependent and time-resolved measurements on
single-layer MoS2 and WS2 flakes grown on a SiO2/Si(001) substrate are
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03698</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Igata</keyname><forenames>Takahisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houri</keyname><forenames>Tsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-similar motion of a Nambu-Goto string</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figure, version to be published in Physical Review D</comments><report-no>RUP-16-24, KOBE-COSMO-16-08</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064029 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the self-similar motion of a string in a self-similar spacetime by
introducing the concept of a self-similar string, which is defined as the world
sheet to which a homothetic vector field is tangent. It is shown that in
Nambu-Goto theory, the equations of motion for a self-similar string reduce to
those for a particle. Moreover, under certain conditions such as the
hypersurface orthogonality of the homothetic vector field, the equations of
motion for a self-similar string simplify to the geodesic equations on a
(pseudo) Riemannian space. As a concrete example, we investigate a self-similar
Nambu-Goto string in a spatially flat Friedmann-Lema\^itre-Robertson-Walker
expanding universe with self-similarity and obtain solutions of open and closed
strings, which have various nontrivial configurations depending on the rate of
the cosmic expansion. For instance, we obtain a circular solution that evolves
linearly in the cosmic time while keeping its configuration by the balance
between the effects of the cosmic expansion and string tension. We also show
the instability for linear radial perturbation of the circular solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06390</id><created>2016-08-23</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amarsi</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lind</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asplund</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barklem</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collet</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-LTE line formation of Fe in late-type stars - III. 3D non-LTE
  analysis of metal-poor stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures; Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2077</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As one of the most important elements in astronomy, iron abundance
determinations need to be as accurate as possible. We investigate the accuracy
of spectroscopic iron abundance analyses using archetypal metal-poor stars. We
perform detailed 3D non-LTE radiative transfer calculations based on 3D
hydrodynamic Stagger model atmospheres, and employ a new model atom that
includes new quantum-mechanical neutral hydrogen collisional rate coefficients.
With the exception of the red giant HD122563, we find that the 3D non-LTE
models achieve Fe i/Fe ii excitation and ionization balance as well as not
having any trends with equivalent width to within modelling uncertainties of
0.05 dex, all without having to invoke any microturbulent broadening; for
HD122563 we predict that the current best parallax-based surface gravity is
over-estimated by 0.5 dex. Using a 3D non-LTE analysis, we infer iron
abundances from the 3D model atmospheres that are roughly 0.1 dex higher than
corresponding abundances from 1D MARCS model atmospheres; these differences go
in the same direction as the non-LTE effects themselves. We make available
grids of departure coefficients, equivalent widths and abundance corrections,
calculated on 1D MARCS model atmospheres and horizontally- and
temporally-averaged 3D Stagger model atmospheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08786</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendner</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cusatis</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author></authors><title>Age-dependent Size Effect and Fracture Characteristics of Ultra High
  Performance Concrete</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1509.07801</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents an investigation of the age-dependent size effect and
fracture characteristics of an ultra high performance concrete (UHPC). The
study is based on a unique set of experimental data connecting aging tests for
two curing protocols of one size and scaled size effect tests of one age. Both
aging and size effect studies are performed on notched three point bending
tests. Experimental data is augmented by state of the art simulations employing
a recently developed discrete element based early-age computational framework.
The framework is constructed by coupling a hygro-thermo-chemical (HTC) model
and the Lattice Discrete Particle Model (LDPM) through a set of aging
functions. The HTC component allows taking into account variable curing
conditions and predicts the maturity of concrete. The mechanical component,
LDPM, simulates the failure behavior of concrete at the length scale of major
heterogeneities. After careful calibration and validation the mesoscale
HTC-LDPM model is uniquely posed to perform predictive simulations. The
ultimate flexural strengths from experiments and simulations are analyzed by
the cohesive size effect curve (CSEC) method, and the classical size effect law
(SEL). The fracture energies obtained by LDPM, CSEC, SEL, and cohesive crack
analyses are compared and an aging formulation for fracture properties is
proposed. Based on experiments, simulations, and size effect analyses, the
age-dependence of size effect and the robustness of analytical size effect
methods are evaluated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08860</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Jermak</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steele</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindfors</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hovatta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamb</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mundell</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Almeida</keyname><forenames>U. Barres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berdyugin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadenius</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinthal</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takalo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>The RINGO2 and DIPOL Optical Polarisation Catalogue of Blazars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>34 pages, 23 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (November 11, 2016) 462 (4): 4267-4299</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1770</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present ~2000 polarimetric and ~3000 photometric observations of 15
gamma-ray bright blazars over a period of 936 days (11/10/2008 - 26/10/2012)
using data from the Tuorla blazar monitoring program (KVA DIPOL) and Liverpool
Telescope (LT) RINGO2 polarimeters (supplemented with data from SkyCamZ (LT)
and Fermi-LAT gamma-ray data). In 11 out of 15 sources we identify a total of
19 electric vector position angle (EVPA) rotations and 95 flaring episodes. We
group the sources into subclasses based on their broadband spectral
characteristics and compare their observed optical and gamma-ray properties. We
find that (1) the optical magnitude and gamma-ray flux are positively
correlated, (2) EVPA rotations can occur in any blazar subclass, 4 sources show
rotations that go in one direction and immediately rotate back, (3) we see no
difference in the gamma-ray flaring rates in the sample; flares can occur
during and outside of rotations with no preference for this behaviour, (4) the
average degree of polarisation (DoP), optical magnitude and gamma-ray flux are
lower during an EVPA rotation compared with during non-rotation and the
distribution of the DoP during EVPA rotations is not drawn from the same parent
sample as the distribution outside rotations, (5) the number of observed
flaring events and optical polarisation rotations are correlated, however we
find no strong evidence for a temporal association between individual flares
and rotations and (6) the maximum observed DoP increases from ~10% to ~30% to
~40% for subclasses with synchrotron peaks at high, intermediate and low
frequencies respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00524</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>&#x17b;ejmo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>Janusz Gil Institute of Astronomy, University of Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Lubuska 2, 65-265 Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Poland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>S&#x142;owikowska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Janusz Gil Institute of Astronomy, University of Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Lubuska 2, 65-265 Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Poland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Krzeszowski</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Janusz Gil Institute of Astronomy, University of Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Lubuska 2, 65-265 Zielona G&#xf3;ra, Poland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reig</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Foundation for Research and Technology, 71110 Heraklion, Crete, Greece</affiliation><affiliation>University of Crete, Physics Department, PO Box 2208, 710 03 Heraklion, Crete, Greece</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Blinov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>Foundation for Research and Technology, 71110 Heraklion, Crete, Greece</affiliation><affiliation>University of Crete, Physics Department, PO Box 2208, 710 03 Heraklion, Crete, Greece</affiliation><affiliation>Astronomical Institute, St. Petersburg State University, Universitetsky pr. 28, Petrodvoretz, 198504 St. Petersburg, Russia</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical linear polarization of 74 white dwarfs with the RoboPol
  polarimeter</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>submitted to MNRAS, electronic version of combined Tab 1 and Tab 4
  under the link http://astro.ia.uz.zgora.pl/~chriss/grant/tables_en.html</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2335</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first linear polarimetric survey of white dwarfs (WDs). Our
sample consists of WDs of DA and DC spectral types in the SDSS r magnitude
range from 13 to 17. We performed polarimetric observations with the RoboPol
polarimeter attached to the 1.3-m telescope at the Skinakas Observatory. We
have 74 WDs in our sample, of which almost all are low polarized WDs with
polarization degree (PD) smaller than 1%, while only 2 have PD higher than 1%.
There is an evidence that on average the isolated WDs of DC type have higher PD
(with median PD of 0.78%) than the isolated DA type WDs (with median PD of
0.36%). On the other hand, the median PD of isolated DA type WDs is almost the
same, i.e. 0.36% as the median PD of DA type white dwarfs in binary systems
with red dwarfs (dM type), i.e. 0.33%. This shows, as expected, that there is
no contribution to the PD from the companion if the WD companion is the red
dwarf, which is the most common situation for WDs binary systems. We do not
find differences in the polarization degree between magnetic and non-magnetic
WDs. Because 97% of WDs in our sample have PD lower than 1%, they can be used
as faint zero--polarized standard star in the magnitude range from 13 up to 17
of SDSS r filter. They cover the Northern sky between 13 hour to 23 hour in
right ascension and from -11 degrees to 78 degrees in declination.
Additionally, we found that for low extinction values (&lt; 0.04) the best model
that describes the dependence of PD on E(B-V) is given by the equation:
PD_{max, ISM}[%] = 0.65 x E(B-V)^{0.12}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02017</id><created>2016-09-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Gilles</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llubaroff</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastorino</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluctuation-induced forces between rings threaded around a polymer chain
  under tension</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 17 figures. Accepted for publication in Physical Review E</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize the fluctuation properties of a polymer chain under external
tension and the fluctuation-induced forces between two ring molecules threaded
around the chain. The problem is relevant in the context of fluctuation-induced
forces in soft matter systems, features of liquid interfaces and to describe
properties of polyrotaxanes and slide-ring materials. We perform molecular
dynamics simulations of the Kremer-Grest bead-spring model for the polymer and
a simple ring-molecule model, in the canonical ensemble. We study transverse
fluctuations of the stretched chain, as a function of chain stretching and in
the presence of ring-shaped threaded molecules. The fluctuation spectra of the
chains are analyzed in equilibrium at constant temperature and the differences
in presence of two ring molecules are compared. For the rings located at fixed
distances, we find an attractive fluctuation-induced force between the rings,
proportional to the temperature and decaying with the ring distance. We
characterize this force as a function of ring distance, chain stretching, ring
radius and measure the differences between the free chain spectrum and the
fluctuations of the chain constrained by the rings. We also compare the
dependence and range of the force found in the simulations with theoretical
models coming from different fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02747</id><created>2016-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Dunajski</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tod</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-diagonal four-dimensional cohomogeneity-one Einstein metrics in
  various signatures</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math.DG</categories><report-no>DAMTP-2016-67</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most known four-dimensional cohomogeneity-one Einstein metrics are diagonal
in the basis defined by the left-invariant one-forms, though some essentially
non-diagonal ones are known. We consider the problem of explicitly seeking
non-diagonal Einstein metrics, and we find solutions which in some cases
exhaust the possibilities. In particular we construct new examples of neutral
signature non--diagonal Bianchi type VIII Einstein metrics with self--dual Weyl
tensor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02996</id><created>2016-09-09</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Akimasa</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent Results on Radiative and Electroweak Penguin B Decays at Belle</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures, proceedings for HQL2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on recent results on radiative and electroweak penguin B decays at
Belle at KEKB accelerator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03822</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03822</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Palyulin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames><affiliation>Physics Dept., TU Munich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chechkin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames><affiliation>Akhiezer Inst. for Theoret. Physics NSC KIPT, Kharkov</affiliation><affiliation>MPIPKS Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>Dept. of Physics and Astronomy, U. of Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Klages</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>MPIPKS Dresden</affiliation><affiliation>School of Math. Sci., Queen Mary U. of London</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Inst. for Physics and Astronomy, U. of Potsdam</affiliation><affiliation>Dept. of Physics, Tampere U. of Technology</affiliation></author></authors><title>Search reliability and search efficiency of combined L\'evy-Brownian
  motion: long relocations mingled with thorough local exploration</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.PE q-bio.QM</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys.A: Math. Theor. 49, 394002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/39/394002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A combined dynamics consisting of Brownian motion and L\'evy flights is
exhibited by a variety of biological systems performing search processes.
Assessing the search reliability of ever locating the target and the search
efficiency of doing so economically of such dynamics thus poses an important
problem. Here we model this dynamics by a one-dimensional fractional
Fokker-Planck equation combining unbiased Brownian motion and L\'evy flights.
By solving this equation both analytically and numerically we show that the
superposition of recurrent Brownian motion and L\'evy flights with stable
exponent $\alpha&lt;1$, by itself implying zero probability of hitting a point on
a line, lead to transient motion with finite probability of hitting any point
on the line. We present results for the exact dependence of the values of both
the search reliability and the search efficiency on the distance between the
starting and target positions as well as the choice of the scaling exponent
$\alpha$ of the L\'evy flight component.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04022</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Tamara M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howlett</keyname><forenames>Cullan</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology with Peculiar Velocities: Observational Effects</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate how observational effects could possibly bias
cosmological inferences from peculiar velocity measurements. Specifically, we
look at how bulk flow measurements are compared with theoretical predictions.
Usually bulk flow calculations try to approximate the flow that would occur in
a sphere around the observer. Using the Horizon Run 2 simulation we show that
the traditional methods for bulk flow estimation can overestimate the magnitude
of the bulk flow for two reasons: when the survey geometry is not spherical
(the data do not cover the whole sky), and when the observations undersample
the velocity distributions. Our results may explain why several bulk flow
measurements found bulk flow velocities that seem larger than those expected in
standard {\Lambda}CDM cosmologies. We recommend a different approach when
comparing bulk flows to cosmological models, in which the theoretical
prediction for each bulk flow measurement is calculated specifically for the
geometry and sampling rate of that survey. This means that bulk flow values
will not be comparable between surveys, but instead they are comparable with
cosmological models, which is the more important measure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04030</id><created>2016-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Rong Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic fields induced by a mechanical singularity in a magnetoelastic
  half plane and their applications to the seismicities in the crust of the
  Chinese continent</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interaction between the magnetic field and the elastic deformation field
in the crust is studied in a simplified way. The magnetic fields generated by
the line singularities in a magnetized elastic half-plane are investigated.
Using the general solution and Fourier transform technique, the exact solutions
for the generated magnetic inductions due to various cases are obtained in a
closed form. The results show that the line concentrated force will induced a
perturbed magnetic field; The induced magnetic field will indicate the line
concentrated force in reverse. The distribution of the vertical component of
the magnetic induction caused by the line mechanical singularities is simpler
than that of the horizontal component, and it is zero at the origin when the
applied magnetic field and the line concentrated force satisfies some
conditions. This result is applied to locate the epicenters of the earthquakes
and historical earthquakes occurred in the Chinese continental crust. Results
show that more than 80\% epicenters are at or near the zero-contours of the
vertical component of the magnetic induction observed from satellite. These
regions of zero-contours, especially those in active tectonic zones, could be
the possible seismogenic zones in the future. The zero-contours of the vertical
component of the magnetic induction from satellite could be as geophysical
constraints to the risk information on the shallow seismicities, or they can be
used as an early monitor for the shallow seismicities in the continental crust,
or an auxiliary sign in the determination of the great historical earthquake.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04031</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Rani</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krichbaum</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hodgson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zensus</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuhrmann</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marscher</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jorstad</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the magnetic field configuration in BL Lac using GMVA</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, to be published in the special issue of the
  Galaxy journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The high radio frequency polarization imaging of non-thermal emission from
active galactic nuclei (AGN) is a direct way to probe the magnetic field
strength and structure in the immediate vicinity of supermassive black holes
(SMBHs) and is crucial in testing the jet-launching scenario. To explore the
the magnetic field configuration at the base of jets in blazars, we took
advantage of the full polarization capabilities of the Global Millimeter VLBI
Array (GMVA). With an angular resolution of $\sim$50 micro-arcseconds ($\mu$as)
at 86 GHz, one could resolve scales up to $\sim$450 gravitational radii (for a
10$^9$ solar mass black hole at a redshift of 0.1). We present here the
preliminary results of our study on the blazar BL~Lac. Our results suggest that
on sub-mas scales the core and the central jet of BL Lac are significantly
polarized with two distinct regions of polarized intensity. We also noted a
great morphological similarity between the 7mm/3mm VLBI images at very similar
angular resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04034</id><created>2016-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Robson</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The generation model of particle physics and the cosmological
  matter-antimatter asymmetry problem</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The matter-antimatter asymmetry problem, corresponding to the virtual
nonexistence of antimatter in the universe, is one of the greatest mysteries of
cosmology. Within the framework of the Generation Model (GM) of particle
physics, it is demonstrated that the matter-antimatter asymmetry problem may be
understood in terms of the composite leptons and quarks of the GM. It is
concluded that there is essentially no matter-antimatter asymmetry in the
present universe and that the observed hydrogen-antihydrogen asymmetry may be
understood in terms of statistical fluctuations associated with the complex
many-body processes involved in the formation of either a hydrogen atom or an
antihydrogen atom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04050</id><created>2016-09-10</created><authors><author><keyname>McKenzie</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author></authors><title>A discrete, finite multiverse</title><categories>physics.gen-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages; 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Many Worlds Interpretation (MWI) famously avoids the issue of wave
function collapse. Different MWI trees representing the same quantum events can
have different topologies, depending upon the observer. However, they are all
isomorphic to the group of block universes containing all of the outcomes of
all of the events, and so, in that sense, the group of block universes is a
more fundamental representation. Different branches of the MWI tree,
representing different universes in MWI, ultimately share the same quantum
state in a common ancestor branch. This branching topology is incompatible with
that of the Minkowski block universe; the resolution is to replace the branches
with discrete, parallel block universes, each of which extends from the trunk
to the outermost twigs. The number of universes in a branch is proportional to
its thickness which, in turn, depends upon the absolute square of the
probability amplitude for the state in that branch. Every quantum event may be
represented by a kernel of universes, which is the smallest group of universes
that will reproduce the quantum probabilities of the outcomes of that event. By
considering the ratios of the probabilities of the outcomes of any event, it
can be shown that the number of universes in every kernel must finite, as must
be the total number of universes in the multiverse. Further, every universe in
the multiverse must be finite both in space and time. Another consequence is
that quantum probabilities must be rational, which suggests that quantum
mechanics is only an approximation to a discrete theory. A corollary is that
not every conceivable universe exists in the multiverse, no doubt to the
disappointment of those who enjoy alternate-history novels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04067</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Gon&#x163;a</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Loock</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum repeater based on cavity-QED evolutions and coherent light</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures. version accepted in Applied Physics B (topical
  collection: Quantum Repeaters - From Components to Strategies). arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1309.1668</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. B (2016) 122: 118</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-016-6388-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of cavity QED, we propose a quantum repeater scheme that
uses coherent light and chains of atoms coupled to optical cavities. In
contrast to conventional repeater schemes, we avoid the usage of two-qubit
quantum logical gates by exploiting solely the cavity QED evolution. In our
previous paper [D. Gonta and P. van Loock: Phys. Rev. A 88, 052308 (2013)], we
already proposed a quantum repeater in which the entanglement between two
neighboring repeater nodes was distributed using controlled displacements of
input coherent light, while the produced low-fidelity entangled pairs were
purified using ancillary (four-partite) entangled states. In this paper, the
entanglement distribution is realized using a sequence of controlled phase
shifts and displacements of input coherent light. Compared to previous
coherent-state-based distribution schemes for two-qubit entanglement, the
present scheme relies only upon a simple discrimination of two coherent states
with opposite signs, which can be performed in a quantum mechanically optimal
fashion via a beam splitter and two on-off detectors. The entanglement
purification utilizes a scheme that avoids the usage of ancillary entangled
resources. Our repeater scheme exhibits reasonable fidelities and repeater
rates providing an attractive platform for long-distance quantum communication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04111</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aihara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amji</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amey</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andreopoulos</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atherton</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ban</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbato</keyname><forenames>F. C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbato</keyname><forenames>F. C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barr</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartet-Friburg</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batkiewicz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berardi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhadra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bienstock</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blondel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolognesi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordoni</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brailsford</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bravar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bronner</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avanzini</keyname><forenames>M. Buizza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calcutt</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calland</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cartwright</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catanesi</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Checchia</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherdack</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chikuma</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christodoulou</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clifton</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collazuol</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coplowe</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cremonesi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cudd</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabrowska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delbart</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Rosa</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dealtry</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denner</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Densham</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dewhurst</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Lodovico</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drapier</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duffy</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumarchez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunkman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dziewiecki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emery-Schrenk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernanddez</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feusels</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finch</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorentini</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorillo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fitton</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friend</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giganti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gizzarelli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadley</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haegel</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haigh</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashino</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayato</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiramoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirota</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holeczek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosomi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichikawa</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imber</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Insler</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Intonti</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwai</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmaylov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jamieson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jo</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonsson</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>C. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabirnezhad</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaboth</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kajita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kakuno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kameda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katori</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kearns</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khabibullin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khotjantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisiel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knox</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koga</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konaka</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondo</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kormos</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korzenev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshio</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalik</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kropp</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudenko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurjata</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutter</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labarga</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagoda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamont</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamoureux</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larkin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasorak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laveder</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liptak</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Litchfield</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longhin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludovici</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magaletti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maruyama</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matveev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavrokoridis</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>W. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzucato</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCauley</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGrew</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mefodiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metelko</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezzetto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mijakowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mineev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mine</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Missert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Th. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakadaira</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakanishi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakaya</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayoshi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nantais</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishikawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Keeffe</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okumura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okusawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovsyannikova</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyama</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palladino</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palomino</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>N. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkin</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickard</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickering</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerra</keyname><forenames>E. S. Pinzon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posiadala-Zezula</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poutissou</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poutissou</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przewlocki</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quilain</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radermacher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radicioni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ratoff</keyname><forenames>P. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravonel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rayner</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinherz-Aronis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riccio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rondio</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruggeri</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rychter</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sacco</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakashita</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scantamburlo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholberg</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwehr</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seiya</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sgalaberna</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaikhiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaker</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiozawa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirahige</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Short</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobczyk</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Southwell</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinmann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stowell</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suvorov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szeptycka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamura</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>H. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terhorst</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terri</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakore</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toki</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Touramanis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsukamoto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vagins</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vacheret</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallari</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasseur</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wachala</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wark</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wascko</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendell</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkes</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilking</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wret</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagisawa</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yano</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yershov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zalewska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zalipska</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zambelli</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaremba</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziembicki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmerman</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zito</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Proposal for an Extended Run of T2K to $20\times10^{21}$ POT</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>68 pages, 31 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent measurements by the T2K neutrino oscillation experiment indicate that
CP violation in neutrino mixing may be observed in the future by long-baseline
neutrino oscillation experiments. We propose an extension to the currently
approved T2K running from $7.8\times 10^{21}~\mbox{POT}$ to $20\times
10^{21}~\mbox{POT}$, aiming at initial observation of CP violation with
3$\,\sigma$ or higher significance for the case of maximum CP violation. The
program also contains a measurement of mixing parameters, $\theta_{23}$ and
$\Delta m^2_{32}$, with a precision of 1.7$^\circ$ or better and 1%,
respectively. With accelerator and beamline upgrades, as well as analysis
improvements, this program would occur before the next generation of
long-baseline neutrino oscillation experiments that are expected to start
operation in 2026.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04122</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>Hiroyasu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanno</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Hongyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tashiro</keyname><forenames>Takaharu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haku</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Akiyo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Rashba-Edelstein Magnetoresistance in Metallic Heterostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 117, 116602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.116602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the observation of magnetoresistance originating from Rashba
spin-orbit coupling (SOC) in a metallic heterostructure: the Rashba-Edelstein
(RE) magnetoresistance. We show that the simultaneous action of the direct and
inverse RE effects in a Bi/Ag/CoFeB trilayer couples current-induced spin
accumulation to the electric resistance. The electric resistance changes with
the magnetic-field angle, reminiscent of the spin Hall magnetoresistance,
despite the fact that bulk SOC is not responsible for the magnetoresistance. We
further found that, even when the magnetization is saturated, the resistance
increases with increasing the magnetic-field strength, which is attributed to
the Hanle magnetoresistance in this system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04149</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cain</keyname><forenames>Tyler A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikheev</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Clayton A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stemmer</keyname><forenames>Susanne</forenames></author></authors><title>Dichotomy of the transport coefficients of correlated electron liquids
  in SrTiO3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the Seebeck coefficient and the Hall mobility of electrons
confined in narrow SrTiO3 quantum wells as a function of the three-dimensional
carrier density and temperature. The quantum wells contain a fixed sheet
carrier density of ~ 7x10^14 cm^-2 and their thickness is varied. At high
temperatures, both properties exhibit apparent Fermi liquid behavior. In
particular, the Seebeck coefficient increases nearly linearly with temperature
(T) when phonon drag contributions are minimized, while the mobility decreases
proportional to T^2. Furthermore, the Seebeck coefficient scales inversely with
the Fermi energy (decreasing quantum well thickness). In contrast, the
transport scattering rate is independent of the Fermi energy, which is
inconsistent with a Fermi liquid. At low temperatures, the Seebeck coefficient
deviates from the linear temperature dependence for those electron liquids that
exhibit a correlation-induced pseudogap, indicating a change in the energy
dependence of the scattering rate. The implications for describing transport in
strongly correlated materials are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04152</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yip</keyname><forenames>Sungkit</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudospin bases for a model of Cu:Bi$_2$Se$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the construction of pseudospin bases for a time-reversal and
inversion symmetric system, illustrated by a model for Cu:Bi$_2$Se$_3$.
Different methods and bases are compared.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04153</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaia Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>The Gaia mission</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>The Gaia Collaboration consists of 625 authors. Accepted by A&amp;A in
  the Gaia Special Feature</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629272</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gaia is a cornerstone mission in the science programme of the European Space
Agency (ESA). The spacecraft construction was approved in 2006, following a
study in which the original interferometric concept was changed to a
direct-imaging approach. Both the spacecraft and the payload were built by
European industry. The involvement of the scientific community focusses on data
processing for which the international Gaia Data Processing and Analysis
Consortium (DPAC) was selected in 2007. Gaia was launched on 19 December 2013
and arrived at its operating point, the second Lagrange point of the
Sun-Earth-Moon system, a few weeks later. The commissioning of the spacecraft
and payload was completed on 19 July 2014. The nominal five-year mission
started with four weeks of special, ecliptic-pole scanning and subsequently
transferred into full-sky scanning mode. We recall the scientific goals of Gaia
and give a description of the as-built spacecraft that is currently (mid-2016)
being operated to achieve these goals. We pay special attention to the payload
module, the performance of which is closely related to the scientific
performance of the mission. We provide a summary of the commissioning
activities and findings, followed by a description of the routine operational
mode. We summarise scientific performance estimates on the basis of in-orbit
operations. Several intermediate Gaia data releases are planned and the data
can be retrieved from the Gaia Archive, which is available through the Gaia
home page at http://www.cosmos.esa.int/gaia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04155</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deb</keyname><forenames>Bimalendu</forenames></author></authors><title>A model study on a pair of trapped particles interacting with an
  arbitrary effective range</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Scr. 91, 085401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-8949/91/8/085401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of the effective range of interaction on the eigenvalues
and eigenstates of two particles confined in a three-dimensional (3D) isotropic
as well as one- or quasi-one dimensional harmonic (1D) traps. For this we
employ model potentials which mimic finite-range s-wave interactions over a
wide range of s-wave scattering length $a_s$ including the unitarity limits
$a_s \rightarrow \pm\infty$. Our results show that when the range is larger
than the 3D or 1D harmonic oscillator length scale, the eigenvalues and
eigenstates are nearly similar to those of noninteracting two particles in the
3D or 1D trap, respectively. In case of 3D, we find that when the range goes to
zero, the results of contact potential as derived by Busch {\it et al.}
[Foundations of Physics, {\bf28}, 549 (1998)] are reproduced. However, in the
case of 1D, such reproducibility does not occur as the range goes to zero. We
have calculated the eigenvalues and eigenstates in 1D harmonic trap taking
one-dimensional finite- range model potential. We have also calculated bound
state properties of two particles confined in a highly anisotropic quasi-1D
trap taking three-dimensional finite-range model potential, and examined
whether these quasi-1D results approach towards 1D ones as the aspect ratio
$\eta$ of the radial to axial frequency of the trap increases. We find that if
the range is very small compared to the axial size of the trap, then one can
reach 1D regime for $\eta \ge 10000$. However, for large range, one can nearly
get 1D results for smaller values of $\eta$. This study will be important for
exploration of two-body or many body physics of trapped ultracold atoms
interacting with narrow Feshbach resonance for which the effective range can be
large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04159</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yuanwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Jingtao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wu-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Steady-state localized-delocalized phase transition of an
  incoherent-pumped dissipative Bose-Hubbard model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate steady-state properties of a two-dimensional incoherent-pumped
dissipative Bose-Hubbard model, which describes a photon square lattice. This
incoherent pumping exhibits an important environment-induced higher-order
fluctuation effect, which induces a strong competition between the
driven-dissipative channel, the photon-photon interaction, and the photon
hopping in multi-photon processes. This new competition gives rise to a
spontaneous breaking of the U(1) symmetry of system. As a result, we predict a
many-body steady-state localized-delocalized phase transition and an
anti-blockade effect, in which the increasing of the repulsive photon-photon
interaction promotes the emergence of phase transition. These unconventional
many-body steady-state phenomena can be understood by analyzing the
single-cavity properties. Our results pave a new way to control many-body
dynamics of driven-dissipative systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04160</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Coniglio</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fierro</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlated Percolation</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>35 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Encyclopedia of Complexity and Systems Science, Part 3, pp
  1596-1615 (2009). Springer New York. ISBN: 978-0-387-75888-6 (Print)
  978-0-387-30440-3 (Online)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cluster concepts have been extremely useful in elucidating many problems in
physics. Percolation theory provides a generic framework to study the behavior
of the cluster distribution. In most cases the theory predicts a geometrical
transition at the percolation threshold, characterized in the percolative phase
by the presence of a spanning cluster, which becomes infinite in the
thermodynamic limit. Standard percolation usually deals with the problem when
the constitutive elements of the clusters are randomly distributed. However
correlations cannot always be neglected. In this case correlated percolation is
the appropriate theory to study such systems. The origin of correlated
percolation could be dated back to 1937 when Mayer [1] proposed a theory to
describe the condensation from a gas to a liquid in terms of mathematical
clusters (for a review of cluster theory in simple fluids see [2]). The
location for the divergence of the size of these clusters was interpreted as
the condensation transition from a gas to a liquid. One of the major drawback
of the theory was that the cluster number for some values of thermodynamic
parameters could become negative. As a consequence the clusters did not have
any physical interpretation [3]. This theory was followed by Frenkel's
phenomenological model [4], in which the fluid was considered as made of non
interacting physical clusters with a given free energy. This model was later
improved by Fisher [3], who proposed a different free energy for the clusters,
now called droplets, and consequently a different scaling form for the droplet
size distribution. This distribution, which depends on two geometrical
parameters, has the nice feature that the mean droplet size exhibits a
divergence at the liquid-gas critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04169</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Perugini</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Campos</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgavi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vetere</keyname><forenames>F. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dingwell</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying magma mixing with the Shannon entropy: application to
  simulations and experiments</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>LITHOS, 2015, Volume 236, p. 299-310</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.lithos.2015.09.008</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new quantity to petrology, the Shannon entropy, as a tool for
quantifying mixing as well as the rate of production of hybrid compositions in
the mixing system. The Shannon entropy approach is applied to time series
numerical simulations and high-temperature experiments performed with natural
melts. We note that in both cases the Shannon entropy increases linearly during
the initial stages of mixing and then saturates toward constant values.
Furthermore, chemical elements with different mobilities display different
rates of increase of the Shannon entropy. This indicates that the hybrid
composition for the different elements is attained at different times
generating a wide range of spatio-compositional domains which further increase
the apparent complexity of the mixing process. Results from the application of
the Shannon entropy analysis are compared with the concept of Relaxation of
Concentration Variance (RCV), a measure recently introduced in petrology to
quantify chemical exchanges during magma mixing. We derive a linear expression
relating the change of concentration variance during mixing and the Shannon
entropy. We show that the combined use of Shannon entropy and RCV provides the
most complete information about the space and time complexity of magma mixing.
As a consequence, detailed information about this fundamental petrogenetic and
volcanic process can be gathered. In particular, the Shannon entropy can be
used as complement to the RCV method to quantify the mobility of chemical
elements in magma mixing systems, to obtain information about the rate of
production of compositional heterogeneities, and to derive empirical
relationships linking the rate of chemical exchanges between interacting magmas
and mixing time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04171</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe1;link&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moln&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>Gy&#xf6;rgy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Chanyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bir&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3; P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osv&#xe1;th</keyname><forenames>Zolt&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the STM tip-graphene repulsive forces by comparative
  STM and AFM measurements on suspended graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>RSC Advances 6 (2016) 86253-86258</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6RA19660H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene grown by chemical vapour deposition is transferred on top of flat
gold nanoislands and characterized by scanning tunnelling microscopy (STM) and
atomic force microscopy (AFM). Graphene bubbles are formed with lateral
dimensions determined by the size and shape of nanoislands. These graphene
bubbles can be squeezed during STM imaging using bias voltages of less than 250
mV and tunnelling currents of 1 nA. Similarly, the graphene suspended over gold
nanovoids is deflected 4 - 5 nm by the STM tip when imaging at low bias
voltages (U = 30 mV). Nanoindentation measurements performed by AFM show that
the squeezing of graphene bubbles occurs at repulsive forces of 20 - 35 nN, and
such forces can result in deflections of several nanometres in suspended
graphene parts, respectively. Comparing the AFM and STM results, this study
reveals that mechanical forces of the order of 10e-8 N occur between the STM
tip and graphene under ambient imaging conditions and typical tunnelling
parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04172</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaia Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>A. G. A.</forenames><affiliation>Leiden Observatory, Leiden University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vallenari</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio astronomico di Padova</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Prusti</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>ESA/ESTEC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>de Bruijne</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>ESA/ESTEC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mignard</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>Observatoire de la Cote d'Azur</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Drimmel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>INAF - Osservatorio Astrofisico di Torino</affiliation></author><author><keyname>co-authors</keyname><forenames>585</forenames></author></authors><title>Gaia Data Release 1. Summary of the astrometric, photometric, and survey
  properties</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>23 pages, 13 figures. This paper has 591 co-authors. Accepted by A&amp;A
  in the Gaia Special Feature. The Gaia data, documentation and access
  facilities can be found at http://archives.esac.esa.int/gaia/</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At about 1000 days after the launch of Gaia we present the first Gaia data
release, Gaia DR1, consisting of astrometry and photometry for over 1 billion
sources brighter than magnitude 20.7. We summarize Gaia DR1 and provide
illustrations of the scientific quality of the data, followed by a discussion
of the limitations due to the preliminary nature of this release. Gaia DR1
consists of: a primary astrometric data set which contains the positions,
parallaxes, and mean proper motions for about 2 million of the brightest stars
in common with the Hipparcos and Tycho-2 catalogues and a secondary astrometric
data set containing the positions for an additional 1.1 billion sources. The
second component is the photometric data set,consisting of mean G-band
magnitudes for all sources. The G-band light curves and the characteristics of
~3000 Cepheid and RR Lyrae stars, observed at high cadence around the south
ecliptic pole, form the third component. For the primary astrometric data set
the typical uncertainty is about 0.3 mas for the positions and parallaxes, and
about 1 mas/yr for the proper motions. A systematic component of ~0.3 mas
should be added to the parallax uncertainties. For the subset of ~94000
Hipparcos stars in the primary data set, the proper motions are much more
precise at about 0.06 mas/yr. For the secondary astrometric data set, the
typical uncertainty of the positions is ~10 mas. The median uncertainties on
the mean G-band magnitudes range from the mmag level to ~0.03 mag over the
magnitude range 5 to 20.7. Gaia DR1 represents a major advance in the mapping
of the heavens and the availability of basic stellar data that underpin
observational astrophysics. Nevertheless, the very preliminary nature of this
first Gaia data release does lead to a number of important limitations to the
data quality which should be carefully considered before drawing conclusions
from the data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04183</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Birender</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirage</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iyo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Pradeep</forenames></author></authors><title>Iron Isotope Effect in SmFeAsO0.65 and SmFeAsO0.77H0.12 Superconductors:
  A Raman Study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the inelastic light scattering studies on SmFeAsO0.65 and
SmFeAsO0.77H0.12 with iron isotopes namely 54Fe and 57Fe. In both of these
systems under investigation we observed a significant shift in the frequency of
the phonon modes associated with the displacement of Fe atoms around ~ 200
cm-1. The observed shift in the Fe mode (B1g) for SmFeAsO0.65 is ~ 1.4 % and
lower in case of SmFeAsO0.77H0.12, which is ~ 0.65 %, attributed to the lower
percentage of isotopic substitution in case of SmFeAsO0.77H0.12. Our study
reveals the significant iron isotope effect in these systems hinting towards
the crucial role of electron-phonon coupling in the pairing mechanism of iron
based superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04184</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>William L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle plasmons: Why shape matters</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>American Journal of Physics, 84, 593-601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4948402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simple analytic expressions for the polarizability of metallic nanoparticles
are in wide use in the field of plasmonics, but their origins are not obvious.
In this article, expressions for the polarizability of a particle are derived
in the quasistatic limit in a manner that allows the physical origin of the
terms to be clearly seen. The discussion is tutorial in nature, with particular
attention given to the role of particle shape since this is a controlling
factor in particle plasmon resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04204</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fukasawa</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Monojit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasuda</keyname><forenames>Osamu</forenames></author></authors><title>Is nonstandard interaction a solution to the three neutrino tensions?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present a scenario in which a nonstandard interaction in
neutrino propagation can explain the three major tensions in the neutrino
oscillation data at present. These tensions are: (i) a non-zero best-fit value
of the non-standard oscillation parameters in the the global analysis of the
solar and KamLAND data which rules out the standard oscillation scenario at
$90\%$ C.L, (ii) the measurement of the non-maximal value of $\theta_{23}$ by
NO$\nu$A which excludes the maximal mixing at $2.5 \sigma$ C.L. and (iii) a
discrepancy in the $\theta_{13}$ measurement by T2K which has a tension with
the reactor best-fit value of $\sin^2\theta_{13}=0.021$ at $90\%$ C.L. Our
results show that all these three above mentioned anomalies can be explained if
one assumes the existence of the non-standard interactions in neutrino
propagation with $\theta_{23}=45^\circ$ and $\sin^2\theta_{13}=0.021$ in the
case of normal hierarchy. In our scenario the phase of $\epsilon_{e\tau}$ is
zero and the most favorable value of the Dirac CP phase is approximately
$255^\circ$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04205</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>Peeyush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huizinga</keyname><forenames>Folkert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kooistra</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Schuur</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunst</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romein</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuiack</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molenaar</keyname><forenames>Gijs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rowlinson</keyname><forenames>Antonia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swinbank</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wijers</keyname><forenames>Ralph A. M. J</forenames></author></authors><title>The AARTFAAC All Sky Monitor: System Design and Implementation</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Submitted to Journal of Astronomical Instrumentation, Special issue
  on 'Digital Signal Processing (DSP) in Radio Astronomy'</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Amsterdam-ASTRON Radio Transients Facility And Analysis Center (AARTFAAC)
all sky monitor is a sensitive, real time transient detector based on the Low
Frequency Array (LOFAR). It generates images of the low frequency radio sky
with spatial resolution of 10s of arcmin, MHz bandwidths, and a time cadence of
a few seconds, while simultaneously but independently observing with LOFAR. The
image timeseries is then monitored for short and bright radio transients. On
detection of a transient, a low latency trigger will be generated for LOFAR,
which can interrupt its schedule to carry out follow-up observations of the
trigger location at high sensitivity and resolutions. In this paper, we
describe our heterogeneous, hierarchical design to manage the 240 Gbps raw data
rate, and large scale computing to produce real-time images with minimum
latency. We discuss the implementation of the instrumentation, its performance,
and scalability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04210</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Magrini</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goncalves</keyname><forenames>Denise R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vajgel</keyname><forenames>Bruna</forenames></author></authors><title>NGC 55: a disc galaxy with flat abundance gradients</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new spectroscopic observations obtained with GMOS@Gemini-S of a
sample of 25 hii regions located in NGC 55, a late-type galaxy in the nearby
Sculptor group. We derive physical conditions and chemical composition through
the te-method for 18 hii regions, and strong-line abundances for 22 hii
regions. We provide abundances of He, O, N, Ne, S, Ar, finding a substantially
homogenous composition in the ionised gas of the disc of NGC 55, with no trace
of radial gradients. The oxygen abundances, both derived with \te- and
strong-line methods, have similar mean values and similarly small dispersion:
12+$\log$(O/H)=8.13$\pm$0.18~dex with the former and
12+$\log$(O/H)=8.17$\pm$0.13~dex with the latter. The average metallicities and
the flat gradients agree with previous studies of smaller samples of \hii\
regions and there is a qualitative agreement with the blue supergiant radial
gradient as well. We investigate the origin of such flat gradients comparing
NGC 55 with NGC 300, its companion galaxy, which is also twin of NGC 55 in
terms of mass and luminosity. We suggest that the differences in the metal
distributions in the two galaxies might be related to the differences in their
K-band surface density profile. The flatter profile of NGC 55 probably causes
in this galaxy higher infall/outflow rates than in similar galaxies. This
likely provokes a strong mixing of gas and a re-distribution of metals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04215</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Tri&#x161;ovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Nemanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antanasijevi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Jelena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogan</keyname><forenames>Jelena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poleti</keyname><forenames>Dejan</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf3;th-Katona</keyname><forenames>Tibor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salamonczyk</keyname><forenames>Miroslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xe1;kli</keyname><forenames>Antal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fodor-Csorba</keyname><forenames>Katalin</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of supramolecular architectures of bent-shaped pyridine
  derivatives: from a three-ring crystalline compound towards five-ring
  mesogens</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures, revised version appeared in New Journal of
  Chemistry</comments><journal-ref>New J. Chem. 40, 6977-6985 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6NJ01515H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In searching for novel photoactive liquid crystals, we have synthesized a
series of five-ring pyridine-based bent-core compounds bearing different
substituents at the peripheral phenyl rings (CH3O, Cl and NO2). Their
mesomorphic behaviour has been investigated by polarizing optical microscopy,
differential scanning calorimetry and X-ray scattering, and then compared with
the unsubstituted parent compound. The introduction of the methoxy groups at
the peripheral phenyl rings of the bent core results in a non-mesomorphic
compound, whereas the chloro- and nitro-substituted compounds form
enantiotropic B1-like phases. Significant changes of the textures and
transition temperatures of the mesophase have been observed under UV light. The
presented investigation of the mesomorphic properties of the synthesized
compounds, coupled with analysis of the molecular packing of the related
three-ring compounds, will help to design self-organized molecules suitable for
UV indicators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04224</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>&#xc9;ber</keyname><forenames>N&#xe1;ndor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salamon</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fekete</keyname><forenames>Bal&#xe1;zs Andr&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karapinar</keyname><forenames>Ridvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krekhov</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buka</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;gnes</forenames></author></authors><title>Suppression of spatially periodic patterns by dc voltage</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>16 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 042701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.042701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of superposed dc and ac applied voltages on two types of spatially
periodic instabilities in nematic liquid crystals, flexoelectric domains (FD)
and electroconvection (EC), was studied. The onset characteristics, threshold
voltages and critical wave vectors, were determined. We found that in general
the superposition of driving with different time symmetries inhibits the
pattern forming mechanisms for FD and EC as well. As a consequence the onset
extends to much higher voltages than the individual dc or ac thresholds. A dc
bias induced reduction of the crossover frequency from the conductive to the
dielectric EC regimes and a peculiar transition between two types of
flexodomains with different wavelengths were detected. Direct measurements of
the change of the electrical conductivity and its anisotropy, induced by the
applied dc voltage component, showed that the dc bias substantially affects
both parameters. Taking into account the experimentally detected variations of
the conductivity in the linear stability analysis of the underlying
nemato-hydrodynamic equations, a qualitative agreement with the experimental
findings on the onset behavior of spatially periodic instabilities was
obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04238</id><created>2016-08-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Sturrock</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Conjecture Concerning Ball Lightning</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is at present no theory that can explain the curious properties of ball
lightning. This suggests that we may not be using the most appropriate
concepts. The concept of a 'parallel space' may point the way to a valid
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04240</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Crowley</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohley</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hambly</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abreu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabricius</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seabroke</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Bruijne</keyname><forenames>J. H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Short</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindegren</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>A. G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarri</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gare</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prusti</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prod'homme</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Fleitas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raison</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lammers</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Mullane</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>On-orbit performance of the Gaia CCDs at L2</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in A&amp;A Gaia special feature</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628990</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The European Space Agency's Gaia satellite was launched into orbit around L2
in December 2013 with a payload containing 106 large-format scientific CCDs.
The primary goal of the mission is to repeatedly obtain high-precision
astrometric and photometric measurements of one thousand million stars over the
course of five years. The scientific value of the down-linked data, and the
operation of the onboard autonomous detection chain, relies on the high
performance of the detectors. As Gaia slowly rotates and scans the sky, the
CCDs are continuously operated in a mode where the line clock rate and the
satellite rotation spin-rate are in synchronisation. Nominal mission operations
began in July 2014 and the first data release is being prepared for release at
the end of Summer 2016.
  In this paper we present an overview of the focal plane, the detector system,
and strategies for on-orbit performance monitoring of the system. This is
followed by a presentation of the performance results based on analysis of data
acquired during a two-year window beginning at payload switch-on. Results for
parameters such as readout noise and electronic offset behaviour are presented
and we pay particular attention to the effects of the L2 radiation environment
on the devices. The radiation-induced degradation in the charge transfer
efficiency (CTE) in the (parallel) scan direction is clearly diagnosed;
however, an extrapolation shows that charge transfer inefficiency (CTI) effects
at end of mission will be approximately an order of magnitude less than
predicted pre-flight. It is shown that the CTI in the serial register
(horizontal direction) is still dominated by the traps inherent to the
manufacturing process and that the radiation-induced degradation so far is only
a few per cent. Finally, we summarise some of the detector effects discovered
on-orbit which are still being investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04242</id><created>2016-09-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Diel</keyname><forenames>Hans H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum objects as elementary units of causality and locality</title><categories>physics.gen-ph quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The author's attempt to construct a local causal model of quantum theory (QT)
that includes quantum field theory (QFT) resulted in the identification of
&quot;quantum objects&quot; as the elementary units of causality and locality. Quantum
objects are collections of particles (including single particles) whose
collective dynamics and measurement results can only be described by the laws
of QT and QFT. Local causal models of quantum objects' internal dynamics are
not possible if a locality is understood as a space-point locality. Within
quantum objects, state transitions may occur which instantly affect the whole
quantum object. The identification of quantum objects as the elementary units
of causality and locality has two primary implications for a causal model of
quantum objects: (1) quantum objects run autonomously with system-state update
frequencies based on their local proper times and with either no or minimal
dependency on external parameters. (2) The laws of physics that describe global
(but relativistic) interrelationships must be translated to a causal model of
interactions between quantum objects and interactions between quantum objects
and the space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04251</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Higgins</keyname><forenames>Luke. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marocico</keyname><forenames>Cristian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karanikolas</keyname><forenames>Vasilios D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>Alan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gough</keyname><forenames>John J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Graham P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parbrook</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradley</keyname><forenames>A. Louise</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Plasmonic Array Geometry on Energy Transfer from a Quantum
  Well to a Quantum Dot Layer</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A range of seven different Ag plasmonic arrays formed using nanostructures of
varying shape, size and gap were fabricated using helium-ion lithography (HIL)
on an InGaN/GaN quantum well (QW) substrate. The influence of the array
geometry on plasmon-enhanced F\&quot;orster resonance energy transfer (FRET) from a
single InGaN QW to a ~ 80 nm layer of CdSe/ZnS quantum dots (QDs) embedded in a
poly(methyl methacrylate) (PMMA) matrix is investigated. It is shown that the
energy transfer efficiency is strongly dependent on the array properties and an
efficiency of ~ 51% is observed for a nanoring array. There were no signatures
of FRET in the absence of the arrays. The QD acceptor layer emission is highly
sensitive to the array geometry. A model was developed to confirm that the
increase in the QD emission on the QW substrate compared with a GaN substrate
can be attributed solely to plasmon-enhanced FRET. The individual contributions
of direct enhancement of the QD layer emission by the array and the
plasmon-enhanced FRET are separated out, with the QD emission described by the
product of an array emission factor and an energy transfer factor. It is shown
that while the nanoring geometry results in an energy transfer factor of ~ 1.7
the competing quenching by the array, with an array emission factor of ~ 0.7,
results in only an overall gain of ~ 14% in the QD emission. The QD emission
was enhanced by ~ 71% for a nanobox array, resulting from the combination of a
more modest energy transfer factor of 1.2 coupled with an array emission factor
of ~ 1.4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04261</id><created>2016-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Dargys</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constitutive relations for electromagnetic field in a form of $6\times
  6$ matrices derived from the geometric algebra</title><categories>physics.class-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To have a closed system, the Maxwell equations should be supplemented by
constitutive relations which connect the primary electromagnetic fields
$(\bE,\bB)$ with the secondary ones $(\bD,\bH)$ induced in a medium. Recently
[Opt. Commun. \textbf{354}, 259 (2015)] the allowed shapes of the constitutive
relations that follow from the relativistic Maxwell equations formulated in
terms of geometric algebra were constructed by author. In this paper the
obtained general relativistic relations between $(\bD,\bH)$ and $(\bE,\bB)$
fields are transformed to four $6\times 6$ matrices that are universal in
constructing various combinations of constitutive relations in terms of more
popular Gibbs-Heaviside vectorial calculus frequently used to investigate the
electromagnetic wave propagation in anisotropic, birefringent, bianisotropic,
chiral etc media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04273</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fabricius</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastian</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portell</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>others</keyname></author></authors><title>Gaia Data Release 1, Pre-processing and source list creation</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628643</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first data release from the Gaia mission contains accurate positions and
magnitudes for more than a billion sources, and proper motions and parallaxes
for the majority of the 2.5~million Hipparcos and Tycho-2 stars.
  We describe three essential elements of the initial data treatment leading to
this catalogue: the image analysis, the construction of a source list, and the
near real-time monitoring of the payload health. We also discuss some weak
points that set limitations for the attainable precision at the present stage
of the mission.
  Image parameters for point sources are derived from one-dimensional scans,
using a maximum likelihood method, under the assumption of a line spread
function constant in time, and a complete modelling of bias and background.
These conditions are, however, not completely fulfilled. The Gaia source list
is built starting from a large ground-based catalogue, but even so a
significant number of new entries have been added, and a large number have been
removed. The autonomous onboard star image detection will pick up many spurious
images, especially around bright sources, and such unwanted detections must be
identified. Another key step of the source list creation consists in arranging
the more than $10^{10}$ individual detections in spatially isolated groups that
can be analysed individually.
  Complete software systems have been built for the Gaia initial data
treatment, that manage approximately 50~million focal plane transits daily,
giving transit times and fluxes for 500~million individual CCD images to the
astrometric and photometric processing chains. The software also carries out a
successful and detailed daily monitoring of Gaia health.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04282</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fenner</keyname><forenames>Trevor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levene</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loizou</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>A multiplicative process for generating the rank-order distribution of
  UK election results</title><categories>physics.soc-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Human dynamics and sociophysics suggest statistical models that may explain
and provide us with a better understanding of social phenomena. Here we propose
a generative multiplicative decrease model that gives rise to a rank-order
distribution and allows us to analyse the results of the last three UK
parliamentary elections. We provide empirical evidence that the additive
Weibull distribution, which can be generated from our model, is a close fit to
the electoral data, offering a novel interpretation of the recent election
results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04286</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Migenda</keyname><forenames>Jost</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting Fast Time Variations in the Supernova Neutrino Flux with
  Hyper-Kamiokande</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM hep-ex</categories><comments>83 pages, 29 figures. Master's thesis at Technische Universit\&quot;at
  M\&quot;unchen / Max-Planck-Institut f\&quot;ur Physik</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For detection of neutrinos from galactic supernovae, the planned
Hyper-Kamiokande detector will be the first detector that delivers both a high
event rate (about one third of the IceCube rate) and event-by-event energy
information. In this thesis, we use a three-dimensional computer simulation by
the Garching group to find out whether this additional information can be used
to improve the detection prospects of fast time variations in the neutrino
flux.
  We find that the amplitude of SASI oscillations of the neutrino number flux
is energy-dependent. However, in this simulation, the larger amplitude in some
energy bins is not sufficient to counteract the increased noise caused by the
lower event rate. Finally, we derive a condition describing when it is
advantageous to consider an energy bin instead of the total signal and show
that this condition is satisfied if the oscillation of the mean neutrino energy
is increased slightly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04298</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Victor A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loebner</keyname><forenames>Keith T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Smartphone Schlieren</title><categories>physics.ed-ph physics.flu-dyn physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a schlieren system comprised of 3D printed optical mounts, a
sub-$10 mirror, and a smartphone camera. The system is intended to make
schlieren imaging accessible to K-through-12 students, educators, as well as
hobbyists. In the manuscript, we detail the design of the system, provide
source files for continued iteration, and show some example schlieren images
and videos of a butane lighter, a jet of compressed air, and an electric stove.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04302</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Dubey</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Malay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of Brownian functionals in physically motivated model with purely
  time dependent drift and diffusion</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we investigate a Brownian motion (BM) with purely time
dependent drift and difusion by suggesting and examining several Brownian
functionals which characterize the lifetime and reactivity of such stochastic
processes. We introduce several probability distribution functions (PDFs)
associated with such time dependent BMs. For instance, for a BM with initial
starting point $x_0$, we derive analytical expressions for : (i) the PDF
$P(t_f|x_0)$ of the first passage time $t_f$ which specify the lifetime of such
stochastic process, (ii) the PDF $P(A|x_0)$ of the area A till the first
passage time and it provides us numerous valuable information about the
effective reactivity of the process, (iii) the PDF $P(M)$ associated with the
maximum size M of the BM process before the first passage time, and (iv)the
joint PDF $P(M; t_m)$ of the maximum size M and its occurrence time $t_m$
before the first passage time. These distributions are examined for the power
law time time dependent drift and diffusion. A simple illustrative example for
the stochastic model of water resources availability in snowmelt dominated
regions with power law time dependent drift and diffusion is demonstrated in
details. We motivate our study with approximate calculation of an unsolved
problem of Brownian functionals including inertia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04304</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Karpishkov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saleev</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shipilova</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>DbarD and DD pair production at the LHCb in the parton Reggeization
  approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, talk at the XXIV International Workshop on
  Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects 11-15 April, 2016 DESY
  Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the inclusive DbarD and DD pair production in proton-proton
collisions at the LHC at lead- ing order of the parton Reggeization approach
endowed with universal scale-depended fragmen- tation functions for c-quark to
D-meson and for gluon to D-meson transitions. We have described DbarD and DD
distributions in azimuthal angle, as well as transverse momentum, rapidity
distance, and invariant mass measured in the region of large rapidity 2 &lt; y &lt; 4
by the LHCb Collabora- tion at the LHC without free parameters. We have used
Reggeized amplitudes for the processes RR - gg and RR - c barc which are
obtained accordingly to Feynman rules of the L.N. Lipatov effective theory of
Reggeized partons, and Kimber-Martin-Ryskin model for unintegrated gluon
distribution function in a proton with Martin-Stirling-Thorne-Watt collinear
parton distributions as inputs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04315</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahato</keyname><forenames>Swaraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meynants</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raskin</keyname><forenames>Gert</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Ridder</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Winckel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise optimization of the source follower of a CMOS pixel using BSIM3
  noise model</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>SPIE Astronomical Telescopes and Instrumentation, 2016</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2231190</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CMOS imagers are becoming increasingly popular in astronomy. A very low noise
level is required to observe extremely faint targets and to get high-precision
flux measurements. Although CMOS technology offers many advantages over CCDs, a
major bottleneck is still the read noise. To move from an industrial CMOS
sensor to one suitable for scientific applications, an improved design that
optimizes the noise level is essential. Here, we study the 1/f and thermal
noise performance of the source follower (SF) of a CMOS pixel in detail. We
identify the relevant design parameters, and analytically study their impact on
the noise level using the BSIM3v3 noise model with an enhanced model of gate
capacitance. Our detailed analysis shows that the dependence of the 1/f noise
on the geometrical size of the source follower is not limited to minimum
channel length, compared to the classical approach to achieve the minimum 1/f
noise. We derive the optimal gate dimensions (the width and the length) of the
source follower that minimize the 1/f noise, and validate our results using
numerical simulations. By considering the thermal noise or white noise along
with 1/f noise, the total input noise of the source follower depends on the
capacitor ratio CG/CFD and the drain current (Id). Here, CG is the total gate
capacitance of the source follower and CFD is the total floating diffusion
capacitor at the input of the source follower. We demonstrate that the optimum
gate capacitance (CG) depends on the chosen bias current but ranges from CFD/3
to CFD to achieve the minimum total noise of the source follower. Numerical
calculation and circuit simulation with 180nm CMOS technology are performed to
validate our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04316</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Nicolini</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordier</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;cile</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bifone</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Community detection in weighted brain connectivity networks beyond the
  resolution limit</title><categories>q-bio.NC physics.soc-ph q-bio.QM</categories><comments>27 pages with 6 figures and 1 table. Conference version for CCS2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graph theory provides a powerful framework to investigate brain functional
connectivity networks and their modular organization. However, most graph-based
methods suffer from a fundamental resolution limit that may have affected
previous studies and prevented detection of modules, or communities, that are
smaller than a specific scale. Surprise, a resolution-limit-free function
rooted in discrete probability theory, has been recently introduced and applied
to brain networks, revealing a wide size-distribution of functional modules, in
contrast with many previous reports. However, the use of Surprise is limited to
binary networks, while brain networks are intrinsically weighted, reflecting a
continuous distribution of connectivity strengths between different brain
regions. Here, we propose Asymptotical Surprise, a continuous version of
Surprise, for the study of weighted brain connectivity networks, and validate
this approach in synthetic networks endowed with a ground-truth modular
structure. We compare Asymptotical Surprise with leading community detection
methods currently in use and show its superior sensitivity in the detection of
small modules even in the presence of noise and intersubject variability such
as those observed in fMRI data. Finally, we apply our novel approach to
functional connectivity networks from resting state fMRI experimenta, and
demonstrate a heterogeneous modular organization, with a wide distribution of
clusters spanning multiple scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04318</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Klaise</keyname><forenames>Janis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author></authors><title>The Origin of Motif Families in Food Webs</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, 1 table. Submitted to Proc. R. Soc. B</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Food webs have been found to exhibit remarkable motif profiles, patterns in
the relative prevalences of all possible three-species sub-graphs, and this has
been related to ecosystem properties such as stability and robustness.
Analysing 46 food webs of various kinds, we find that most food webs fall into
one of two distinct motif families. The separation between the families is well
predicted by a global measure of hierarchical order in directed networks -
trophic coherence. We find that trophic coherence is also a good predictor for
the extent of omnivory, defined as the tendency of species to feed on multiple
trophic levels. We compare our results to a network assembly model that admits
tunable trophic coherence via a single free parameter. The model is able to
generate food webs in either of the two families by varying this parameter, and
correctly classifies almost all the food webs in our database. This establishes
a link between global order and local preying patterns in food webs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04332</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Antipin</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubikovsky</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silaev</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of collapse dynamics in relativistic theory of gravitation in
  the case of smooth initial matter distributions</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use both numerical and analytical approaches to study the dynamics of the
gravitational collapse in the framework of the relativistic theory of
gravitation (RTG). We use various equations of state for the collapsing matter
and relatively realistic initial conditions with smooth matter distribution,
which corresponds to static solution for the given equation of state. We also
obtain results concerning the influence of the graviton mass on the properties
of static solutions. We specify several characteristics of the process of the
collapse, in particular, we determine the dependence of the turning point time
(when contraction is replaced by inflation) on the graviton mass. We also study
the influence of non-zero pressure on the dynamics of the collapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04348</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Combot</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrability of the one dimensional Schroedinger equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>56 pages, 2 figures</comments><msc-class>34M46, 34M50, 37J30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a definition of integrability for the one dimensional Schroedinger
equation, which encompasses all known integrable systems, i.e. systems for
which the spectrum can be explicitly computed. For this, we introduce the class
of rigid functions, built as Liouvillian functions, but containing all
solutions of rigid differential operators in the sense of Katz, and a notion of
natural boundary conditions. We then make a complete classification of rational
integrable potentials. Many new integrable cases are found, some of them
physically interesting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04364</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Constant</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Favier</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meldi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meliga</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serre</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Implementation of a discrete Immersed Boundary Method in OpenFOAM</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the Immersed Boundary Method (IBM) proposed by Pinelli is
implemented for finite volume approximations of incompressible Navier-Stokes
equations solutions in the open source toolbox OpenFOAM version 2.2. Solid
obstacles are described using a discrete forcing approach for boundary
conditions. Unlike traditional approaches encompassing the presence of a solid
body using conformal meshes and imposing no-slip boundary conditions on the
boundary faces of the mesh, the solid body is here represented on the Eulerian
Cartesian mesh through an ad-hoc body force evaluated on a set of Lagrangian
markers. The markers can move across the Eulerian mesh, hence allowing for a
straightforward analysis of motion or deformation of the body. The IBM method
is described and implemented in PisoFOAM, whose Pressure-Implicit
Split-Operator (PISO) solver is modified accordingly. The presence of the solid
body and the divergence-free of the fluid velocity are imposed simultaneously
by sub-iterating between IBM and the pressure correction step. This scheme
allows for the use of fast optimized Poisson solvers while granting excellent
accuracy with respect to the previously mentioned constraints. Various 2D and
3D well-documented test cases of flows around fixed or moving circular
cylinders are simulated and carefully validated against existing data from the
literature. The capability of the new solver is discussed in terms of accuracy
and numerical performances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04373</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Soliman</keyname><forenames>Aiman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soltani</keyname><forenames>Kiumars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>Anand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shaowen</forenames></author></authors><title>Consistency of Social Sensing Signatures Across Major US Cities</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>CyberGIS16</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous studies have shown that Twitter users have biases to tweet from
certain locations, locational bias, and during certain hours, temporal bias. We
used three years of geolocated Twitter Data to quantify these biases and test
our central hypothesis that Twitter users biases are consistent across US
cities. Our results suggest that temporal and locational bias of Twitter users
are inconsistent between three US metropolitan cities. We derive conclusions
about the role of the complexity of the underlying data producing process on
its consistency and argue for the potential research avenue for Geospatial Data
Science to test and quantify these inconsistencies in the class of organically
evolved Big Data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:math/0209044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>math/0209044</id><created>2002-09-04</created><updated>2002-12-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grassi</keyname><forenames>Antonella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Large N dualities and transitions in geometry</title><categories>math.AG hep-th math.DG math.SG</categories><comments>Survey article based on lectures given by the first author in May
  2001 during 4th SIGRAV and SAGP2001 Graduate School (Typos corrected,
  clarifications and references added.)</comments><journal-ref>Geometry and physics of branes (Como, 2001), Ser. High Energy
  Phys. Cosmol. Gravit., IOP, Bristol, 2003</journal-ref><abstract>  The focus of these lectures is the Gopakumar-Vafa's insight that ``Large N
dualities'' (relating gauge theories and closed strings) are realized, in
certain cases, by &quot;transition in geometry&quot;. In their pivotal 1998 example, the
gauge theory is SU(N) Chern-Simons theory on S^3, for large N, and the
transition is the &quot;conifold&quot; transition between two Calabi--Yau varieties. Much
progress has been made to support Gopakumar and Vafa's conjecture, including
the lift of the transition to a transformation between 7-manifolds with G_2
holonomy. In another direction, this set up brings us to consider the uncharted
territory of &quot;open Gromov-Witten invariants&quot;. The lectures, hence the notes,
were prepared for an audience of beginning graduate students, in mathematics
and physics, whom we hope to get interested in this subject. Because most of
the material presented in these lectures comes from the physics literature, we
aimed to build a bridge for the mathematicians towards the physics papers on
the subject.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
