<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:43:01Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-04-24" from="2017-04-24" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0710.4516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0710.4516</id><created>2007-10-24</created><updated>2007-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassberger</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>The predictability of letters in written english</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.CL stat.ML</categories><comments>3 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Fractals, Vol. 4, No. 1 (1996) 1-5</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218348X96000029</doi><abstract>  We show that the predictability of letters in written English texts depends
strongly on their position in the word. The first letters are usually the least
easy to predict. This agrees with the intuitive notion that words are well
defined subunits in written languages, with much weaker correlations across
these units than within them. It implies that the average entropy of a letter
deep inside a word is roughly 4 times smaller than the entropy of the first
letter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.4994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.4994</id><created>2011-09-22</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Margolus</keyname><forenames>Norman</forenames></author></authors><title>The finite-state character of physical dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.IT math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 17 figures, ancillary file with mathematica notebook</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Finite physical systems have only a finite amount of distinct state. This
finiteness is fundamental in statistical mechanics, where the maximum number of
distinct states compatible with macroscopic constraints defines entropy. Here
we show that finiteness of distinct state is similarly fundamental in ordinary
mechanics: energy and momentum are defined by the maximum number of distinct
states possible in a given time or distance. More generally, any moment of
energy or momentum bounds distinct states in time or space. These results
generalize both the Nyquist bandwidth-bound on distinct values in classical
signals, and quantum uncertainty bounds. The new certainty bounds are achieved
by finite-bandwidth evolutions in which time and space are effectively
discrete, including quantum evolutions that are effectively classical. Since
energy and momentum count distinct states, they are defined in finite-state
dynamics, and they relate classical mechanics to finite-state evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.4217</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.4217</id><created>2014-07-16</created><updated>2016-05-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density matrix approach to the orbital ordering in the spinel vanadates:
  A case study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 figures, 9 tables</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 87 197 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2014-50365-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we apply the density matrices approach to orbital ordering (OO)
in order to study the OO of the spinel vanadates AV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A $\equiv$
Zn, Cd and Mg), which is normally believed to be responsible for the structural
transition from cubic to tetragonal phase observed in these compounds. The
density matrices of vanadium atoms are obtained by using {\it state-of-the-art}
full-potential linearized augmented plane wave method based GGA+U calculations.
In the absence of spin-orbit coupling, the present study shows the existence of
anti-ferro OO in the global (local octahedral) coordinate system where $d_{xz}$
and $d_{yz}$ ($d_{xz}$+$d_{yz}$ and $d_{xz}$-$d_{yz}$) orbitals are mainly
occupied at the neighboring V sites for all the compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1762</id><created>2014-11-06</created><updated>2014-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of binary supermassive black holes and the final-parsec
  problem</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 pages; proceedings of IAU symposium #312, &quot;Star clusters and black
  holes in galaxies across cosmic time&quot; (refs updated)</comments><journal-ref>Star Clusters and Black Holes in Galaxies across Cosmic Time,
  Proceedings of the International Astronomical Union, IAU Symposium, Volume
  312, pp. 92-100, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1743921315007607</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I review the evolution of binary supermassive black holes and focus on the
stellar-dynamical mechanisms that may help to overcome the final-parsec problem
- the possible stalling of the binary at a separation much larger than is
required for an efficient gravitational wave emission. Recent N-body
simulations have suggested that a departure from spherical symmetry in the
nucleus of the galaxy may keep the rate of interaction of stars with the binary
at a high enough level so that the binary continues to shrink rather rapidly.
However, a major problem of all these simulations is that they do not probe the
regime where collisionless effects are dominant - in other words, the number of
particles in the simulation is still not sufficient to reach the asymptotic
behaviour of the system. I present a novel Monte Carlo method for simulating
both collisional and collisionless evolution of non-spherical stellar systems,
and apply it for the problem of binary supermassive black hole evolution. I
show that in triaxial galaxies the final-parsec problem is largely
non-existent, while in the axisymmetric case it seems to still exist in the
limit of purely collisionless regime relevant for real galaxies, but disappears
in the N-body simulations where the feasible values of N are still too low to
get rid of collisional effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4119</id><created>2014-11-15</created><updated>2016-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Limitations of unconstrained LSDA+$U$ calculations in predicting the
  electronic and magnetic ground state of a geometrically frustrated
  ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ compound</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Magn. Magn. Mater., 412 23 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2016.03.075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, we investigate the applicability of the LSDA+$U$ method
in understanding the electronic and magnetic properties of a geometrically
frustrated ZnV$_2$O$_4$ compound, where the delicate balance of electrons,
lattice, orbital and spin interactions play an important role in deciding its
physical properties. In the ferromagnetic solution of the compound, only one
type of orbital solution is found to exist in all ranges of $U$ studied here.
However, in antiferromagnetic (AFM) phase, two types of orbital solutions,
AFM(OS1) and AFM(OS2), exist for $U &gt;$3 eV. If the difference of the electronic
occupancy of $d_{xz}$ and $d_{yz}$ orbitals is less than 0.25, then AFM(OS1)
solution is stabilized, whereas for higher values AFM(OS2) solution is
stabilized. The use of unconstrained calculations within the fully localized
double counting scheme is unable to predict the AFM ground state for $U
\leqslant$3 eV. Our results clearly suggest the importance of constrained
calculations in understanding the electronic and magnetic properties of a
compound, where various competing interactions are present. In the AFM
solution, the orbital ground state of the compound changes with varying $U$,
where AFM(OS1) is found to be the ground state for $U \leqslant$3 eV and for
higher values of $U$, AFM(OS2) is the ground state. The analysis of the band
gap suggests that the AFM(OS2) is the real ground state of the compound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04764</id><created>2015-03-16</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garrison</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Extracting Gravitational Waves Induced by Plasma Turbulence in the Early
  Universe through an Averaging Process</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures and 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work is a follow-up to the paper, &quot;Numerical Relativity as a Tool for
Studying the Early Universe&quot;. In this article, we determine if cosmological
gravitational waves can be accurately extracted from a dynamical spacetime
using an averaging process as opposed to conventional methods of gravitational
wave extraction using a complex Weyl scalar. We calculate the normalized energy
density, strain and degree of polarization of gravitational waves produced by a
simulated turbulent plasma similar to what was believed to have existed shortly
after the electroweak scale. This calculation is completed using two numerical
codes, one which utilizes full General Relativity calculations based on
modified BSSN equations while the other utilizes a linearized approximation of
General Relativity. Our results show that the spectrum of gravitational waves
calculated from the nonlinear code using an averaging process are nearly
indistinguishable from those calculated from the linear code. This result
validates the use of the averaging process for gravitational wave extraction of
cosmological systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05570</id><created>2015-04-21</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duplantier</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Xuan Hieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Le</keyname><forenames>Thanh Binh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinsmeister</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Logarithmic Coefficients and Generalized Multifractality of Whole-Plane
  SLE</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.CV math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>51 pages, 11 figures; considerably revised and extended version.
  Sections 4 and 5 fused, Section 7 deleted. Complete proof of Theorem 1.7
  given. New Figures 2, 6 and 7</comments><msc-class>28A80, 30C50, 30C99, 35K10, 60G51, 60G99, 60J67</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the whole-plane SLE conformal map f from the unit disk to the
slit plane, and show that its mixed moments, involving a power p of the
derivative modulus |f'| and a power q of the map |f| itself, have closed forms
along some integrability curves in the (p,q) moment plane, which depend
continuously on the SLE parameter kappa. The generalization of this
integrability property to the m-fold transform of f is also given. We define a
generalized integral means spectrum corresponding to the singular behavior of
the mixed moments above. By inversion, it allows for a unified description of
the unbounded interior and bounded exterior versions of whole-plane SLE, and of
their m-fold generalizations. The average generalized spectrum of whole-plane
SLE takes four possible forms, separated by five phase transition lines in the
moment plane, whereas the average generalized spectrum of the m-fold
whole-plane SLE is directly obtained from a linear map acting in that plane. We
also conjecture the form of the universal generalized integral means spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01601</id><created>2015-05-07</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of orbital degrees of freedom in investigating the magnetic
  properties of geometrically frustrated vanadium spinels</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>27 pages, 9 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Mater. Sci., 126 373 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.commatsci.2016.09.043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inconsistency about the degree of geometrical frustration has been a long
issue in AV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A $\equiv$ Zn, Cd and Mg) compounds, which arises
from the two experimental results: (i) frustration indices and (ii) magnetic
moments. In the present study, we try to understand such inconsistency by using
{\it ab initio} electronic structure calculations. The orbital degrees of
freedom are found to play an important role in understanding the geometrically
frustrated magnetic behaviour of these compounds. The inclusion of the orbital
and spin angular momenta for calculating the frustration indices improves the
understanding about the degree of geometrical frustration in these compounds.
The calculated values of the frustration indices ($f$$_{\it J}$) are largest
for MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and smallest for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ for 3.3$\leq$ $U
\leq$5.3 eV. In this range of $U$, the calculated values of
$\Delta$M$_{2}$=M$_{\rm total}$-M$_{\rm exp}$ are largest for MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$
and smallest for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$. Hence, the consistency about the degree of
geometrical frustration is achieved. The absolute values of the nearest
neighbour exchange coupling constant ({\it J$_{nn}$}) between V spins are found
to be largest for MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and smallest for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, which
indicate that the calculated absolute values of the Curie-Weiss temperature
($\varTheta$$_{CW}$)$_{\it J}$ are highest for MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and smallest
for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ for 3.3$\leq$ $U \leq$5.3 eV. In this range of $U$, the
magnetic transition temperature ($T$$_{N}$)$_{\it J}$ is found to be $\sim$150
K, $\sim$60 K and $\sim$22 K for MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and
CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, respectively, which shows that the order of ($T$$_{N}$)$_{\it
J}$ is similar to that of ($T$$_{N}$)$_{\rm exp}$ for these compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06679</id><created>2015-08-26</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tachikawa</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author></authors><title>Frozen</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>1+8 pages; v2: minor corrections and improvements in Sec. 2</comments><report-no>IPMU-15-0138, UT-15-30</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the duality between ALE singularities in M-theory and 7-branes on
a circle in F-theory. We see that a frozen M-theory singularity maps to a
circle compactification involving a rotation of the plane transverse to the
7-brane, showing an interesting correspondence between commuting triples in
simply-laced groups and Kodaira's classification of singular elliptic
fibrations. Our analysis strongly suggests that the O7+ plane is the only
completely frozen F-theory singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03509</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bednorz</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of assumptions of recent tests of local realism</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, published version, analysis of both runs in Delft
  and experiments in NIST, Vienna and Munich</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042118 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Local realism in recent experiments is excluded on condition of freedom or
randomness of choice combined with no signaling between observers by
implementations of simple quantum models. Both no-signaling and the underlying
quantum model can be directly checked by analysis of experimental data. For
particular tests performed on the data, it is shown that two of these
experiments give the probability of the data under no-signaling (or choice
independence in one of them) hypothesis at the level of 5%, accounting for the
look-elsewhere-effect, moderately suggesting that no-signaling is violated with
95% confidence. On the other hand the data from the two other experiments
violate the assumption of the simple quantum model. Further experiments are
necessary to clarify these issues and freedom and randomness of choice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06791</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Uitert</keyname><forenames>Edo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cacciato</keyname><forenames>Marcello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoekstra</keyname><forenames>Henk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brouwer</keyname><forenames>Margot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sif&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Crist&#xf3;bal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viola</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldry</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>Joss</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brough</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>M. J. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Ami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Driver</keyname><forenames>Simon P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erben</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heymans</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hildebrandt</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joachimi</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuijken</keyname><forenames>Konrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liske</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loveday</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Lance</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Reiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peacock</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radovich</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robotham</keyname><forenames>A. S. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikkema</keyname><forenames>Gert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Edward N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleijn</keyname><forenames>Gijs Verdoes</forenames></author></authors><title>The stellar-to-halo mass relation of GAMA galaxies from 100 square
  degrees of KiDS weak lensing data</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 12 figures. Replaced with accepted version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw747</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the stellar-to-halo mass relation of central galaxies in the range
9.7&lt;log_10(M_*/h^-2 M_sun)&lt;11.7 and z&lt;0.4, obtained from a combined analysis of
the Kilo Degree Survey (KiDS) and the Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) survey.
We use ~100 deg^2 of KiDS data to study the lensing signal around galaxies for
which spectroscopic redshifts and stellar masses were determined by GAMA. We
show that lensing alone results in poor constraints on the stellar-to-halo mass
relation due to a degeneracy between the satellite fraction and the halo mass,
which is lifted when we simultaneously fit the stellar mass function. At
M_sun&gt;5x10^10 h^-2 M_sun, the stellar mass increases with halo mass as
~M_h^0.25. The ratio of dark matter to stellar mass has a minimum at a halo
mass of 8x10^11 h^-1 M_sun with a value of M_h/M_*=56_-10^+16 [h]. We also use
the GAMA group catalogue to select centrals and satellites in groups with five
or more members, which trace regions in space where the local matter density is
higher than average, and determine for the first time the stellar-to-halo mass
relation in these denser environments. We find no significant differences
compared to the relation from the full sample, which suggests that the
stellar-to-halo mass relation does not vary strongly with local density.
Furthermore, we find that the stellar-to-halo mass relation of central galaxies
can also be obtained by modelling the lensing signal and stellar mass function
of satellite galaxies only, which shows that the assumptions to model the
satellite contribution in the halo model do not significantly bias the
stellar-to-halo mass relation. Finally, we show that the combination of weak
lensing with the stellar mass function can be used to test the purity of group
catalogues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01056</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Uitert</keyname><forenames>Edo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Systematic tests for position-dependent additive shear bias</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>15 pages, 16 figures. Replaced with accepted version</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 595, A93 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628846</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new tests to identify stationary position-dependent additive shear
biases in weak gravitational lensing data sets. These tests are important
diagnostics for currently ongoing and planned cosmic shear surveys, as such
biases induce coherent shear patterns that can mimic and potentially bias the
cosmic shear signal. The central idea of these tests is to determine the
average ellipticity of all galaxies with shape measurements in a grid in the
pixel plane. The distribution of the absolute values of these averaged
ellipticities can be compared to randomized catalogues; a difference points to
systematics in the data. In addition, we introduce a method to quantify the
spatial correlation of the additive bias, which suppresses the contribution
from cosmic shear and therefore eases the identification of a
position-dependent additive shear bias in the data. We apply these tests to the
publicly available shear catalogues from the Canada-France-Hawaii Telescope
Lensing Survey (CFHTLenS) and the Kilo Degree Survey (KiDS) and find evidence
for a small but non-negligible residual additive bias at small scales. As this
residual bias is smaller than the error on the shear correlation signal at
those scales, it is highly unlikely that it causes a significant bias in the
published cosmic shear results of CFHTLenS. In CFHTLenS, the amplitude of this
systematic signal is consistent with zero in fields where the number of stars
used to model the PSF is higher than average, suggesting that the
position-dependent additive shear bias originates from undersampled PSF
variations across the image.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03112</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03112</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beliaev</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duplantier</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinsmeister</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Integral means spectrum of whole-plane SLE</title><categories>math-ph math.CV math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 figure; final version</comments><msc-class>28A80, 30C35, 30C85, 31A15, 35B50, 60J67, 60J45</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2868-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We complete the mathematical analysis of the fine structure of harmonic
measure on SLE curves that was initiated by Beliaev and Smirnov, as described
by the averaged integral means spectrum. For the unbounded version of
whole-plane SLE as studied by Duplantier, Nguyen, Nguyen and Zinsmeister, and
Loutsenko and Yermolayeva, a phase transition has been shown to occur for high
enough moments from the bulk spectrum towards a novel spectrum related to the
point at infinity. For the bounded version of whole-plane SLE studied here, a
similar transition phenomenon, now associated with the SLE origin, is proved to
exist for low enough moments, but we show that it is superseded by the earlier
occurrence of the transition to the SLE tip spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04152</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of ionic sizes in inducing the cubic to tetragonal distortion
  in AV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and ACr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A=Zn, Mg and Cd) compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Mat. Res. Express, 3 116301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1591/3/11/116301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cubic to tetragonal distortion in spinel compounds have been a contentious
issue for last two decades. Different groups have proposed different mechanisms
to understand such a distortion in these spinels, which are: (i) spin lattice
coupling mechanism known as the spin driven Jahn-Teller (JT) effect, (ii) the
strong relativistic spin-orbit coupling, a moderate JT distortion and weak V-V
interactions and (iii) the JT effect. Now, in order to know the possible cause
for such a distortion, we have avoided these complexities (various interactions
among spin, electronic, orbital and lattice degrees of freedom) by carrying out
spin unpolarized calculations. The calculated values of bulk moduli for
ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$), MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$) and
CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (CdCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$) are found to be $\sim$289 ($\sim$254),
$\sim$244 ($\sim$243) and $\sim$230 ($\sim$233) GPa, respectively. For
vanadates and chromates, the order of calculated values of lattice parameter
$a$ are found to CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and
CdCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$, respectively and are
consistent with the experimental results. The calculated values of cubic to
tetragonal distortion (c/a), with c/a$&lt;$1 for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$
(ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$), MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$) and CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$
(CdCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$) are $\sim$0.996 ($\sim$0.997), $\sim$0.995 ($\sim$0.994)
and $\sim$0.997 ($\sim$0.998), respectively. These values are in good agreement
with the experimental data for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$,
ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ compounds. The present study clearly
shows the role of ionic sizes in inducing the cubic to tetragonal distortion in
these spinels. These mechanisms also appear to be responsible for deciding the
other physical properties of these compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05424</id><created>2016-05-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Rafsanjani</keyname><forenames>Seyed Mohammad Hashemi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirhosseini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magana-Loaiza</keyname><forenames>Omar S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gard</keyname><forenames>Bryan T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birrittella</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koltenbah</keyname><forenames>B. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parazzoli</keyname><forenames>C. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capron</keyname><forenames>Barbara A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerry</keyname><forenames>Christopher C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dowling</keyname><forenames>Jonathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interferometry with Photon-Subtracted Thermal Light</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Optica 4, (4) pp. 487-491 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000487</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and implement a quantum procedure for enhancing the sensitivity
with which one can determine the phase shift experienced by a weak light beam
possessing thermal statistics in passing through an interferometer. Our
procedure entails subtracting exactly one (which can be generalized to m)
photons from the light field exiting an interferometer containing a
phase-shifting element in one of its arms. As a consequence of the process of
photon subtraction, and somewhat surprisingly, the mean photon number and
signal-to-noise ratio of the resulting light field are thereby increased,
leading to enhanced interferometry. This method can be used to increase
measurement sensitivity in a variety of practical applications, including that
of forming the image of an object illuminated only by weak thermal light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06473</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bergholm</keyname><forenames>Ville</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilhelm</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulte-Herbrueggen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Arbitrary n-Qubit State Transfer Implemented by Coherent Control and
  Simplest Switchable Local Noise</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 7 figures. Supersedes arXiv:1206.4945</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study reachable sets of open n-qubit quantum systems, whose coherent parts
are under full unitary control, by adding as a further degree of incoherent
control switchable Markovian noise on a single qubit. In particular, adding
bang-bang control of amplitude damping noise (non-unital) allows the dynamic
system to act transitively on the entire set of density operators. Thus one can
transform any initial quantum state into any desired target state. Adding
switchable bit-flip noise (unital) instead suffices to get all states majorised
by the initial state. Our open-loop optimal control package DYNAMO is extended
by incoherent control to exploit these unprecedented reachable sets in
experiments. We propose implementation by a GMon, a superconducting device with
fast tunable coupling to an open transmission line, and illustrate how
open-loop control with noise switching achieves all state transfers without
measurement-based closed-loop feedback and resettable ancilla.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09408</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Puri</keyname><forenames>Shruti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boutin</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blais</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Engineering the quantum states of light in a Kerr-nonlinear resonator by
  two-photon driving</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><doi>10.1038/s41534-017-0019-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cat states of the microwave field stored in high-Q resonators show great
promise for robust encoding and manipulation of quantum information. Here we
propose an approach to efficiently prepare such cat states in a Kerr-nonlinear
resonator by the use of a two-photon drive. We show that this preparation is
robust against single-photon loss. We moreover find that it is possible to
remove undesirable phase evolution induced by a Kerr nonlinearity using a
two-photon drive of appropriate amplitude and phase. Finally, we present a
universal set of quantum logical gates that can be performed on the engineered
eigenspace of the two-photon driven Kerr-nonlinear resonator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09397</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames><affiliation>SJTU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengjie</forenames><affiliation>SJTU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Wentao</forenames><affiliation>SHAO</affiliation></author></authors><title>Approaching the Cramer-Rao Bound in Weak Lensing with PDF Symmetrization</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 834, Issue 1, article id. 8, 13
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/1/8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weak lensing statistics is typically measured as weighted sum of shear
estimators or their products (shear-shear correlation). The weighting schemes
are designed in the hope of minimizing the statistical error without
introducing systematic errors. It would be ideal to approach the Cramer-Rao
bound (the lower bound of the statistical uncertainty) in shear statistics,
though it is generally difficult to do so in practice. The reasons may include:
difficulties in galaxy shape measurement, inaccurate knowledge of the
probability-distribution-function (PDF) of the shear estimator,
misidentification of point sources as galaxies, etc.. Using the shear
estimators defined in Zhang et al. (2015), we show that one can overcome all
these problems, and allow shear measurement accuracy to approach the Cramer-Rao
bound. This can be achieved by symmetrizing the PDF of the shear estimator, or
the joint PDF of shear estimator pairs (for shear-shear correlation), without
any prior knowledge of the PDF. Using simulated galaxy images, we demonstrate
that under general observing conditions, this idea works as expected: it
minimizes the statistical uncertainty without introducing systematic error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03062</id><created>2016-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Fillion-Gourdeau</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blain</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gagnon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lefebvre</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacLean</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical computation of dynamical Schwinger-like pair production in
  graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, contribution to the Workshop Proceedings of the
  International Workshop SFP-2016: Strong Field Problems in Quantum Theory,
  Tomsk, Russia, June 6-11, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Russ Phys J (2017) 59: 1875</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11182-017-0990-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The density of electron-hole pairs produced in a graphene sample immersed in
a homogeneous time-dependent electrical field is evaluated. Because low energy
charge carriers in graphene are described by relativistic quantum mechanics,
the calculation is performed within the strong field quantum electrodynamics
formalism, requiring a solution of the Dirac equation in momentum space. The
latter is solved using a split-operator numerical scheme on parallel computers,
allowing for the investigation of several field configurations. The strength of
the method is illustrated by computing the electron momentum density generated
from a realistic laser pulse model. We observe quantum interference patterns
reminiscent of Landau-Zener-St\&quot;{u}ckelberg interferometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06504</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2017-04-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shiozaki</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryu</keyname><forenames>Shinsei</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix product states and equivariant topological field theories for
  bosonic symmetry-protected topological phases in (1+1) dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>1+48 pages, many figures. One paragraph &quot;Discrete torsion phase (2):
  partial symmetry action and swapping&quot; in page 10 has been added. final
  version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)100</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Matrix Product States (MPSs) provide a powerful framework to study and
classify gapped quantum phases --symmetry-protected topological (SPT) phases in
particular--defined in one dimensional lattices. On the other hand, it is
natural to expect that gapped quantum phases in the limit of zero correlation
length are described by topological quantum field theories (TFTs or TQFTs). In
this paper, for (1+1)-dimensional bosonic SPT phases protected by symmetry $G$,
we bridge their descriptions in terms of MPSs, and those in terms of
$G$-equivariant TFTs. In particular, for various topological invariants (SPT
invariants) constructed previously using MPSs, we provide derivations from the
point of view of (1+1) TFTs. We also discuss the connection between boundary
degrees of freedom, which appear when one introduces a physical boundary in SPT
phases, and &quot;open&quot; TFTs, which are TFTs defined on spacetimes with boundaries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07225</id><created>2016-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained DFT+$U$ approach for understanding the magnetic behaviour of
  ACr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A=Zn, Mg, Cd and Hg) compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A, 381 917 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.01.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we try to understand the inconsistency reported by [Yaresko,
Phys. Rev. B. {\bf 77}, 115106 (2008)] in the theoretically estimated nature
and the variation of magnitude of nearest neighbour exchange coupling constant
($\arrowvert${\it J$_{1}$}$\arrowvert$) with increasing $U$ in ACr$_{2}$O$_{4}$
(A=Zn, Cd, Mg and Hg) compounds by using density functional theory. In
unconstrained calculations, the nature and variation of $\arrowvert${\it
J$_{1}$}$\arrowvert$ as a function of $U$ in the present study are not
consistent with the experimental data and not according to the relation, {\it
J$_{1}$}$\propto$$\frac{t^{2}}{U}$ especially for CdCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and
HgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ for $U &gt;$3 eV and U=2-6 eV, respectively. Such an
inconsistent behavior of $\arrowvert${\it J$_{1}$}$\arrowvert$ is almost
similar to that of Yaresko for these two compounds for $U$=2-4 eV. For
ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$, the nature and the variation of
$\arrowvert${\it J$_{1}$}$\arrowvert$ in the present work are in accordance
with the experimental data and above mentioned relation for $U$=2-6 eV and are
similar to that of Yaresko for ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$ for $U$=2-4 eV. However, in
constrained calculations the nature and variation of $\arrowvert${\it
J$_{1}$}$_{c}$$\arrowvert$ in the present work are according to experimental
data and above above mentioned relation for all four compounds. Hence, the
present study shows the importance of constrained calculations in understanding
the magnetic behaviour of these spinels. The values of magnitude of Curie-Weiss
temperature [$\arrowvert$($\varTheta$$_{CW}$)$_{c}$$\arrowvert$] for
ZnCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$MgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$CdCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$HgCr$_{2}$O$_{4}$
for $U$=2-5 eV, which are according to the order of experimentally observed
values for these spinels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05322</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2016-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Zhang-qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tongcang</forenames></author></authors><title>Bringing quantum mechanics to life: from Schr\&quot;{o}dinger's cat to
  Schr\&quot;{o}dinger's microbe</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>review article for Contemporary Physics, 28 pages</comments><journal-ref>Contemporary Physics 58, 119 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00107514.2016.1261860</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The question whether quantum mechanics is complete and the nature of the
transition between quantum mechanics and classical mechanics have intrigued
physicists for decades. There have been many experimental breakthroughs in
creating larger and larger quantum superposition and entangled states since
Erwin Schr\&quot;odinger proposed his famous thought experiment of putting a cat in
a superposition of both alive and dead states in 1935. Remarkably, recent
developments in quantum optomechanics and electromechanics may lead to the
realization of quantum superposition of living microbes soon. Recent evidence
also suggests that quantum coherence may play an important role in several
biological processes. In this review, we first give a brief introduction to
basic concepts in quantum mechanics and the Schr\&quot;odinger's cat thought
experiment. We then review developments in creating quantum superposition and
entangled states and the realization of quantum teleportation. Non-trivial
quantum effects in photosynthetic light harvesting and avian magnetoreception
are also discussed. At last, we review recent proposals to realize quantum
superposition, entanglement and state teleportation of microorganisms, such as
viruses and bacteria.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06927</id><created>2016-08-24</created><updated>2017-02-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schlief</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunts</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sung-Sik</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact critical exponents for the antiferromagnetic quantum critical
  metal in two dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>19 pages + supplementary materials; v4) discussion on
  superconductivity expanded; comparison with experiments added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 021010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.021010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unconventional metallic states which do not support well defined
single-particle excitations can arise near quantum phase transitions as strong
quantum fluctuations of incipient order parameters prevent electrons from
forming coherent quasiparticles. Although antiferromagnetic phase transitions
occur commonly in correlated metals, understanding the nature of the strange
metal realized at the critical point in layered systems has been hampered by a
lack of reliable theoretical methods that take into account strong quantum
fluctuations. We present a non-perturbative solution to the low-energy theory
for the antiferromagnetic quantum critical metal in two spatial dimensions.
Being a strongly coupled theory, it can still be solved reliably in the
low-energy limit as quantum fluctuations are organized by a new control
parameter that emerges dynamically. We predict the exact critical exponents
that govern the universal scaling of physical observables at low temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00723</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2016-09-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goon</keyname><forenames>Garrett</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinterbichler</keyname><forenames>Kurt</forenames></author></authors><title>Superluminality, Black Holes and Effective Field Theory</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>51 pages, many figures. v2 typo fixed, refs added</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 02 (2017) 134</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2017)134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under the assumption that a UV theory does not display superluminal behavior,
we ask what constraints on superluminality are satisfied in the effective field
theory (EFT). We study two examples of effective theories: quantum
electrodynamics (QED) coupled to gravity after the electron is integrated out,
and the flat-space galileon. The first is realized in nature, the second is
more speculative, but they both exhibit apparent superluminality around
non-trivial backgrounds. In the QED case, we attempt, and fail, to find
backgrounds for which the superluminal signal advance can be made larger than
the putative resolving power of the EFT. In contrast, in the galileon case it
is easy to find such backgrounds, indicating that if the UV completion of the
galileon is (sub)luminal, quantum corrections must become important at distance
scales of order the Vainshtein radius of the background configuration, much
larger than the naive EFT strong coupling distance scale. Such corrections
would be reminiscent of the non-perturbative Schwarzschild scale quantum
effects that are expected to resolve the black hole information problem.
Finally, a byproduct of our analysis is a calculation of how perturbative
quantum effects alter charged Reissner-Nordstrom black holes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04415</id><created>2016-09-14</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication of fully automated setup for high temperature thermal
  conductivity measurement</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 88, 015107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973779</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we report the fabrication of experimental setup for high
temperature thermal conductivity ($\kappa$) measurement. It can characterize
samples with various dimensions and shapes. Steady state based axial heat flow
technique is used for $\kappa$ measurement. Heat loss is measured using
parallel thermal conductance technique. Simple design, lightweight and small
size sample holder is developed by using a thin heater and limited components.
Low heat loss value is achieved by using very low thermal conductive insulator
block with small cross sectional area. Power delivered to the heater is
measured accurately by using 4-wire technique and for this, heater is developed
with 4-wire. This setup is validated by using $Bi_{0.36}Sb_{1.45}Te_3$,
polycrystalline bismuth, gadolinium, and alumina samples. The data obtained for
these samples are found to be in good agreement with the reported data. The
maximum deviation of 6 \% in the value $\kappa$ are observed. This maximum
deviation is observed with the gadolinium sample. We also report the thermal
conductivity of polycrystalline tellurium from 320 K to 550 K and the non
monotonous behavior of $\kappa$ with temperature is observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05213</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brauner</keyname><forenames>Tomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral Soliton Lattice and Charged Pion Condensation in Strong Magnetic
  Fields</title><categories>hep-ph cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>v2: 19 pages, 6 figures; substantially extended version of the paper,
  published in JHEP</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)132</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Chiral Soliton Lattice (CSL) is a state with a periodic array of
topological solitons that spontaneously breaks parity and translational
symmetries. Such a state is known to appear in chiral magnets. We show that CSL
also appears as a ground state of quantum chromodynamics at nonzero chemical
potential in a magnetic field. By analyzing the fluctuations of the CSL, we
furthermore demonstrate that in strong but achievable magnetic fields, charged
pions undergo Bose-Einstein condensation. Our results, based on a systematic
low-energy effective theory, are model-independent and fully analytic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05624</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oikawa</keyname><forenames>Akane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omoto</keyname><forenames>Naoya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saga</keyname><forenames>Ikumi</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on small-field axion inflation</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures; v2 published version</comments><report-no>EPHOU-16-016, WU-HEP-16-017</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 063514 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.063514</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study general class of small-field axion inflations which are the mixture
of polynomial and sinusoidal functions suggested by the natural and axion
monodromy inflations. The axion decay constants leading to the successful axion
inflations are severely constrained in order not to spoil the Big-Bang
nucleosynthesis and overproduce the isocurvature perturbation originating from
the QCD axion. We in turn find that the cosmologically favorable axion decay
constants are typically of order the grand unification scale or the string
scale which is consistent with the prediction of closed string axions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09324</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Performance of algorithms that reconstruct missing transverse momentum
  in $\sqrt{s}=$ 8 TeV proton-proton collisions in the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>69 pages in total, author list starting page 53, 26 figures, 6
  tables, published version, all figures including auxiliary figures are
  available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/PERF-2014-04/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-134</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C77 (2017) 241</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4780-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reconstruction and calibration algorithms used to calculate missing
transverse momentum ($E_{\rm T}^{\rm miss}$) with the ATLAS detector exploit
energy deposits in the calorimeter and tracks reconstructed in the inner
detector as well as the muon spectrometer. Various strategies are used to
suppress effects arising from additional proton-proton interactions, called
pileup, concurrent with the hard-scatter processes. Tracking information is
used to distinguish contributions from the pileup interactions using their
vertex separation along the beam axis. The performance of the $E_{\rm T}^{\rm
miss}$ reconstruction algorithms, especially with respect to the amount of
pileup, is evaluated using data collected in proton-proton collisions at a
centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV during 2012, and results are shown for a data
sample corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 20.3 fb$^{-1}$. The results
of simulation modelling of $E_{\rm T}^{\rm miss}$ in events containing a $Z$
boson decaying to two charged leptons (electrons or muons) or a $W$ boson
decaying to a charged lepton and a neutrino is compared to data. The acceptance
for different event topologies, with and without high transverse momentum
neutrinos, is shown for a range of threshold criteria for $E_{\rm T}^{\rm
miss}$, and estimates of the systematic uncertainties in the $E_{\rm T}^{\rm
miss}$ measurements are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09639</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09639</id><created>2016-09-30</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Attaccalite</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear response in extended systems: a real-time approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Habilitation \'a Diriger des Recherches (HDR) [thesis, Marseille]</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this thesis we present a new formalism to study linear and non-linear
response in extended systems. Our approach is based on real-time solution of an
effective Schr\&quot;odinger equation. The coupling between electrons and external
field is described by means of Modern Theory of Polarization. Correlation
effects are derived from Green's function theory. We show that the inclusion of
local-field effects and electron-hole interaction is crucial to predict and
reproduce second and third harmonic generation in low dimensional structures,
where strong bound excitons are present. Finally in the last part we introduce
a real-time density functional approach suitable for infinite periodic crystals
in which we work within the so-called length gauge and calculate the
polarisation as a dynamical Berry's phase. This approach, in addition to the
electron density considers also the macroscopic polarisation as a main variable
to correctly treat periodic crystals in presence of electric fields within a
density functional framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09644</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09644</id><created>2016-09-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eichler</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degen</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanoscale imaging of current density with a single-spin magnetometer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Letters 17, 2367 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b05304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Charge transport in nanostructures and thin films is fundamental to many
phenomena and processes in science and technology, ranging from quantum effects
and electronic correlations in mesoscopic physics, to integrated charge- or
spin-based electronic circuits, to photoactive layers in energy research.
Direct visualization of the charge flow in such structures is challenging due
to their nanometer size and the itinerant nature of currents. In this work, we
demonstrate non-invasive magnetic imaging of current density in two-dimensional
conductor networks including metallic nanowires and carbon nanotubes. Our
sensor is the electronic spin of a diamond nitrogen-vacancy center attached to
a scanning tip. Using a differential measurement technique, we detect DC
currents down to a few uA above a baseline current density of 2e4 A/cm2.
Reconstructed images have a spatial resolution of typically 50 nm, with a
best-effort value of 22 nm. Current density imaging offers a new route for
studying electronic transport and conductance variations in two-dimensional
materials and devices, with many exciting applications in condensed matter
physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02910</id><created>2016-10-10</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Richard S.</forenames><affiliation>BIPM, France</affiliation></author></authors><title>Determining the value of the fine-structure constant from a current
  balance: getting acquainted with some upcoming changes to the SI</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>The updated version (version 3) has been published in the American
  Journal of Physics after reformatting by the journal</comments><journal-ref>Am. J. Phys. 85(5), 364-368, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4976701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The revised International System of Units (SI), expected to be approved late
in 2018, has implications for physics pedagogy; the ampere definition which
dates from 1948 will be replaced by a definition that fixes the numerical value
of the elementary charge, e, in coulombs. The kilogram definition which dates
from 1889 will be replaced by a definition that fixes the numerical value of
the Planck constant, h, in joule seconds. Existing SI equations are completely
unaffected. However, there will be a largely-negligible, but nevertheless
necessary, change to published numerical factors relating SI electrical units
to their corresponding units in the Gaussian and other CGS systems of units.
The implications of the revised SI for electrical metrology are neatly
illustrated by considering the interpretation of results obtained from a
current balance in the present SI and in the revised SI.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03422</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Portmann</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum authentication with key recycling</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>38+17 pages, 13 figures. v2: constructed ideal secure channel and
  secret key resource have been slightly redefined; also added a proof in the
  appendix for quantum authentication without key recycling that has better
  parameters and only requires weak purity testing codes</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Cryptology - EUROCRYPT 2017, Proceedings, Part III,
  vol. 10212 of LNCS, pages 339-368. Springer, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-56617-7_12</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a family of quantum authentication protocols introduced in
[Barnum et al., FOCS 2002] can be used to construct a secure quantum channel
and additionally recycle all of the secret key if the message is successfully
authenticated, and recycle part of the key if tampering is detected. We give a
full security proof that constructs the secure channel given only insecure
noisy channels and a shared secret key. We also prove that the number of
recycled key bits is optimal for this family of protocols, i.e., there exists
an adversarial strategy to obtain all non-recycled bits. Previous works
recycled less key and only gave partial security proofs, since they did not
consider all possible distinguishers (environments) that may be used to
distinguish the real setting from the ideal secure quantum channel and secret
key resource.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04226</id><created>2016-10-13</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Uitert</keyname><forenames>Edo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoekstra</keyname><forenames>Henk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joachimi</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>Joss</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Ami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erben</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heymans</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hildebrandt</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klaes</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuijken</keyname><forenames>Konrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Reiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Napolitano</keyname><forenames>Nicola R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schrabback</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valentijn</keyname><forenames>Edwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viola</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Halo ellipticity of GAMA galaxy groups from KiDS weak lensing</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 13 figures. Replaced with accepted version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx344</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We constrain the average halo ellipticity of ~2 600 galaxy groups from the
Galaxy And Mass Assembly (GAMA) survey, using the weak gravitational lensing
signal measured from the overlapping Kilo Degree Survey (KiDS). To do so, we
quantify the azimuthal dependence of the stacked lensing signal around seven
different proxies for the orientation of the dark matter distribution, as it is
a priori unknown which one traces the orientation best. On small scales, the
major axis of the brightest group/cluster member (BCG) provides the best proxy,
leading to a clear detection of an anisotropic signal. In order to relate that
to a halo ellipticity, we have to adopt a model density profile. We derive new
expressions for the quadrupole moments of the shear field given an elliptical
model surface mass density profile. Modeling the signal with an elliptical
Navarro-Frenk-White (NFW) profile on scales &lt; 250 kpc, which roughly
corresponds to half the virial radius, and assuming that the BCG is perfectly
aligned with the dark matter, we find an average halo ellipticity of e_h=0.38
+/- 0.12. This agrees well with results from cold-dark-matter-only simulations,
which typically report values of e_h ~ 0.3. On larger scales, the lensing
signal around the BCGs does not trace the dark matter distribution well, and
the distribution of group satellites provides a better proxy for the halo's
orientation instead, leading to a 3--4 sigma detection of a non-zero halo
ellipticity at scales between 250 kpc and 750 kpc. Our results suggest that the
distribution of stars enclosed within a certain radius forms a good proxy for
the orientation of the dark matter within that radius, which has also been
observed in hydrodynamical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07944</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07944</id><created>2016-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Battista</keyname><forenames>Nicholas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strickland</keyname><forenames>W. Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Laura A.</forenames></author></authors><title>IB2d: a Python and MATLAB implementation of the immersed boundary method</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cs.MS</categories><comments>34 pages, 24 figures</comments><msc-class>76Z99, 74F10, 92C10, 92C99, 76D99</msc-class><doi>10.1088/1748-3190/aa5e08</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The development of fluid-structure interaction (FSI) software involves
trade-offs between ease of use, generality, performance, and cost. Typically
there are large learning curves when using low-level software to model the
interaction of an elastic structure immersed in a uniform density fluid. Many
existing codes are not publicly available, and the commercial software that
exists usually requires expensive licenses and may not be as robust or allow
the necessary flexibility that in house codes can provide. We present an open
source immersed boundary software package, IB2d, with full implementations in
both MATLAB and Python, that is capable of running a vast range of biomechanics
models and is accessible to scientists who have experience in high-level
programming environments. IB2d contains multiple options for constructing
material properties of the fiber structure, as well as the advection-diffusion
of a chemical gradient, muscle mechanics models, and artificial forcing to
drive boundaries with a preferred motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09828</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Tianhuan</forenames><affiliation>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames><affiliation>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Fuyu</forenames><affiliation>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yingke</forenames><affiliation>Shanghai Jiao Tong University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dezi</forenames><affiliation>Peking University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Liping</forenames><affiliation>Shanghai Normal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guoliang</forenames><affiliation>Purple Mountain Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Zuhui</forenames><affiliation>Peking University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Testing PSF Interpolation In Weak Lensing With Real Data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astronomical Journal, Volume 153, Issue 4, article id. 197, 13
  pp. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/aa661e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reconstruction of the point spread function (PSF) is a critical process in
weak lensing measurement. We develop a real-data based and galaxy-oriented
pipeline to compare the performances of various PSF reconstruction schemes.
Making use of a large amount of the CFHTLenS data, the performances of three
classes of interpolating schemes - polynomial, Kriging, and Shepard - are
evaluated. We find that polynomial interpolations with optimal orders and
domains perform the best. We quantify the effect of the residual PSF
reconstruction error on shear recovery in terms of the multiplicative and
additive biases, and their spatial correlations using the shear measurement
method of Zhang et al. (2015). We find that the impact of PSF reconstruction
uncertainty on the shear-shear correlation can be significantly reduced by
cross correlating the shear estimators from different exposures. It takes only
0.2 stars (SNR &gt; 100) per square arcmin on each exposure to reach the best
performance of PSF interpolation, a requirement that is generally satisfied in
the CFHTlenS data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01367</id><created>2016-10-25</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prochazka</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwicky</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>On Finiteness of 2- and 3-point Functions and the Renormalisation Group</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages plus refs, open access version - identical to version in PRD</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2016-004 DNRF90, DIAS-2016-4</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 065027 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.065027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two and three point functions of composite operators are analysed with regard
to (logarithmically) divergent contact terms. Using the renormalisation group
of dimensional regularisation it is established that the divergences are
governed by the anomalous dimensions of the operators and the leading
UV-behaviour of the $1/\epsilon$-coefficient. Explicit examples are given by
the $&lt;G^2G^2&gt;$-, $&lt;\Theta \Theta&gt;$-trace of the energy momentum tensor) and
$&lt;\bar q q \bar q q&gt;$- correlators in QCD-like theories. The former two are
convergent when all orders are taken into account but divergent at each order
in perturbation theory implying that the latter and the the $\epsilon \to 0$
limit do not generally commute. Finite correlation functions obey unsubtracted
dispersion relations which is of importance when they are directly related to
physical observables. As a byproduct the $R^2$-anomaly is extended to NNLO
($O(\alpha^5)$) using a recent $&lt;G^2G^2&gt;$-computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01394</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petraki</keyname><forenames>Kalliopi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postma</keyname><forenames>Marieke</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Vries</keyname><forenames>Jordy</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative bound-state-formation cross-sections for dark matter
  interacting via a Yukawa potential</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>v1: 53 pages, many figures; v2: discussion and references added,
  results unchanged, published version, 61 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)077</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the cross-sections for the radiative formation of bound states
by dark matter whose interactions are described in the non-relativistic regime
by a Yukawa potential. These cross-sections are important for cosmological and
phenomenological studies of dark matter with long-range interactions, residing
in a hidden sector, as well as for TeV-scale WIMP dark matter. We provide the
leading-order contributions to the cross-sections for the dominant capture
processes occurring via emission of a vector or a scalar boson. We offer a
detailed inspection of their features, including their velocity dependence
within and outside the Coulomb regime, and their resonance structure. For pairs
of annihilating particles, we compare bound-state formation with annihilation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02028</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-consistent evaluation of effective Coulomb interaction of V atom
  and its importance to understand the comparative electronic behaviour of
  vanadium spinels</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.04.026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In present work, we try to understand the importance of effective Coulomb
interaction ($U_{ef}$) between localized electrons of V atom to understand the
comparative electronic behaviour of AV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A=Zn, Cd and Mg)
compounds. The suitable values of $d$-linearization energy ($E_{d}$) of
impurity V atom for calculating the $U_{ef}$ for these compounds are found to
be $\geq$44.89 eV above the Fermi level. Corresponding to these values of
$E_{d}$, the self-consistently calculated values of effective $U_{LSDA}$
($U_{PBEsol}$) for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ are
$\sim$5.73 ($\sim$5.92), $\sim$6.06 ($\sim$6.22) and $\sim$5.59 ($\sim$5.71)
eV, respectively. The calculated values of $\frac{t}{U_{ef}}$ ($t$ is the
transfer integral between neighbouring sites) increases with decreasing V-V
distance from CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ to MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ to ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and are
found to be consistent with experimentally reported band gap. The values of
$\frac{t}{U_{ef}}$ for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$
are found to be $\sim$0.023, $\sim$0.020 and $\sim$0.018, respectively. Hence,
CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ with small (large) $\frac{t}{U_{ef}}$ (experimental band gap)
as compared to ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ is found to be in
localized-electron regime, while ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ are
intermediate between localized and an itinerant-electron regime. The calculated
values of lattice parameters $a_{LSDS}$ ($a_{PBEsol}$) are found to be
$\sim$1.7\%, $\sim$2.0\% and $\sim$2.4\% ($\sim$0.6\%, $\sim$0.7\% and
$\sim$0.7\%) smaller than $a_{exp}$ for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and
ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, respectively, which indicates that the PBEsol functional
predicts the lattice parameters in good agreement with the experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06602</id><created>2016-11-20</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cirkovic</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devetak</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dordevic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milosevic</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stojanovic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-leading flow modes in PbPb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$ = 2.76 TeV
  from HYDJET++ model</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C Vol. 41, No. 7 (2017) 074001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/7/074001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent LHC results on the appearance of sub-leading flow modes in PbPb
collisions at 2.76~TeV, related to initial-state fluctuations, are analyzed and
interpreted within the HYDJET++ model. Using the newly introduced Principal
Component Analysis (PCA) method applied to two-particle azimuthal correlations
extracted from the model calculations, the leading and the sub-leading flow
modes are studied as a function of the transverse momentum ($p_{T}$) over a
wide centrality range. The leading modes of the elliptic ($v^{(1)}_{2}$) and
triangular ($v^{(1)}_{3}$) flow calculated within the HYDJET++ model reproduce
rather well the $v_{2}\{2\}$ and $v_{3}\{2\}$ coefficients experimentally
measured using the two-particle correlations. Within the $p_{T} \le $~3~GeV/c
range where hydrodynamics dominates, the sub-leading flow effects are greatest
at the highest $p_{T}$ of around 3~GeV/c. The sub-leading elliptic flow mode
($v^{(2)}_{2}$), which corresponds to $n = 2$ harmonic, has a small non-zero
value and slowly increases from central to peripheral collisions, while the
sub-leading triangular flow mode ($v^{(2)}_{3}$), which corresponds to $n = 3$
harmonic, is even smaller and does not depend on centrality. For $n = $~2, the
relative magnitude of the effect measured with respect to the leading flow mode
shows a shallow minimum for semi-central collisions and increases for very
central and for peripheral collisions. For $n = $~3 case, there is no
centrality dependence. The sub-leading flow mode results obtained from the
HYDJET++ model are in a rather good agreement with the experimental
measurements of the CMS Collaboration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01273</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2017-03-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>Sohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic structure study of vanadium spinels by using density
  functional theory and dynamical mean field theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Europhys. Lett., 117 37002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/37002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretically, various physical properties of AV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ (A=Zn, Cd and
Mg) spinels have been extensively studied for last 15 years. Besides of this,
no systematic comparative study has been done for these compounds, where the
material specific parameters are used. Here, we report the comparative
electronic behaviour of these spinels by using a combination of density
functional theory and dynamical mean-field theory, where the self-consistent
calculated Coulomb interaction $U$ and Hund's coupling $J$ (determined by
Yukawa screening $\lambda$) are used. The main features, such as insulating
band gaps ($E_{g}$), degree of itinerancy of V 3$d$ electrons and position of
lower Hubbard band are observed for these parameters in these spinels. The
calculated values of $E_{g}$ for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and
MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ are found to be $\sim$0.9 eV, $\sim$0.95 eV and $\sim$1.15 eV,
respectively, where the values of $E_{g}$ are close to experiment for
ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$. The position of lower Hubbard band are
observed around $\sim$-1.05 eV, $\sim$-1.25 eV and $\sim$-1.15 eV for
ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, respectively, which
are also in good agreement with the experimental data for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$. The
order of average impurity hybridization function of V site are found to be
ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$MgV$_{2}$O$_{4}$$&gt;$CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$. Hence, the degree of
localization of V 3$d$ electrons is largest for CdV$_{2}$O$_{4}$ and smallest
for ZnV$_{2}$O$_{4}$, which is in accordance with our earlier results. Hence,
present work shows the importance of material specific parameters to understand
the comparative electronic behaviour of these compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04991</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campaioli</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pollock</keyname><forenames>Felix A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binder</keyname><forenames>Felix C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xe9;leri</keyname><forenames>Lucas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goold</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinjanampathy</keyname><forenames>Sai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modi</keyname><forenames>Kavan</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing the charging power of quantum batteries</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>In this new updated version Theorem 1 has been changed with
  Proposition 1. The paper has been published on PRL, and DOI included
  accordingly</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 150601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.150601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Can collective quantum effects make a difference in a meaningful
thermodynamic operation? Focusing on energy storage and batteries, we
demonstrate that quantum mechanics can lead to an enhancement in the amount of
work deposited per unit time, i.e., the charging power, when $N$ batteries are
charged collectively. We first derive analytic upper bounds for the collective
\emph{quantum advantage} in charging power for two choices of constraints on
the charging Hamiltonian. We then highlight the importance of entanglement by
proving that the quantum advantage vanishes when the collective state of the
batteries is restricted to be in the separable ball. Finally, we provide an
upper bound to the achievable quantum advantage when the interaction order is
restricted, i.e., at most $k$ batteries are interacting. Our result is a
fundamental limit on the advantage offered by quantum technologies over their
classical counterparts as far as energy deposition is concerned.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05542</id><created>2016-12-16</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fedortchenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jezouin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coudreau</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huard</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milman</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum simulation of ultrastrongly coupled bosonic modes using
  superconducting circuits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042313 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042313</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ground state of a pair of ultrastrongly coupled bosonic modes is
predicted to be a two-mode squeezed vacuum. However, the corresponding quantum
correlations are currently unobservable in condensed matter where such a
coupling can be reached, since it cannot be extracted from these systems. Here,
we show that superconducting circuits can be used to perform an analog
simulation of a system of two bosonic modes in regimes ranging from strong to
ultrastrong coupling. More importantly, our quantum simulation setup enables us
to detect output excitations that are related to the ground-state properties of
the bosonic modes. We compute the emission spectra of this physical system and
show that the produced state presents single- and two-mode squeezing
simultaneously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05886</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asorey</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balachandran</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizzi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marmo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equations of Motion as Constraints: Superselection Rules, Ward
  Identities</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 1 reference added and typos corrected</comments><report-no>ICCUB-16-042</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The meaning of local observables is poorly understood in gauge theories, not
to speak of quantum gravity. As a step towards a better understanding we study
asymptotic (infrared) transformation in local quantum physics. Our observables
are smeared by test functions, at first vanishing at infinity. In this context
we show that the equations of motion can be seen as constraints, which generate
a group, the group of space and time dependent gauge transformations.This is
one of the main points of the paper. Infrared nontrivial effects are captured
allowing test functions which do not vanish at infinity. These extended
operators generate a larger group. The quotient of the two groups generate
superselection sectors, which differentiate different infrared sectors. The BMS
group changes the superselection sector, a result long known for its Lorentz
subgroup. It is hence spontaneously broken. Ward identities implied by the
gauge invariance of the S-matrix generalize the standard results and lead to
charge conservation and low energy theorems. Their validity does not require
Lorentz invariance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08744</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08744</id><created>2016-12-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Foster</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostelecky</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on Nonmetricity from Bounds on Lorentz Violation</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><report-no>IUHET 623, December 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 084033 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spacetime nonmetricity can be studied experimentally through its couplings to
fermions and photons. We use recent high-precision searches for Lorentz
violation to deduce first constraints involving the 40 independent nonmetricity
components down to levels of order $10^{-43}$ GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02366</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Plan</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel Lance Christopher VI Medillo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vincenzi</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibbon</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Lyapunov dimension of elastic turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-Reynolds-number polymer solutions exhibit a chaotic behaviour known as
'elastic turbulence' when the Weissenberg number exceeds a critical value. The
two-dimensional Oldroyd-B model is the simplest constitutive model that
reproduces this phenomenon. To make a practical estimate of the resolution
scale of the dynamics requires an assumption that an attractor of the Oldroyd-B
model exists : numerical simulations show that the quantities on which this
assumption is based are bounded. We estimate the Lyapunov dimension of this
assumed attractor as a function of the Weissenberg number by combining a
mathematical analysis of the model with direct numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02727</id><created>2016-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Yastrebov</keyname><forenames>Vladislav A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anciaux</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molinari</keyname><forenames>Jean-Francois</forenames></author></authors><title>On the accurate computation of the true contact-area in mechanical
  contact of random rough surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.class-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Tribology International, 114:161-171 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.triboint.2017.04.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a corrective function to compensate errors in contact area
computations coming from mesh discretization. The correction is based on
geometrical arguments and requires only one additional quantity to be computed:
the length of contact/non-contact interfaces. The new technique enables us to
evaluate accurately the true contact area using a coarse mesh for which the
shortest wavelength in the surface spectrum reaches the grid size. The validity
of the approach is demonstrated for surfaces with different fractal dimensions
and different spectral content using a properly designed mesh convergence test.
In addition, we use a topology preserving smoothing technique to adjust the
morphology of contact clusters obtained with a coarse grid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03544</id><created>2017-01-12</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Yao-Tai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Wei-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Dao-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation of pairing symmetry with bond disorder in unconventional
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134513 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134513</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a two-orbital $t$-$J_1$-$J_2$ model, originally developed to
describe iron-based superconductors at low energies, in the presence of bond
disorder (via next-nearest-neighbor $J_2$-bond dilution). By using the
Bogoliubov--de Gennes approach, we self-consistently calculate the local
pairing amplitudes and the corresponding density of states, which demonstrate a
change of dominant pairing symmetry from $s_\pm$ wave to $d$ wave when
increasing disorder strength as long as $J_1\lesssim J_2$. Moreover, the
combined pairing interaction and strong bond disorder lead to the formation of
$s_\pm$ wave &quot;islands&quot; with length scale of the superconducting coherence
length embedded in a $d$ wave &quot;sea.&quot; This picture is further complemented by
the disorder-averaged pair-pair correlation functions, distinct from the case
with potential disorder, where the &quot;sea&quot; is insulating. Due to this inevitable
formation of spatial inhomogeneity, the superconducting $T_c$ determined by the
superfluid density $\rho_s(T)$ obviously deviates from the value predicted by
the conventional Abrikosov-Gorkov theory, where the pairing amplitudes are
viewed as uniformly suppressed as the disorder increases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03875</id><created>2017-01-13</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>S. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tam</keyname><forenames>K. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidhyadhiraja</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarrell</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Calculation of Two-Particle Quantities in the Typical Medium
  Dynamical Cluster Approximation</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 144208 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.144208</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mean-field theory for disordered electron systems without interaction is
widely and successfully used to describe equilibrium properties of materials
over the whole range of disorder strengths. However, it fails to take into
account the effects of quantum coherence and information of localization.
Vertex corrections due to multiple back-scatterings may drive the electrical
conductivity to zero and make expansions around the mean field in strong
disorder problematic. Here, we present a method for the calculation of
two-particle quantities which enable us to characterize the metal-insulator
transitions (MIT) in disordered electron systems by using the Typical Medium
Dynamical Cluster Approximation (TMDCA). We show how to include vertex
corrections and the information about the mobility edge to the typical
mean-field theory. We successfully demonstrate the application of the developed
method by showing that the conductivity formulated in this way properly
characterizes the MIT in disordered systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05089</id><created>2017-01-18</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yanhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>I-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>A Computational Study of Yttria-Stabilized Zirconia: I. Using Crystal
  Chemistry to Search for the Ground State on a Glassy Energy Landscape</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Acta Mater. 127 (2017) 73-84</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.01.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Yttria-stabilized zirconia (YSZ), a ZrO2-Y2O3 solid solution that contains a
large population of oxygen vacancies, is widely used in energy and industrial
applications. Past computational studies correctly predicted the anion
diffusivity but not the cation diffusivity, which is important for material
processing and stability. One of the challenges lies in identifying a plausible
configuration akin to the ground state in a glassy landscape. This is unlikely
to come from random sampling of even a very large sample space, but the odds
are much improved by incorporating packing preferences revealed by a modest
sized configurational library established from empirical potential
calculations. Ab initio calculations corroborated these preferences, which
prove remarkably robust extending to the fifth cation-oxygen shell about 8
{\AA} away. Yet because of frustration there are still rampant violations of
packing preferences and charge neutrality in the ground state, and the approach
toward it bears a close analogy to glass relaxations. Fast relaxations proceed
by fast oxygen movement around cations, while slow relaxations require slow
cation diffusion. The latter is necessarily cooperative because of strong
coupling imposed by the long-range packing preferences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05679</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yanhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>I-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>A Computational Study of Yttria-Stabilized Zirconia: II. Cation
  Diffusion</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Acta Mater. 126 (2017) 438-450</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.01.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cubic yttria-stabilized zirconia is widely used in industrial electrochemical
devices. While its fast oxygen ion diffusion is well understood, why cation
diffusion is much slower-its activation energy (~5 eV) is 10 times that of
anion diffusion-remains a mystery. Indeed, all previous computational studies
predicted more than 5 eV is needed for forming a cation defect, and another 5
eV for moving one. In contrast, our ab initio calculations have correctly
predicted the experimentally observed cation diffusivity. We found Schottky
pairs are the dominant defects that provide cation vacancies, and their local
environments and migrating path are dictated by packing preferences. As a
cation exchanges position with a neighboring vacancy, it passes by an empty
interstitial site and severely displaces two oxygen neighbors with shortened
Zr-O distances. This causes a short-range repulsion against the migrating
cation and a long-range disturbance of the surrounding, which explains why
cation diffusion is relatively difficult. In comparison, cubic zirconia's
migrating oxygen only minimally disturbs neighboring Zr, which explains why it
is a fast oxygen conductor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06604</id><created>2017-01-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Lyutikov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames><affiliation>Purdue University, McGill University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Ultra-relativistic double explosions</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><journal-ref>Physics of Fluids 29, 047101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4977445</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider fluid dynamics of relativistic double explosion - when a point
explosion with energy $E_1$ is followed by a second explosion with energy $E_2$
after time $t_d$ (the second explosion could be in a form of a long lasting
wind). The primary explosion creates a self-similar relativistic blast wave
propagating with \Lf\ $\Gamma_1(t)$. A sufficiently strong second explosion,
with total energy $E_2 \geq 10^{-2} E_1$, creates a fast second shock in the
external fluid previously shocked by the primary shock. At times longer than
the interval between the explosions $t_d$, yet short compared with the time
when the second shock catches up the primary shock at $\sim t_d \Gamma_1^2$,
the structure of the second shock is approximately self-similar. Self-similar
structure of the second shock exist for the case of constant external density
(in this case $\Gamma_2 \propto t^{-7/3}$), but not for the wind environment.
  At early times the \Lf\ of the second shock may exceed that of the primary
shock and may boost the synchrotron emission of locally accelerated electrons
into the Fermi LAT range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07600</id><created>2017-01-26</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Yingshun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Fusan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Mei</forenames></author></authors><title>An improved design method for conventional straight dipole magnets</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>8 pages,7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The standard design method for conventional straight dipole magnets is
improved in this paper. The good field region is not symmetric with respect to
the magnet mechanical center, and its width is not enlarged to include the beam
sagitta. The integrated field quality is obtained by integrating the field
along nominal beam paths. 2D and 3D design procedures of the improved design
method are introduced, and two application examples of straight dipole magnets
are presented. It is shown that the differences in integrated field quality
between different field integration paths cannot be neglected. Compared with
the traditional design method of straight dipole magnets, the advantage of the
improved method is that the integrated field quality is accurate; the pole
width, magnet dimension and weight of a straight dipole magnet can be reduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07728</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Xun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Zhiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xianxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Xiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shancai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jiangping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yujie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>FeTe$_{1-x}$Se$_{x}$ monolayer films: towards the realization of
  high-temperature connate topological superconductivity</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Bulletin 62, 503-507 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.scib.2017.03.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We performed angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy studies on a series of
FeTe$_{1-x}$Se$_{x}$ monolayer films grown on SrTiO$_{3}$. The
superconductivity of the films is robust and rather insensitive to the
variations of the band position and effective mass caused by the substitution
of Se by Te. However, the band gap between the electron- and hole-like bands at
the Brillouin zone center decreases towards band inversion and parity exchange,
which drive the system to a nontrivial topological state predicted by
theoretical calculations. Our results provide a clear experimental indication
that the FeTe$_{1-x}$Se$_{x}$ monolayer materials are high-temperature connate
topological superconductors in which band topology and superconductivity are
integrated intrinsically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00038</id><created>2017-01-31</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>La Nave</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Form of Boundary Operators Dual to Interacting Bulk Scalar Fields
  in the AdS/CFT Correspondence</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el math.DG</categories><comments>The new submission has an extended discussion of the
  Caffarelli/Silvestre extension theorem and its application to the AdS/CFT
  correspondence</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using holographic renormalization coupled with the
Caffarelli/Silvestre\cite{caffarelli} extension theorem, we calculate the
precise form of the boundary operator dual to a bulk scalar field rather than
just its average value. We show that even in the presence of interactions in
the bulk, the boundary operator dual to a bulk scalar field is an anti-local
operator, namely the fractional Laplacian. The propagator associated with such
operators is of the general power-law (fixed by the dimension of the scalar
field) type indicative of the absence of particle-like excitations at the
Wilson-Fisher fixed point or the phenomenological unparticle construction.
Holographic renormalization also allows us to show how radial quantization can
be extended to such non-local conformal operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00623</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Sanjay K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maulik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raha</keyname><forenames>Sibaji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Syam</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of radiation background at various high altitude locations in
  preparation for rare event search in cosmic rays</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP04(2017)035</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/04/035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Various phenomenological models presented over the years have hinted at the
possible presence of strangelets, which are nuggets of Strange Quark Matter
(SQM), in cosmic rays. One way to search for such rare events is through the
deployment of large area Nuclear Track Detector (NTD) arrays at high mountain
altitudes. Before the deployment of any such array can begin, a detailed study
of the radiation background is essential. Also a proper understanding of the
response of detectors exposed to extreme weather conditions is necessary. With
that aim, pilot studies were carried out at various high altitude locations in
India such as Darjeeling (2200 m a.m.s.l), Ooty (2200 m a.m.s.l) and Hanle
(4500 m a.m.s.l). Small arrays of CR-39 as well as high threshold Polyethylene
Terephthalate (PET) detectors were given open air exposures for periods ranging
from three months to two years. The findings of such studies are reported in
this paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00964</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akbar</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical Spacelike Geometries in Static Spherically Symmetric
  Spacetimes: Generalized Painlev\`e-Gullstrand Coordinates, Foliation, and
  Embedding</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages; Journal version, minor changes</comments><msc-class>53C12, 30L05</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 769 (2017) 372</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that static spherically symmetric spacetimes can admit
foliations by flat spacelike hypersurfaces, which are best described in terms
of the Painlev\`{e}--Gullstrand coordinates. The uniqueness and existence of
such foliations were addressed earlier. In this paper, we prove, purely
geometrically, that any possible foliation of a static spherically symmetric
spacetime by an arbitrary codimension-one spherical spacelike geometry, up to
time translation and rotation, is unique, and we find the algebraic condition
under which it exists. This leads us to what can be considered as the most
natural generalization of the Painlev\`{e}--Gullstrand coordinate system for
static spherically symmetric metrics, which, in turn, makes it easy to derive
generic conclusions on foliation and to study specific cases as well as to
easily reproduce previously obtained generalizations as special cases. In
particular, we note that the existence of foliation by flat hypersurfaces
guarantees the existence of foliation by hypersurfaces whose Ricci curvature
tensor is everywhere non-positive (constant negative curvature is a special
case). The study of uniqueness and the existence concurrently solves the
question of embeddability of a spherical spacelike geometry in one-dimensional
higher static spherically symmetric spacetimes, and this produces known and new
results geometrically, without having to go through the momentum and
Hamiltonian constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01461</id><created>2017-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Lepp&#xe4;nen</keyname><forenames>Juho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenlund</keyname><forenames>Mikko</forenames></author></authors><title>A note on the finite-dimensional distributions of dispersing billiard
  processes</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><msc-class>37D20, 37A25</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s10955-017-1790-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this short note we consider the finite-dimensional distributions of sets
of states generated by dispersing billiards with a random initial condition. We
establish a functional correlation bound on the distance between the
finite-dimensional distributions and corresponding product distributions. We
demonstrate the usefulness of the bound by showing that it implies several
limit theorems. The purpose of this note is to provide a tool facilitating the
study of more general functionals of the billiard process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01904</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01904</id><created>2017-02-07</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ophus</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author></authors><title>A Fast Image Simulation Algorithm for Scanning Transmission Electron
  Microscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Image simulation for scanning transmission electron microscopy at atomic
resolution for samples with realistic dimensions can require very large
computation times using existing simulation algorithms. We present a new
algorithm named PRISM that combines features of the two most commonly used
algorithms, the Bloch wave and multislice methods. PRISM uses a Fourier
interpolation factor $f$ that has typical values of 4-20 for atomic resolution
simulations. We show that in many cases PRISM can provide a speedup that scales
with $f^4$ compared to multislice simulations, with a negligible loss of
accuracy. We demonstrate the usefulness of this method with large-scale
scanning transmission electron microscopy image simulations of a crystalline
nanoparticle on an amorphous carbon substrate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06483</id><created>2017-02-21</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rex</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Flavio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudb&#xf8;</keyname><forenames>Asle</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological staggered field-electric effect with bipartite magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 155430 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interface physics of bipartite magnetic materials deposited on a
topological insulator. This comprises antiferromagnets as well as ferrimagnets
and ferromagnets with multiple magnetic moments per unit cell. If an energy gap
is induced in the Dirac states on the topological surface, a topological
magnetoelectric effect has been predicted. Here, we show that this effect can
act in opposite directions on the two components of the magnet in certain
parameter regions. Consequently, an electric field will mainly generate a
staggered field rather than a net magnetization in the plane. This is relevant
for the current attempts to detect the magnetoelectric effect experimentally,
as well as for possible applications. We take a field-theoretic approach that
includes the quantum fluctuations of both the Dirac fermions on the topological
surface as well as the fermions in the surface layer of the magnet in an
analytically solvable model. The effective Lagrangian and the Landau-Lifshitz
equation describing the interfacial magnetization dynamics are derived.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08556</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Castillero</keyname><forenames>Paulino Monroy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yochelis</keyname><forenames>Arik</forenames></author></authors><title>Comb-like Turing patterns embedded in Hopf oscillations: Spatially
  localized states outside the 2:1 frequency locked region</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaos 27, 043110 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981394</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generic distinct mechanism for the emergence of spatially localized states
embedded in an oscillatory background is demonstrated by using 2:1 frequency
locking oscillatory system. The localization is of Turing type and appears in
two space dimensions as a comb-like state in either $\pi$ phase shifted Hopf
oscillations or inside a spiral core. Specifically, the localized states appear
in absence of the well known flip-flop dynamics (associated with collapsed
homoclinic snaking) that is known to arise in the vicinity of Hopf-Turing
bifurcation in one space dimension. Derivation and analysis of three
Hopf-Turing amplitude equations in two space dimensions reveals a local
dynamics pinning mechanism for Hopf fronts, which in turn allows the emergence
of perpendicular (to the Hopf front) Turing states. The results are shown to
agree well with the comb-like core size that forms inside spiral waves. In the
context of 2:1 resonance, these localized states form outside the 2:1 resonance
region and thus extend the frequency locking domain for spatially extended
media, such as periodically driven Belousov-Zhabotinsky chemical reactions.
Implications to chlorite-iodide-malonic-acid and shaken granular media are also
addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08702</id><created>2017-02-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Daszkiewicz</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author></authors><title>The Henon-Heiles system defined on Lie-algebraically deformed Galilei
  space-time</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Latex source, 18 pages, 8 figures, paper accepted for publication in
  MPLA. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1610.08361</comments><journal-ref>Mod.Phys.Lett. A32 (2017) 1750075</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317500754</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we provide the Henon-Heiles system defined on
Lie-algebraically deformed nonrelativistic space-time with the commutator of
two spatial directions proportional to time. Particularly, we demonstrate that
in such a model the total energy is not conserved and for this reason the role
of control parameter is taken by the initial energy value $E_{0,{\rm tot}} =
E_{{\rm tot}}(t=0)$. Besides, we show that in contrast with the commutative
case, for chosen values of deformation parameter $\kappa$, there appears chaos
in the system for initial total energies $E_{0,{\rm tot}}$ below the threshold
$E_{0,{\rm th}} = 1/6$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08839</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the $t\bar{t}$ production cross section in the $\tau$ +
  jets final state in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV using the ATLAS
  detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>37 pages in total, author list starts at page 21, 2 figures, 6
  tables, published version, all figures and tables including auxiliary figures
  are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/TOPQ-2015-18/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-288</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 072003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.072003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement of the inclusive $pp\to t\bar{t}+X$ production cross section in
the $\tau+{\rm jets}$ final state using only the hadronic decays of the $\tau$
lepton is presented. The measurement is performed using 20.2 fb$^{-1}$ of
proton-proton collision data recorded at a center-of-mass energy of
$\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV with the ATLAS detector at the Large Hadron Collider. The
cross section is measured via a counting experiment by imposing a set of
selection criteria on the identification and kinematic variables of the
reconstructed particles and jets, and on event kinematic variables and
characteristics. The production cross section is measured to be
$\sigma_{t\bar{t}}= 239 \pm 29$ pb, which is in agreement with the measurements
in other final states and the theoretical predictions at this center-of-mass
energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00310</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Timofeev</keyname><forenames>Ivan V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pankin</keyname><forenames>Pavel S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vetrov</keyname><forenames>Stepan Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arkhipkin</keyname><forenames>Vasily G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zyryanov</keyname><forenames>Victor Ya.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral Optical Tamm States: Temporal Coupled-Mode Theory</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>the text is available both in English and in Russian, reported at
  ACLC-2017 (http://aclc2017.conf.tw/)</comments><journal-ref>Crystals 7, 113 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/cryst7040113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The chiral optical Tamm state (COTS) is a special localized state at the
interface of a handedness-preserving mirror and a structurally chiral medium
such as a cholesteric liquid crystal or a chiral sculptured thin film. The
spectral behavior of COTS, observed as reflection resonances, is described by
the temporal coupled-mode theory. Mode coupling is different for two circular
light polarizations because COTS has a helix structure replicating that of the
cholesteric. The mode coupling for co-handed circularly polarized light
exponentially attenuates with the cholesteric layer thickness since the COTS
frequency falls into the stop band. Cross-handed circularly polarized light
freely goes through the cholesteric layer and can excite COTS when reflected
from the handedness-preserving mirror. The coupling in this case is
proportional to anisotropy of the cholesteric and theoretically it is only
anisotropy of magnetic permittivity that can ultimately cancel this coupling.
These two couplings being equal results in a polarization crossover (the
Kopp--Genack effect) for which a linear polarization is optimal to excite COTS.
The corresponding cholesteric thickness and scattering matrix for COTS are
generally described by simple expressions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04607</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaudenzi</keyname><forenames>Rocco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burzur&#xed;</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maegawa</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>Herre S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luis</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-enhanced Landauer erasure and storage</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The erasure of a bit of information encoded in a physical system is an
irreversible operation bound to dissipate an amount of energy $Q = k_\text{B}
T\ln 2$. As a result, work $W \geq Q$ has to be applied to the physical system
to restore the erased information content. This limit, called Landauer limit,
sets a minimal energy dissipation inherent to any classical computation. In the
pursuit of the fastest and most efficient means of computation, the ultimate
challenge is to produce a memory device executing an operation as close to this
limit in the shortest time possible. Here, we use a crystal of molecular
nanomagnets as a spin-memory device and measure the work needed to carry out a
storage operation. Exploiting a form of quantum annealing, we border the
Landauer limit while preserving fast operation. Owing to the tunable and fast
dynamics of this process, the performance of our device in terms of energy-time
cost is orders of magnitude better than existing memory devices to date. This
result suggests a way to enhance classical computations by using quantum
processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05609</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dundas</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulholland</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wardlow</keyname><forenames>Abigail</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Calle</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the role of excited states in ionization of acetylene</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><doi>10.1039/C7CP01661A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ionization of acetylene by linearly-polarized, vacuum ultraviolet (VUV) laser
pulses is modelled using time-dependent density functional theory. Several
laser wavelengths are considered including one that produces direct ionization
to the first excited cationic state while another excites the molecules to a
Rydberg series incorporating an autoionizing state. We show that for the
wavelengths and intensities considered, ionization is greatest whenever the
molecule is aligned along the laser polarization direction. By considering high
harmonic generation we show that populating excited states can lead to a large
enhancement in the harmonic yield. Lastly, angularly-resolved photoelectron
spectra are calculated which show how the energy profile of the emitted
electrons significantly changes in the presence of these excited states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08645</id><created>2017-03-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shengyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tongcang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Zhang-qi</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling librational and translational motion of a levitated
  nanoparticle in an optical cavity</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Optical Society of America B Vol. 34, Issue 6, pp.
  C8-C13 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.34.0000C8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An optically levitated nonspherical nanoparticle can exhibit both librational
and translational vibrations due to orientational and translational
confinements of the optical tweezer, respectively. Usually, the frequency of
its librational mode in a linearly-polarized optical tweezer is much larger
than the frequency of its translational mode. Because of the frequency
mismatch, the intrinsic coupling between librational and translational modes is
very weak in vacuum. Here we propose a scheme to couple its librational and
center-of-mass modes with an optical cavity mode. By adiabatically eliminating
the cavity mode, the beam splitter Hamiltonian between librational and
center-of-mass modes can be realized. We find that high-fidelity quantum state
transfer between the librational and translational modes can be achieved with
practical parameters. Our work may find applications in sympathetic cooling of
multiple modes and quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09118</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eckart</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huettemann</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiefer</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britzen</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zajacek</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laemmerzahl</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockler</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valencia-S.</keyname><forenames>Monica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karas</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Marin</keyname><forenames>Macarena</forenames></author></authors><title>The Milky Way's Supermassive Black Hole: How good a case is it? A
  Challenge for Astrophysics &amp; Philosophy of Science</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>64 pages; 13 pages of references; 13 figures; 3 tables; 4 appendices;
  With minor differences published in -Foundations of Physics- Published by
  Springer in March 2017 in Foundations of Physics, 47(5), 553-624, here
  resubmitted with extended abstract</comments><doi>10.1007/s10701-017-0079-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The compact and, with 4.3+-0.3 million solar masses, very massive object
located at the center of the Milky Way is currently the very best candidate for
a supermassive black hole (SMBH) in our immediate vicinity. The strongest
evidence for this is provided by measurements of stellar orbits, variable X-ray
emission, and strongly variable polarized near-infrared emission from the
location of the radio source Sagittarius~A* (SgrA*) in the middle of the
central stellar cluster. If SgrA* is indeed a SMBH it will, in projection onto
the sky, have the largest event horizon and will certainly be the first and
most important target of the Event Horizon Telescope (EHT) Very Long Baseline
Interferometry (VLBI) observations currently being prepared. These observations
in combination with the infrared interferometry experiment GRAVITY at the Very
Large Telescope Interferometer (VLTI) and other experiments across the
electromagnetic spectrum might yield proof for the presence of a black hole at
the center of the Milky Way. It is, however, unclear when the ever mounting
evidence for SgrA* being associated with a SMBH will suffice as a convincing
proof. Additional compelling evidence may come from future gravitational wave
observatories. This manuscript reviews the observational facts, theoretical
grounds and conceptual aspects for the case of SgrA* being a black hole. We
treat theory and observations in the framework of the philosophical discussions
about &quot;(Anti)Realism and Underdetermination&quot;, as this line of arguments allows
us to describe the situation in observational astrophysics with respect to
supermassive black holes. Questions concerning the existence of supermassive
black holes and in particular SgrA* are discussed using causation as an
indispensable element. We show that the results of our investigation are
convincingly mapped out by this combination of concepts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09591</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Reindl</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bier</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrolyte solutions at curved electrodes. I. Mesoscopic approach</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>accepted for publication in the Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 154703 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979947</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the Poisson-Boltzmann (PB) approach electrolytes in contact with
planar, spherical, and cylindrical electrodes are analyzed systematically. The
dependences of their capacitance $C$ on the surface charge density $\sigma$ and
the ionic strength $I$ are examined as function of the wall curvature. The
surface charge density has a strong effect on the capacitance for small
curvatures whereas for large curvatures the behavior becomes independent of
$\sigma$. An expansion for small curvatures gives rise to capacitance
coefficients which depend only on a single parameter, allowing for a convenient
analysis. The universal behavior at large curvatures can be captured by an
analytic expression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09661</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Reindl</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bier</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrolyte solutions at curved electrodes. II. Microscopic approach</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>accepted for publication in the Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 154704 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4979948</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density functional theory is used to describe electrolyte solutions in
contact with electrodes of planar or spherical shape. For the electrolyte
solutions we consider the so-called civilized model, in which all species
present are treated on equal footing. This allows us to discuss the features of
the electric double layer in terms of the differential capacitance. The model
provides insight into the microscopic structure of the electric double layer,
which goes beyond the mesoscopic approach studied in the accompanying paper.
This enables us to judge the relevance of microscopic details, such as the
radii of the particles forming the electrolyte solutions or the dipolar
character of the solvent particles, and to compare the predictions of various
models. Similar to the preceding paper, a general behavior is observed for
small radii of the electrode in that in this limit the results become
independent of the surface charge density and of the particle radii. However,
for large electrode radii non-trivial behaviors are observed. Especially the
particle radii and the surface charge density strongly influence the
capacitance. From the comparison with the Poisson-Boltzmann approach it becomes
apparent that the shape of the electrode determines whether the microscopic
details of the full civilized model have to be taken into account or whether
already simpler models yield acceptable predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03534</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Canbay</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaya</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketenoglu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oner</keyname><forenames>B. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultansoy</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>SppC based energy frontier lepton-proton colliders: luminosity and
  physics</title><categories>physics.acc-ph hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, 8 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, main parameters of Super proton-proton Collider (SppC) based
lepton-proton colliders are estimated. For electron beam parameters, highest
energy International Linear Collider (ILC) and Plasma Wake Field
Accelerator-Linear Collider (PWFA-LC) options are taken into account. For muon
beams, 1.5 TeV and 3 TeV center of mass energy Muon Collider parameters are
used. In addition, ultimate $\mu$p collider which assumes construction of
additional 50 TeV muon ring in the SppC tunnel is considered as well. It is
shown that $L_{ep}$ $\sim$ $10^{32}$ $cm^{-2}s^{-1}$ can be achieved with
moderate upgrade of the SppC proton beam parameters. Physics search potential
of proposed lepton-proton colliders is illustrated by considering small Bjorken
x region as an example of SM physics and resonant production of color octet
leptons as an example of BSM physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05726</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05726</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-04-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amsellem</keyname><forenames>Elsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moynier</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pringle</keyname><forenames>Emily A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouvier</keyname><forenames>Audrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Day</keyname><forenames>James M. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the chondrule-rich accretion model for planetary embryos using
  calcium isotopes</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>39 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables 1 supplementary material (1 table)</comments><report-no>EPSL14417</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.epsl.2017.04.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the composition of raw materials that formed the Earth is a
crucial step towards understanding the formation of terrestrial planets and
their bulk composition. Calcium is the fifth most abundant element in
terrestrial planets and, therefore, is a key element with which to trace
planetary composition. However, in order to use Ca isotopes as a tracer of
Earth's accretion history, it is first necessary to understand the isotopic
behavior of Ca during the earliest stages of planetary formation. Chondrites
are some of the oldest materials of the Solar System, and the study of their
isotopic composition enables understanding of how and in what conditions the
Solar System formed. Here we present Ca isotope data for a suite of bulk
chondrites as well as Allende (CV) chondrules. We show that most groups of
carbonaceous chondrites (CV, CI, CR and CM) are significantly enriched in the
lighter Ca isotopes ($\delta^{44/40}Ca$ = +0.1 to +0.93 permill) compared with
bulk silicate Earth ($\delta^{44/40}Ca$ = +1.05 $\pm$ 0.04 permill, Huang et
al., 2010) or Mars, while enstatite chondrites are indistinguishable from Earth
in Ca isotope composition ($\delta^{44/40}Ca$ = +0.91 to +1.06 permill).
Chondrules from Allende are enriched in the heavier isotopes of Ca compared to
the bulk and the matrix of the meteorite ($\delta^{44/40}Ca$ = +1.00 to +1.21
permill). This implies that Earth and Mars have Ca isotope compositions that
are distinct from most carbonaceous chondrites but that may be like chondrules.
This Ca isotopic similarity between Earth, Mars, and chondrules is permissive
of recent dynamical models of planetary formation that propose a chondrule-rich
accretion model for planetary embryos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06284</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Greg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peshier</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-shear QCD plasma from perturbation theory</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that the phenomenologically inferred ratio of shear viscosity to
entropy density of the quark-gluon plasma, $\eta/\s &lt; 0.5$ near the
deconfinement temperature $T_c$, can be understood from perturbative QCD. To
rebut the widespread, opposite view we first show that, and why, the existing
leading order result in (fixed) coupling should not be further expanded in
logarithms. Emphasizing then that the resummation mandatory for screening also
settles the often neglected question of scale setting for the running coupling,
we establish a temperature dependence of $\eta/\s$ which agrees well with
constraints from hydrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06291</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wilming</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goihl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krumnow</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards local equilibration in closed interacting quantum many-body
  systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the main questions of research on quantum many-body systems following
unitary out of equilibrium dynamics is to find out how local expectation values
equilibrate in time. For non-interacting models, this question is rather well
understood. However, the best known bounds for general quantum systems are
vastly crude, scaling unfavorable with the system size. Nevertheless, empirical
and numerical evidence suggests that for generic interacting many-body systems,
generic local observables, and sufficiently well-behaved states, the
equilibration time does not depend strongly on the system size, but only the
precision with which this occurs does. In this discussion paper, we aim at
giving very simple and plausible arguments for why this happens. While our
discussion does not yield rigorous results about equilibration time scales, we
believe that it helps to clarify the essential underlying mechanisms, the
intuition and important figure of merits behind equilibration. We then connect
our arguments to common assumptions and numerical results in the field of
equilibration and thermalization of closed quantum systems, such as the
eigenstate thermalization hypothesis as well as rigorous results on interacting
quantum many-body systems. Finally, we complement our discussions with
numerical results - both in the case of examples and counter-examples of
equilibrating systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06308</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Close</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pittard</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamic ablation of protoplanetary disks via supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures, 2 tables, accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx897</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present three-dimensional simulations of a protoplanetary disk subject to
the effect of a nearby (0.3pc distant) supernova, using a time-dependent flow
from a one dimensional numerical model of the supernova remnant (SNR), in
addition to constant peak ram pressure simulations. Simulations are performed
for a variety of disk masses and inclination angles. We find disk mass-loss
rates that are typically 1e-7 to 1e-6 Msol/yr (but peak near 1e-5 Msol/yr
during the &quot;instantaneous&quot; stripping phase) and are sustained for around 200
yr. Inclination angle has little effect on the mass loss unless the disk is
close to edge-on. Inclined disks also strip asymmetrically with the trailing
edge ablating more easily. Since the interaction lasts less than one outer
rotation period, there is not enough time for the disk to restore its symmetry,
leaving the disk asymmetrical after the flow has passed. Of the low-mass disks
considered, only the edge-on disk is able to survive interaction with the SNR
(with 50% of its initial mass remaining). At the end of the simulations, disks
that survive contain fractional masses of SN material up to 5e-6. This is too
low to explain the abundance of short-lived radionuclides in the early solar
system, but a larger disk and the inclusion of radiative cooling might allow
the disk to capture a higher fraction of SN material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06313</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pinho</keyname><forenames>A. M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>C. J. A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining spatial variations of the fine-structure constant in
  symmetron models</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Phys. Lett. B (in press)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a methodology to test models with spatial variations of the
fine-structure constant $\alpha$, based on the calculation of the angular power
spectrum of these measurements. This methodology enables comparisons of
observations and theoretical models through their predictions on the statistics
of the $\alpha$ variation. Here we apply it to the case of symmetron models. We
find no indications of deviations from the standard behavior, with current data
providing an upper limit to the strength of the symmetron coupling to gravity
($\log{\beta^2}&lt;-0.9$) when this is the only free parameter, and not able to
constrain the model when also the symmetry breaking scale factor $a_{SSB}$ is
free to vary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06316</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>McComas</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zirnstein</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bzowski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dayeh</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Funsten</keyname><forenames>H. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuselier</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janzen</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubiak</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kucharek</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;bius</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reisenfeld</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwadron</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sok&#xf3;&#x142;</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szalay</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokumaru</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seven Years of Imaging the Global Heliosphere with IBEX</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Pre-print, 59 pages, 33 figures, published in ApJS</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, 229:41 (32pp), 2017
  April</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4365/aa66d8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Interstellar Boundary Explorer (IBEX) has now operated in space for 7
years and returned nearly continuous observations that have led to scientific
discoveries and reshaped our entire understanding of the outer heliosphere and
its interaction with the local interstellar medium. Here we extend prior work,
adding the 2014-2015 data for the first time, and examine, validate, initially
analyze, and provide a complete 7-year set of Energetic Neutral Atom (ENA)
observations from ~0.1 to 6 keV. The data, maps, and documentation provided
here represent the 10th major release of IBEX data and include improvements to
various prior corrections to provide the citable reference for the current
version of IBEX data. We are now able to study time variations in the outer
heliosphere and interstellar interaction over more than half a solar cycle. We
find that the Ribbon has evolved differently than the globally distributed flux
(GDF), with a leveling off and partial recovery of ENAs from the GDF, owing to
solar wind output flattening and recovery. The Ribbon has now also lost its
latitudinal ordering, which reflects the breakdown of solar minimum solar wind
conditions and exhibits a greater time delay than for the surrounding GDF.
Together, the IBEX observations strongly support a secondary ENA source for the
Ribbon, and we suggest that this be adopted as the nominal explanation of the
Ribbon going forward.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06323</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashby</keyname><forenames>Neil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Judah</forenames></author></authors><title>Incorporating an Optical Clock into a Time Scale</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses how to build a time scale with an
intermittently-operated optical clock. In particular, it gives suggestions on
how long and how often to run an optical clock. It also explores the benefits
of having an optical clock in a time scale, by comparing with the current
UTC(NIST) performance and the time scale with a continuously-operated Cs
fountain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06330</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06330</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Miyahara</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grutter</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipation modulated Kelvin probe force microscopy method</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>Chapter of the forthcoming book &quot;Kelvin probe force microscopy - From
  single charge detection to device characterization&quot; edited by Sascha
  Sadewasser and Thilo Glatzel</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review a new implementation of Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) in
which the dissipation signal of frequency modulation atomic force microscopy
(FM-AFM) is used for dc bias voltage feedback (D-KPFM). The dissipation arises
from an oscillating electrostatic force that is coherent with the tip
oscillation, which is caused by applying the ac voltage between the tip and
sample. The magnitude of the externally induced dissipation is found to be
proportional to the effective dc bias voltage, which is the difference between
the applied dc voltage and the contact potential difference. Two different
implementations of D-KPFM are presented. In the first implementation, the
frequency of the applied ac voltage, $f_\mathrm{el}$, is chosen to be the same
as the tip oscillation ($f_\mathrm{el} = f_\mathrm{m}$: $1\omega$D-KPFM). In
the second one, the ac voltage frequency, $f_\mathrm{el}$, is chosen to be
twice the tip oscillation frequency ($f_\mathrm{el}= 2 f_\mathrm{m}$:
$2\omega$D-KPFM). In $1\omega$D-KPFM, the dissipation is proportional to the
electrostatic force, which enables the use of a small ac voltage amplitude even
down to $\approx 10$\,mV. In $2\omega$D-KPFM, the dissipation is proportional
to the electrostatic force gradient, which results in the same potential
contrast as that obtained by FM-KPFM. D-KPFM features a simple implementation
with no lock-in amplifier and faster scanning as it requires no low frequency
modulation. The use of a small ac voltage amplitude in $1\omega$D-KPFM is of
great importance in characterizing of technically relevant materials in which
their electrical properties can be disturbed by the applied electric field.
$2\omega$D-KPFM is useful when more accurate potential measurement is required.
The operations in $1\omega$ and $2\omega$D-KPFM can be switched easily to take
advantage of both features at the same location on a sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06338</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Huck</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>Beam Energy Dependence of Dielectron Production in Au+Au Collisions from
  STAR at RHIC</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>206 pages; to be published in library of Goethe University Frankfurt
  am Main</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Enabled by the addition of a TOF detector system in 2010, the first phase of
the Beam Energy Scan (BES-I) at RHIC allows STAR to conduct an unprecedented
energy-dependent study of dielectron production within a homogeneous
experimental environment, and hence close the wide gap in the QCD phase diagram
between SPS and top RHIC energies. This thesis concentrates on the
understanding of the LMR enhancement regarding its $M_{ee}$, $p_{T}$ and energy
dependence. It studies dielectron production in Au+Au collisions at beam
energies of 19.6, 27, 39, and 62.4 GeV with sufficient statistics. In
conjunction with the published STAR results at top RHIC energy, this thesis
presents results on the first comprehensive energy-dependent study of
dielectron production.
  The comparison of $M_{ee}$- and $p_{T}$-spectra with cocktail simulations of
hadronic sources reveals a sizeable and steadily increasing excess yield in the
LMR at all beam energies. The scenario of broadened in-medium $\rho$ spectral
functions proves to not only serve well as dominating underlying source but
also to be universal in nature since it quantitatively and qualitatively
explains the LMR enhancements from SPS to top RHIC energies. It shows that most
of the enhancement is governed by interactions of the $\rho$ meson with thermal
resonance excitations in the late(r)-stage hot and dense hadronic phase. This
conclusion is supported by the energy-dependent measurement of integrated LMR
excess yields and enhancement factors. The former do not exhibit a strong
dependence on beam energy as expected from the approximately constant total
baryon density above 20 GeV, and the latter show agreement with the CERES
measurement at SPS energy. The consistency in excess yields and agreement with
model calculations over the wide RHIC energy regime makes a strong case for LMR
enhancements on the order of a factor 2-3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06350</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Crump</keyname><forenames>Iain</forenames></author></authors><title>Graph Invariants with Connections to the Feynman Period in $\phi^4$
  Theory</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>101 pages, Dissertation Submitted in Partial Fulfillment of the
  Requirements for the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy</comments><msc-class>81T18, 05C21, 05C31</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Feynman diagrams in $\phi^4$ theory have as their underlying structure
4-regular graphs. In particular, any 4-point $\phi^4$ graph can be uniquely
derived from a 4-regular graph by deleting a vertex. The Feynman period is a
simplified version of the Feynman integral, and is of special interest, as it
maintains much of the important number theoretic information from the Feynman
integral. It is also of structural interest, as it is known to be preserved by
a number of graph theoretic operations. In particular, the vertex deleted in
constructing the 4-point graph does not affect the Feynman period, and it is
invariant under planar duality and the Schnetz twist, an operation that
redirects edges incident to a 4-vertex cut. Further, a 4-regular graph may be
produced by a 3-sum operation on triangles in two 4-regular graphs. The Feynman
period of this graph with a vertex deleted is equal to the product of the
Feynman periods of the two smaller graphs with one vertex deleted each. These
operations currently explain all known instances of non-isomorphic 4-point
$\phi^4$ graphs with equal periods.
  With this in mind, other graph invariants that are preserved by these
operations for 4-point $\phi^4$ graphs are of interest, as they may provide
insight into the Feynman period. In this thesis the extended graph permanent is
introduced; an infinite sequence of residues from prime order finite fields. It
is shown that this sequence is preserved by these three operations, and has a
product property. Additionally, computational techniques will be established,
and an alternate interpretation will be presented as the point count of a novel
graph polynomial.
  Further, the previously existing $c_2$ invariant and Hepp bound are examined,
two graph invariants that are conjectured to be preserved by these graph
operations. A combinatorial approach to the $c_2$ invariant is introduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06362</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf6;bel</keyname><forenames>Carla</forenames></author></authors><title>Charm Physics and CKM</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>Invited talk given at the 9th International Workshop on the CKM
  Unitarity Triangle (CKM 2016), Tata Institute for Fundamental Research
  (TIFR), Mumbai (India), 28 Nov - 2 Dec 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An overview of the most important progresses in charm physics since the last
CKM Workshop (2014) is presented. Due emphasis is given to the experimental
measurements directly related to the CKM matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06364</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Christodoulou</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laycock</keyname><forenames>S. G. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazanas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Retrograde Accretion Disks in High-Mass Be/X-ray Binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To appear in MNRAS Letters</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have compiled a comprehensive library of all X-ray observations of
Magellanic pulsars carried out by {\it XMM-Newton}, {\it Chandra}, and {\it
RXTE} in the period 1997-2014. In this work, we use the data from 53 high-mass
Be/X-ray binaries in the Small Magellanic Cloud to demonstrate that the
distribution of spin-period derivatives vs. spin periods of spinning-down
pulsars is not at all different than that of the accreting spinning-up pulsars.
The inescapable conclusion is that the up and down samples were drawn from the
same continuous parent population, therefore Be/X-ray pulsars that are spinning
down over periods spanning 18 years are in fact accreting from retrograde
disks. The presence of prograde and retrograde disks in roughly equal numbers
supports a new evolutionary scenario for Be/X-ray pulsars in their spin
period-period derivative diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06365</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Rotta</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sebastiano</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charbon</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prati</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum information density scaling and qubit operation time constraints
  of CMOS silicon based quantum computer architectures</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Even the quantum simulation of simple molecules such as Fe$_2$S$_2$ requires
more than 10$^6$ qubits. In order to assess such a multimillion scale of
identical qubits and control lines, the silicon platform seems to be one of the
most indicated routes as it provides the capability of nanometric, serial and
industrial quality fabrication. The maximum amount of quantum information per
unit surface and the consequent space constraints on qubit operations are key
parameters towards fault-tolerant quantum information processing (QIP) with Si
qubits. Such maximum density of quantum information is expressed for the
compact exchange-only Si double quantum dot qubit architecture as a function of
the CMOS technology node. The size scale optimizing both physical qubit
operation time and quantum error correction (QEC) requirements is assessed by
reviewing the physical and technological constraints. We determine the workable
operation frequency range of a Si-CMOS quantum processor to be within 1 and 100
GHz, which limits its feasibility only to the most advanced nodes. The
compatibility with classical control circuitry is discussed, focusing on the
cryogenic CMOS operation required to bring the classical controller as close as
possible to the quantum processor and to enable interfacing thousands of qubits
on the same chip. The operation time range prospected for cryogenic control
electronics is found to be compatible with the qubit operation time. By
combining the forecast of technology development with operation time and
classical circuitry constraints, we derive a maximum quantum information
density for logical qubits of 2.8 and 4 Mqb/cm$^2$ for the 10-nm and 7-nm
technology nodes respectively for the Steane code. The density is one and two
orders of magnitude less for surface and concatenated codes respectively. Such
values provide a benchmark for the development of Si-based fault tolerant QIP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06367</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Marcolli</keyname><forenames>Matilde</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author></authors><title>q-deformations of statistical mechanical systems and motives over finite
  fields</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>25 pages, LaTeX</comments><msc-class>13F35, 11M38, 82B10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider q-deformations of Witt rings, based on geometric operations on
zeta functions of motives over finite fields, and we use these deformations to
construct q-analogs of the Bost-Connes quantum statistical mechanical system.
We show that the q-deformations obtained in this way can be related to Habiro
ring constructions of analytic functions over the field with one element and to
categorifications of Bost-Connes systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06372</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pogna</keyname><forenames>Eva A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsili</keyname><forenames>Margherita</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Fazio</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conte</keyname><forenames>Stefano Dal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzoni</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangalli</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Duhee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lombardo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>Andrea C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerullo</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prezzi</keyname><forenames>Deborah</forenames></author></authors><title>Photo-Induced Bandgap Renormalization Governs the Ultrafast Response of
  Single-Layer MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>This document is the Accepted Manuscript version of a Published Work
  that appeared in final form in ACS Nano after peer review and technical
  editing by the publisher. To access the final edited and published work see:
  http://pubs.acs.org/articlesonrequest/AOR-fcCuTYn5m6wiDTIg98Kx</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano 10, 1182 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.5b06488</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) are emerging as promising
two-dimensional (2d) semiconductors for optoelectronic and flexible devices.
However, a microscopic explanation of their photophysics -- of pivotal
importance for the understanding and optimization of device operation -- is
still lacking. Here we use femtosecond transient absorption spectroscopy, with
pump pulse tunability and broadband probing, to monitor the relaxation dynamics
of single-layer MoS2 over the entire visible range, upon photoexcitation of
different excitonic transitions. We find that, irrespective of excitation
photon energy, the transient absorption spectrum shows the simultaneous
bleaching of all excitonic transitions and corresponding red-shifted
photoinduced absorption bands. First-principle modeling of the ultrafast
optical response reveals that a transient bandgap renormalization, caused by
the presence of photo-excited carriers, is primarily responsible for the
observed features. Our results demonstrate the strong impact of many-body
effects in the transient optical response of TMDs even in the
low-excitation-density regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06373</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Della Pia</keyname><forenames>Ada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avvisati</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ourdjini</keyname><forenames>Oualid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varsano</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prezzi</keyname><forenames>Deborah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferretti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Betti</keyname><forenames>Maria Grazia</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic Structure Evolution during the Growth of Graphene Nanoribbons
  on Au(110)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This document is the Accepted Manuscript version of a Published Work
  that appeared in final form in J. Phys. Chem C after peer review and
  technical editing by the publisher. To access the final edited and published
  work see: http://pubsdc3.acs.org/articlesonrequest/AOR-IB49uBxIS3X6JdF3ieQ9</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C 120, 7323 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b11884</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface-assisted polymerization of molecular monomers into extended chains
can be used as the seed of graphene nanoribbon (GNR) formation, resulting from
a subsequent cyclo-dehydrogenation process. By means of valence-band
photoemission and ab-initio density-functional theory (DFT) calculations, we
investigate the evolution of molecular states from monomer
10,10'-dibromo-9,9'bianthracene (DBBA) precursors to polyanthryl polymers, and
eventually to GNRs, as driven by the Au(110) surface. The molecular orbitals
and the energy level alignment at the metal-organic interface are studied in
depth for the DBBA precursors deposited at room temperature. On this basis, we
can identify a spectral fingerprint of C-Au interaction in both DBBA
single-layer and polymerized chains obtained upon heating. Furthermore, DFT
calculations help us evidencing that GNRs interact more strongly than DBBA and
polyanthryl with the Au(110) substrate, as a result of their flatter
conformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06389</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iskandar</keyname><forenames>Kholmanov</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Er</keyname><forenames>Dequan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Weibing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Zehua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shenoy</keyname><forenames>Vivek B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Janus Monolayer Transition Metal Dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel crystal configuration of sandwiched S-Mo-Se structure (Janus SMoSe)
at the monolayer limit has been synthesized and carefully characterized in this
work. By controlled sulfurization of monolayer MoSe2 the top layer of selenium
atoms are substituted by sulfur atoms while the bottom selenium layer remains
intact. The peculiar structure of this new material is systematically
investigated by Raman, photoluminescence and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy
and confirmed by transmission-electron microscopy and time-of-flight secondary
ion mass spectrometry. Density-functional theory calculations are performed to
better understand the Raman vibration modes and electronic structures of the
Janus SMoSe monolayer, which are found to correlate well with corresponding
experimental results. Finally, high basal plane hydrogen evolution reaction
(HER) activity is discovered for the Janus monolayer and DFT calculation
implies that the activity originates from the synergistic effect of the
intrinsic defects and structural strain inherent in the Janus structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06391</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yujia</forenames><affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Technology and Systems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames><affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Technology and Systems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames><affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Technology and Systems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Yulong</forenames><affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Technology and Systems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jingdong</forenames><affiliation>Key Laboratory of Optoelectronic Technology and Systems</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical-controlled wavelength-tunable Q-switched mode-locked fiber laser
  based on graphene-deposited micro-FBG</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a wavelength-tunable Q-switched mode-locked fiber laser based on a
compact optical tuning device, which is fabricated by coating single-layer
graphene on the surface of micro-fiber Bragg grating (MFBG). Based on
thermal-optical effect through evanescent interaction between graphene and
MFBG, the center wavelength of MFBG can be accurately controlled by adjusting
power of an external laser. By inserting the fabricated device into a compact
fiber laser cavity mode-locked by single-wall carbon nanotubes, stable
Q-switched mode-locked pulse is generated. Experimental results show that the
wavelength can be precisely optical-tuned from 1550.1 nm to 1551.9 nm with a
linear sensitivity of 6.3 pm/mW. Such an optical-controlled wavelength-tunable
Q-switched mode-locked fiber laser may find potential applications in
all-optical computing, all-optical logic gating and generation of microwave
source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06407</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06407</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsukioka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakada</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical and numerical assessment of accuracy of the approximated
  nuclear symmetry energy in the Hartree-Fock theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures (each has 2 panels)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nuclear symmetry energy is defined by the second derivative of the energy
per nucleon with respect to the proton-neutron asymmetry, and is sometimes
approximated by the energy difference between the neutron matter and the
symmetric matter. Accuracy of this approximation is assessed analytically and
numerically, within the Hartree-Fock theory using effective interactions. By
decomposing the nuclear-matter energy, the relative error of each term is
expressed analytically; it is constant or is a single-variable function
determined by the function type. The full errors are evaluated for several
effective interactions, by inserting values of the parameters. Although the
errors stay within $10\%$ up to twice of the normal density irrespective of the
interactions, at higher densities accuracy of the approximation significantly
depends on the interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06425</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Marinkovic</keyname><forenames>Marina Krstic</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice calculations and the muon anomalous magnetic moment</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 table, 2 figures, invited talk presented at Light Cone
  2016, September 5-8, 2016. Accepted for publication in Few-Body Systems
  (Light-Cone 2016, Topical Collection)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anomalous magnetic moment of the muon, $a_{\mu}=(g_{\mu}-2)/2$, is one of the
most precisely measured quantities in particle physics and it provides a
stringent test of the Standard Model. The planned improvements of the
experimental precision at Fermilab and at J-PARC propel further reduction of
the theoretical uncertainty of $a_{\mu}$. The hope is that the efforts on both
sides will help resolve the current discrepancy between the experimental
measurement of $a_{\mu}$ and its theoretical prediction, and potentially gain
insight into new physics. The dominant sources of the uncertainty in the
theoretical prediction of $a_{\mu}$ are the errors of the hadronic
contributions. I will discuss recent progress on determination of hadronic
contributions to $a_{\mu}$ from lattice calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06433</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Randall</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Three dimensional near-horizon metrics that are Einstein-Weyl</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><msc-class>53B15, 53B30 (primary), 83C57 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate which three dimensional near-horizon metrics $g_{NH}$ admit a
compatible 1-form $X$ such that $(X, [g_{NH}])$ defines an Einstein-Weyl
structure. We find explicit examples and see that some of the solutions give
rise to Einstein-Weyl structures of dispersionless KP type and dispersionless
Hirota (aka hyperCR) type.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06435</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Narimanov</keyname><forenames>Evgenii</forenames></author></authors><title>Ghost Waves in Anisotropic Materials: negative refractive index and
  evanescent field enhancement in lossless media</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that transparent dielectrics with strong optical anisotropy support a
new class of electromagnetic waves that combine the properties of propagating
and evanescent fields. These &quot;ghost waves&quot; are created in tangent bifurcations
that &quot;annihilate&quot; pairs of positive- and negative-index modes, and represent
the optical analogue of the &quot;ghost orbits&quot; in the quantum theory of
non-integrable dynamical systems. Similarly to the regular evanescent fields,
ghost waves support high transverse wavenumbers, but in addition to the
exponential decay show oscillatory behavior in the direction of propagation.
Ghost waves can be resonantly coupled to the incident evanescent waves, which
then grow exponentially through the anisotropic media - as in the case of
negative index materials.As ghost waves are supported by transparent dielectric
media, they are free from the &quot;curse&quot; of material loss that is inherent to
conventional negative index composites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06441</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mokdad</keyname><forenames>Mokdad</forenames></author></authors><title>Decay of Maxwell Fields on Reissner-Nordstr{\o}m-de Sitter Black Holes</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>57 page, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:0710.4102, arXiv:1206.0272 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we use Morawetz estimates with geometric energy estimates -the
so-called vector field method- to prove decay results for the Maxwell field in
the static exterior region of the Reissner-Nordstr{\o}m-de Sitter black hole.
We prove two types of decay: The first is a uniform decay of the energy of the
Maxwell field on achronal hypersurfaces as the hypersurfaces approach timelike
infinities. The second decay result is a pointwise decay in time with a rate of
$t^{-1}$ which follows from local energy decay by Sobolev estimates. Both
results are consequences of bounds on the conformal energy defined by the
Morawetz conformal vector field. These bounds are obtained through wave
analysis on the middle spin component of the field. The results hold for a more
general class of spherically symmetric spacetimes with the same arguments used
in this paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06449</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Teranishi</keyname><forenames>Shingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyao</keyname><forenames>Satoaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishiguchi</keyname><forenames>Kazutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusakabe</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author></authors><title>An enhancement mechanism of two-particle exchange interactions in
  single- and multi-layer cuprate superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, to be submitted in Journal of the Physical
  Society of Japan</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To explore material dependence of layered cuprate superconductors, we examine
effective two-particle interactions for Hg1201 and Tl1201, where Tl1201 having
a nearly half value of Tc of Hg1201 even at the optimal oxygen concentration.
Although the 3dx_2-y_2 band, the Fermi surface, and its Wannier-orbitals are
similar for these superconductors, there is an apparent difference in the
unoccupied levels above EF. Based on a multi-reference
density-functional-theory formulation, effective two-particle exchange
interactions are estimated to derive enhancement in intra-layer exchange
interactions for HgBa2CuO4, while it is weakened in TlBaLaCuO5 and furthermore
it is weak in TlBa2CuO5. The characteristic difference in the band structure is
correlated with oxygen contents in the buffer layer. We also comment on the
similar feature in triple-layered compounds. Our spin-fluctuation enhancement
mechanism in an electron-correlation regime is consistent with the experimental
fact.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06457</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Voyant</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames><affiliation>SPE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Julian</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames><affiliation>CHD Castellucio</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Short Synthesis Concerning Biological Effects and Equivalent Doses in
  Radiotherapy</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1308.5906</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Radiology and Oncology, heighten science, 2017, 1,
  pp.39 - 45</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has long been known that radiation biology plays an important role and it
is necessary for radiotherapy treatments. The radiation effects on normal and
malignant tissues after exposure range from a femtosecond to months and years
thereafter [1,2]. Therefore, to optimize treatment, it is crucial to explain
and understand these mechanisms [3-5]. Providing a conceptual basis for
radiotherapy and identifying the mechanisms and processes that underlie the
tumor and normal tissue responses to irradiation can help to explain the
observed phenomena [6]. Examples include understanding hypoxia, reoxygenation,
tumor cell repopulation, or the mechanisms of repair of DNA damage [3,7,8]. The
different biological effects of radiation should be divided into several
phases: physical (interaction between charged particles and tissue atoms),
chemical (the period during which the damaged atoms and molecules react with
other cellular components in rapid chemical reactions), and biological (impact
of the generated lesions on the biological tissue [4]). The following section
describes the models most often used in radiotherapy. These are simplistic
models that actual treatments are based, and that are validated and approved
[9-12].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06458</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>de Le&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sard&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A geometric Hamilton--Jacobi theory on a Nambu-Jacobi manifold</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we propose a geometric Hamilton--Jacobi theory on a
Nambu--Jacobi manifold. The advantange of a geometric Hamilton--Jacobi theory
is that if a Hamiltonian vector field $X_H$ can be projected into a
configuration manifold by means of a one-form $dW$, then the integral curves of
the projected vector field $X_H^{dW}$ can be transformed into integral curves
of the vector field $X_H$ provided that $W$ is a solution of the
Hamilton--Jacobi equation. This procedure allows us to reduce the dynamics to a
lower dimensional manifold in which we integrate the motion. On the other hand,
the interest of a Nambu--Jacobi structure resides in its role in the
description of dynamics in terms of several Hamiltonian functions. It appears
in fluid dynamics, for instance. Here, we derive an explicit expression for a
geometric Hamilton--Jacobi equation on a Nambu--Jacobi manifold and apply it to
the third-order Riccati differential equation as an example.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06463</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Mac&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jagannathan</keyname><forenames>Anuradha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pi&#xe9;chon</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Gap structure of 1D cut and project Hamiltonians</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>Issued for the 13th International Conference on Quasicrystals (ICQ13)</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/809/1/012023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the gap properties of nearest neighbors tight binding models on
quasiperiodic chains. We argue that two kind of gaps should be distinguished:
stable and transient. We show that stable gaps have a well defined
quasiperiodic limit. We also show that there is a direct relation between the
gap size and the gap label.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06471</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Moiseev</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moiseev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>All-optical photon echo and memory on a chip</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Laser Phys. Lett. 14 015202 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1612-202X/aa4fc2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that a photon echo can be implemented by all-optical means
using an array of on-chip high-finesse ring cavities whose parameters are
chirped in such a way as to support equidistant spectra of cavity modes. When
launched into such a system, a classical or quantum optical signal -- even a
single-photon field -- becomes distributed between individual cavities, giving
rise to prominent coherence echo revivals at well-defined delay times,
controlled by the chirp of cavity parameters. This effect enables long storage
times for high-throughput broadband optical delay and quantum memory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06475</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Santucci</keyname><forenames>Enrica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sergioli</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Classification Problem in a Quantum Framework</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to provide a quantum counterpart of the well known
minimum-distance classifier named Nearest Mean Classifier (NMC). In particular,
we refer to the following previous works: i) in Sergioli et al. 2016, we have
introduced a detailed quantum version of the NMC, named Quantum Nearest Mean
Classifier (QNMC), for two-dimensional problems and we have proposed a
generalization to abitrary dimensions; ii) in Sergioli et al. 2017, the
n-dimensional problem was analyzed in detail and a particular encoding for
arbitrary n-feature vectors into density operators has been presented. In this
paper, we introduce a new promizing encoding of arbitrary n-dimensional
patterns into density operators, starting from the two-feature encoding
provided in the first work. Further, unlike the NMC, the QNMC shows to be not
invariant by rescaling the features of each pattern. This property allows us to
introduce a free parameter whose variation provides, in some case, an
improvement of the QNMC performance. We show experimental results where: i) the
NMC and QNMC performances are compared on different datasets; ii) the effects
of the non-invariance under uniform rescaling for the QNMC are investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06476</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Donges</keyname><forenames>Jonathan F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucht</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller-Hansen</keyname><forenames>Finn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steffen</keyname><forenames>Will</forenames></author></authors><title>The technosphere in Earth system analysis: a coevolutionary perspective</title><categories>physics.soc-ph nlin.AO</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Anthropocene Review 4(1), 23-33, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1177/2053019616676608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Earth system analysis is the study of the joint dynamics of biogeophysical,
social and technological processes on our planet. To advance our understanding
of possible future development pathways and identify management options for
navigating to safe operating spaces while avoiding undesirable domains,
computer models of the Earth system are developed and applied. These models
hardly represent dynamical properties of technological processes despite their
great planetary-scale influence on the biogeophysical components of the Earth
system and the associated risks for human societies posed, e.g., by climatic
change or novel entities. In this contribution, we reflect on the technosphere
from the perspective of Earth system analysis with a threefold focus on agency,
networks and complex coevolutionary dynamics. First, we argue that Haff's
conception of the technosphere takes an extreme position in implying a strongly
constrained human agency in the Earth system. Assuming that the technosphere
develops according to dynamics largely independently of human intentions,
Haff's perspective appears incompatible with a humanistic view that underlies
the sustainability discourse at large and, more specifically, current
frameworks such as UN sustainable development goals and the safe and just
operating space for humanity. Second, as an alternative to Haff's static
three-stratum picture, we propose complex adaptive networks as a concept for
describing the interplay of social agents and technospheric entities and their
emergent dynamics for Earth system analysis. Third, we argue that following a
coevolutionary approach in conceptualising and modelling technospheric
dynamics, also including the socio-cultural and biophysical spheres of the
Earth system, could resolve the apparent conflict between the discourses on
sustainability and the technosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06480</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Fayyazuddin</keyname></author></authors><title>Two Body Hadronic Decays $\Lambda_{b}(\frac{1}{2}^{+})\rightarrow
  B^{\ast}(\frac{3}{2}^{+})+P$ in a quark model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>No Figure, 10 pages, A version that appeared in the Physics Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D95 (2017) no.5, 053008</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The framework under which decays $\Lambda_{b}(\frac{1}{2}^{+})\rightarrow
B(\frac{1}{2}^{+})+M$ are analyzed is not applicable for the decays
$\Lambda_{b}(\frac{1}{2}^{+})\rightarrow B^{\ast}(\frac{3}{2} ^{+})+M$. These
decays occur through a baryon pole $\Sigma^{0}_{c}$ which is generated by the
W-exchange diagram in the process $b+u \xrightarrow {W} c+d$. The effective
Hamiltonian which arises from the W-exchange diagram is expressed in the non
relativistic limit. Since $% \Sigma^{0}_{c}$ belongs to representation $6$ of
SU(3), it contributes to two sets of decays:
$\Lambda_{b}\rightarrow\Delta^{0}D^{0},\Delta^{-}D^{+},% \Sigma^{*-}D_s^{+}$
and $\Lambda_{b}\rightarrow\Sigma^{\ast-}_{c}\pi^{+},%
  \Sigma^{\ast 0}_{c}\pi^{0}\;, \Xi^{\ast 0}_{c}K^{0}$. The branching ratios
for these decays are evaluated which can be compared with their experimental
values when the data become available. Other prediction of the model is that
asymmetry parameter $\alpha = 0$, since baryon pole contributes to parity
conserving (p-wave) amplitude and does not contribute to parity violating
(d-wave) amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06482</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Matlovi&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>Pavol</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf3;th</keyname><forenames>Juraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudawska</keyname><forenames>Regina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korno&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Leonard</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra and physical properties of Taurid meteoroids</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2017.02.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Taurids are an extensive stream of particles produced by comet 2P/Encke,
which can be observed mainly in October and November as a series of meteor
showers rich in bright fireballs. Several near-Earth asteroids have also been
linked with the meteoroid complex, and recently the orbits of two carbonaceous
meteorites were proposed to be related to the stream, raising interesting
questions about the origin of the complex and the composition of 2P/Encke. Our
aim is to investigate the nature and diversity of Taurid meteoroids by studying
their spectral, orbital, and physical properties determined from video meteor
observations. Here we analyze 33 Taurid meteor spectra captured during the
predicted outburst in November 2015 by stations in Slovakia and Chile,
including 14 multi-station observations for which the orbital elements,
material strength parameters, dynamic pressures, and mineralogical densities
were determined. It was found that while orbits of the 2015 Taurids show
similarities with several associated asteroids, the obtained spectral and
physical characteristics point towards cometary origin with highly
heterogeneous content. Observed spectra exhibited large dispersion of iron
content and significant Na intensity in all cases. The determined material
strengths are typically cometary in the $K_B$ classification, while $P_E$
criterion is on average close to values characteristic for carbonaceous bodies.
The studied meteoroids were found to break up under low dynamic pressures of
0.02 - 0.10 MPa, and were characterized by low mineralogical densities of 1.3 -
2.5 g cm$^{-3}$. The widest spectral classification of Taurid meteors to date
is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06483</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Valente</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werlang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic Stark shift induced by a single photon packet</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1604.06183</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters, v.42, n.9, p.1692-1695, (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.001692</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamic Stark shift results from the interaction of an atom with the
electromagnetic field. We show how a propagating single-photon wave packet can
induce a time-dependent dynamical Stark shift on a two-level system (TLS). A
non-perturbative fully-quantum treatment is employed, where the quantum
dynamics of both the field and the TLS are analyzed. We also provide the means
to experimentally access such time-dependent frequency by measuring the
interference pattern in the electromagnetic field inside a one-dimensional (1D)
waveguide. The effect we evidence here may find applications in the autonomous
quantum control of quantum systems without classical external fields, that can
be useful for quantum information processing as well as for quantum
thermodynamical tasks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06494</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Adam</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahnen</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baack</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balbo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergmann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biland</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blank</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bretz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruegge</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buss</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dmytriiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Domke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorner</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Einecke</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hempfling</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hildebrand</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linhoff</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mannheim</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neise</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neronov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noethe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paravac</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pauss</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhode</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Temme</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thaele</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mirror Position Determination for the Alignment of Cherenkov Telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>11 figures, small ray tracing performance simulation, and
  implementation demonstration</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.03.062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Imaging Atmospheric Cherenkov Telescopes (IACTs) need imaging optics with
large apertures to map the faint Cherenkov light emitted in extensive air
showers onto their image sensors. Segmented reflectors fulfill these needs
using mass produced and light weight mirror facets. However, as the overall
image is the sum of the individual mirror facet images, alignment is important.
Here we present a method to determine the mirror facet positions on a segmented
reflector in a very direct way. Our method reconstructs the mirror facet
positions from photographs and a laser distance meter measurement which goes
from the center of the image sensor plane to the center of each mirror facet.
We use our method to both align the mirror facet positions and to feed the
measured positions into our IACT simulation. We demonstrate our implementation
on the 4 m First Geiger-mode Avalanche Cherenkov Telescope (FACT).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06495</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Baur</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campesato</keyname><forenames>Roberta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casale</keyname><forenames>Mariacristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gervasi</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gombia</keyname><forenames>Enos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>Erminio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kingma</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rancoita</keyname><forenames>Pier Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozza</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacconi</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Displacement Damage dose and DLTS Analyses on Triple and Single Junction
  solar cells irradiated with electrons and protons</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Abstract accepted for poster session at 2017 IEEE Nuclear and Space
  Radiation Effects Conference, July 17-21, New Orleans</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  Space solar cells radiation hardness is of fundamental importance in view of
the future missions towards harsh radiation environment (like e.g. missions to
Jupiter) and for the new spacecraft using electrical propulsion. In this paper
we report the radiation data for triple junction (TJ) solar cells and related
component cells. Triple junction solar cells, InGaP top cells and GaAs middle
cells degrade after electron radiation as expected. With proton irradiation, a
high spread in the remaining factors was observed, especially for the TJ and
bottom cells. Very surprising was the germanium bottom junction that showed
very high degradation after protons whereas it is quite stable against
electrons. Radiation results have been analyzed by means of the Displacement
Damage Dose method and DLTS spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06503</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Gopikishan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahapatra</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of magnetic field on plasma parameters and thin film
  deposition along axial and radial distances in DC magnetron</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>8pages, 11figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic field (B) distribution of the magnetron was measured and discussed
its effect on plasma parameters and deposition rate. Plasma parameters such as
electron temperature (Te), electron number density (ne) were estimated using
electron flux (EF) and electron energy distribution function (EEDF) methods as
function of axial, radial distances from the cathode. Te and ne decreased with
increasing of axial, radial distances from the cathode. Dr was obtained for the
same positions where the above plasma parameters were measured, and found that
similar profile with Te and ne. Magnetron configuration was simulated using
COMSOL Multiphysics software and compared with the experimentally measured
profile. Further, density distribution was simulated using measured B through
particle in cell - Monte Carlo collision and found simulation results are well
supported to the experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06508</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Lemoy</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;mi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling evidence of the homothetic nature of cities</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-fin.EC</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we analyse the profile of land use and population density with
respect to the distance to the city centre for the European city. In addition
to providing the radial population density and soil-sealing profiles for a
large set of cities, we demonstrate a remarkable constancy of the profiles
across city size.
  Our analysis combines the GMES/Copernicus Urban Atlas 2006 land use database
at 5m resolution for 300 European cities with more than 100.000 inhabitants and
the Geostat population grid at 1km resolution. Population is allocated
proportionally to surface and weighted by soil sealing and density classes of
the Urban Atlas. We analyse the profile of each artificial land use and
population with distance to the town hall.
  In line with earlier literature, we confirm the strong monocentricity of the
European city and the negative exponential curve for population density.
Moreover, we find that land use curves, in particular the share of housing and
roads, scale along the two horizontal dimensions with the square root of city
population, while population curves scale in three dimensions with the cubic
root of city population. In short, European cities of different sizes are
homothetic in terms of land use and population density. While earlier
literature documented the scaling of average densities (total surface and
population) with city size, we document the scaling of the whole radial
distance profile with city size, thus liaising intra-urban radial analysis and
systems of cities. In addition to providing a new empirical view of the
European city, our scaling offers a set of practical and coherent definitions
of a city, independent of its population, from which we can re-question urban
scaling laws and Zipf's law for cities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06540</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Vekstein</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusano</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hall-mediated magnetic reconnection and onset of plasmoid instability</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to Physics of Plasmas</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a role of the Hall-effect in the current sheet evolution and
onset of the secondary tearing (plasmoid) instability in the framework of the
incompressible resistive Hall-magnetohydrodynamics (MHD). The model under
consideration is a force-free modification of the Taylor's problem. Thus, the
first part of the paper is devoted to a detailed analytical study of the
Hall-MHD forced magnetic reconnection in a tearing stable force-free magnetic
configuration. Then, in the second part, these results are used to investigate
when and how the plasmoid instability can develop in the course of this
process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06542</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Prodan</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobiszewski</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanwal</keyname><forenames>Alokik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palmieri</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prodan</keyname><forenames>Camelia</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Majorana Edge Modes in a Broad Class of Topological Mechanical
  Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 14587 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms14587</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mechanical systems can display topological characteristics similar to that of
topological insulators. Here we report a large class of topological mechanical
systems related to the BDI symmetry class. These are self-assembled chains of
rigid bodies with an inversion center and no reflection planes. The
particle-hole symmetry characteristic to the BDI symmetry class stems from the
distinct behavior of the translational and rotational degrees of freedom under
inversion. This and other generic properties led us to the remarkable
conclusion that, by adjusting the gyration radius of the bodies, one can always
simultaneously open a gap in the phonon spectrum, lock-in all the
characteristic symmetries and generate a non-trivial topological invariant. The
particle-hole symmetry occurs around a finite frequency, hence we can witness a
dynamical topological Majorana edge mode. Contrasting a floppy mode occurring
at zero frequency, a dynamical edge mode can absorb and store mechanical
energy, potentially opening new applications of topological mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06543</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06543</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jyun-Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Kuang-Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Pang-Shiuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chien-Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Tung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Yao-Jen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Tuo-Hung</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-Area Two-Dimensional Layered MoTe$_2$ by Physical Vapor Deposition
  and Solid-Phase Crystallization in a Tellurium-Free Atmosphere</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Submitted version</comments><journal-ref>Advanced Materials Interfaces,1700157, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/admi.201700157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molybdenum ditelluride (MoTe$_2$) has attracted considerable interest for
nanoelectronic, optoelectronic, spintronic, and valleytronic applications
because of its modest band gap, high field-effect mobility, large
spin-orbit-coupling splitting, and tunable 1T'/2H phases. However, synthesizing
large-area, high-quality MoTe$_2$ remains challenging. The complicated design
of gas-phase reactant transport and reaction for chemical vapor deposition or
tellurization is nontrivial because of the weak bonding energy between Mo and
Te. Here, we report a new method for depositing MoTe$_2$ that entails using
physical vapor deposition followed by a post-annealing process in a Te-free
atmosphere. Both Mo and Te were physically deposited onto the substrate by
sputtering a MoTe$_2$ target. A composite SiO$_2$ capping layer was designed to
prevent Te sublimation during the post-annealing process. The post-annealing
process facilitated 1T'-to-2H phase transition and solid-phase crystallization,
leading to the formation of high-crystallinity few-layer 2H-MoTe$_2$ with a
field-effect mobility of ~10 cm$^2$/(V-s), the highest among all nonexfoliated
2H-MoTe$_2$ currently reported. Furthermore, 2H-MoS$_2$ and Td-WTe$_2$ can be
deposited using similar methods. Requiring no transfer or chemical reaction of
metal and chalcogen reactants in the gas phase, the proposed method is
potentially a general yet simple approach for depositing a wide variety of
large-area, high-quality, two-dimensional layered structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06545</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Suparti</keyname></author><author><keyname>Sulaksono</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Imprint of Nucleon Radius on the Slowly Rotating Neutron Star Properties</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, Phys. Rev. C (accepted)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the effect of free space nucleon radius on the nuclear matter
and slowly rotating neutron star properties within a relativistic mean field
model with the inclusion of omega-rho mixing nonlinear term. We use the same
density dependent radius as in our previous work. However, in the present work
we utilize the parameter sets with more proper symmetric nuclear matter (SNM)
predictions for a number of different nucleon radii. To this end, the isoscalar
parameters in each parameter set and the cutoff parameter $\beta$ are adjusted
by fitting the corresponding SNM properties at sub-saturation density to the
prediction of IUFSU parameter set. We have obtained that the assumption of
composite nucleons with free space radius $r \le 0.83$ fm is still compatible
with the currently acceptable nuclear matter (NM) properties beyond the
saturation density. We have also found that the effect of free space nucleon
radius could be imprinted in the radius, moment of inertia, and crust
properties of the slowly rotating neutron star.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06555</id><created>2017-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ennadifi</keyname><forenames>Salah-Eddine</forenames></author></authors><title>A Quantum Approach to Gravitational Waves</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In light of the Gravitational Waves observation and the discrete structure of
spacetime at high scales M_QG, we investigate the behavior of Gravitational
Waves and the spacetime deformation patterns in terms of gravitons and derive
the effective results with respect to photons. Using the GW150914 data and
related signals, we probe the underlying quantum scale M_QG 10_6 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06560</id><created>2017-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Jacak</keyname><forenames>Janusz E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Confinement and fractional charge of quarks from braid group approach to
  holographic principle</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The so-called holographic principle, originally addressed to high energy
physics, suggests more generally that the information contents of the system
(measured by its entropy) scales as the event horizon surface. It has been
formulated also a holographic super-string model for the anti de Sitter space,
which allows for implementation of quantum gravity in the volume by only
quantum boundary---hologram. The locally planar topology of the boundary of 3D
space leads, however, to more reach possibilities of quantization of many
particle systems according to representations of related braid groups (i.e.,
first homotopy groups of the configuration space for multiparticle systems).
This level of freedom would be helpful in symmetry-term considerations of
hypothetical locally 2D hologram properties corresponding to anyons. Specific
properties of anyons on a sphere are compared with fractional charge of quarks.
The confinement of quarks in hadrons is conjectured to be linked with the
collective behavior of anyons precluding their individual separation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06562</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Marton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piscicchia</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curceanu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cargnelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Grande</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabbietti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandaglio</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moskal</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scordo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirghi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skurzok</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucakovic</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doce</keyname><forenames>O. Vazquez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wycech</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmeskal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antikaon Interactions with Nucleons and Nuclei - AMADEUS At Da$\Phi$ne</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of AMADEUS is to provide unprecedented experimental information on
K$^-$ absorption in light nuclear targets, to face major open problems in
hadron nuclear physics in the strangeness sector, namely the nature of the
$\Lambda$(1405), strongly related to the possible existence of kaonic nuclear
clusters, kaons and hyperon scattering cross sections on nucleons and nuclei.
These issues are fundamental for a better understanding of the non-perturbative
QCD in the strangeness sector.
  AMADEUS step 0 deals with the analysis of the 2004-2005 KLOE collected data.
The interactions of the negative kaons produced by the DA$\Phi$NE collider (a
unique source of monochromatic low-momentum kaons) with the materials of the
KLOE detector, used as active targets, provide samples of K$^-$ absorptions on
H, ${}^4$He, ${}^{9}$Be and ${}^{12}$C, both at-rest and in-flight. A second
step deals with the data from the implementation in the central region of the
KLOE detector of a pure graphite target, providing a high statistic sample of
K$^- \, {}^{12}$C nuclear captures at rest. For the future a new setup, with
various dedicated gaseous and solid targets, is under preparation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06564</id><created>2017-04-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Rozenberg</keyname><forenames>Shay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yahalom</keyname><forenames>Asher</forenames></author></authors><title>A THz Slot Antenna Optimization Using Analytical Techniques</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Slot antennas are very popular microwave antennas and slotted wave guides are
used for high frequency radar systems. A thin slot in an infinite ground plane
is the complement to a dipole in free space. This was described by H.G. Booker
[2] who extended Babinet's principle from optics to show that the slot will
have the same radiation pattern as a dipole such that the E and H fields are
swapped. As a result, the polarization is rotated, so that radiation from
vertical slot is polarized horizontally. In this work we show how analytical
techniques can be used for optimization of THz slot antennas, the analysis is
then corroborated by using a numerical simulation which validates the
performance parameters predicted by the analytical technique.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06568</id><created>2017-04-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Auer</keyname><forenames>Sabine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinke</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chunsen</keyname><forenames>Wang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabo</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sollacher</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author></authors><title>Can Distribution Grids Significantly Contribute to Transmission Grids'
  Voltage Management?</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><journal-ref>S. Auer, F. Steinke, W. Chunsen, A. Szabo and R. Sollacher, 2016
  IEEE PES Innovative Smart Grid Technologies Conference Europe (ISGT-Europe),
  2016, pp. 1-6</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ISGTEurope.2016.7856194</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Power generation in Germany is currently transitioning from a system based on
large, central, thermal power plants to one that heavily relies on small,
decentral, mostly renewable power generators. This development poses the
question how transmission grids' reactive power demand for voltage management,
covered by central power plants today, can be supplied in the future.
  In this work, we estimate the future technical potential of such an approach
for the whole of Germany. For a 100% renewable electricity scenario we set the
possible reactive power supply in comparison with the reactive power
requirements that are needed to realize the simulated future transmission grid
power flows. Since an exact calculation of distribution grids' reactive power
potential is difficult due to the unavailability of detailed grid models on
such scale, we optimistically estimate the potential by assuming a scaled,
averaged distribution grid model connected to each of the transmission grid
nodes.
  We find that for all except a few transmission grid nodes, the required
reactive power can be fully supplied from the modeled distribution grids. This
implies that - even if our estimate is overly optimistic - distributed reactive
power provisioning will be a technical solution for many future reactive power
challenges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06578</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Weeber</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holm</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay between particle microstructure, network topology and sample
  shape in magnetic gels -- A molecular dynamics simulation study</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ferrogels, i.e., hydrogels loaded with magnetic nanoparticles, have the
ability to deform in external magnetic fields. The precise shape of deformation
and the alignment of the gel in the field, however, depend on the interplay of
several factors. In this paper, we introduce a coarse-grained simulation model,
which takes into account the configuration of magnetic particles in the gel,
the sample shape, and aspects of the polymer network topology. We use this
model to show that in gels with an isotropic microstructure, an external
magnetic field reduces clustering, while this is not the case for uniaxial
gels, in which the particle configuration is anisotropic due to the presence of
a magnetic field during cross-linking. For ellipsoidal gels, we find that a
uniaxial microstructure additionally can override the deformation and alignment
expected as indicated the demagnetization energy. Finally, we examine to what
degree gels with different network topologies maintain the particle
microstructure ``frozen in`` during the cross-linking process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06587</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirza</keyname><forenames>Babur M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transmission time and resonant tunneling through barriers using
  localized quantum density soliton waves</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. B28 (32), 1450253 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217984914502534</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the interaction and transmission time of quantum density
solitons waves representing particles passing through finite barrier potentials
is investigated. Using the conservation of energy and of quantum density, it is
first demonstrated that these waves have finite de Broglie wavelength and
represent particles in quantum theory. The passage of the quantum density
solitons (particles) through barriers of finite energies is then shown to lead
to the phenomena of resonant tunneling and, in Josephson-like configurations,
to the quantization of magnetic flux. A precise general measure for barrier
tunneling time is derived which is found to give a new interpretation of the
quantum indeterminacy principles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06595</id><created>2017-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrowolska</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koper</keyname><forenames>Ger J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bimodal molecular mass distribution in surfactant-free emulsion
  polymerization as a consequence of coagulative nucleation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is demonstrated that the often observed broadness of the molecular weight
distribution obtained from latex particles synthesized by means of
surfactant-free emulsion polymerization results from the multistage kinetics.
The initial stage of the polymerization, by which the primary particles are
formed, is of the 01-kind which means that it can be assumed that the particles
are so small that at any moment of time there is no more than one radical chain
per particle. After the aggregation of primary particles into secondary
particles, the so called coagulative nucleation step, the polymerization
kinetics in the subsequently coalesced secondary particles is of the
pseudo-bulk kind which means that there are so many radicals in the particles
that the polymerization process proceeds as in bulk. The important consequence
is that the molecular weight of the 01-process is about one order of magnitude
larger than that of the pseudo-bulk process. Hence, each of these
polymerization modes and the aggregation stage in-between leave their traces in
the molecular weight distribution as is shown by experiments aimed at
prolonging the initial formation kinetics. Bimodal molecular weight
distributions are found both for ionic and non-ionic initiators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06599</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bouteiller</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames><affiliation>CMGPCE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Terrier</keyname><forenames>Marie-France</forenames><affiliation>CMGPCE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tobaly</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames><affiliation>CMGPCE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Experimental Study of Heat Pump Thermodynamic Cycles Using CO 2 Based
  Mixtures -Methodology and First Results</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>TECHNOLOGIES AND MATERIALS FOR RENEWABLE ENERGY, ENVIRONMENT AND
  SUSTAINABILITY: TMREES16-Cnam, Nov 2016, Paris, France. AIP, AIP conference
  proceedings, 2017, TECHNOLOGIES AND MATERIALS FOR RENEWABLE ENERGY,
  ENVIRONMENT AND SUSTAINABILITY: TMREES16-Cnam</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4976271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this work is to study heat pump cycles, using CO 2 based mixtures
as working fluids. Since adding other chemicals to CO 2 moves the critical
point and generally equilibrium lines, it is expected that lower operating
pressures as well as higher global efficiencies may be reached. A simple stage
pure CO 2 cycle is used as reference, with fixed external conditions. Two
scenarios are considered: water is heated from 10 {\textdegree}C to 65
{\textdegree}C for Domestic Hot Water scenario and from 30 {\textdegree}C to 35
{\textdegree}C for Central Heating scenario. In both cases, water at the
evaporator inlet is set at 7 {\textdegree}C to account for such outdoor
temperature conditions. In order to understand the dynamic behaviour of
thermodynamic cycles with mixtures, it is essential to measure the fluid
circulating composition. To this end, we have developed a non intrusive method.
Online optical flow cells allow the recording of infrared spectra by means of a
Fourier Transform Infra Red spectrometer. A careful calibration is performed by
measuring a statistically significant number of spectra for samples of known
composition. Then, a statistical model is constructed to relate spectra to
compositions. After calibration, compositions are obtained by recording the
spectrum in few seconds, thus allowing for a dynamic analysis. This article
will describe the experimental setup and the composition measurement
techniques. Then a first account of results with pure CO 2 , and with the
addition of propane or R-1234yf will be given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06601</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>JiaYi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xu Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yi Xue</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear Data and Fuel/Assembly Manufacturing Uncertainties Analysis and
  Preliminary Validation of SUACL</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As the sensitivity and uncertainty analysis of nuclear system can provide
more confident bounds for the Best-estimate Prediction used to assess the
performance and safety of nuclear plant, the uncertainty and sensitivity
analysis has been a component of analysis of nuclear system. Both the cross
section uncertainty and the uncertainty of parameters of fuel/assembly
manufacturing are analyzed in this paper. All results of SUACL were found in
accordance with the results of reference codes.238U and 235U play an important
role in determining the uncertainty of Keff in TMI-1 cell. The uncertainty of
Keff in MOX is mainly affected by 239Pu and 238U. It is obvious that the
uncertainty mostly depends on the covariance library and insensitivities to
cross section library. The uncertainties based on the covariance library
obtained from ENDF/B-VII.1 differ from the result of JENDL4.0, which verified
the relationship of covariance matrix and the uncertainty of cross section. And
the parameters of fuel/assembly manufacturing uncertainty are comparable to
uncertainty of some cross section, especially the 235U concentration, clad
thickness. The uncertainty analysis of these parameters is of great
significance to evaluate the parameter of actual cell and help to improve the
model simulated. More attentions need paid to improve the accuracy of the
parameters analysis talked in the paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06602</id><created>2017-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bakaraju</keyname><forenames>Vikram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>E. Senthil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaturvedi</keyname><forenames>Harsh</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-triggered on/off-switchable bioelectronic FET device</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report fabrication of an optically active, bio-electronic device based on
thin film of purple membrane and single walled carbon nanotubes (SWNT). Two
dimensional (2D) crystals of photoactive bacteriorhodopsin forms the optical
center of the purple membrane where as pure SWNTs provides the necessary
electronic support to the complex. Electro-optically functional and stable,
hybrid complex was prepared using surface functionalization of SWNTs with
indigenous, batch-process synthesized purple membrane. Raman spectra of the
hybrid complex shows significant charge transfer and surface functionalization
of SWNTs. Optically active, field effect transistor based on the prepared thin
film of bio-nano hybrid complex is fabricated using direct laser lithography
and conventional lift off technology. Significant optical doping is observed in
the fabricated field effect transistor. Fabricated devices show repeatable
stable performance with well-controlled optical and electronic gating. Device
shows essentially n-type FET characteristics and transistor is ON for positive
gate voltages. However, same n-type FET shows complimentary p-type
characteristics under visible light illumination, with transistor being ON for
negative gate voltages. Significant optical doping, photo-conductivity and
optical switching were observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06603</id><created>2017-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Nandal</keyname><forenames>Vikas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Pradeep R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predictive modeling of ion migration induced degradation in perovskite
  solar cells</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With excellent efficiencies being reported from multiple labs across the
world, device stability and the degradation mechanisms have emerged as the key
aspects that could determine the future prospects of perovskite solar cells.
However, the related experimental efforts remain scattered due to the lack of
any unifying theoretical framework. In this context, here we provide a
comprehensive analysis of ion migration effects in perovskite solar cells.
Specifically, we show, for the first time, that (a) the effect of ionic charges
is almost indistinguishable from that of dopant ions, (b) ion migration could
lead to simultaneous improvement in Voc and degradation in Jsc - a unique
observation which is beyond the realm of mere parametric variation in carrier
mobility and lifetime, (c) champion devices are more resilient towards the ill
effects of ion migration, and finally (d) we propose unique characterization
schemes to determine both magnitude and polarity of ionic species. Our results,
supported by detailed numerical simulations and direct comparison with
experimental data, are of broad interest and provide a much needed predictive
capability towards the research on performance degradation mechanisms in
perovskite solar cells
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06604</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chatterji</keyname><forenames>Nithin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antony</keyname><forenames>Aldrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Pradeep R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling based screening for optimal carrier selective material for Si
  based solar cells</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures and 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Carrier selective (CS) silicon solar cells are increasingly explored using a
variety of different materials. However, the optimum properties of such CS
materials are not well understood. In this context, through detailed analytical
and numerical modeling, here we provide several interesting insights on the
efficiency tradeoff with CS material properties. First, we show that perfect
band alignment is a desirable feature only if the interface is devoid of any
trap states. Otherwise, a band offset of around 0.2eV-0.4eV provides sufficient
band bending to reduce the effect of interface recombination, thus improving
the performance. Surprisingly, the interface passivation quality for the
minority carrier extraction layer is found to be far less demanding than that
for the majority carrier extraction layer. Additionally, doping density and
dielectric constant of CS layers have a similar effect as band offset on solar
cell performance. Our results have obvious implications toward the selection of
appropriate materials as carrier selective layers and hence are of broad
interest to the community.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06630</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Navarro</keyname><forenames>Anamaria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lora-Clavijo</keyname><forenames>F. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Guillermo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic Static Thin Disks of Polarized Matter</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, 70 and 70 Gravitation Fest, 28 September 2016,
  Cartagena, Colombia</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys.Conf.Ser. 831 (2017) no.1, 012010</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/831/1/012010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An infinite family of exact solutions of the electrovacuum Einstein-Maxwell
equations is presented. The family is static, axially symmetric and describe
thin disks composed by electrically polarized material in a conformastatic
spacetime. The form of the conformastatic metric allows us to write down the
metric functions and the electromagnetic potentials in terms of a solution of
the Laplace equation. We find a general expression for the surface energy
density of the disk, the pressure, the polarization vector, the electromagnetic
fields and the velocity rotation for circular orbits. As an example, we present
the first model of the family and show the behavior of the different physical
variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06637</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Pastore</keyname><forenames>Raffaele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pesce</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caggioni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Differential Variance Analysis of soft glassy materials: a direct method
  to quantify and visualize dynamic heterogeneities</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 43496 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep43496</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many amorphous materials show spatially heterogenous dynamics, as different
regions of the same system relax at different rates. Such a signature, known as
Dynamic Heterogeneity, has been crucial to understand the jamming transition in
simple model systems and, currently, is considered very promising to
characterize more complex fluids of industrial and biological relevance.
Unfortunately, measurements of dynamic heterogeneities typically require
sophysticated experimental set-ups and are performed by few specialized groups.
It is now possible to quantitatively characterize the relaxation process and
the emergence of dynamic heterogeneities using a straightforward method, here
validated on video microscopy data of hard-sphere colloidal glasses. We call
this method Differential Variance Analysis (DVA), since it focuses on the
variance of the differential frames, obtained subtracting images at different
lag-times. Moreover, direct visualization of dynamic heterogeneities naturally
appears in the differential frames, when the lag-time is set to the one
corresponding to the maximum dynamic susceptibility. This approach opens the
way to effectively characterize and tailor a wide variety of soft materials,
from complex formulated products to biological tissues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06647</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Prior</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The SNO+ experiment physics goals and background mitigation</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>for the SNO+ Collaboration</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main physics goal of the SNO+ experiment is the search for neutrinoless
double-beta decay (0$\nu\beta\beta$), a rare process which if detected, will
prove the Majorana nature of neutrinos and provide information on the absolute
scale of the neutrino mass. Additional physics goals include the study of solar
neutrinos, anti-neutrinos from nuclear reactors and the Earth's natural
radioactivity as well as Supernovae neutrinos. Located in the SNOLAB (Canada)
deep underground laboratory, it will re-use the SNO detector. A short phase
with the detector completely filled with water has started at the beginning of
2017, before running the detector with scintillator. This paper describes in
details the SNO+ sensitivity to 0$\nu\beta\beta$ decays, as well as the other
physics goals. Crucial to these large volume liquid scintillator experiments,
is the ability to constraint the low-energy background from radioactive decays.
Methods to mitigate those are also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06650</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruijl</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>NIKHEF, Amsterdam &amp; Leiden U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>NIKHEF, Amsterdam</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vermaseren</keyname><forenames>J. A. M.</forenames><affiliation>NIKHEF, Amsterdam</affiliation></author></authors><title>Forcer, a FORM program for the parametric reduction of four-loop
  massless propagator diagrams</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>43 pages, 6 figures, source code available from
  https://github.com/benruijl/forcer</comments><report-no>Nikhef 2017-019</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explain the construction of Forcer, a FORM program for the reduction of
four-loop massless propagator-type integrals to master integrals. The resulting
program performs parametric IBP reductions similar to the three-loop Mincer
program. We show how one can solve many systems of IBP identities
parametrically in a computer-assisted manner. Next, we discuss the structure of
the Forcer program, which involves recognizing reduction actions for each
topology, applying symmetries, and transitioning between topologies after edges
have been removed. This part is entirely precomputed and automatically
generated. We give examples of recent applications of Forcer, and study the
performance of the program. Finally we demonstrate how to use the Forcer
package and sketch how to prepare physical diagrams for evaluation by Forcer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0601669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0601669</id><created>2006-01-30</created><updated>2006-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple analytical model for dark matter halo structure and adiabatic
  contraction</title><categories>astro-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures. v3 - major improvements, another halo model
  introduced, discussion extended</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters 84, 2, p.45 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364006140013</doi><abstract>  A simple analytical model for describing inner parts of dark matter halo is
considered. It is assumed that dark matter density is power-law. The model
deals with dark matter distribution function in phase space of adiabatic
invariants (radial action and angular momentum). Two variants are considered
for the angular part of the distribution function: narrow and broad
distribution. The model allows to describe explicitly the process of adiabatic
contraction of halo due to change of gravitational potential caused by
condensation of baryonic matter in the centre. The modification of dark matter
density in the centre is calculated, and is it shown that the standard
algorithm of adiabatic contraction calculation overestimates the compressed
halo density, especially in the case of strong radial anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0203409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0203409</id><created>2002-03-20</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling behaviour of entropy estimates</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, no content changed, typesetting improved</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Gen. 35 (2002) 1589-1596</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0305-4470/35/7/308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entropy estimation of information sources is highly non trivial for symbol
sequences with strong long-range correlations. The rabbit sequence, related to
the symbolic dynamics of the nonlinear circle map at the critical point as well
as the logistic map at the Feigenbaum point have been argued to exhibit long
memory tails. For both dynamical systems the scaling behavior of the block
entropy of order n has been shown to increase like as log(n). In contrast to
probabilistic concepts, we investigate the scaling behavior of certain
non-probabilistic entropy estimation schemes suggested by Lempel and Ziv in the
context of algorithmic complexity and data compression. These are applied in a
sequential manner with the scaling variable being the length N of the sequence.
We determine the scaling law for the Lempel-Ziv entropy estimate applied to the
case of the critical circle map and the logistic map at the Feigenbaum point in
a binary partition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0203436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-24</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0203436</id><created>2002-03-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassberger</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy estimation of symbol sequences</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cs.CL cs.IT math.IT physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><comments>14 pages, 13 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>CHAOS Vol. 6, No. 3 (1996) 414-427</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.166191</doi><abstract>  We discuss algorithms for estimating the Shannon entropy h of finite symbol
sequences with long range correlations. In particular, we consider algorithms
which estimate h from the code lengths produced by some compression algorithm.
Our interest is in describing their convergence with sequence length, assuming
no limits for the space and time complexities of the compression algorithms. A
scaling law is proposed for extrapolation from finite sample lengths. This is
applied to sequences of dynamical systems in non-trivial chaotic regimes, a 1-D
cellular automaton, and to written English texts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
