<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:37:56Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-04-10" from="2017-04-10" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1103.5920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1103.5920</id><created>2011-03-30</created><updated>2015-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Yunhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Chenchang</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher Extensions of Lie Algebroids</title><categories>math-ph math.DG math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>32 pages</comments><journal-ref>Commun. Contemp. Math. 19, 1650034 (2017) [41 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219199716500346</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the extension of a Lie algebroid by a representation up to homotopy,
including semidirect products of a Lie algebroid with such representations. The
extension results in a higher Lie algebroid. We give exact Courant algebroids
and string Lie 2-algebras as examples of such extensions. We then apply this to
obtain a Lie 2-groupoid integration of an exact Courant algebroid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.6698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.6698</id><created>2014-03-26</created><updated>2015-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nishimoto</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katukuri</keyname><forenames>Vamshi M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yushankhai</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoll</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roessler</keyname><forenames>Ulrich K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hozoi</keyname><forenames>Liviu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rousochatzakis</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Jeroen van den</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly frustrated triangular spin lattice emerging from triplet dimer
  formation in honeycomb Li2IrO3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, revised from the previous version</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7:10273 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms10273</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In quantum magnetism spin dimers are typically associated with spin-singlet
states. To date, $triplet$ $dimerization$ has not been observed in any 3D or
quasi-2D material. With this in mind we here discuss the electronic structure
of the spin-orbit driven $5d^5$ Mott insulator Li$_2$IrO$_3$, a
honeycomb-lattice system with two crystallographically inequivalent Ir-Ir
bonds. From $ab$ $initio$ many-body calculations we find that, while both
Heisenberg and Kitaev couplings are present, the magnetic interactions are
dominated by a strong isotropic ferromagnetic exchange on only one set of
bonds. This causes the formation of triplet spin dimers effectively placed on a
strongly frustrated triangular lattice. The triplet dimers remain protected in
a large region of the phase diagram, suggesting that Li$_2$IrO$_3$ has a
long-range incommensurate magnetic ground state that is pushed by the Kitaev
exchange interactions beyond a standard planar helix configuration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.1124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.1124</id><created>2014-07-04</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mikovic</keyname><forenames>Aleksandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vojinovic</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Constant in a Quantum Gravity Theory for a Piecewise-linear
  Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages. v11: small modification of the abstract</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum contributions to the classical cosmological constant in
a quantum gravity theory for GR with matter on a piecewise linear spacetime
corresponding to a triangulation of a smooth manifold. We use the effective
action approach and a special path-integral (PI) measure which depends on a
free parameter, while matter is modeled by a massive self-interacting scalar
field. The effective cosmological constant (CC) is given as a sum of 3 terms:
the classical CC, the quantum gravity CC and the matter CC. We show that the
free parameters of the theory can be chosen such that the classical CC cancels
the matter CC so that the effective CC is given by the QG CC. Since the value
of the quantum gravity CC is determined by the PI measure only, the PI measure
parameter can be chosen such that the effective CC gives the observed value.
This is equivalent to the statement that the experimentally observed CC value
belongs to the spectrum of the CC operator in this QG theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.01703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.01703</id><created>2015-01-07</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mangum</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirley</keyname><forenames>Yancy L.</forenames></author></authors><title>How to Calculate Molecular Column Density</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>35 pages with 15 figures and 20 tables. Appeared in the March 2015
  issue of PASP. Latest version corrects a factor-of-two error in Eq. 100
  (corrigendum to appear in PASP) and previous corrigendum (February 2016 issue
  of PASP): (1) Fix error in dipole moment units; (2) Fixed errors in constants
  for worked column density equations for C18O 1-0 (Eq. 90), C17O 1-0 (Eq. 93),
  and N2H+ 1-0 (Eq. 96)</comments><doi>10.1086/680323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The calculation of the molecular column density from molecular spectral
(rotational or ro-vibrational) transition measurements is one of the most basic
quantities derived from molecular spectroscopy. Starting from first principles
where we describe the basic physics behind the radiative and collisional
excitation of molecules and the radiative transfer of their emission, we derive
a general expression for the molecular column density. As the calculation of
the molecular column density involves a knowledge of the molecular energy level
degeneracies, rotational partition functions, dipole moment matrix elements,
and line strengths, we include generalized derivations of these
molecule-specific quantities. Given that approximations to the column density
equation are often useful, we explore the optically thin, optically thick, and
low-frequency limits to our derived general molecular column density relation.
We also evaluate the limitations of the common assumption that the molecular
excitation temperature is constant, and address the distinction between beam-
and source-averaged column densities. We conclude our discussion of the
molecular column density with worked examples for C$^{18}$O, C$^{17}$O,
N$_2$H$^+$, NH$_3$, and H$_2$CO. Ancillary information on some subtleties
involving line profile functions, conversion between integrated flux and
brightness temperature, the calculation of the uncertainty associated with an
integrated intensity measurement, the calculation of spectral line optical
depth using hyperfine or isotopologue measurements, the calculation of the
kinetic temperature from a symmetric molecule excitation temperature
measurement, and relative hyperfine intensity calculations for NH$_3$ are
presented in appendices. The intent of this document is to provide a reference
for researchers studying astrophysical molecular spectroscopic measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07529</id><created>2015-05-27</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Yuanxun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>Alexander D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaye</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peskin</keyname><forenames>Charles S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gaussian-Like Immersed Boundary Kernels with Three Continuous
  Derivatives and Improved Translational Invariance</title><categories>math.NA physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures. This is an updated manuscript to the published
  version with a new 5-point kernel</comments><msc-class>74F10, 76D05</msc-class><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.04.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The immersed boundary (IB) method is a general mathematical framework for
studying problems involving fluid-structure interactions in which an elastic
structure is immersed in a viscous incompressible fluid. In the IB formulation,
the fluid described by Eulerian variables is coupled with the immersed
structure described by Lagrangian variables via the use of the Dirac delta
function. From a numerical standpoint, the Lagrangian force spreading and the
Eulerian velocity interpolation are carried out by a regularized, compactly
supported discrete delta function, which is assumed to be a tensor product of a
single-variable immersed-boundary kernel. IB kernels are derived from a set of
postulates designed to achieve approximate grid translational invariance,
interpolation accuracy and computational efficiency. In this note, we present
new 5-point and 6-point immersed-boundary kernels that are $\mathscr{C}^3$ and
yield a substantially improved translational invariance compared to other
common IB kernels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08186</id><created>2015-06-26</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Uttam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bera</keyname><forenames>Manabendra Nath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Avijit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pati</keyname><forenames>Arun Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Erasing Quantum Coherence: An Operational Approach</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>latex, 8 pages, 1 figure, minor changes, affiliation of one author is
  appended!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite being one of the hallmarks of quantum physics, there is a lack of
operational interpretations of quantum coherence. Here we provide an
operational interpretation of coherence of a quantum system, in terms of the
amount of noise that is to be injected in order to fully decohere it. In
particular, we show that in the asymptotic limit, the minimum amount of noise
that is required to fully decohere a quantum system, is equal to the relative
entropy of coherence. This quantifies the erasure cost of quantum coherence. We
employ the entropy exchanged between system and environment during the
decohering operation and the memory required to store the information about the
decohering operation as the quantifiers of noise. We show that both the
quantifiers yield the same cost of erasing coherence in the asymptotic limit.
The relative entropy of coherence, hence, is endowed with a thermodynamical and
operational interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02452</id><created>2015-09-08</created><updated>2016-07-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guchait</keyname><forenames>Monoranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Jacky</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Higgs Bosons in NMSSM at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>29 pages, 20 Figures</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217751X1650069X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The next-to-minimal supersymmetric standard model (NMSSM) with an extended
Higgs sector offers one of the Higgs boson as the Standard model (SM) like
Higgs with a mass around 125 GeV along with other Higgs bosons with lighter and
heavier masses and not excluded by any current experiments. At the LHC,
phenomenology of these non SM like Higgs bosons is very rich and considerably
different from the other supersymmetric models. In this work, assuming one of
the Higgs bosons to be the SM like, we revisit the mass spectrum and couplings
of non SM like Higgs bosons taking into consideration all existing constraints
and identify the relevant region of parameter space. The discovery potential of
these non SM like Higgs bosons, apart from their masses, is guided by their
couplings with gauge bosons and fermions which are very much parameter space
sensitive. We evaluate the rates of productions of these non SM like Higgs
bosons at the LHC for a variety of decay channels in the allowed region of the
parameter space. Although bb, {\tau}{\tau} decay modes appear to be the most
promising, it is observed that for a substantial region of parameter space the
two-photon decay mode has a remarkably large rate. In this work we emphasize
that this diphoton mode can be exploited to find the NMSSM Higgs signal and can
also be potential avenue to distinguish the NMSSM from the MSSM. In addition,
we discuss briefly the various detectable signals of these non SM Higgs bosons
at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03884</id><created>2015-09-13</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bambi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing black hole candidates with electromagnetic radiation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>47 pages, 26 figures. Invited review paper for Reviews of Modern
  Physics. v3: refereed version. v4: minor typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Mod. Phys. 89, 025001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/RevModPhys.89.025001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Astrophysical black hole candidates are thought to be the Kerr black holes of
general relativity, but there is not yet direct observational evidence that the
spacetime geometry around these objects is described by the Kerr solution. The
study of the properties of the electromagnetic radiation emitted by gas or
stars orbiting these objects can potentially test the Kerr black hole
hypothesis. In this paper, I review the state of the art of this research
field, describing the possible approaches to test the Kerr metric with current
and future observational facilities and discussing current constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05871</id><created>2015-09-19</created><updated>2016-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Visinelli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Condensation of Galactic Cold Dark Matter</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures, Version accepted for publication on JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1607, 009 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/07/009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the steady-state regime describing the density profile of a dark
matter halo, if dark matter is treated as a Bose-Einstein condensate. We first
solve the fluid equation for &quot;canonical&quot; cold dark matter, obtaining a class of
density profiles which includes the Navarro-Frenk-White profile, and which
diverge at the halo core. We then solve numerically the equation obtained when
an additional &quot;quantum pressure&quot; term is included in the computation of the
density profile. The solution to this latter case is finite at the halo core,
possibly avoiding the &quot;cuspy halo problem&quot; present in some cold dark matter
theories. Within the model proposed, we predict the mass of the cold dark
matter particle to be of the order of M_chi c2 = 10^-24 eV, which is of the
same order of magnitude as that predicted in ultra-light scalar cold dark
matter models. Finally, we derive the differential equation describing
perturbations in the density and the pressure of the dark matter fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04420</id><created>2015-11-13</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lostaglio</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jennings</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudolph</keyname><forenames>Terry</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic resource theories, non-commutativity and maximum entropy
  principles</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 043008 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa617f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss some features of thermodynamics in the presence of multiple
conserved quantities. We prove a generalisation of Landauer principle
illustrating tradeoffs between the erasure costs paid in different
&quot;currencies&quot;. We then show how the maximum entropy and complete passivity
approaches give different answers in the presence of multiple observables. We
discuss how this seems to prevent current resource theories from fully
capturing thermodynamic aspects of non-commutativity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08214</id><created>2015-11-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Amariti</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnecchi</keyname><forenames>Alessandra</forenames></author></authors><title>3D $\tau_{RR}$-minimization in AdS$_4$ gauged supergravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we propose the identification in AdS4 N = 2 gauged supergravity
of the coefficient $\tau_{RR}$ of 3D N = 2 SCFTs. We constraint the structure
of this function in supergravity by combining the results from unitarity,
holography and localization. We show that our conjectured function is minimized
by the exact R-charge, corresponding to a gravitational attractor for the
scalars in the special geometry. We identify this mechanism with the
supergravity dual of the $\tau_{RR}$-minimization. We check this proposal in
the ABJM model, comparing with the expectations from localization and the
AdS/CFT duality. We comment also on some possible relations with the black hole
microstate counting, recently obtained from the application of localization
techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08737</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Figueroa-O'Farrill</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Spencer cohomology and eleven-dimensional supergravity</title><categories>hep-th math.DG math.RT</categories><comments>32 pages (v2: minor comments, reference added, final version to be
  published in CMP)</comments><report-no>EMPG-15-22</report-no><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 349 (2017), 627-660</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2700-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recover the classification of the maximally supersymmetric bosonic
backgrounds of eleven-dimensional supergravity by Lie algebraic means. We
classify all filtered deformations of the $\mathbb Z$-graded subalgebras
$\mathfrak{h}=\mathfrak{h}_{-2}\oplus\mathfrak{h}_{-1}\oplus\mathfrak{h}_{0}$
of the Poincar\'e superalgebra
$\mathfrak{g}=\mathfrak{g}_{-2}\oplus\mathfrak{g}_{-1}\oplus\mathfrak{g}_{0}=V\oplus
S\oplus \mathfrak{so}(V)$ which differ only in zero degree, that is
$\mathfrak{h}_0\subset\mathfrak{g}_0$ and $\mathfrak{h}_j=\mathfrak{g}_j$ for
$j&lt;0$. Aside from the Poincar\'e superalgebra itself and its $\mathbb Z$-graded
subalgebras, there are only three other Lie superalgebras, which are the
symmetry superalgebras of the non-flat maximally supersymmetric backgrounds. In
passing we identify the gravitino variation with (a component of) a Spencer
cocycle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08046</id><created>2015-12-25</created><updated>2017-01-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vovchenko</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoecker</keyname><forenames>Horst</forenames></author></authors><title>Surprisingly large uncertainties in temperature extraction from thermal
  fits to hadron yield data at LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, v3: added calculations for baryon-baryon only
  eigenvolume interactions fitted to nuclear ground state, added table with
  fitted data, title and discussion modified in order to ensure more clarity
  about the presented results</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G 44, 055103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa6409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conventional hadron-resonance gas (HRG) model with the Particle Data
Group (PDG) hadron input, full chemical equilibrium, and the hadron type
dependent eigenvolume interactions is employed to fit the hadron mid-rapidity
yield data of ALICE Collaboration for the most central Pb+Pb collisions. For
the case of point-like hadrons the well-known fit result $T = 154 \pm 2$ MeV is
reproduced. However, the situation changes if hadrons have different
eigenvolumes. In the case when all mesons are point-like while all baryons have
an effective hard-core radius of 0.3 fm the $\chi^2$ temperature dependence of
the $\chi^2$ has a broad minimum in the temperature range of $155-210$ MeV,
with fit quality comparable to the $T \sim 155$ MeV minimum in the
point-particle case. Very similar result is obtained when only baryon-baryon
eigenvolume interactions are considered, with eigenvolume parameter taken from
previous fit to ground state of nuclear matter. Finally, when we apply the
eigenvolume corrections with mass-proportional eigenvolume $v_i \sim m_i$,
fixed to particular proton hard-core radius $r_p$, we observe a second minimum
in the temperature dependence of the $\chi^2$, located at the significantly
higher temperatures. For instance, at $r_p = 0.5$ fm the fit quality is better
than in the point-particle HRG case in a very wide temperature range of
$170-320$ MeV, which gives an uncertainty in the temperature determination from
the fit to the data of 150 MeV. These results show that thermal fits to the
heavy-ion hadron yield data are very sensitive to the modeling of the
short-range repulsion eigenvolume between hadrons, and that chemical freeze-out
temperature can be extracted from the LHC hadron yield data only with sizable
uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05619</id><created>2016-01-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbach</keyname><forenames>H. Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Shaping the focal field of radially/azimuthally polarized phase vortex
  with Zernike polynomials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/6/065608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The focal field properties of radially/azimuthally polarized Zernike
polynomials are studied. A method to design the pupil field in order to shape
the focal field of radially or azimuthally polarized phase vortex is
introduced. With this method, we are able to obtain a pupil field to achieve a
longitudinally polarized hollow spot with a depth of focus up to $12\lambda$
and $0.14\lambda$ lateral resolution for a optical system with numerical
aperture 0.99; A pupil field to generate 8 circularly polarized focal spots
along the optical axis is also obtained with this method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07942</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Luke F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippuner</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duez</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faber</keyname><forenames>Joshua A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foucart</keyname><forenames>Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lombardi</keyname><forenames>James C.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Sandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Christian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponce</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author></authors><title>The Influence of Neutrinos on r-Process Nucleosynthesis in the Ejecta of
  Black Hole-Neutron Star Mergers</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the merger of a black hole and a neutron star, baryonic mass can
become unbound from the system. Because the ejected material is extremely
neutron-rich, the r-process rapidly synthesizes heavy nuclides as the material
expands and cools. In this work, we map general relativistic models of black
hole-neutron star (BHNS) mergers into a Newtonian smoothed particle
hydrodynamics (SPH) code and follow the evolution of the thermodynamics and
morphology of the ejecta until the outflows become homologous. We investigate
how the subsequent evolution depends on our mapping procedure and find that the
results are robust. Using thermodynamic histories from the SPH particles, we
then calculate the expected nucleosynthesis in these outflows while varying the
level of neutrino irradiation coming from the postmerger accretion disk. We
find that the ejected material robustly produces r-process nucleosynthesis even
for unrealistically high neutrino luminosities, due to the rapid velocities of
the outflow. Nonetheless, we find that neutrinos can have an impact on the
detailed pat- tern of the r-process nucleosynthesis. Electron neutrinos are
captured by neutrons to produce protons while neutron capture is occurring. The
produced protons rapidly form low mass seed nuclei for the r-process. These low
mass seeds are eventually incorporated into the first r-process peak at A~78,
producing mainly Ge and Se. We consider the mechanism of this process in detail
and discuss if it can impact galactic chemical evolution of the first peak
r-process nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08145</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xi</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Nandini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbach</keyname><forenames>H. Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation of radiationless anapole mode of isotropic dielectric
  nanoparticles with tightly focused radially polarized beam</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.000799</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A high index dielectric nano-sphere can be excited and yet remain
radiationless. A method to excite the non-radiating anapole mode of a high
index isotropic dielectric nanosphere is presented. With tightly focused
radially polarized beam illumination, the main-contributing electric dipole
mode and magnetic modes can be zero with only a weak electric quadruple
contributing to the total scattering. Further, with a standing wave
illumination formed by two counter-propagating focused radially polarized beam
under $4\pi$ configuration, the ideal radiationless ananpole can be excited.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02453</id><created>2016-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Harbour</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>NRC Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dharma-wardana</keyname><forenames>M. W. C.</forenames><affiliation>NRC Canada</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Klug</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A critical assessment of models of pair-interactions and screening used
  in analyzing recent warm-dense matter (WDM) experiments</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>five figures, four pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E, vol. 94, issue 5, pages 053211 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.053211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra-fast laser experiments yield increasingly reliable data on warm-dense
matter (WDM), but rely on entrenched simplistic theoretical models. We
re-analyze two topical experiments, avoiding (i) {\it ad hoc} core-repulsion
models, (ii) &quot;Yukawa screening&quot; models and (iii) electron-ion equilibrium
assumptions. An accurate, rapid density-functional neutral-pseudoatom model
coupled to a hyper-netted-chain (HNC) equation with a bridge term is used to
compute structure factors, X-Ray scattering, compressibility, phonons and
resistivity. Electronic-structure codes are used to confirm the calculations.
The Yukawa and core-repulsion models are shown to be misleading.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03873</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Visinelli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflating without a flat potential: Viscous inflation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>4 pages, references added, results unchanged with respect to version
  1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bulk viscosity leads to negative pressure, which is a key ingredient for
successful inflation. We build an inflationary model where the slow-roll of the
inflaton field is driven by a viscous component instead of the flat potential
commonly used. Since viscosity does not contribute to the energy density of the
Universe, the Hubble rate depends only on the kinetic energy of the inflaton.
The power spectrum is almost scale-invariant, with a tilt depending on the
slow-roll parameters defined within the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07848</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07848</id><created>2016-04-26</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Luke F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Christian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haas</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Evan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diener</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnetter</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>General Relativistic Three-Dimensional Multi-Group Neutrino
  Radiation-Hydrodynamics Simulations of Core-Collapse Supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted to ApJ</comments><report-no>YITP-16-54</report-no><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/831/1/98</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a set of long-term general-relativistic three-dimensional (3D)
multi-group (energy-dependent) neutrino-radiation hydrodynamics simulations of
core-collapse supernovae. We employ a full 3D two-moment scheme with the local
M1 closure, three neutrino species, and 12 energy groups per species. With
this, we follow the post-core-bounce evolution of the core of a nonrotating
$27$-$M_\odot$ progenitor in full unconstrained 3D and in octant symmetry for
$\gtrsim$$ 380\,\mathrm{ms}$. We find the development of an asymmetric runaway
explosion in our unconstrained simulation. We test the resolution dependence of
our results and, in agreement with previous work, find that low resolution
artificially aids explosion and leads to an earlier runaway expansion of the
shock. At low resolution, the octant and full 3D dynamics are qualitatively
very similar, but at high resolution, only the full 3D simulation exhibits the
onset of explosion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01370</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gim&#xe9;nez</keyname><forenames>Marcos H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salinas</keyname><forenames>Isabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro-Palacio</keyname><forenames>Juan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Tejedor</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monsoriu</keyname><forenames>Juan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Visualizing acoustical beats with a smartphones</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, a new Physics laboratory experiment on Acoustics beats is
presented. We have designed a simple experimental setup to study superposition
of sound waves of slightly different frequencies (acoustic beat). The
microphone of a smartphone is used to capture the sound waves emitted by two
equidistant speakers from the mobile which are at the same time connected to
two AC generators. The smartphone is used as a measuring instrument. By means
of a simple and free AndroidTM application, the sound level (in dB) as a
function of time is measured and exported to a .csv format file. Applying
common graphing analysis and a fitting procedure, the frequency of the beat is
obtained. The beat frequencies as obtained from the smartphone data are
compared with the difference of the frequencies set at the AC generator. A very
good agreement is obtained being the percentage discrepancies within 1 %.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01922</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yi-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Fang-qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>An analogous Wu-Yang monopole in superfluid</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.optics</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to a crucial sign
  error in some equations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By identifying the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation with the hydrodynamic equations
in superfluid ${^3}$He, the effective potential is introduced in the
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation to solve the quantum pressure in steady state. The
pure gauge velocity solutions of hydrodynamic equations provide an analogous
Wu-Yang monopole potential. The two cases of velocity in superfluid are
equivalent to the two regions of Wu-Yang monopole potential. Due to the
compressibility of superfluid, the physical models are limited, such as hard
core and harmonic oscillator. It is important that the constraint condition of
$\nabla\rho\cdot \textbf{v}=0$ plays a key role, which determines that the
integral quantum numbers are selected in monopole harmonics and shows the
special analogous Wu-Yang monopole. The results provide a new possibility for
the simulation of Wu-Yang monopole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02622</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Udalov</keyname><forenames>O. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beloborodov</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of the Coulomb interaction on the exchange coupling in
  granular magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29 (2017) 155801 (14pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa6181</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a theory of the exchange interaction between ferromagnetic (FM)
metallic grains embedded into insulating matrix by taking into account the
Coulomb blockade effects. For bulk ferromagnets separated by the insulating
layer the exchange interaction strongly depends on the height and thickness of
the tunneling barrier created by the insulator. We show that for FM grains
embedded into insulating matrix the exchange coupling additionally depends on
the dielectric properties of this matrix due to the Coulomb blockade effects.
In particular, the FM coupling decreases with decreasing the dielectric
permittivity of insulating matrix. We find that the change in the exchange
interaction due to the Coulomb blockade effects can be a few tens of percent.
Also, we study dependence of the intergrain exchange interaction on the grain
size and other parameters of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06170</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rico</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sab&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement of superconducting qubits via acceleration radiation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 + 2 pages, 5 + 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 657 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-00770-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that simulated relativistic motion can generate entanglement between
artificial atoms and protect them from spontaneous emission. We consider a pair
of superconducting qubits coupled to a resonator mode, where the modulation of
the coupling strength can mimic the harmonic motion of the qubits at
relativistic speeds, generating acceleration radiation. We find the optimal
feasible conditions for generating a stationary entangled state between the
qubits when they are initially prepared in their ground state. Furthermore, we
analyze the effects of motion on the probability of spontaneous emission in the
standard scenarios of single-atom and two-atom superradiance, where one or two
excitations are initially present. Finally, we show that relativistic motion
induces sub-radiance and can generate a Zeno-like effect, preserving the
excitations from radiative decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06637</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mohammedi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>Tim. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A solvable double well</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><comments>This paper is withdrawn because the model is already treated in a
  substantially similar way in Merzbacher's text-book</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum behaviour of a particle moving in a one-dimensional
double well potential. This double well is obtained by gluing together, at the
origin, two shifted harmonic oscillator potentials. The Schr\&quot;odinger equation
is exactly solvable. The requirement that discontinuities, in the wavefunction
and its first derivative, are absent at the origin, leads to the quantisation
of the energy eigenvalues. We also show that oscillations in time take place
between two nearby single harmonic oscillator ground states. Finally, the
double well potential is augmented by a Dirac delta-function potentials at the
origin and the corresponding Schr\&quot;odinger equation is solved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08329</id><created>2016-06-27</created><authors><author><keyname>L&#xf6;ffler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bugnet</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauquelin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazar</keyname><forenames>Sorin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Assmann</keyname><forenames>Elias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botton</keyname><forenames>Gianluigi A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schattschneider</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-space mapping of electronic orbitals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Ultramicroscopy 177 (2017) 26</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ultramic.2017.01.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electronic states are responsible for most material properties, including
chemical bonds, electrical and thermal conductivity, as well as optical and
magnetic properties. Experimentally, however, they remain mostly elusive. Here,
we report the real-space mapping of selected transitions between p and d states
on the {\AA}ngstr\&quot;om scale in bulk rutile (TiO2) using electron energy-loss
spectrometry (EELS), revealing information on individual bonds between atoms.
On the one hand, this enables the experimental verification of theoretical
predictions about electronic states. On the other hand, it paves the way for
directly investigating electronic states under conditions that are at the limit
of the current capabilities of numerical simulations such as, e.g., the
electronic states at defects, interfaces, and quantum dots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08458</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hals</keyname><forenames>Kjetil M. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetoelectric coupling in superconductor-helimagnet heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Final version accepted by Physical Review B</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134504 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Ginzburg-Landau free energy of a conventional superconductor coupled to a
helimagnet is microscopically derived using functional field integral
techniques. We show that the spin texture leads to a Lifshitz invariant in the
free energy, which couples the momentum density of the superconducting
condensate to the magnetization of the helimagnet. For helimagnets with a
conical texture, the Lifshitz invariant yields a spatial modulation of the
superconducting phase along the helical wavevector of the magnetic texture.
Based on self-consistent numerical calculations, we verify the theoretical
formalism by investigating a superconductor that contains a helical
Yu-Shiba-Rusinov (YSR) chain. We demonstrate that the texture-induced
magnetoelectric coupling produces a strong supercurrent along the YSR chain,
which induces a detectable magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09306</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wilce</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>A Royal Road to Quantum Theory (or Thereabouts)</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 3 figures. An expanded and somewhat informal account of
  material from arXiv:1206:2897, plus some new results. A number of typos and
  other minor errors are corrected in version 2</comments><msc-class>Q1P16, Q1P45, 17C90</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper fails to derive quantum mechanics from a few simple postulates.
But it gets very close --- and it does so without much exertion. More exactly,
I obtain a representation of finite-dimensional probabilistic systems in terms
of euclidean Jordan algebras, in a strikingly easy way, from simple
assumptions. This provides a framework within which real, complex and
quaternionic QM can play happily together, and allows some --- but not too much
--- room for more exotic alternatives. (This is a leisurely summary, based on
recent lectures, of material from the papers arXiv:1206:2897 and
arXiv:1507.06278, the latter joint work with Howard Barnum and Matthew Graydon.
Some further ideas are also explored.)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00313</id><created>2016-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>Prarit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amariti</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on S-folds and $\mathcal{N}=3$ theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider D3 branes in presence of an S-fold plane. The latter is a non
perturbative object, arising from the combined projection of an S-duality twist
and a discrete orbifold of the R-symmetry group. This construction naively
gives rise to 4d $\mathcal{N}=3$ SCFTs. Nevertheless it has been observed that
in some cases supersymmetry is enhanced to $\mathcal{N}=4$. In this paper we
study the explicit counting of degrees of freedom arising from vector
multiplets associated to strings suspended between the D3 branes probing the
S-fold. We propose that, for trivial discrete torsion, there is no vector
multiplet associated to $(1,0)$ strings stretched between a brane and its
image. We then focus on the case of rank 2 $\mathcal{N}=3$ theory that enhances
to $SU(3)$ $\mathcal{N}=4$ SYM, explicitly spelling out the isomorphism between
the BPS-spectrum of the manifestly $\mathcal{N}=3$ theory and that of three D3
branes in flat spacetime. Subsequently, we consider 3-pronged strings in these
setups and show how wall-crossing in the S-fold background implies wall
crossing in the flat geometry. This can be considered a consistency check of
the \emph{conjectured} SUSY enhancement. We also find that the above
isomorphism implies that a $(1,0)$ string, suspended between a brane and its
image in the S-fold, corresponds to a 3-string junction in the flat geometry.
This is in agreement with our claim on the absence of a vector multiplet
associated to such $(1,0)$ strings. This is because the 3-string junction in
flat geometry gives rise to a $1/4$-th BPS multiplet of the $\mathcal{N}=4$
algebra. Such multiplets always include particles with spin $&gt;1$ as opposed to
a vector multiplet which is restricted by the requirement that the spins must
be $\leq 1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00403</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Udalov</keyname><forenames>O. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beloborodov</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic theory of the Coulomb based exchange coupling in magnetic
  tunnel junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29 (2017) 175804 (16pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa6647</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study interlayer exchange coupling (IEC) based on the many-body Coulomb
interaction between conduction electrons in magnetic tunnel junction (MTJ).
This mechanism complements the known IEC based on virtual electron hopping (or
spin currents). We find that these two mechanisms have different behavior on
system parameters. The Coulomb based IEC may exceed the hopping based exchange
coupling. We show that the Coulomb based exchange coupling, in contrast to the
hopping based coupling, depends strongly on the dielectric constant of the
insulating layer. The dependence of the IEC on the dielectric properties of the
insulating layer in MTJ is similar to magneto-electric (ME) effect where
electric and magnetic degrees of freedom are coupled. We calculate the IEC as a
function of temperature and electric field for MTJ with ferroelectric (FE)
layer and show that IEC has a sharp decrease in the vicinity of the FE phase
transition and varies strongly with external electric field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01671</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2017-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Hanyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shaomin</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery potential for supernova relic neutrinos with slow liquid
  scintillator detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 769 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.03.071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Detection of supernova relic neutrinos could provide key support for our
current understanding of stellar and cosmological evolution, and precise
measurements of these neutrinos could yield novel insights into the universe.
In this paper, we studied the detection potential of supernova relic neutrinos
using linear alkyl benzene (LAB) as a slow liquid scintillator. The linear
alkyl benzene features good separation of Cherenkov and scintillation lights,
thereby providing a new route for particle identification. We further addressed
key issues in current experiments, including (1) the charged current background
of atmospheric neutrinos in water Cherenkov detectors and (2) the neutral
current background of atmospheric neutrinos in typical liquid scintillator
detectors. A kiloton-scale LAB detector at Jinping with $\mathcal{O}$(10) years
of data could discover supernova relic neutrinos with a sensitivity comparable
to that of large-volume water Cherenkov detectors, typical liquid scintillator
detectors, and liquid argon detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02671</id><created>2016-07-09</created><updated>2017-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>The IceCube-Gen2</forenames></author></authors><title>PINGU: A Vision for Neutrino and Particle Physics at the South Pole</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>28 pages, 10 figures, submitted to J. Phys. G</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G44, 054006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/44/5/054006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Precision IceCube Next Generation Upgrade (PINGU) is a proposed
low-energy in-fill extension to the IceCube Neutrino Observatory. With
detection technology modeled closely on the successful IceCube example, PINGU
will provide a 6Mton effective mass for neutrino detection with an energy
threshold of a few GeV. With an unprecedented sample of over 60,000 atmospheric
neutrinos per year in this energy range, PINGU will make highly competitive
measurements of neutrino oscillation parameters in an energy range over an
order of magnitude higher than long-baseline neutrino beam experiments. PINGU
will measure the mixing parameters $\theta_{\rm 23}$ and $\Delta m^2_{\rm 32}$,
including the octant of $\theta_{\rm 23}$ for a wide range of values, and
determine the neutrino mass ordering at $3\sigma$ median significance within 4
years of operation. PINGU's high precision measurement of the rate of
${\nu_\tau}$ appearance will provide essential tests of the unitarity of the
$3\times 3$ PMNS neutrino mixing matrix. PINGU will also improve the
sensitivity of searches for low mass dark matter in the Sun, use neutrino
tomography to directly probe the composition of the Earth's core, and improve
IceCube's sensitivity to neutrinos from Galactic supernovae. Reoptimization of
the PINGU design has permitted substantial reduction in both cost and
logistical requirements while delivering performance nearly identical to
configurations previously studied. This document summarizes the results of
detailed studies described in a more comprehensive document to be released
soon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03329</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Azinovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Marlon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herr</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heim</keyname><forenames>Bettina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troyer</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Assessment of Quantum Annealing for the Construction of Satisfiability
  Filters</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Submission to SciPost</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 2, 013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.2.2.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Satisfiability filters, introduced by S. A. Weaver et al. in 2014, are a new
and promising type of filters to address set membership testing. In order to
construct satisfiability filters, it is necessary to find disparate solutions
to hard random $k$-SAT problems. This paper compares simulated annealing,
simulated quantum annealing and walkSAT, an open-source SAT solver, in terms of
their ability to find such solutions. The results indicate that solutions found
by simulated quantum annealing are generally less disparate than solutions
found by the other solvers and therefore less useful for the construction of
satisfiability filters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04258</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shuve</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peskin</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Revision of the LHCb Limit on Majorana Neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure; v2 includes improvements suggested by the referee
  and refers to a revised result from Belle</comments><report-no>SLAC--PUB--16768</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 113007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.113007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the recent limits from LHCb on a Majorana neutrino N in the mass
range 250 - 5000 MeV. These limits are among the best currently available, and
they will be improved soon by the addition of data from Run 2 of the LHC. LHCb
presented a model-independent constraint on the rate of like-sign leptonic
decays, and then derived a constraint on the mixing angle V{\mu}4 based on a
theoretical model for the B decay width to N and the N lifetime. The model used
is unfortunately unsound. We revise the conclusions of the paper based on a
decay model similar to the one used for the tau lepton and provide formulae
useful for future analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05277</id><created>2016-07-18</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Else</keyname><forenames>Dominic V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Bela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Chetan</forenames></author></authors><title>Pre-thermal phases of matter protected by time-translation symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>Published version, with new title and introduction</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 011026 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.011026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a periodically driven (Floquet) system, there is the possibility for new
phases of matter, not present in stationary systems, protected by discrete
time-translation symmetry. This includes topological phases protected in part
by time-translation symmetry, as well as phases distinguished by the
spontaneous breaking of this symmetry, dubbed &quot;Floquet time crystals&quot;. We show
that such phases of matter can exist in the pre-thermal regime of
periodically-driven systems, which exists generically for sufficiently large
drive frequency, thereby eliminating the need for integrability or strong
quenched disorder that limited previous constructions. We prove a theorem that
states that such a pre-thermal regime persists until times that are nearly
exponentially-long in the ratio of certain couplings to the drive frequency. By
similar techniques, we can also construct stationary systems which
spontaneously break *continuous* time-translation symmetry. We argue
furthermore that for driven systems coupled to a cold bath, the pre-thermal
regime could potentially persist to infinite time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05637</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Barnali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Kaushik</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-minimally coupled dark fluid in Schwarzschild spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures, latex file. New material added, modifications
  done and typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2017) 49:63</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-017-2226-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If one assumes a particular form of non-minimal coupling, called the
conformal coupling, of a perfect fluid with gravity in the fluid-gravity
Lagrangian then one gets modified Einstein field equation. In the modified
Einstein equation, the effect of the non-minimal coupling does not vanish if
one works with spacetimes for which the Ricci scalar vanishes. In the present
work we use the Schwarzschild metric in the modified Einstein equation, in
presence of non-minimal coupling with a fluid, and find out the energy-density
and pressure of the fluid. In the present case the perfect fluid is part of the
solution of the modified Einstein equation. We also solve the modified Einstein
equation, using the flat spacetime metric and show that in presence of
non-minimal coupling one can accommodate a perfect fluid of uniform
energy-density and pressure in the flat spacetime. In both the cases the fluid
pressure turns out to be negative. Except these non-trivial solutions it must
be noted that the vacuum solutions also remain as trivial valid solutions of
the modified Einstein equation in presence of non-minimal coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05655</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>LeBlanc</keyname><forenames>J. P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gull</keyname><forenames>Emanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Knight shifts, nuclear spin-relaxation rates, and spin echo decay times
  in the pseudogap regime of the cuprates: Simulation and relation to
  experiment</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages,4 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/ncomms14986</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the temperature and doping evolution of the NMR Knight shift, spin
relaxation rate, and spin echo decay time in the pseudogap regime of the
two-dimensional Hubbard model for parameters believed to be relevant to cuprate
superconductors using cluster dynamical mean field theory. We recover the
suppression of the Knight shift seen in experiment upon entering the pseudogap
regime and find agreement between single and two-particle measures of the
pseudogap onset temperature. The simulated spin-echo decay time shows a linear
in T behavior at high T which flattens off as T is lowered, and increases as
doping is increased. The relaxation rate shows a marked increase as T is
lowered but no indication of a pseudogap on the Cu site, and a clear downturn
on the O site, consistent with experimental results on single layer materials
but different from double layer materials. The consistency of the simulated
susceptibilities with experiment, along with similar agreement on the
single-particle level and the absence of long-range order and symmetry breaking
suggests that the pseudogap is well described by strong short-range correlation
effects and that long-range order and multi-orbital effects are not required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05354</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaboriaud</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinet</keyname><forenames>Luc</forenames></author></authors><title>An algebraic interpretation of the $q$-Meixner polynomials</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages Added AMS classification numbers, a few references and
  thanks for useful comments on 1st version</comments><msc-class>33D45, 81R50</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s11139-017-9908-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An algebraic interpretation of the $q$-Meixner polynomials is obtained. It is
based on representations of $\mathcal{U}_q(\mathfrak{su}(1,1))$ on
$q$-oscillator states with the polynomials appearing as matrix elements of
unitary $q$-pseudorotation operators. These operators are built from
$q$-exponentials of the $\mathcal{U}_q(\mathfrak{su}(1,1))$ generators. The
orthogonality, recurrence relation, difference equation, and other properties
of the $q$-Mexiner polynomials are systematically obtained in the proposed
framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08794</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-09-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Jacky</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paraskevas</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Distinguishing between MSSM and NMSSM through $\Delta F=2$ processes</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>30 pp. text, 13 pp. appendix. Phrase &quot;Recent limits&quot; replaced by the
  more appropriate &quot;LHC Run-I limits&quot; due to new data becoming available from
  ATLAS, CMS. Note added with a brief discussion on these preliminary results.
  Refs added</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2016)134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study deviations between MSSM and $Z_3$-invariant NMSSM, with respect to
their predictions in $\Delta F=2 $ processes. We find that potentially
significant effects arise either from the well known double-penguin diagrams,
due to the extra scalar NMSSM states, or from neutralino-gluino box
contributions, due to the extended neutralino sector. Both are discussed to be
effective in the large $\tan\beta$ regime. Enhanced genuine-NMSSM contributions
in double penguins are expected for a light singlet spectrum (CP-even,CP-odd),
while the magnitude of box effects is primarily controlled through singlino
mixing. The latter is found to be typically subleading (but non-negligible) for
$\lambda \lesssim 0.5$, however it can become dominant for $\lambda\sim
\mathcal{O}(1)$. We also study the low $\tan\beta$ regime, where a distinction
between MSSM and NMSSM can come instead due to experimental constraints, acting
differently on the allowed parameter space of each model. To this end, we
incorporate the LHC Run-I limits from $H\rightarrow Z Z$, $A \rightarrow hZ$
and $H^\pm \rightarrow \tau \nu $ non-observation along with Higgs observables
and set (different) upper bounds for new physics contributions in $\Delta F=2 $
processes. We find that a $\sim 25\%$ contribution in $\Delta M_{s(d)}$ is
still possible for MFV models, however such a large effect is nowadays severely
constrained for the case of MSSM, due to stronger bounds on the charged Higgs
masses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03185</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Jiafeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>D. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Xiaohui</forenames></author></authors><title>A large enhancement of carrier mobility in phosphorene by introducing
  hexagonal boron nitride substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Carrier mobility is a crucial character for electronic devices since it
domains power dissipation and switching speed. Materials with certain high
carrier mobility, equally, unveil rich unusual physical phenomena elusive in
their conventional counterparts. As a consequence, the methods to enhance the
carrier mobility of materials receive immense research interests due to their
potential applications in more effective electronic devices and enrichment of
more unusual phenomena. For instance, introducing a flat hexagonal boron
nitride (h-BN) substrate to enhance the carrier mobility has been achieved
experimentally. However, the underlying mechanics is not well understood. In
this study, we estimate the carrier mobility of phosphorene on h-BN substrate
(P/h-BN) within the framework of the phonon-limited scattering model at
first-principles level. %Our results are generic. Besides high-$\kappa$
dielectric property, h-BN also possesses excellent mechanical property of a
high two-dimensional elastic modulus. The P/h-BN heterostructure inherits the
high elastic modulus of h-BN, leading to an enhanced carrier mobility in
phosphorene. Owing to the weak van der Waals interactions between the layers,
the unique electronic properties of phosphorene are almost perfectly preserved
near the Fermi level, guaranteeing the superior electronic transport in P/h-BN.
Our findings offer a new perspective to improve the carrier mobility in
phosphorene as well as other 2D materials based field effect transistors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03432</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-03-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spurgeon</keyname><forenames>Steven R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Yingge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chambers</keyname><forenames>Scott A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement Error in Atomic-Scale STEM-EDS Mapping of a Model Oxide
  Interface</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures; revised during peer-review</comments><doi>10.1017/S1431927617000368</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the development of affordable aberration-correctors, analytical scanning
transmission electron microscopy (STEM) studies of complex interfaces can now
be conducted at high spatial resolution at laboratories worldwide.
Energy-dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (STEM-EDS) in particular has grown in
popularity, since it enables elemental mapping over a wide range of ionization
energies. However, the interpretation of atomically-resolved data is greatly
complicated by beam-sample interactions that are often overlooked by novice
users. Here we describe the practical factors---namely, sample thickness and
the choice of ionization edge---that affect the quantification of a model
perovskite oxide interface. Our measurements of the same sample in regions of
different thickness indicate that interface profiles can vary by as much as 2-5
unit cells, depending on the spectral feature. This finding is supported by
multislice simulations, which reveal that on-axis maps of even perfectly abrupt
interfaces exhibit significant delocalization. Quantification of thicker
samples is further complicated by channeling to heavier sites across the
interface, as well as an increased signal background. We show that extreme care
must be taken to prepare samples to minimize channeling effects and argue that
it may not be possible to extract atomically-resolved information from many
chemical maps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07585</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the $ZZ$ production cross section in $pp$ collisions at
  $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV using the $ZZ\to\ell^{-}\ell^{+}\ell^{\prime
  -}\ell^{\prime +}$ and $ZZ\to\ell^{-}\ell^{+}\nu\bar{\nu}$ channels with the
  ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>55 pages in total, author list starting page 39, 9 figures, 11
  tables, accepted for publication in JHEP. All figures including auxiliary
  figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2014-16/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-194</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 01 (2017) 099</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement of the $ZZ$ production in the $\ell^{-}\ell^{+}\ell^{\prime
-}\ell^{\prime +}$ and $\ell^{-}\ell^{+}\nu\bar{\nu}$ channels $(\ell = e,
\mu)$ in proton--proton collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV at the Large Hadron
Collider at CERN, using data corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 20.3
fb$^{-1}$ collected by the ATLAS experiment in 2012 is presented. The fiducial
cross sections for $ZZ\to\ell^{-}\ell^{+}\ell^{\prime -}\ell^{\prime +}$ and
$ZZ\to \ell^{-}\ell^{+}\nu\bar{\nu}$ are measured in selected phase-space
regions. The total cross section for $ZZ$ events produced with both $Z$ bosons
in the mass range 66 to 116 GeV is measured from the combination of the two
channels to be
$7.3\pm0.4\textrm{(stat)}\pm0.3\textrm{(syst)}\pm0.2\textrm{(lumi)}$ pb, which
is consistent with the Standard Model prediction of $6.6^{+0.7}_{-0.6}$ pb. The
differential cross sections in bins of various kinematic variables are
presented. The differential event yield as a function of the transverse
momentum of the leading $Z$ boson is used to set limits on anomalous neutral
triple gauge boson couplings in $ZZ$ production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08755</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kostelecky</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunghi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vieira</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz violation and deep inelastic scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, version published in Physics Letters B</comments><report-no>IUHET 615, October 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B 769: 272-280, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.03.047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects of quark-sector Lorentz violation on deep inelastic
electron-proton scattering are studied. We show that existing data can be used
to establish first constraints on numerous coefficients for Lorentz violation
in the quark sector at an estimated sensitivity of parts in a million.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09805</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naidon</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Endo</keyname><forenames>Shimpei</forenames></author></authors><title>Efimov Physics: a review</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas nucl-th physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>97 pages, 31 figures. Added a few sections and many corrections.
  Improved presentation</comments><journal-ref>Rep. Prog. Phys. 80 056001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6633/aa50e8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article reviews theoretical and experimental advances in Efimov physics,
an array of quantum few-body and many-body phenomena arising for particles
interacting via short-range resonant interactions, that is based on the
appearance of a scale-invariant three-body attraction theoretically discovered
by Vitaly Efimov in 1970. This three-body effect was originally proposed to
explain the binding of nuclei such as the triton and the Hoyle state of
carbon-12, and later considered as a simple explanation for the existence of
some halo nuclei. It was subsequently evidenced in trapped ultra-cold atomic
clouds and in diffracted molecular beams of gaseous helium. These experiments
revealed that the previously undetermined three-body parameter introduced in
the Efimov theory to stabilise the three-body attraction typically scales with
the range of atomic interactions. The few- and many-body consequences of the
Efimov attraction have been since investigated theoretically, and are expected
to be observed in a broader spectrum of physical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01014</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barsan</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>New applications of the Lambert and generalized Lambert functions to
  ferromagnetism and quantum mechanics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figures</comments><msc-class>33, 78, 81</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The applications of the recent results obtained in the theory of generalized
Lambert functions, to the mean field theory of ferromagnetism are presented. As
a consequence, all the predictions of the Weiss theory of ferromagnetism can be
explicitly and exactly formulated. In several quantum mechanical problems
involving delta function potentials, the solutions of the transcendental
eigenvalue equations are expressed in terms of two parameters generalized
Lambert functions. Some others, till unnoticed examples of eigenvalue equations
whose solutions can be written using the Lambert W function, are also
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01183</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2016-12-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boudjemaa</keyname><forenames>Abdelaali</forenames></author></authors><title>Unconventional superfluids of fermionic polar molecules in a bilayer
  system</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A 381, 1745 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.03.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study unconventional superfluids of fermionic polar molecules in a
two-dimensional bilayer system with dipoles are head-to-tail across the layers.
We analyze the critical temperature of several unconventional pairings as a
function of different system parameters. The peculiar competition between the
$d$- and the $s$- wave pairings is discussed. We show that the experimental
observation of such unconventional superfluids requires ulralow temperatures,
which opens up new possibilities to realize several topological phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01483</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rivas</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;ngel</forenames></author></authors><title>Refined Weak Coupling Limit: Coherence, Entanglement and
  Non-Markovianity</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>RevTex4 file, color figures. Close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the properties of a refined weak coupling limit that preserves
complete positivity in order to describe non-Markovian dynamics in the
spin-boson model. With this tool, we show the system presents a rich and new
non-Markovian phenomenology. This implies a dynamical difference between
entanglement and coherence: the latter undergoes revivals whereas the former
not, despite the induced dynamics being fully incoherent. In addition, the
evolution presents &quot;quasieternal&quot; non-Markovianity, becoming non-divisible at
any time period where the system evolves qualitatively. Furthermore, the method
allows for an exact derivation of a master equation that accounts for a
reversible energy exchange between system and environment. Specifically, this
is obtained in the form of a time-dependent Lamb shift term.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02430</id><created>2016-11-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Schiavon</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calderaro</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pittaluga</keyname><forenames>Mirko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallone</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villoresi</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-observer Bell inequality violation on a two-qubit entangled state</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Revtex, 5 pages + appendix</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Sci. Technol. 2 015010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa62be</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bipartite Bell inequalities can be simultaneously violated by two different
pairs of observers when weak measurements and signaling is employed. Here we
experimentally demonstrate the violation of two simultaneous CHSH inequalities
by exploiting a two-photon polarization maximally entangled state. Our results
demonstrate that large double violation is experimentally achievable. Our
demonstration may have impact for Quantum Key Distribution or certification of
Quantum Random Number generators based on weak measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.04263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.04263</id><created>2016-11-14</created><updated>2017-03-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Zongjian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Qi-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Shu-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Transition between strong and weak topological insulator in ZrTe$_5$ and
  HfTe$_5$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7 45667 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep45667</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ZrTe$_5$ and HfTe$_5$ have attracted increasingly attention recently since
the theoretical prediction of being topological insulators (TIs). However,
subsequent works show many contradictions about their topological nature.Three
possible phases, i.e. strong TI, weak TI, and Dirac semi-metal, have been
observed in different experiments until now. Essentially whether ZrTe$_5$ or
HfTe$_5$ has a band gap or not is still a question. Here, we present detailed
first-principles calculations on the electronic and topological properties of
ZrTe$_5$ and HfTe$_5$ on variant volumes and clearly demonstrate the
topological phase transition from a strong TI, going through an intermediate
Dirac semi-metal phase, then to a weak TI when the crystal expands.Our work
might give a unified explain about the divergent experimental results and
propose the crucial clue to further experiments to elucidate the topological
nature of these materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06690</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chhita</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames><affiliation>Bonn University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Spohn</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Technical University of Munich</affiliation></author></authors><title>Limit distributions for KPZ growth models with spatially homogeneous
  random initial conditions</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 7 figures, LaTeX</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For stationary KPZ growth in 1+1 dimensions the height fluctuations are
governed by the Baik-Rains distribution. Using the totally asymmetric single
step growth model, alias TASEP, we investigate height fluctuations for a
general class of spatially homogeneous random initial conditions. We prove that
for TASEP there is a one-parameter family of limit distributions, labeled by
the diffusion coefficient of the initial conditions. The distributions are
defined through a variational formula. We use Monte Carlo simulations to obtain
their numerical plots. Also discussed is the connection to the six-vertex model
at its conical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09463</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakai</keyname><forenames>Ryota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryu</keyname><forenames>Shinsei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Laughlin's argument for the quantized thermal Hall effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 165405 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.165405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend Laughlin's magnetic-flux-threading argument to the quantized
thermal Hall effect. A proper analogue of Laughlin's adiabatic magnetic-flux
threading process for the case of the thermal Hall effect is given in terms of
an external gravitational field. From the perspective of the edge theories of
quantum Hall systems, the quantized thermal Hall effect is closely tied to the
breakdown of large diffeomorphism invariance, that is, a global gravitational
anomaly. In addition, we also give an argument from the bulk perspective in
which a free energy, decomposed into its Fourier modes, is adiabatically
transferred under an adiabatic process involving external gravitational
perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01865</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Haber</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixing of charged and neutral Bose condensates at nonzero temperature
  and magnetic field</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>11 pages, contribution to the proceedings of &quot;Quark Confinement and
  the Hadron Spectrum XII&quot;, Aug 28 - Sep 4, 2016, in Thessaloniki, Greece; v2:
  small corrections in Eqs. (9) and (13), references added</comments><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713709003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is expected that in the interior of compact stars a proton superconductor
coexists with and couples to a neutron superfluid. Starting from a
field-theoretical model for two complex scalar fields - one of which is
electrically charged - we derive a Ginzburg-Landau potential which includes
entrainment between the two fluids and temperature effects from thermal
excitations of the two scalar fields and the gauge field. The Ginzburg-Landau
description is then used for an analysis of the phase structure in the presence
of an external magnetic field. In particular, we study the effect of the
superfluid on the flux tube phase by computing the various critical magnetic
fields and deriving an approximation for the flux tube interaction. As a
result, we point out differences to the naive expectations from an isolated
superconductor, for instance the existence of a first-order flux tube onset,
resulting in a more complicated phase structure in the region between type-I
and type-II superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02565</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nicolas</keyname><forenames>Bain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denis</keyname><forenames>Bartolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical mingling and universal correlations in model binary active
  liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, and supplementary material (7 pages, 3 figures)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ensembles of driven or motile bodies moving along opposite directions are
generically reported to self-organize into strongly anisotropic lanes. Here,
building on a minimal model of self-propelled bodies targeting opposite
directions, we first evidence a critical phase transition between a mingled
state and a phase-separated lane state specific to active particles. We then
demonstrate that the mingled state displays algebraic structural correlations
also found in driven binary mixtures. Finally, constructing a hydrodynamic
theory, we single out the physical mechanisms responsible for these universal
long-range correlations typical of ensembles of oppositely moving bodies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04397</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2016-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kennedy</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Callanan</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnavich</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fausnaugh</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinn</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>XMM-Newton Observations of the Peculiar Cataclysmic Variable Lanning
  386: X-ray evidence for a Magnetic Primary</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 466 (2): 2202-2211</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3282</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first X-ray observations of the eclipsing cataclysmic
variables Lanning 386 and MASTER OTJ192328.22+612413.5, possible SW Sextantis
systems. The X-ray light curve of Lanning 386 shows deep eclipses, similar to
the eclipses seen in the optical light curve, confirming the high inclination
of the system. There is evidence of a periodicity between 17-22 min in the
X-ray and optical light curves of Lanning 386, which is associated with
quasi-periodic oscillations. This system also displays a hard X-ray spectrum
which is well fit by a partially covered, absorbed 2 temperature plasma. The
cool plasma temperature (0.24$^{+0.17}_{-0.08}$ keV) and hot plasma temperature
(9$^{+4}_{-2}$ keV) are not atypical plasma temperatures of known intermediate
polar systems. Based on this model, we suggest that Lanning 386 is an
intermediate polar with a high accretion rate. The hot plasma temperature
limits the white dwarf mass to $&gt;$0.5 M$_{\odot}$. From the optical spectrum
obtained using the Large Binocular Telescope, we find that the secondary in the
system is consistent with an M5V star, and refine the distance to Lanning 386
to be 160$\pm$50 pc. Finally, we use the high time resolution of the optical
spectra to crudely constrain the magnetic moment of the white dwarf in Lanning
386. J1923 was not detected during the observations, but the upper limit on the
flux is inline with J1923 and Lanning 386 being related.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00491</id><created>2017-01-02</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buccella</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chianese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mangano</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miele</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morisi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santorelli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A neutrino mass-mixing sum rule from SO(10) and neutrinoless double beta
  decay</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. Version published in JEHP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1704 (2017) 004</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Minimal SO(10) grand unified models provide phenomenological predictions for
neutrino mass patterns and mixing. These are the outcome of the interplay of
several features, namely: i) the seesaw mechanism; ii) the presence of an
intermediate scale where B-L gauge symmetry is broken and the right-handed
neutrinos acquire a Majorana mass; iii) a symmetric Dirac neutrino mass matrix
whose pattern is close to the up-type quark one. In this framework two natural
characteristics emerge. Normal neutrino mass hierarchy is the only allowed, and
there is an approximate relation involving both light-neutrino masses and
mixing parameters. This differs from what occurring when horizontal flavour
symmetries are invoked. In this case, in fact, neutrino mixing or mass
relations have been separately obtained in literature. In this paper we discuss
an example of such comprehensive mixing-mass relation in a specific realization
of SO(10) and, in particular, analyse its impact on the expected neutrinoless
double beta decay effective mass parameter $\langle m_{ee} \rangle$, and on the
neutrino mass scale. Remarkably a lower limit for the lightest neutrino mass is
obtained ($m_{\rm lightest} \gtrsim 7.5 \times 10^{-4}$ eV, at 3 $\sigma$
level).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01372</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Danovich</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xf3;lyomi</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fal'ko</keyname><forenames>Vladimir I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark trions and biexcitons in WS2 and WSe2 made bright by e-e scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>29 pages including supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 45998, (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep45998</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The direct band gap character and large spin-orbit splitting of the valence
band edges (at the K and K' valleys) in monolayer transition metal
dichalcogenides have put these two-dimensional materials under the spot-light
of intense experimental and theoretical studies. In particular, for Tungsten
dichalcogenides it has been found that the sign of spin splitting of conduction
band edges makes ground state excitons radiatively inactive (dark) due to spin
and momentum mismatch between the constituent electron and hole. One might
similarly assume that the ground states of charged excitons and biexcitons in
these monolayers are also dark. Here, we show that the intervalley
K$\leftrightarrows$K' electron-electron scattering mixes bright and dark states
of these complexes, and estimate the radiative lifetimes in the ground states
of these &quot;semi-dark&quot; trions and biexcitons to be ~ 10ps, and analyse how these
complexes appear in the temperature-dependent photoluminescence spectra of WS2
and WSe2 monolayers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03347</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03347</id><created>2017-01-12</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buchert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>France</keyname><forenames>Martin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Model-independent analyses of non-Gaussianity in Planck CMB maps using
  Minkowski Functionals</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Invited article for focus issue &quot;Planck and fundamentals of
  cosmology&quot;, matches published version in Classical and Quantum Gravity, 55
  pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 094002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa5ce2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite the wealth of $Planck$ results, there are difficulties in
disentangling the primordial non-Gaussianity of the Cosmic Microwave Background
(CMB) from the secondary and the foreground non-Gaussianity (NG). For each of
these forms of NG the lack of complete data introduces model-dependencies.
Aiming at detecting the NGs of the CMB temperature anisotropy $\delta T$, while
paying particular attention to a model-independent quantification of NGs, our
analysis is based upon statistical and morphological univariate descriptors,
respectively: the probability density function $P(\delta T)$, related to
${\mathrm v}_{0}$, the first Minkowski Functional (MF), and the two other MFs,
${\mathrm v}_{1}$ and ${\mathrm v}_{2}$. From their analytical Gaussian
predictions we build the discrepancy functions $\Delta_{k}$ ($k=P,0,1,2$) which
are applied to an ensemble of $10^{5}$ CMB realization maps of the $\Lambda$CDM
model and to the $Planck$ CMB maps. In our analysis we use general Hermite
expansions of the $\Delta_{k}$ up to the $12^{th}$ order, where the
coefficients are explicitly given in terms of cumulants. Assuming hierarchical
ordering of the cumulants, we obtain the perturbative expansions generalizing
the $2^{nd}$ order expansions of Matsubara to arbitrary order in the standard
deviation $\sigma_0$ for $P(\delta T)$ and ${\mathrm v}_0$, where the
perturbative expansion coefficients are explicitly given in terms of complete
Bell polynomials. The comparison of the Hermite expansions and the perturbative
expansions is performed for the $\Lambda$CDM map sample and the $Planck$ data.
We confirm the weak level of non-Gaussianity ($1$-$2$)$\sigma$ of the
foreground corrected masked $Planck$ $2015$ maps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00491</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shekhar</keyname><forenames>Prashant</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malac</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaind</keyname><forenames>Vaibhav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalili</keyname><forenames>Neda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meldrum</keyname><forenames>Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacob</keyname><forenames>Zubin</forenames></author></authors><title>Momentum-resolved Electron Energy Loss Spectroscopy for Mapping the
  Photonic Density of States</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 Pages, 4 Figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong nanoscale light-matter interaction is often accompanied by
ultra-confined photonic modes and large momentum polaritons existing far beyond
the light cone. A direct probe of such phenomena is difficult due to the
momentum mismatch of these modes with free space light however, fast electron
probes can reveal the fundamental quantum and spatially dispersive behavior of
these excitations. Here, we use momentum-resolved electron energy loss
spectroscopy (q-EELS) in a transmission electron microscope to explore the
optical response of plasmonic thin films including momentum transfer up to
wavevectors (q) significantly exceeding the light line wave vector. We show
close agreement between experimental q-EELS maps, theoretical simulations of
fast electrons passing through thin films and the momentum-resolved photonic
density of states (q-PDOS) dispersion. Although a direct link between q-EELS
and the q-PDOS exists for an infinite medium, here we show fundamental
differences between q-EELS measurements and the q-PDOS that must be taken into
consideration for realistic finite structures with no translational invariance
along the direction of electron motion. Our work paves the way for using q-EELS
as the preeminent tool for mapping the q-PDOS of exotic phenomena with large
momenta (high-q) such as hyperbolic polaritons and spatially-dispersive
plasmons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04110</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grigoryan</keyname><forenames>Smbat</forenames></author></authors><title>Using the Tsallis distribution for hadron spectra in $pp$ collisions:
  Pions and quarkonia at $\sqrt{s}$ = 5--13000 GeV</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 20 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 056021 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.056021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A thermal model, based on the Tsallis distribution and blast-wave model, is
proposed to compute hadron double-differential spectra $d^{2}N/dp_{T}dy$ in
$pp$ (also high energy $p\overline{p}$) collisions. It successfully describes
the available experimental data on pion and quarkonia ($\phi$, $J/\psi$,
$\psi(2S)$, $\Upsilon$ family) production at energies from $\sqrt{s} = 5$ GeV
to the LHC ones. Simple parametrizations for the $\sqrt{s}$ dependence of the
model parameters are provided allowing predictions for the yields of these
particles at new collision energies. The model can be used also for the pion
Bose-Einstein correlation studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05400</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Braunstein</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muntoni</keyname><forenames>Anna Paola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagnani</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>An analytic approximation of the feasible space of metabolic networks</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.MN</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8 14915, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms14915</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assuming a steady-state condition within a cell, metabolic fluxes satisfy an
under-determined linear system of stoichiometric equations. Characterizing the
space of fluxes that satisfy such equations along with given bounds (and
possibly additional relevant constraints) is considered of utmost importance
for the understanding of cellular metabolism. Extreme values for each
individual flux can be computed with Linear Programming (as Flux Balance
Analysis), and their marginal distributions can be approximately computed with
Monte-Carlo sampling. Here we present an approximate analytic method for the
latter task based on Expectation Propagation equations that does not involve
sampling and can achieve much better predictions than other existing analytic
methods. The method is iterative, and its computation time is dominated by one
matrix inversion per iteration. With respect to sampling, we show through
extensive simulation that it has some advantages including computation time,
and the ability to efficiently fix empirically estimated distributions of
fluxes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06304</id><created>2017-02-21</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dremin</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A toy model of elastic scattering of high energy protons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>11 p</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ratio of elastic to total proton cross sections is related to the
darkness of the spatial profile of inelastic interactions by a single parameter
in the framework of a simple analytical model. Their critical values at LHC
energies are discussed. Two possible variants of their asymptotical behavior
are described.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06965</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eisenreich</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naab</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Ena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostriker</keyname><forenames>Jeremiah P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emsellem</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>AGN feedback, quiescence and CGM metal enrichment in early-type galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 15 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 468 (1): 751-768</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx473</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present three-dimensional hydrodynamical simulations showing the effect of
kinetic and radiative AGN feedback on a model galaxy representing a massive
quiescent low-redshift early-type galaxy of $M_* = 8.41\times 10^{10} M_\odot$,
harbouring a $M_\mathrm{BH} = 4\times 10^8 M_\odot $ black hole surrounded by a
cooling gaseous halo. We show that, for a total baryon fraction of $\sim 20\%$
of the cosmological value, feedback from the AGN can keep the galaxy quiescent
for about 4.35 Gyr and with properties consistent with black hole mass and
X-ray luminosity scaling relations. However, this can only be achieved if the
AGN feedback model includes both kinetic and radiative feedback modes. The
simulation with only kinetic feedback fails to keep the model galaxy fully
quiescent, while one with only radiative feedback leads to excessive black-hole
growth. For higher baryon fractions (e.g. 50\% of the cosmological value), the
X-ray luminosities exceed observed values by at least one order of magnitude,
and rapid cooling results in a star-forming galaxy. The AGN plays a major role
in keeping the circumgalactic gas at observed metallicities of $Z/Z_\odot
\gtrsim 0.3 $ within the central $\sim 30$ kpc by venting nuclear gas enriched
with metals from residual star formation activity. As indicated by previous
cosmological simulations, our results are consistent with a model for which the
black hole mass and the total baryon fraction are set at higher redshifts $z &gt;
1$ and the AGN alone can keep the model galaxy on observed scaling relations.
Models without AGN feedback violate both the quiescence criterion as well as
CGM metallicity constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07404</id><created>2017-02-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Accioly</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Almeida</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Brito</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correia</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalizability in $D$-dimensional higher-order gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Physical Review D</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple expression for calculating the classical potential concerning
$D$-dimensional gravitational models is obtained through a method based on the
generating functional. The prescription is then used as a mathematical tool to
probe the conjecture that renormalizable higher-order gravity models --- which
are, of course, nonunitary --- are endowed with a classical potential that is
nonsingular at the origin. It is also shown that the converse of this statement
is not true, which implies that the finiteness of the classical potential at
the origin is a necessary but not a sufficient condition for the
renormalizability of the model. The systems we have utilized to verify the
conjecture were fourth- and sixth- order gravity models in $D$-dimensions. A
discussion about the polemic question related to the renormalizability of new
massive gravity, which Oda claimed to be renormalizable in 2009 and three years
late was shown to be nonrenormalizable by Muneyuki and Ohta, is considered. We
remark that the solution of this issue is straightforward if the aforementioned
conjecture is employed. We point out that our analysis is restricted to local
models in which the propagator has simple and real poles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08467</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cormier</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bendo</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hony</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebouteiller</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madden</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galliano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glover</keyname><forenames>S. C. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klessen</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abel</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bigiel</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>New ALMA constraints on the star-forming ISM at low metallicity: A 50 pc
  view of the blue compact dwarf galaxy SBS0335-052</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>corrected typos</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Properties of the cold interstellar medium of low-metallicity galaxies are
not well-known due to the faintness and extremely small scale on which emission
is expected. We present deep ALMA band 6 (230GHz) observations of the nearby,
low-metallicity (12 + log(O/H) = 7.25) blue compact dwarf galaxy SBS0335-052 at
an unprecedented resolution of 0.2 arcsec (52 pc). The 12CO J=2-1 line is not
detected and we report a 3-sigma upper limit of LCO(2-1) = 3.6x10^4 K km/s
pc^2. Assuming that molecular gas is converted into stars with a given
depletion time, ranging from 0.02 to 2 Gyr, we find lower limits on the
CO-to-H2 conversion factor alpha_CO in the range 10^2-10^4 Msun pc^-2 (K
km/s)^-1. The continuum emission is detected and resolved over the two main
super star clusters. Re-analysis of the IR-radio spectral energy distribution
suggests that the mm-fluxes are not only free-free emission but are most likely
also associated with a cold dust component coincident with the position of the
brightest cluster. With standard dust properties, we estimate its mass to be as
large as 10^5 Msun. Both line and continuum results suggest the presence of a
large cold gas reservoir unseen in CO even with ALMA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08990</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Polaki</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamruddin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyagi</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of substrate bias and nitrogen doping on the structural
  evolution and local elastic modulus of diamond-like carbon films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted in J. Phys. D Appl. Phys</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 50 175601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6463/aa6492</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diamond-like carbon (DLC) films are synthesized on Si using plasma enhanced
chemical vapor deposition. The role of substrate bias and nitrogen doping on
the structural evolution and local elastic modulus of DLC films are
systematically investigated. Raman spectroscopic studies reveal that the amount
of graphitic C=C sp2 bonding increases with substrate bias and nitrogen doping.
The density and hydrogen concentration in the films are found to vary from 0.7
to 2.2 g/cm3 and 16 to 38 atomic %, respectively, depending upon the substrate
bias and nitrogen concentration in the DLC films. Atomic force acoustic
microscopic (AFAM) analysis shows a direct correlation between local elastic
modulus and structural properties estimated by Raman spectroscopy, Rutherford
back scattering and elastic recoil detection analysis. AFAM analysis further
confirms the evolution of soft second phases at high substrate biases (&gt; -150V)
in undoped DLC films. Further, N doping leads to formation of such soft second
phases in DLC films even at lower substrate bias of -100 V. The AFAM studies
provide a direct microscopic evidence for the &quot;sub-implantation growth model&quot;
which predicts the formation of graphitic second phases in DLC matrix at high
substrate biases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09156</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Schachinger</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;ffler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiger-Thirsfeld</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xf6;ger-Pollach</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pohl</keyname><forenames>Darius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rellinghaus</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schattschneider</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>EMCD with an electron vortex filter: Limitations and possibilities</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Ultramicroscopy 179 (2017) 15</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ultramic.2017.03.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the feasibility of detecting spin polarized electronic transitions
with a vortex filter. This approach does not rely on the principal condition of
the standard energy loss magnetic chiral dichroism (EMCD) technique, the
precise alignment of the crystal, and thus paves the way for the application of
EMCD to new classes of materials and problems. The dichroic signal strength in
the L$_{2,3}$-edge of ferromagnetic cobalt is estimated on theoretical grounds.
It is shown that magnetic dichroism can, in principle, be detected. However, as
an experimental test shows, count rates are currently too low under standard
conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09243</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Wunderlich</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohlrautz</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abel</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haase</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meijer</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Room temperature bulk diamond 13-C hyperpolarisation -- Strong evidence
  for a complex four spin coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hyperpolarisation at room temperature is one of the most important research
fields in order to improve liquid, gas or nanoparticle tracer for Magnetic
Resonance Imaging (MRI) in medical applications. In this paper we utilize
nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) to investigate the hyperpolarisation effect of
negatively charged nitrogen vacancy (NV) centres on carbon-13 nuclei and their
spin diffusion in a diamond single crystal close to the excited state level
anti crossing (ESLAC) around 50 mT. Whereas the electron spins of the NV centre
can be easily polarized in its m = 0 ground state at room temperature just by
irradiation with green light , the swop of the NV electron spin polarization to
a carbon-13 nuclei is a complex task. We found that the coupling between the
polarized NV electron spin, the electron spin of a substitutional nitrogen
impurity (P1) as well as its nitrogen-14 nuclei and the carbon-13 nuclear spin
has to be considered. Here we show that through an optimization of this
procedure, in about two minutes a signal to noise ratio which corresponds to a
23 hour standard measurement without hyperpolarisation and an accumulation of
460 single scans can be obtained. Furthermore we were able to identify several
polarisation peaks of different sign at different magnetic fields in a region
of some tens of gauss. Most of the peaks can be attributed to a coupling of the
NV centres to nearby P1 centres. We present a new theoretical model in a
framework of cross polarisation of a four spin dynamic model in good agreement
with our experimental data. The results demonstrate the opportunities and power
as well as limitations of hyperpolarisation in diamond via NV centres. We
expect that the current work may have a significant impact on future
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09315</id><created>2017-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Rotabi</keyname><forenames>Rahmtin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinberg</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author></authors><title>Tracing the Use of Practices through Networks of Collaboration</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>To Appear in Proceedings of ICWSM 2017, data at
  https://github.com/CornellNLP/Macros</comments><acm-class>H.2.8</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An active line of research has used on-line data to study the ways in which
discrete units of information---including messages, photos, product
recommendations, group invitations---spread through social networks. There is
relatively little understanding, however, of how on-line data might help in
studying the diffusion of more complex {\em practices}---roughly, routines or
styles of work that are generally handed down from one person to another
through collaboration or mentorship. In this work, we propose a framework
together with a novel type of data analysis that seeks to study the spread of
such practices by tracking their syntactic signatures in large document
collections. Central to this framework is the notion of an &quot;inheritance graph&quot;
that represents how people pass the practice on to others through
collaboration. Our analysis of these inheritance graphs demonstrates that we
can trace a significant number of practices over long time-spans, and we show
that the structure of these graphs can help in predicting the longevity of
collaborations within a field, as well as the fitness of the practices
themselves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09449</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Mokshin</keyname><forenames>Anatolii V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galimzyanov</keyname><forenames>Bulat N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetics of the Crystalline Nuclei Growth in Glassy Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7CP00879A</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the crystalline nuclei growth in glassy systems
focusing primarily on the early stages of the process, at which the size of a
growing nucleus is still comparable with the critical size. On the basis of
molecular dynamics simulation results for two crystallizing glassy systems, we
evaluate the growth laws of the crystalline nuclei and the parameters of the
growth kinetics at the temperatures corresponding to deep supercoolings;
herein, the statistical treatment of the simulation results is done within the
mean-first-passage-time method. It is found for the considered systems at
different temperatures that the crystal growth laws rescaled onto the waiting
times of the critically-sized nucleus follow the unified dependence, that can
simplify significantly theoretical description of the post-nucleation growth of
crystalline nuclei. The evaluated size-dependent growth rates are characterized
by transition to the steady-state growth regime, which depends on the
temperature and occurs in the glassy systems when the size of a growing nucleus
becomes two-three times larger than a critical size. It is suggested to
consider the temperature dependencies of the crystal growth rate
characteristics by using the reduced temperature scale $\widetilde{T}$. Thus,
it is revealed that the scaled values of the crystal growth rate
characteristics (namely, the steady-state growth rate and the attachment rate
for the critically-sized nucleus) as functions of the reduced temperature
$\widetilde{T}$ for glassy systems follow the unified power-law dependencies.
This finding is supported by available simulation results; the correspondence
with the experimental data for the crystal growth rate in glassy systems at the
temperatures near the glass transition is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09457</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Itakura</keyname><forenames>Kyohei</forenames></author></authors><title>Rellich's theorem for spherically symmetric repulsive Hamiltonians</title><categories>math.FA math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For spherically symmetric repulsive Hamiltonians we prove Rellich's theorem,
or identify the largest weighted space of Agmon-H\&quot;ormander type where the
generalized eigenfunctions are absent. The proof is intensively dependent on
commutator arguments. Our novelty here is a use of conjugate operator
associated with some radial flow, not with dilations and translations. Our
method is simple and elementary, and does not employ any advanced tools such as
the operational calculus or the Fourier analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09584</id><created>2017-03-28</created><updated>2017-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koivisto</keyname><forenames>Juha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korhonen</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alava</keyname><forenames>Mikko J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Carlos P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durian</keyname><forenames>Douglas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puisto</keyname><forenames>Antti</forenames></author></authors><title>Friction controls submerged granular flows</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, 2 Supplementary videos at
  https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLlB0dcWeUNfvpPvM6nAU1KsGv_4wbMKPw</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the coupling between interstitial medium and granular
particles by studying the hopper flow of dry and submerged system
experimentally and numerically. In accordance with earlier studies, we find,
that the dry hopper empties at a constant rate. However, in the submerged
system we observe the surging of the flow rate. We model both systems using the
discrete element method, which we couple with computational fluid dynamics in
the case of a submerged hopper. We are able to match the simulations and the
experiments with good accuracy. To do that, we fit the particle-particle
contact friction for each system separately, finding that submerging the hopper
changes the particle-particle contact friction from $\mu_{vacuum}=0.15$ to
$\mu_{sub}=0.13$, while all the other simulation parameters remain the same.
Furthermore, our experiments find a particle size dependence to the flow rate,
which is comprehended based on arguments on the terminal velocity and drag.
These results jointly allow us to conclude that at the large particle limit,
the interstitial medium does not matter, in contrast to small particles. The
particle size limit, where this occurs depends on the viscosity of the
interstitial fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09693</id><created>2017-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Pachev</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast link prediction for large networks using spectral embedding</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many link prediction algorithms require the computation of a similarity
metric on each vertex pair, which is quadratic in the number of vertices and
infeasible for large networks. We develop a class of link prediction algorithms
based on a spectral embedding and the k closest pairs algorithm that are
scalable to very large networks. We compare the prediction accuracy and runtime
of these methods to existing algorithms on several large link prediction tasks.
Our methods achieve comparable accuracy to standard algorithms but are
significantly faster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01348</id><created>2017-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Ono</keyname><forenames>Takafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okamoto</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanida</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Holger F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Shigeki</forenames></author></authors><title>Implementation of a quantum controlled-SWAP gate with photonic circuits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, Sci. Rep. 7, 45353 (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 7, 45353 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum information science addresses how the processing and transmission of
information are affected by uniquely quantum mechanical phenomena. Combination
of two-qubit gates has been used to realize quantum circuits, however,
scalability is becoming a critical problem. The use of three-qubit gates may
simplify the structure of quantum circuits dramatically. Among them, the
controlled-SWAP (Fredkin) gates are essential since they can be directly
applied to important protocols, e.g., error correction, fingerprinting, and
optimal cloning. Here we report a realization of the Fredkin gate for photonic
qubits. We achieve a fidelity of 0.85 in the computational basis and an output
state fidelity of 0.81 for a 3-photon Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger state. The
estimated process fidelity of 0.77 indicates that our Fredkin gate can be
applied to various quantum tasks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01838</id><created>2017-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Shigemoto</keyname><forenames>Kazuyasu</forenames></author></authors><title>Isotropic Metric in the Theory of General Relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>Tezukayama Academic Review, Vol.3, p.59-p.67 (1997)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explain why the isotropic metric is quite appropriate to put the physical
meaning of spacial variables in the theory of general relativity. Using the
isotropic metric, we conclude that i)g_{00} does not become positive even
inside the black hole, ii) there exists the center of the Universe if the
curvature of the Universe k \ne 0, iii)the Universe is spacially finite but not
colsed for k&gt;0.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01963</id><created>2017-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Sajjadi</keyname><forenames>Shahrdad G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robertson</keyname><forenames>Sarena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harvey</keyname><forenames>Rebecca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Mary</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave Motion Induced By Turbulent Shear Flows Over Growing Stokes Waves</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 13 figures</comments><msc-class>76B15</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent analytical of multi-layer analyses proposed by Sajjadi, Hunt and
Drullion (2014) (SHD14) is solved numerically for atmospheric turbulent shear
fows blowing over unsteady Stokes water waves, of low to moderate steepness. It
is demonstrated that as the wave steepens further the inner layer exceeds the
critical layer and beneath the cat's-eye there is a strong reverse flow which
will then affect the surface drag, but at the surface the flow adjusts itself
to the orbital velocity of the wave. We show that in the limit as c_r=U_* is
very small, namely slow moving waves the energy-transfer rate to the waves,
\beta, computed here using an eddy-viscosity model, agrees with the asymptotic
steady state analysis of Belcher and Hunt (1993) and the earlier model of
Townsend (1980). Computations for the cases when the waves are traveling faster
and growing significantly show a critical shear layer forms outside the inner
surface shear layer for steeper waves. We show that the critical layer produces
a significant but not the dominant effect; a weak lee-side jet is formed by the
inertial dynamics in the critical layer, which adds to the drag produced by the
sheltering effect. Over peaked waves, the inner layer flow on the lee-side
tends to slow and separate, which over a growing fast wave defects the
streamlines and the critical layer upwards on the lee side. Hence, it is
proposed, using an earlier study SHD14, that the mechanisms identified here for
wave-induced motion contributes to a larger net growth of wind driven water
waves when the waves are non-linear compared with growth rates for
monochromatic waves. This is because in non- linear waves individual harmonics
have stronger positive and weaker negative growth rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01964</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Meher</keyname><forenames>Nilakantha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sivakumar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>Prasanta K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Duality and quantum state engineering in cavity arrays</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, g figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A system of two coupled cavities with $N-1$ photons is shown to be
dynamically equivalent to an array of $N$ coupled cavities containing one
photon. Every transition in the two cavity system has a dual phenomenon in
terms of photon transport in the cavity array. This duality is employed to
arrive at the required coupling strengths and nonlinearities in the cavity
array so that controlled photon transfer is possible between any two cavities.
This transfer of photons between two of the cavities in the array is effected
without populating the other cavities. The condition for perfect transport
enables perfect state transfer between any two cavities in the array. Further,
possibility of high fidelity generation of generalized NOON states in two
coupled cavities, which are dual to the Bell states of the photon in the cavity
array, is established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01965</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Shahi</keyname><forenames>Farzad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rezakhani</keyname><forenames>Ali T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Binary classification of quantum states: Supervised and unsupervised
  learning</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we develop two quantum-computational models for supervised and
unsupervised classification tasks in quantum world. Presuming that the states
of a set of given quantum systems (or objects) belong to one of two known
classes, the objective here is to decide to which of these classes each system
belongs---without knowing its state. The supervised binary classification
algorithm is based on having a training sample of quantum systems whose class
memberships are already known. The unsupervised binary classification
algorithm, however, uses a quantum oracle which knows the class memberships of
the states of the computational basis. Both algorithms require the ability to
evaluate the fidelity between states of the quantum systems with unknown
states, for which here we also develop a general scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01966</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zimnik</keyname><forenames>Samantha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dickmann</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugenschmidt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>In-situ observation of temperature-dependent segregation of Ni adatoms
  on oriented Pd surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the direct observation of the in-situ temperature-dependent surface
segregation of Ni adatoms on single crystalline Pd surfaces using Positron
annihilation induced Auger Electron Spectroscopy (PAES). For this study, a
single atomic layer of Ni was grown on Pd with the crystallographic
orientations Pd(111), Pd(110) and Pd(100). The sample temperature was increased
from room temperature to 350$^\circ$C and the intensity of the Ni and Pd signal
was evaluated from the recorded PAES spectra. Due to the outstanding surface
sensitivity of PAES a clear tendency for Pd segregation was observed for all
samples. Moreover the activation temperature T$_0$ for surface segregation was
found to depend strongly on the surface orientation: We determined T$_0$ to
172$\pm$4$^\circ$C, 261$\pm$12$^\circ$C and 326$\pm$11$^\circ$C for Pd(111),
Pd(100) and Pd(110), respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01989</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Oxman</keyname><forenames>Luis E.</forenames></author></authors><title>${\rm SU}(N) \to {\rm Z}(N)$ dual superconductor models: the magnetic
  loop ensemble point of view</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures, proceedings of the XII Quark Confinement
  conference, Thessaloniki, Greece, from 28th August to 4rd September 2016</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 137, 03015 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201713703015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we initially discuss some physical properties of effective
${\rm SU}(N) \to {\rm Z}(N)$ YMH models, emphasizing the important role of
valence gluons. Next, we review how adjoint fields are naturally generated as
an effective description of &quot;adjoint&quot; loops in $4D$. Finally, we discuss the
consequences that can be learnt from this point of view, and briefly comment on
some improvements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01997</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Fleeman</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simanek</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Torsional Rigidity and Bergman Analytic Content of Simply Connected
  Regions</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We exploit the equality of Bergman analytic content and torsional rigidity of
a simply connected domain to develop a new method for calculating these
quantities. This method is particularly suitable for the case when the region
in question is a polygon. A large number of examples are computed in explicit
detail to demonstrate the utility of our ideas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02005</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huanian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaritsky</keyname><forenames>Dennis</forenames></author></authors><title>The Galaxy's Veil of Excited Hydrogen</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many of the baryons in our Galaxy probably lie outside the well known disk
and bulge components. Despite a wealth of evidence for the presence of some gas
in galactic halos, including absorption line systems in the spectra of quasars,
high velocity neutral hydrogen clouds in our Galaxy halo, line emitting ionised
hydrogen originating from galactic winds in nearby starburst galaxies, and the
X-ray coronas surrounding the most massive galaxies, accounting for the gas in
the halo of any galaxy has been observationally challenging primarily because
of its low density in the expansive halo. The most sensitive measurements come
from detecting absorption by the intervening gas in the spectra of distant
objects such as quasars or distant halo stars, but these have typically been
limited to a few lines of sight to sufficiently bright objects. Massive
spectroscopic surveys of millions of objects provide an alternative approach to
the problem. Here, we present the first evidence for a widely distributed,
neutral, excited hydrogen component of the Galaxy's halo. It is observed as the
slight, (0.779 $\pm$ 0.006)\%, absorption of flux near the rest wavelength of
H$\alpha$ in the combined spectra of hundreds of thousands of galaxy spectra
and is ubiquitous in high latitude lines of sight. This observation provides an
avenue to tracing, both spatially and kinematically, the majority of the gas in
the halo of our Galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02008</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Cariolaro</keyname><forenames>Gianfranco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierobon</keyname><forenames>Gianfranco</forenames></author></authors><title>From Hamiltonians to complex symplectic transformations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gaussian unitaries are specified by a second order polynomial in the bosonic
operators, that is, by a quadratic polynomial and a linear term. From the
Hamiltonian other equivalent representations of the Gaussian unitaries are
obtained, such as Bogoliubov and real symplectic transformations. The paper
develops an alternative representation, called complex symplectic
transformation, which is more compact and is comprehensive of both Bogoliubov
and real symplectic transformations. Moreover, it has other advantages. One of
the main results of the theory, not available in the literature, is that the
final displacement is not simply given by the linear part of the Hamiltonian,
but depends also on the quadratic part. In particular, it is shown that by
combining squeezing and rotation, it is possible to achieve a final
displacement with an arbitrary amount.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02009</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Jobunga</keyname><forenames>Eric Ouma</forenames></author></authors><title>Alternative Multipole Expansion of the Electron Correlation Term</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An alternative multipole expansion of the correlation term is derived.
Modified spherical Bessel type functions which simplify as a summation of
multiple orders of basic trigonometric functions are generated from this new
method. We use this new expansion to obtain useful insights into the
electron-electron interaction. An analytic expression for the electronic
correlation term is suggested. Also, a pseudopotential for helium-like system
is derived from this alternative expansion, and some reasonable eigenvalues for
the ground state and two autoionizing levels of helium atom, is provided as a
test of efficiency of this solution approach. With some additional corrections
beyond the non-relativistic limit, a helium atom groundstate energy of -2.9036
is obtained using the analytical form derived from this method and the Slater
determinant expansion of the wavefunction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02017</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Yurduseven</keyname><forenames>Okan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flowers</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Shengrong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marks</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gollub</keyname><forenames>Jonah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fromenteze</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiley</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational Microwave Imaging Using 3D Printed Conductive Polymer
  Frequency-Diverse Metasurface Antennas</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Original manuscript as submitted to IET Microwaves, Antennas &amp;
  Propagation (2017). 17 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A frequency-diverse computational imaging system synthesized using
three-dimensional (3D) printed frequency-diverse metasurface antennas is
demonstrated. The 3D fabrication of the antennas is achieved using a
combination of PolyLactic Acid (PLA) polymer material and conductive polymer
material (Electrifi), circumventing the requirement for expensive and
time-consuming conventional fabrication techniques, such as machine milling,
photolithography and laser-etching. Using the 3D printed frequency- diverse
metasurface antennas, a composite aperture is designed and simulated for
imaging in the K-band frequency regime (17.5-26.5 GHz). The frequency-diverse
system is capable of imaging by means of a simple frequency-sweep in an-all
electronic manner, avoiding mechanical scanning and active circuit components.
Using the synthesized system, microwave imaging of objects is achieved at the
diffraction limit. It is also demonstrated that the conductivity of the
Electrifi polymer material significantly affects the performance of the 3D
printed antennas and therefore is a critical factor governing the fidelity of
the reconstructed images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02027</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kohli</keyname><forenames>Ikjyot Singh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haslam</keyname><forenames>Michael C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of a Bianchi Type I Model With a Concave Potential</title><categories>gr-qc math.DS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the dynamics of a Bianchi Type I potential in the
presence of a concave potential of the form $V(\phi) = V_0 \left[1- \left(
\frac{\phi}{\mu}\right)^n\right]$, where $V_0$ is a constant, and $\mu$ is a
mass scale. We show that there are two classes of equilibrium points. The first
class corresponds to $\phi \neq 0$, $\mu \neq 0$, $n = 0$, and $\dot{\phi} =
0$, which describe expanding and contracting de Sitter universes, for which the
shear anisotropy is zero. We show that the expanding de Sitter universe is a
local sink of the system, and therefore has associated to it a stable manifold.
Thus, orbits will approach this point at late times. In other words, such a
model is found to inflate and isotropize at late times as long as $n = 0$. The
second class of equilibrium points corresponds to an expanding and contracting
anisotropic universe. However, these points are found to emerge only when $n &gt;
1$, $\phi = \dot{\phi} = 0$, which importantly implies that $V = V_0 &lt; 0$ at
this point in order to ensure that the square of the shear scalar, $\sigma^2$
is real. Therefore, such equilibrium points correspond to the ekpyrotic
cosmological models. Further, we show that for $n = 2$, by Lyapunov's stability
theorem, the expanding equilibrium point is asymptotically stable, while for $n
&gt; 2$, a two-dimensional stable manifold exists corresponding to the fact that
for $n &gt; 2$, such an equilibrium point represents a local sink of the system.
Finally, we give a general condition for inflation to occur in this model in
terms of the deceleration parameter, and show that the expanding ekpyrotic
equilibrium point undergoes the phenomenon of anisotropic inflation if
$-3\Lambda/5 &lt; V_0 &lt; 0$, where $\Lambda &gt; 0$ is the cosmological constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02031</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Rik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pramanik</keyname><forenames>Tanmoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Amritesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shin</keyname><forenames>Seung Heon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumder</keyname><forenames>Sarmita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Register</keyname><forenames>Leonard F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sanjay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of current induced spin polarization in epitaxial Bi$_2$Te$_3$
  thin film</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages (including references), 4 figures (including supplementary
  information), accepted in journal</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 110, 122403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4978691</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We electrically detect charge current induced spin polarization on the
surface of molecular beam epitaxy grown Bi$_2$Te$_3$ thin film in a
two-terminal device with a ferromagnetic MgO/Fe and a nonmagnetic Ti/Au
contact. The two-point resistance, measured in an applied magnetic field, shows
a hysteresis tracking the magnetization of the Fe. A theoretical estimate is
obtained for the change in resistance on reversing the magnetization direction
of Fe from coupled spin-charge transport equations based on quantum kinetic
theory. The order of magnitude and the sign of the hysteresis is consistent
with spin-polarized surface state of Bi$_2$Te$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02039</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Toudert</keyname><forenames>Johann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serna</keyname><forenames>Rosalia</forenames></author></authors><title>Interband transitions in semi-metals, semiconductors, and topological
  insulators: A new driving force for plasmonics and nanophotonics</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasmonic and Mie resonances in subwavelength nanostructures provide an
efficient way to manipulate light below the diffraction limit that has fostered
the growth of plasmonics and nanophotonics. Plasmonic resonances have been
mainly related with the excitation of free charge carriers, initially in
metals, and Mie resonances have been identified in Si nanostructures.
Remarkably, although much less studied, semi-metals, semiconductors and
topological insulators of the p-block enable plasmonic resonances without free
charge carriers and Mie resonances with enhanced properties compared with Si.
In this review, we explain how interband transitions in these materials show a
major role in this duality. We evaluate the plasmonic and Mie performance of
nanostructures made of relevant p-block elements and compounds, especially Bi,
and discuss their promising potential for applications ranging from switchable
plasmonics and nanophotonics to energy conversion, especially photocatalysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02044</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02044</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Takeshita</keyname><forenames>Tyler Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Jong</keyname><forenames>Wibe A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neuhauser</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baer</keyname><forenames>Roi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabani</keyname><forenames>Eran</forenames></author></authors><title>A Stochastic Formulation of the Resolution of Identity: Application to
  Second Order M{\o}ller-Plesset Perturbation Theory</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A stochastic orbital approach to the resolution of identity (RI)
approximation for 4-index 2-electron electron repulsion integrals (ERIs) is
presented. The stochastic RI-ERIs are then applied to M\o ller-Plesset
perturbation theory (MP2) utilizing a \textit{multiple stochastic orbital
approach}. The introduction of multiple stochastic orbitals results in an $N^3$
scaling for both the stochastic RI-ERIs and stochastic RI-MP2. We demonstrate
that this method exhibits a small prefactor and an observed scaling of
$N^{2.4}$ for a range of water clusters, already outperforming MP2 for clusters
with as few as 21 water molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02070</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Zhiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jingsong</forenames></author></authors><title>New Hierarchies of Derivative nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger-Type Equation</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><journal-ref>Romanian Reports in Physics, Vol. 68, No. 4, P. 1425-1446 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We generate hierarchies of derivative nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger-type equations
and their nonlocal extensions from Lie algebra splittings and automorphisms.
This provides an algebraic explanation of some known reductions and newly
established nonlocal reductions in integrable systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02085</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Xinzhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Shifei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Yulei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kunhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiaohong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author></authors><title>Realization of Quantum Anomalous Hall Effect in Graphene from
  \textit{n}-\textit{p} Codoping Induced Stable Atomic-Adsorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 121410 (R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.121410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using first-principles calculation methods, we study the possibility of
realizing quantum anomalous Hall effect in graphene from stable
3\textit{d}-atomic adsorption via charge-compensated \textit{n}-\textit{p}
codoping scheme. As concrete examples, we show that long-range ferromagnetism
can be established by codoping 3\textit{d} transition metal and boron atoms,
but only the Ni codopants can open up a global bulk gap to harbour the quantum
anomalous Hall effect. Our estimated ferromagnetic Curie transition temperature
can reach over 10 Kelvin for various codoping concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02092</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Sandip K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Latest trends in the study of accretion and outflows around compact
  objects</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages 3 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:astro-ph/0007259</comments><journal-ref>Indian Journal of Physics, 1999, v. 73B, No. 6, P. 931-944</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Study of astrophysics of black holes and neutron stars has taken a new turn
in the present decade with the realization that sub-Keplerian flows and the
associated centrifugal barrier near the horizon or the surface of a neutron
star play a major role in deciding the nature of the emitted spectra and the
formation of outflows from the accreting matter. This region may remain steady
or oscillate depending on the accretion rate, specific angular momentum and
specific energy of the flow. Intricacies of oscillation may depend on the
degree of feedback the inflow receives from the outflow. This region may emit
hard or soft X-rays depending on relative numbers of hot elections and soft
photons intercepted by this region. We discuss how these properties come about
and how they explain the observational results of black hole candidates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02095</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Sela</keyname><forenames>Alon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milo-Cohen</keyname><forenames>Orit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ben-Gal</keyname><forenames>Irad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kagan</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author></authors><title>Increasing the Flow of Rumors in Social Networks by Spreading Groups</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper addresses a method for spreading messages in social networks
through an initial acceleration by Spreading Groups. These groups start the
spread which eventually reaches a larger portion of the network. The use of
spreading groups creates a final flow which resembles the spread through the
nodes with the highest level of influence (opinion leaders). While harnessing
opinion leaders to spread messages is generally costly, the formation of
spreading groups is merely a technical issue, and can be done by computerized
bots. The paper presents an information flow model and inspects the model
through a dataset of Nasdaq-related tweets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02104</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Kannika</keyname><forenames>Jakapat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herold</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limphirat</keyname><forenames>Ayut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobdaj</keyname><forenames>Chinorat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Yupeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical formation of center domains in quark-gluon plasma</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C95 (2017) no.3, 034903</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.034903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the formation of domain structures due to spontaneous breakdown of
center symmetry at high temperatures in quenched QCD. We develop a
phenomenological model for the explicit propagation of the Polyakov loop as the
relevant order parameter of the deconfinement phase transition. The surface
tension in the equation of motion is fit in comparison with lattice QCD data.
Results give insight into the dynamical formation of center domains as well as
the formation of energy bands along domain walls and let us estimate the
required time to form such structures above the critical temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02108</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Prasoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gandhi</keyname><forenames>Prasanna S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumder</keyname><forenames>Mainak</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiscale fabrication of scalable biomimetic 3-D, integrated
  micro-nanochannels network in PDMS for solute exchange</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, conference proceedings in 11th International
  Conference on MicroManufacturing, UC Irvine, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Integrated micro-nanochannel networks in fluidic devices are desirable in a
number of applications ranging from self-healing/cooling materials to
bioengineering. The conventional micro-manufacturing techniques are capable of
either producing microchannel or nanochannel networks for a fluidic application
but lack proficiency in the production of an integrated micro-nanochannel
network with a smooth transition from micro-to-nano scale dimension. In
addition, these techniques possess limitations such as heavy initial
investment, sophistication in operation and scale-up capabilities. Therefore,
the current paper demonstrates the combination of micro/nanotechnologies to
design and develop a biomimetic 3-D integrated micro-nanochannel network in
PDMS device for solute exchange. We have used 3-D printer, a scalable
technology, to design and manufacture micro-mold having fractal-shaped
features. Further, electrospinning was used to deposit nanofibrous network on
the fractal mold. Subsequent micro-molding with PDMS was used to obtain
fractal-shaped microchannels integrated with embedded nanofibers. Henceforth,
solvent etching of nanofibers followed by bonding of thin PDMS membrane
generated by spin coating to open end of channels leads to the formation of
functional microdevices. These PDMS devices mimic the natural vasculature of a
living system, where fractal-shaped microchannels will assist in efficient
fluid flow and the site of nanovascular network participates in heat/mass
transport operations. Further, dye flow propounds the functionality of such
devices. Our study hence proposes a simple and scalable hybrid microtechnolgy
to fabricate fluidic devices having multiscale architecture. This will also
facilitate the rapid fabrication of microfluidic devices for biomedical,
diagnostics, sensors and micro-TAS applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02123</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Hertog</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartle</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Observational Implications of Fuzzball Formation</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>Dedicated to the memory of Pierre Binetruy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the quantum dynamics of gravitational collapse in a model in
which the wave function spreads out over a large ensemble of geometries as
envisioned in the fuzzball proposal. We show that the probabilities of
coarse-grained observables are highly peaked around the classical black hole
values. By contrast, probabilities for finer-grained observables probing the
neighbourhood of collapsed objects are more broadly distributed and no notion
of `averaging' applies to them. This implies that the formation of fuzzballs
gives rise to distinct observational signatures that are more significant than
has hitherto been thought and may be tested against observations in the near
future. We also predict a novel kind of gravitational wave burst associated
with the spreading of the wave function in gravitational collapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02144</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>Lo&#xef;c</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindler</keyname><forenames>Baptiste</forenames></author><author><keyname>Compagnon</keyname><forenames>Isabelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allouche</keyname><forenames>Abdul-Rahman</forenames></author></authors><title>iGVPT2 : an interface to computational chemistry packages for anharmonic
  corrections to vibrational frequencies</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  iGVPT2 is a program for computing anharmonic corrections to vibration
frequencies, based on force field expansion of the potential energy surface in
normal mode coordinates. It includes second order vibrational perturbation
theory (VPT2) algorithm and its derived methods (VPT2+K, DCPT2, HDCPT2). iGVPT2
is interfaced with several computation chemistry packages to compute the
potential energies and dipoles derivatives. The second, third and quartic
derivatives can be computed at the same level of theory but they can be also
computed using different methods via one or two computational packages. iGPVT2
includes also a very fast hybrid QM//MM approach for biomolecules. It is
provided free-of-charge for non-commercial research (see
\url{https://sites.google.com/site/allouchear/igvpt2}).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02146</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Schuld</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petruccione</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum ensembles of quantum classifiers</title><categories>quant-ph cs.LG math.ST stat.TH</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum machine learning witnesses an increasing amount of quantum algorithms
for data-driven decision making, a problem with potential applications ranging
from automated image recognition to medical diagnosis. Many of those algorithms
are implementations of quantum classifiers, or models for the classification of
data inputs with a quantum computer. Following the success of collective
decision making with ensembles in classical machine learning, this paper
introduces the concept of quantum ensembles of quantum classifiers. Creating
the ensemble corresponds to a state preparation routine, after which the
quantum classifiers are evaluated in parallel and their combined decision is
accessed by a single-qubit measurement. This framework naturally allows for
exponentially large ensembles in which -- similar to Bayesian learning -- the
individual classifiers do not have to be trained. As an example, we analyse an
exponentially large quantum ensemble in which each classifier is weighed
according to its performance in classifying the training data, leading to new
results for quantum as well as classical machine learning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02165</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Subrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polaki</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilango</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amirthapandian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamruddin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyagi</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Flipping growth orientation of nanographitic structures by plasma
  enhanced chemical vapor deposition</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>RSC Adv., 5, 91922-91931 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C5RA20820C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanographitic structures (NGSs) with multitude of morphological features are
grown on SiO2/Si substrates by electron cyclotron resonance - plasma enhanced
chemical vapor deposition (ECR-PECVD). CH4 is used as source gas with Ar and H2
as dilutants. Field emission scanning electron microscopy, high resolution
transmission electron microscopy (HRTEM) and Raman spectroscopy are used to
study the structural and morphological features of the grown films. Herein, we
demonstrate, how the morphology can be tuned from planar to vertical structure
using single control parameter namely, dilution of CH4 with Ar and/or H2. Our
results show that the competitive growth and etching processes dictate the
morphology of the NGSs. While Ar-rich composition favors vertically oriented
graphene nanosheets, H2-rich composition aids growth of planar films. Raman
analysis reveals dilution of CH4 with either Ar or H2 or in combination helps
to improve the structural quality of the films. Line shape analysis of Raman 2D
band shows nearly symmetric Lorentzian profile which confirms the turbostratic
nature of the grown NGSs. Further, this aspect is elucidated by HRTEM studies
by observing elliptical diffraction pattern. Based on these experiments, a
comprehensive understanding is obtained on the growth and structural properties
of NGSs grown over a wide range of feedstock compositions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02172</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Sokolovski</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to L.Vaidman's comment on &quot;Asking photons where they have been in
  plain language&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Vaidman's analysis of the photon's past is based on incorrect interpretation
of quantum probability amplitudes. The confusion stems from his original work
[{\it Phys. Rev. Lett.} \textbf{60}, 1351 (1988)], which missed the connection
between the amplitudes and the &quot;weak values&quot; introduced therein.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02185</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Drezet</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genet</keyname><forenames>Cyriaque</forenames></author></authors><title>Reciprocity and optical chirality</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>This text was published as Chapter 2 in \textsl{Singular and Chiral
  Nano Plasmonics}, Edited by S.V. Boriskina, N. I. Zheludev, PanStanford
  Publishing, pp. 57-96 (2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this text we describe the role of optical chirality in the context of
plasmonics. We clearly distinguish between 2D an 3D optical chirality and
connect the problem with reciprocity and time symmetry. We compare our analysis
with recent experimental results in nano-plasmonics and photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02195</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuzmenko</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuvaev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dziom</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimenov</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schiebl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>V. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezmaternykh</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimenov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant gigahertz optical activity in multiferroic ferroborate</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 89, 174407 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.174407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In contrast to well studied multiferroic manganites with a spiral structure,
the electric polarization in multiferroic borates is induced within collinear
antiferromagnetic structure and can easily be switched by small static fields.
Because of specific symmetry conditions, static and dynamic properties in
borates are directly connected, which leads to giant magnetoelectric and
magnetodielectric effects. Here we prove experimentally that the giant
magnetodielectric effect in samarium ferroborate SmFe3(BO3)4 is of intrinsic
origin and is caused by an unusually large electromagnon situated in the
microwave range. This electromagnon reveals strong optical activity exceeding
120 degrees of polarization rotation in a millimeter thick sample.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02198</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuzmenko</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>V. Vu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komandin</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuvaev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pimenov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dziom</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezmaternykh</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudim</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Terahertz spectroscopy of crystal-field transitions in magnetoelectric
  TmAl3(BO3)4</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 174419 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.174419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamic magnetic properties of magnetoelectric TmAl3(BO3)4 borate have been
investigated by terahertz spectroscopy. Crystal field (CF) transitions within
the ground multiplet 3H6 of Tm3+ ions are observed and they are identified as
magnetic-dipole transitions from the ground singlet A1 to the next excited
doublet E of Tm3+ ions. Unexpected fine structure of the transitions is
detected at low temperatures. The new modes are assigned to local distortions
of the sites with D3 symmetry by Bi3+ impurities, which resulted in the
splitting of A1 -&gt; E transition. Two types of locally distorted sites are
identified and investigated. The main contribution to the static magnetic
susceptibility is shown to be determined by the matrix elements of the observed
magnetic transitions. We demonstrate that even in case of local distortions the
symmetry of the undistorted crystal is recovered for magnetic and for quadratic
magnetoelectric susceptibilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02221</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Da-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Yao</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiqubit Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger state generated by synthetic
  magnetic field in circuit QED</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scheme to generate Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) state for N
superconducting qubits in a circuit QED system. By sinusoidally modulating the
qubit-qubit coupling, a synthetic magnetic field has been made which broken the
time-reversal symmetry of the system. Directional rotation of qubit excitation
can be realized in a three-qubit loop under the artificial magnetic field.
Based on the special quality that the rotation of qubit excitation has
different direction for single- and double-excitation loops, we can generate
three-qubit GHZ state and extend this preparation method to arbitrary
multiqubit GHZ state. Our analysis also shows that the scheme is robust to
various operation errors and environmental noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02228</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Bagheri-Mohagheghi</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pourhassan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adelifard</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shokooh-Saremi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The feasibility of correlation between superconductivity and magnetic
  monopole: Establishment of semi-classical electrodynamics projection, TKH
  topological theory and dynamic vortex models</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>24 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a feasibility of semi-classical electromagnetic description
together with experimental data, T-K-H topological and dynamic models and
theory of vortex considered to justify the relation between superconductivity
phenomena and magnetic monopole. We find that the electromagnetic energy of
magnetic monopole is in agreement with vortex energy in topological theory and
it can get close to thermal energy at room temperature. Indeed, these models
suggest that the origin of the hot superconductivity may be magnetic monopoles
with QM-Cl = 137 e (magnetic charge in classical approach) or QM-Q =137/2 e
(magnetic charge in quantum approach), and the electrical conductivity is
related to the mobile monopole or vortices. This research shows that the
electrical permittivity ({\epsilon}) and magnetic permeability ({\mu}) of
matter have a key role in the superconductive properties. We propose that this
model may justify the hot superconductivity properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02243</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Raja</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murali</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posselt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satyanarayana</keyname><forenames>S. V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Importance of phonon contribution to the free migration energy of the O
  vacancy in BaZrO3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  BaZrO3 exhibits excellent proton conductivity and good high-temperature
stability. It is therefore a promising electrolyte material for solid oxide
fuel cells. The stability of BaZrO3 at high temperatures is generally explained
by the low diffusivity of the O vacancy. Present first-principle
Density-Functional-Theory calculations show that the slow migration of the
doubly positively charged O vacancy at high temperature cannot be solely caused
by the ground-state migration energy but by the contribution of phonon
excitations to the free migration energy. With increasing temperature, the
effective barrier for oxygen vacancy migration increases. At about 1000K, which
is the operating temperature of fuel cells, the calculated O vacancy
diffusivity is more than one order of magnitude lower than that determined
using solely the ground-state migration barrier. The calculated diffusivity
data agree well with experimental results from literature. The present work
reveals that the high-temperature stability of BaZrO3 is mainly due to the
phonon contribution to the free migration energy of the O vacancy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02244</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fu-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yongming</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent-induced state ordering with fixed mixedness</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study coherence-induced state ordering with Tsallis
relative entropy of coherence, relative entropy of coherence and $l_{1}$ norm
of coherence. Firstly, we show that these measures give the same ordering for
single-qubit states with a fixed mixedness or a fixed length along the
direction $\sigma_{z}$. Secondly, we consider some special cases of high
dimensional states, we show that these measures generate the same ordering for
the set of high dimensional pure states if any two states of the set satisfy
majorization relation. Moreover, these three measures generate the same
ordering for all $X$ states with a fixed mixedness. Finally, we discuss
dynamics of coherence-induced state ordering under Markovian channels. We find
phase damping channel don't change the coherence-induced state ordering for
some single-qubit states with fixed mixedness, instead amplitude damping
channel change the coherence-induced ordering even though for single-qubit
states with fixed mixedness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02250</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Giovanelli</keyname><forenames>Emerson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellanos-Gomez</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>Emilio M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surfactant-Free Polar-to-Non-Polar-Phase Transfer of Exfoliated MoS2
  Two-Dimensional Colloids</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures, 7 supporting figures</comments><doi>10.1002/cplu.201700038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exfoliation of lamellar materials into their corresponding layers represented
a breakthrough, due to the outstanding properties arising from the nanometric
thickness confinement. Among the cleavage techniques, liquid-phase exfoliation
is now on the rise because it is scalable and leads to easy-to-manipulate
colloids. However, all appropriate exfoliating solvents exhibit strong
polarity, which restrains a lot the scope of feasible functionalization or
processing of the resulting flakes. Here we propose to extend this scope,
demonstrating that nanosheets exfoliated in a polar medium can be properly
dispersed in a non-polar solvent. To that purpose, we prepared suspensions of
molybdenum disulfide flakes in isopropanol/water and developed a phase transfer
of the nanosheets to chloroform via precipitation and
redispersion/centrifugation sequences, without any assisting surfactant. The
colloidal stability of the nanosheets in chloroform was found to be governed by
their lateral dimensions and, although lower than in polar media, proved to be
high enough to open the way to subsequent functionalization or processing of
the flakes in non-polar medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02285</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Toro&#x161;</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gro&#xdf;ardt</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassi</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to Comment on &quot;Quantum mechanics for non-inertial observers&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our recent paper (arXiv:1701.04298 [quant-ph]) discussed the occurrence of a
coupling of centre of mass and internal degrees of freedom for complex quantum
systems in non-inertial frames. There, we pointed out that an external force
supporting the system against gravity plays a crucial role for the coupling
between center of mass position to the internal degrees of freedom. In a
comment (arXiv:1702.06670 [quant-ph]) to our paper, Pikovski et al. question
our conclusion and present the argument that the lack of the coupling term
would be in contradiction with the observation of gravitational time dilation
using atomic clocks. Here, we elaborate on our results in reply to their
criticism and clarify why our arguments remain valid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02287</id><created>2017-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Petrascheck</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Folk</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Helmholtz decomposition theorem and Blumenthal's extension by
  regularization</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>11 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1506.00235</comments><proxy>Iryna Bzovska</proxy><journal-ref>Condens. Matter Phys., 2017, vol. 20, No. 1, 13002</journal-ref><doi>10.5488/CMP.20.13002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Helmholtz decomposition theorem for vector fields is usually presented with
too strong restrictions on the fields and only for time independent fields.
Blumenthal showed in 1905 that decomposition is possible for any asymptotically
weakly decreasing vector field. He used a regularization method in his proof
which can be extended to prove the theorem even for vector fields
asymptotically increasing sublinearly. Blumenthal's result is then applied to
the time-dependent fields of the dipole radiation and an artificial sublinearly
increasing field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02292</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Cheviakov</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Symbolic Computation Framework for Constitutive Modelling Based On
  Entropy Principles</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The entropy principle in the formulation of M\&quot;{u}ller and Liu is a common
tool used in constitutive modelling for the development of restrictions on the
unknown constitutive functions describing material properties of various
physical continua. In the current work, a symbolic software implementation of
the Liu algorithm, based on \verb|Maple| software and the \verb|GeM| package,
is presented. The computational framework is used to algorithmically perform
technically demanding symbolic computations related to the entropy principle,
to simplify and reduce Liu's identities, and ultimately to derive explicit
formulas describing classes of constitutive functions that do not violate the
entropy principle. Detailed physical examples are presented and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02294</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferguson</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological States in the Kuramoto Model</title><categories>math.DS nlin.AO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>34C15, 34D06</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Kuramoto model is a system of nonlinear differential equations that
models networks of coupled oscillators and is often used to study
synchronization among the oscillators. In this paper we study steady state
solutions of the Kuramoto model by assigning to each steady state a tuple of
integers which records how the state twists around the cycles in the network.
We then use this new classification of steady states to obtain a &quot;Weyl&quot; type of
asymptotic estimate for the number of steady states as the number of
oscillators becomes arbitrarily large while preserving the cycle structure. We
further show how this asymptotic estimate can be maximized, and as a special
case we obtain an asymptotic lower bound for the number of stable steady states
of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02300</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Eckstein</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-channel Kondo physics in a periodically driven single-impurity
  Anderson model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a quantum dot (Anderson impurity) coupled to metallic leads,
with a time-periodic voltage bias across the device. Using a time-dependent
Schrieffer-Wolff transformation, we show that the Floquet Hamiltonian of the
model can be mapped onto a two-channel Kondo model, in which the impurity is
screened by separate conduction bands corresponding to parity-even and odd
superpositions of the metallic leads. By changing the frequency and amplitude
of the perturbation, one can tune the system to a quantum critical point with
symmetric coupling of the impurity to both channels. For the understanding of
the driven state, energy absorption from the drive must be considered: Although
the absorption at the impurity is balanced by the energy flow into the
conduction band, locally it leads to non-thermal distribution functions which
can have a detrimental effect on the Kondo physics. However, a numerical
simulation demonstrates that the absorption can be systematically suppressed at
a fixed value of the induced couplings by increasing the frequency, so that the
time-averaged dynamics in the driven one-channel Anderson model can be used to
study the critical behavior of the two-channel model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02309</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-10</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02309</id><created>2017-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zwart</keyname><forenames>Maaike</forenames><affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Coecke</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames><affiliation>University of Oxford</affiliation></author></authors><title>Double Dilation $\neq$ Double Mixing</title><categories>quant-ph math.CT</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><msc-class>81Q10, 18D10, 18D20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density operators are one of the key ingredients of quantum theory. They can
be constructed in two ways: via a convex sum of `doubled kets' (i.e. mixing),
and by tracing out part of a `doubled' two-system ket (i.e. dilation). Both
constructions can be iterated, yielding new mathematical species that have
already found applications outside physics. However, as we show in this paper,
the iterated constructions no longer yield the same mathematical species.
Hence, the constructions `mixing' and `dilation' themselves are by no means
equivalent. Concretely, when applying the Choi-Jamiolkowski isomorphism to the
second iteration, dilation produces arbitrary symmetric bipartite states, while
mixing only yields the disentangled ones. All results are proven using
diagrams, and hence they hold not only for quantum theory, but also for a much
more general class of process theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
