<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:42:03Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-04-21" from="2017-04-21" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1207.2290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1207.2290</id><created>2012-07-10</created><updated>2012-10-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xf3;nico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Ostilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>Richard J. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal Taylor-Couette flow: direct numerical simulations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Under consideration for publication in JFM, 31 pages, 25 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Fluid Mech. 719, 14-46 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2012.596</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically simulate turbulent Taylor-Couette flow for independently
rotating inner and outer cylinders, focusing on the analogy with turbulent
Rayleigh-B\'enard flow. Reynolds numbers of $Re_i=8\cdot10^3$ and
$Re_o=\pm4\cdot10^3$ of the inner and outer cylinders, respectively, are
reached, corresponding to Taylor numbers Ta up to $10^8$. Effective scaling
laws for the torque and other system responses are found. Recent experiments
with the Twente turbulent Taylor-Couette ($T^3C$) setup and with a similar
facility in Maryland at very high Reynolds numbers have revealed an optimum
transport at a certain non-zero rotation rate ratio $a = -\omega_o / \omega_i$
of about $a_{opt}=0.33-0.35$. For large enough $Ta$ in the numerically
accessible range we also find such an optimum transport at non-zero
counter-rotation. The position of this maximum is found to shift with the
driving, reaching a maximum of $a_{opt}=0.15$ for $Ta=2.5\cdot10^7$. An
explanation for this shift is elucidated, consistent with the experimental
result that $a_{opt}$ becomes approximately independent of the driving strength
for large enough Reynolds numbers. We furthermore numerically calculate the
angular velocity profiles and visualize the different flow structures for the
various regimes. By writing the equations in a frame co-rotating with the outer
cylinder a link is found between the local angular velocity profiles and the
global transport quantities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.6331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.6331</id><created>2013-04-23</created><updated>2013-10-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Ostilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huisman</keyname><forenames>Sander G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jannink</keyname><forenames>Tim J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Gils</keyname><forenames>Dennis P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal Taylor-Couette flow: Radius ratio dependence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Submitted to JFM, 28 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics / Volume 747 / May 2014, pp 1- 29</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2014.134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Taylor-Couette flow with independently rotating inner (i) and outer (o)
cylinders is explored numerically and experimentally to determine the effects
of the radius ratio {\eta} on the system response. Numerical simulations reach
Reynolds numbers of up to Re_i=9.5 x 10^3 and Re_o=5x10^3, corresponding to
Taylor numbers of up to Ta=10^8 for four different radius ratios {\eta}=r_i/r_o
between 0.5 and 0.909. The experiments, performed in the Twente Turbulent
Taylor-Couette (T^3C) setup, reach Reynolds numbers of up to Re_i=2x10^6$ and
Re_o=1.5x10^6, corresponding to Ta=5x10^{12} for {\eta}=0.714-0.909. Effective
scaling laws for the torque J^{\omega}(Ta) are found, which for sufficiently
large driving Ta are independent of the radius ratio {\eta}. As previously
reported for {\eta}=0.714, optimum transport at a non-zero Rossby number
Ro=r_i|{\omega}_i-{\omega}_o|/[2(r_o-r_i){\omega}_o] is found in both
experiments and numerics. Ro_opt is found to depend on the radius ratio and the
driving of the system. At a driving in the range between {Ta\sim3\cdot10^8} and
{Ta\sim10^{10}}, Ro_opt saturates to an asymptotic {\eta}-dependent value.
Theoretical predictions for the asymptotic value of Ro_{opt} are compared to
the experimental results, and found to differ notably. Furthermore, the local
angular velocity profiles from experiments and numerics are compared, and a
link between a flat bulk profile and optimum transport for all radius ratios is
reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.1009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.1009</id><created>2013-05-05</created><updated>2015-03-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardone</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durante</keyname><forenames>Tiziana</forenames></author></authors><title>Homogenization and norm resolvent convergence for elliptic operators in
  a strip perforated along a curve</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society of Edinburgh, Section: A
  Mathematics, V. 146. No. 6. P. 1115-1158 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0308210516000019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider an infinite planar straight strip perforated by small holes along
a curve. In such domain, we consider a general second order elliptic operator
subject to classical boundary conditions on the holes. Assuming that the
perforation is non-periodic and satisfies rather weak assumptions, we describe
all possible homogenized problems. Our main result is the norm resolvent
convergence of the perturbed operator to a homogenized one in various operator
norms and the estimates for the rate of convergence. On the basis of the norm
resolvent convergence, we prove the convergence of the spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.2911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.2911</id><created>2013-06-12</created><updated>2013-10-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Ostilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Poel</keyname><forenames>Erwin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Boundary layer dynamics at the transition between the classical and the
  ultimate regime of Taylor-Couette flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>22 pages, submitted to PoF</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Fluids 26, 015114 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4863312</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct numerical simulations of turbulent Taylor-Couette flow are performed
up to inner cylinder Reynolds numbers of {Re_i=10^5} for a radius ratio of
{\eta=r_i/r_o=0.714} between the inner and outer cylinder. With increasing
{Re_i}, the flow undergoes transitions between three different regimes: (i) a
flow dominated by large coherent structures, (ii) an intermediate transitional
regime, and (iii) a flow with developed turbulence. In the first regime the
large--scale rolls completely drive the meridional flow while in the second one
the coherent structures recover only on average. The presence of a mean flow
allows for the coexistence of laminar and turbulent boundary layer dynamics. In
the third regime the mean flow effects fade away and the flow becomes dominated
by plumes. The effect of the local driving on the azimuthal and angular
velocity profiles is quantified, in particular we show when and where those
profiles develop.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.2463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.2463</id><created>2013-11-11</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xf3;nico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Ostilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulence decay towards the linearly-stable regime of Taylor-Couette
  flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Preprint submitted to PRL, 12 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1017/jfm.2014.242</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Taylor-Couette (TC) flow is used to probe the hydrodynamical stability of
astrophysical accretion disks. Experimental data on the subcritical stability
of TC are in conflict about the existence of turbulence (cf. Ji et al. Nature,
444, 343-346 (2006) and Paoletti et al., A$\&amp;$A, 547, A64 (2012)), with
discrepancies attributed to end-plate effects. In this paper we numerically
simulate TC flow with axially periodic boundary conditions to explore the
existence of sub-critical transitions to turbulence when no end-plates are
present. We start the simulations with a fully turbulent state in the unstable
regime and enter the linearly stable regime by suddenly starting a
(stabilizing) outer cylinder rotation. The shear Reynolds number of the
turbulent initial state is up to $Re_s \sim10^5$ and the radius ratio is
$\eta=0.714$. The stabilization causes the system to behave as a damped
oscillator and correspondingly the turbulence decays. The evolution of the
torque and turbulent kinetic energy is analysed and the periodicity and damping
of the oscillations are quantified and explained as a function of shear
Reynolds number. Though the initially turbulent flow state decays,
surprisingly, the system is found to absorb energy during this decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.6941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.6941</id><created>2014-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sultan</keyname><forenames>M. Atif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akbar</keyname><forenames>Nosheen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masud</keyname><forenames>Bilal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akram</keyname><forenames>Faisal</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher Hybrid Charmonia in an Extended Potential Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 90, 054001 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.90.054001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quark potential model for mesons and its extension for hybrid mesons are
used to study the effects of radial excitations on the masses, sizes and radial
wave functions at the origin for conventional and hybrid charmonium mesons.
These results can help in experimentally recognizing hybrid mesons. The
properties of conventional and hybrid charmonium mesons are calculated for the
ground and radially excited states using the shooting method to numerically
solve the required Schrodinger equation for the radial wave functions. We
compare our results with the experimentally observed masses and theoretically
predicted results of the other models. Our results have implications for scalar
form factors, energy shifts, and polarizabilities of conventional and hybrid
mesons. The comparison of masses of conventional and hybrid charmonium meson
with the masses of recent discovered XYZ-particles is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.0124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.0124</id><created>2014-05-01</created><updated>2014-10-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xf3;nico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo Ostilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Poel</keyname><forenames>Erwin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Siegfried</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the phase diagram of fully turbulent Taylor-Couette flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>23 pages, submitted to JFM</comments><doi>10.1017/jfm.2014.618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct numerical simulations of Taylor-Couette flow (TC). Shear Reynolds
numbers of up to $3\cdot10^5$, corresponding to Taylor numbers of
$Ta=4.6\cdot10^{10}$, were reached. Effective scaling laws for the torque are
presented. The transition to the ultimate regime, in which asymptotic scaling
laws (with logarithmic corrections) for the torque are expected to hold up to
arbitrarily high driving, is analysed for different radius ratios $\eta$,
different aspect ratios $\Gamma$ and different rotation ratios $Ro$. It is
shown that the transition is approximately independent of $Ro$ and $\Gamma$,
but depends significantly on $\eta$. We furthermore calculate the local angular
velocity profiles and visualize different flow regimes that depend both on the
shearing of the flow, and the Coriolis force originating from the outer
cylinder rotation. Two main regimes are distinguished, based on the magnitude
of the Coriolis force, namely the co-rotating and weakly counter-rotating
regime dominated by Rayleigh-unstable regions, and the strongly
counter-rotating regime where a mixture of stable and unstable regions exist.
Furthermore, an analogy between $\eta$ and outer-cylinder rotation is revealed,
namely that smaller gaps behave like a wider gap with co-rotating cylinders,
and that wider gaps behave like smaller gaps with weakly counter-rotating
cylinders. Finally, the effect of $\Gamma$ on the effective torque versus $Ta$
scaling is analysed and it is shown that different branches of the
torque-versus-$Ta$ relationships associated to different aspect ratios are
found to cross within $15%$ of the $Re$ associated to the transition to the
ultimate regime. The paper culminates in phase diagram in the inner vs outer
$Re$ number parameter space and in the $Ta$ vs $Ro$ parameter space, which can
be seen as the extension of the Andereck \emph{et al.} phase diagram towards
the ultimate regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.6469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.6469</id><created>2014-09-23</created><updated>2016-02-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunnen</keyname><forenames>Rudie P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostilla-M&#xf3;nico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Poel</keyname><forenames>Erwin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Geostrophic convective turbulence: The effect of boundary layers</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Submitted to JFM</comments><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.394</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rayleigh--B\'enard (RB) convection, the flow in a fluid layer heated from
below and cooled from above, is used to analyze the transition to the
geostrophic regime of thermal convection. In the geostrophic regime, which is
of direct relevance to most geo- and astrophysical flows, the system is
strongly rotated while maintaining a sufficiently large thermal driving to
generate turbulence. We directly simulate the Navier--Stokes equations for two
values of the thermal forcing, i.e. $Ra=10^{10}$ and $Ra=5\cdot10^{10}$, a
constant Prandtl number~$Pr=1$, and vary the Ekman number in the range
$Ek=1.3\cdot10^{-7}$ to $Ek=2\cdot10^{-6}$ which satisfies both requirements of
super-criticality and strong rotation. We focus on the differences between the
application of no-slip vs. stress-free boundary conditions on the horizontal
plates. The transition is found at roughly the same parameter values for both
boundary conditions, i.e. at~$Ek\approx 9\times 10^{-7}$ for~$Ra=1\times
10^{10}$ and at~$Ek\approx 3\times 10^{-7}$ for~$Ra=5\times 10^{10}$. However,
the transition is gradual and it does not exactly coincide in~$Ek$ for
different flow indicators. In particular, we report the characteristics of the
transitions in the heat transfer scaling laws, the boundary-layer thicknesses,
the bulk/boundary-layer distribution of dissipations and the mean temperature
gradient in the bulk. The flow phenomenology in the geostrophic regime evolves
differently for no-slip and stress-free plates. For stress-free conditions the
formation of a large-scale barotropic vortex with associated inverse energy
cascade is apparent. For no-slip plates, a turbulent state without large-scale
coherent structures is found; the absence of large-scale structure formation is
reflected in the energy transfer in the sense that the inverse cascade, present
for stress-free boundary conditions, vanishes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.8831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.8831</id><created>2014-10-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Aschenauer</keyname><forenames>Elke-Caroline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balitsky</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland</keyname><forenames>Leslie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodsky</keyname><forenames>Stanley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkardt</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkert</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jian-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deshpande</keyname><forenames>Abhay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamberg</keyname><forenames>Leonard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdekamp</keyname><forenames>Matthias Grosse</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hyde</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Xiangdong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Zhong-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubarovsky</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lajoie</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Keh-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liuti</keyname><forenames>Simonetta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melnitchouk</keyname><forenames>Wally</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulders</keyname><forenames>Piet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokudin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarasov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radyushkin</keyname><forenames>Anatoly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richards</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sichtermann</keyname><forenames>Ernst</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stratmann</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsang</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Pre-Town Meeting on Spin Physics at an Electron-Ion Collider</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures; Summary of the Informal Pre-Town Meeting held at
  Jefferson Lab, Newport News, VA, from August 13 - 15, 2014</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A53 (2017), 71</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12251-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A polarized $ep/eA$ collider (Electron--Ion Collider, or EIC), with polarized
proton and light-ion beams and unpolarized heavy-ion beams with a variable
center--of--mass energy $\sqrt{s} \sim 20$ to $\sim100$~GeV (upgradable to
$\sim 150$ GeV) and a luminosity up to $\sim 10^{34} \, \textrm{cm}^{-2}
\textrm{s}^{-1}$, would be uniquely suited to address several outstanding
questions of Quantum Chromodynamics, and thereby lead to new qualitative and
quantitative information on the microscopic structure of hadrons and nuclei.
During this meeting at Jefferson Lab we addressed recent theoretical and
experimental developments in the spin and the three--dimensional structure of
the nucleon (sea quark and gluon spatial distributions, orbital motion,
polarization, and their correlations). This mini--review contains a short
update on progress in these areas since the EIC White
paper~\cite{Accardi:2012qut}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7392</id><created>2014-11-26</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>von Manteuffel</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panzer</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schabinger</keyname><forenames>Robert M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A quasi-finite basis for multi-loop Feynman integrals</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 3 figures; in v2: added additional references. v2 is the
  version published in JHEP; in v3: fixed references</comments><report-no>MITP/14-076</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, February 2015:120</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2015)120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new method for the decomposition of multi-loop Euclidean Feynman
integrals into quasi-finite Feynman integrals. These are defined in shifted
dimensions with higher powers of the propagators, make explicit both infrared
and ultraviolet divergences, and allow for an immediate and trivial expansion
in the parameter of dimensional regularization. Our approach avoids the
introduction of spurious structures and thereby leaves integrals particularly
accessible to direct analytical integration techniques. Alternatively, the
resulting convergent Feynman parameter integrals may be evaluated numerically.
Our approach is guided by previous work by the second author but overcomes
practical limitations of the original procedure by employing integration by
parts reduction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.00849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.00849</id><created>2015-06-02</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rieder</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teyssier</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author></authors><title>A small-scale dynamo in feedback-dominated galaxies as the origin of
  cosmic magnetic fields - I. The kinematic phase</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>19 pages, 19 figures. This is a pre-copyedited, author-produced
  version of an article accepted for publication in MNRAS following peer
  review. The version of record is available online (see information below)</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 04/2016, Volume
  457, Issue 2, p.1722-1738</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin and evolution of magnetic fields in the Universe is still an open
question. Their observations in galaxies suggest strong magnetic fields already
at high redshift as well as at present time. However, neither primordial
magnetic fields nor battery processes can account for such high field
strengths, which implies the presence of a dynamo process with rapid growth
rates in high-redshift galaxies and subsequent maintenance against decay. We
investigate the particular role played by feedback mechanisms in creating
strong fluid turbulence, allowing for a magnetic dynamo to emerge. Performing
magnetohydrodynamic simulations of isolated cooling gas halos, we compare the
magnetic field evolution for various initial field topologies and various
stellar feedback mechanisms. We find that feedback can indeed drive strong gas
turbulence and dynamo action. We see typical properties of Kolmogorov
turbulence with a $k^{-5/3}$ kinetic energy spectrum, as well as a small-scale
dynamo, with a $k^{3/2}$ magnetic energy spectrum predicted by Kazantsev dynamo
theory. We also investigate simulations with a final quiescent phase. As
turbulence decreases, the galactic fountain settles into a thin, rotationally
supported disk. The magnetic field develops a large-scale, well-ordered
structure with even symmetry, which is in good agreement with magnetic field
observations of nearby spirals. Our findings suggest that weak initial seed
fields were first amplified by a small-scale dynamo during a violent,
feedback-dominated early phase in the galaxy formation history, followed by a
more quiescent evolution, where the fields have slowly decayed or were
maintained via large-scale dynamo action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08350</id><created>2015-09-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Pimenova</keyname><forenames>Anastasiya V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldobin</keyname><forenames>Denis S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence of Noisy Oscillators with Delayed Feedback Inducing
  Multistability</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.AO</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, proceeding paper for International Conference on
  Computer Simulation in Physics and beyond (September 6-10, 2015, Moscow,
  Russia)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series, Vol. 681, 012045 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/681/1/012045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For self-sustained oscillators subject to noise the coherence, understood as
a constancy of the instantaneous oscillation frequency, is one of the primary
characteristics. The delayed feedback has been previously revealed to be an
efficient tool for controlling coherence of noise-driven self-sustained
oscillator. The effect of the delayed feedback control on coherence is stronger
for a longer delay time. Meanwhile, the instantaneous frequency of a noise-free
oscillator can exhibit multistability for long delay time. The impact of the
delay-feedback--induced multistability on the oscillation coherence, measured
by the phase diffusion constant, of a noisy oscillator is studied in this work
both numerically and analytically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00522</id><created>2015-10-02</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baykal</keyname><forenames>Ahmet</forenames></author></authors><title>pp-waves in modified gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>References updated. Additions/corrections have been made. 70 pages</comments><journal-ref>Turk. J. Phys. 40 (2016) 77-112</journal-ref><doi>10.3906/fiz-1508-16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The family of metrics corresponding to the plane-fronted gravitational waves
with parallel propagation, commonly referred to as the family of pp-wave
metrics, is studied in the context of various modified gravitational models in
a self-contained and coherent manner by using a variant of the null coframe
formulation of Newman and Penrose and the exterior algebra of differential
forms on pseudo-Riemannian manifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02468</id><created>2015-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Pimenova</keyname><forenames>Anastasiya V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldobin</keyname><forenames>Denis S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Boiling of Crude Oil under Elevated Pressure</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure, proceeding paper for International Conference on
  Computer Simulation in Physics and beyond (September 6-10, 2015, Moscow,
  Russia)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series, Vol. 681, 012031 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/681/1/012031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a thermodynamic model for theoretical calculation of the boiling
process of multicomponent mixtures of hydrocarbons (e.g., crude oil). The model
governs kinetics of the mixture composition in the course of the distillation
process along with the boiling temperature increase. The model heavily relies
on the theory of dilute solutions of gases in liquids. Importantly, our results
are applicable for modelling the process under elevated pressure (while the
empiric models for oil cracking are not scalable to the case of extreme
pressure), such as in an oil field heated by lava intrusions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03311</id><created>2015-11-10</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Qing-Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yandong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>Measuring Trilinear Higgs Coupling in $WHH$ and $ZHH$ Productions at the
  HL-LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 073006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.073006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Determination of trilinear Higgs coupling
($\lambda_{HHH}=\kappa\lambda_{HHH}^{\rm SM}$) through Higgs pair productions
is a major motivation for the LHC high luminosity phase. We perform a detailed
collider simulation to explore the potential of measuring $\lambda_{HHH}$ in
the $VHH$ ($V=W,Z$) production at the HL-LHC. We find that the trilinear Higgs
coupling in the SM ($\lambda_{HHH}^{\rm SM}$) could be measured at the level of
$1.3\sigma$. Combining with the gluon fusion, vector boson fusion and
$t\bar{t}HH$ channels, $\lambda_{HHH}^{\rm SM}$ is expected to be measured at
the level of $3.13\sigma$. If no evidence of Higgs pair productions were
observed, the $VHH$ production, together with the gluon fusion channel, would
impose a bound of $0.5\leq \kappa \leq 2.2$ at the 95\% confidence level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03632</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akbar</keyname><forenames>Nosheen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultan</keyname><forenames>M. Atif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masud</keyname><forenames>Bilal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akram</keyname><forenames>Faisal</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher Hybrid Bottomonia in an Extended Potential Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages,1 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 074018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.074018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using our extension of the quark potential model to hybrid mesons that fits
well to the available lattice results, we now calculate the masses, radii, wave
functions at origin, leptonic and two photon decay widths, E1 and M1 radiative
transitions for a significant number of bottomonium mesons. These mesons
include both conventional and hybrid ones with radial and angular excitations.
Our numerical solutions of the Schrodinger equation are related to QCD through
the Born-Oppenheimer approach. Relativistic corrections in masses and decay
widths are also calculated by applying the leading order perturbation theory.
The calculated results are compared with available experimental data and the
theoretical results by other groups. We also identify the states of
$\Upsilon(10860)$, $\Upsilon(11020)$, and $Y_b(10890)$ mesons by comparing
their experimental masses and decay widths with our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06117</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06117</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2017-04-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller-Hermes</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reeb</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Monotonicity of the Quantum Relative Entropy Under Positive Maps</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v3: published version; v2: 9 pages, extended results to infinite
  dimensions and lifted trace-preservation condition, added discussions and
  references; v1: 5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincare 18, 1777-1788 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-017-0550-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the quantum relative entropy decreases monotonically under the
application of any positive trace-preserving linear map, for underlying
separable Hilbert spaces. This answers in the affirmative a natural question
that has been open for a long time, as monotonicity had previously only been
shown to hold under additional assumptions, such as complete positivity or
Schwarz-positivity of the adjoint map. The first step in our proof is to show
monotonicity of the sandwiched Renyi divergences under positive
trace-preserving maps, extending a proof of the data processing inequality by
Beigi [J. Math. Phys. 54, 122202 (2013)] that is based on complex interpolation
techniques. Our result calls into question several measures of non-Markovianity
that have been proposed, as these would assess all positive trace-preserving
time evolutions as Markovian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07401</id><created>2015-12-23</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gheorghiu</keyname><forenames>Alexandru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallden</keyname><forenames>Petros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashefi</keyname><forenames>Elham</forenames></author></authors><title>Rigidity of quantum steering and one-sided device-independent verifiable
  quantum computation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Journal version. We acknowledge discussions with Matty J Hoban on his
  and Ivan \v{S}upi\'c's independent work on self-testing using quantum
  steering, arXiv:1601.01552</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 (2017) 023043</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa5cff</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relationship between correlations and entanglement has played a major
role in understanding quantum theory since the work of Einstein, Podolsky and
Rosen (1935). Tsirelson (1980) proved that Bell states, shared among two
parties, when measured suitably, achieve the maximum non-local correlations
allowed by quantum mechanics. Conversely, Reichardt, Unger and Vazirani (2013)
showed that observing the maximal correlation value over a sequence of repeated
measurements, implies that the underlying quantum state is close to a tensor
product of maximally entangled states and, moreover, that it is measured
according to an ideal strategy. However, this strong rigidity result comes at a
high price, requiring a large number of entangled pairs to be tested. In this
paper, we present a significant improvement in terms of the overhead by instead
considering quantum steering where the device of the one side is trusted. We
first demonstrate a robust one-sided device-independent version of
self-testing, which characterises the shared state and measurement operators of
two parties up to a certain bound. We show that this bound is optimal up to
constant factors and we generalise the results for the most general attacks.
This leads us to a rigidity theorem for maximal steering correlations. As a key
application we give a one-sided device-independent protocol for verifiable
delegated quantum computation, and compare it to other existing protocols, to
highlight the cost of trust assumptions. Finally, we show that under reasonable
assumptions, the states shared in order to run a certain type of verification
protocol must be unitarily equivalent to perfect Bell states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05707</id><created>2016-01-21</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okolow</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinematic projective quantum states for Loop Quantum Gravity coupled to
  tensor fields</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, LaTex2e</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 58, 042302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4980014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a construction of kinematic quantum states for theories of tensor
fields of an arbitrary sort. The construction is based on projective techniques
by Kijowski. Applying projective quantum states for Loop Quantum Gravity
obtained by Lanery and Thiemann we construct quantum states for LQG coupled to
tensor fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06607</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benguria</keyname><forenames>Rafael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fournais</keyname><forenames>S&#xf8;ren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockmeyer</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosch</keyname><forenames>Hanne Van Den</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral gaps of Dirac operators describing graphene quantum dots</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>final version, improved introduction on boundary conditions in
  physics literature, self-adjointness-result deferred to other paper,
  references added</comments><msc-class>35Pxx (primary), 81Q05, 81Q10 (secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Math Phys Anal Geom (2017) 20: 11</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11040-017-9242-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The two-dimensional Dirac operator describes low-energy excitations in
graphene. Different choices for the boundary conditions give rise to
qualitative differences in the spectrum of the resulting operator. For a family
of boundary conditions, we find a lower bound to the spectral gap around zero,
proportional to $|\Omega|^{-1/2}$, where $\Omega \subset \mathbb{R}^2$ is the
bounded region where the Dirac operator acts. This family contains the
so-called infinite mass and armchair cases used in the physics literature for
the description of graphene quantum dots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05442</id><created>2016-02-17</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ostilla-M&#xf3;nico</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verzicco</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of roll number on the statistics of turbulent Taylor-Couette
  flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Fluids, 5 (1), 054402, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/physrevfluids.1.054402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A series of direct numerical simulations in large computational domains has
been performed in order to probe the spatial feature robustness of the Taylor
rolls in turbulent Taylor-Couette (TC) flow. The latter is the flow between two
coaxial independently rotating cylinders of radius $r_i$ and $r_o$,
respectively. Large axial aspect ratios $\Gamma = 7$-$8$ (with $\Gamma =
L/(r_o-r_i)$, and $L$ the axial length of the domain) and a simulation with
$\Gamma=14$ were used in order to allow the system to select the most unstable
wavenumber and to possibly develop multiple states. The radius ratio was taken
as $\eta=r_i/r_o=0.909$, the inner cylinder Reynolds number was fixed to
$Re_i=3.4\cdot10^4$, and the outer cylinder was kept stationary, resulting in a
frictional Reynolds number of $Re_\tau\approx500$, except for the $\Gamma=14$
simulation where $Re_i=1.5\cdot10^4$ and $Re_\tau\approx240$. The large-scale
rolls were found to remain axially pinned for all simulations. Depending on the
initial conditions, stable solutions with different number of rolls $n_r$ and
roll wavelength $\lambda_z$ were found for $\Gamma=7$. The effect of
$\lambda_z$ and $n_r$ on the statistics was quantified. The torque and mean
flow statistics were found to be independent of both $\lambda_z$ and $n_r$,
while the velocity fluctuations and energy spectra showed some box-size
dependence. Finally, the axial velocity spectra was found to have a very sharp
drop off for wavelengths larger than $\lambda_z$, while for the small
wavelengths they collapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00065</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ortiz-Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabrielly</keyname><forenames>Bruna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Luis F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Kain&#xe3; T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filgueiras</keyname><forenames>Jefferson G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villar</keyname><forenames>Alessandro S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuous variables quantum computation over the vibrational modes of a
  single trapped ion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Commun. 397, 166 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.optcom.2017.04.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the quantum processor based on a chain of trapped ions to propose
an architecture wherein the motional degrees of freedom of trapped ions
(position and momentum) could be exploited as the computational Hilbert space.
We adopt a continuous-variables approach to develop a toolbox of quantum
operations to manipulate one or two vibrational modes at a time. Together with
the intrinsic non-linearity of the qubit degree of freedom, employed to mediate
the interaction between modes, arbitrary manipulation and readout of the ionic
wave function could be achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01465</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-08-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moradpour</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>Rafael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abreu</keyname><forenames>Everton M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>Jorge Ananias</forenames></author></authors><title>A note on the relations between thermodynamics, energy definitions and
  Friedmann equations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>The text has been increased</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A (2017), Vol. 32, No. 13, 1750078</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231750078X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In what follows, we investigate the relation between the Friedmann and
thermodynamic pressure equations, through solving the Friedmann and
thermodynamic pressure equations simultaneously. Our investigation shows that a
perfect fluid, as a suitable solution for the Friedmann equations leading to
the standard modelling of the universe expansion history, cannot simultaneously
satisfy the thermodynamic pressure equation and those of Friedmann. Moreover,
we consider various energy definitions, such as the Komar mass, and solve the
Friedmann and thermodynamic pressure equations simultaneously to get some
models for dark energy. The cosmological consequences of obtained solutions are
also addressed. Our results indicate that some of obtained solutions may unify
the dominated fluid in both the primary inflationary and current accelerating
eras into one model. In addition, by taking into account a cosmic fluid of a
known equation of state, and combining it with the Friedmann and thermodynamic
pressure equations, we obtain the corresponding energy of these cosmic fluids
and face their limitations. Finally, we point out the cosmological features of
this cosmic fluid and also study its observational constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06367</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-12-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral corrections to the $1^{-+}$ exotic meson mass</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, references added, revised. Version to be
  published in Chinese Physics C</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C41 (2017) no.4, 043101</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/4/043101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We first construct the effective chiral Lagrangians for the $1^{-+}$ exotic
mesons. With the infrared regularization scheme, we derive the one-loop
infrared singular chiral corrections to the $\pi_1(1600)$ mass explicitly. We
investigate the variation of the different chiral corrections with the pion
mass under two schemes. Hopefully, the explicit non-analytical chiral
structures will be helpful to the chiral extrapolation of the lattice data from
the dynamical lattice QCD simulation of either the exotic light hybrid meson or
tetraquark state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00963</id><created>2016-04-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Diakonova</keyname><forenames>Marina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramasco</keyname><forenames>Jose J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eguiluz</keyname><forenames>Victor M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical leaps due to microscopic changes in multiplex networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI nlin.AO</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL (Europhysics Letters) 117, 48004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/48004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent developments of the multiplex paradigm included efforts to understand
the role played by the presence of several layers on the dynamics of processes
running on these networks. The possible existence of new phenomena associated
to the richer topology has been discussed and examples of these differences
have been systematically searched. Here, we show that the interconnectivity of
the layers may have an important impact on the speed of the dynamics run in the
network and that microscopic changes such as the addition of one single
inter-layer link can notably affect the arrival at a global stationary state.
As a practical verification, these results obtained with spectral techniques
are confirmed with a Kuramoto dynamics for which the synchronization
consistently delays after the addition of single inter-layer links.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01332</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valderrama</keyname><forenames>Manuel Pavon</forenames></author></authors><title>Power Counting and Wilsonian Renormalization in Nuclear Effective Field
  Theory</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to the IJMPE special issue on &quot;Effective Field Theories
  in Nuclear Physics&quot;. This update includes the corrections and changes of the
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Int.J.Mod.Phys. E25 (2016) no.05, 1641007</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021830131641007X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effective field theories are the most general tool for the description of low
energy phenomena. They are universal and systematic: they can be formulated for
any low energy systems we can think of and offer a clear guide on how to
calculate predictions with reliable error estimates, a feature that is called
power counting. These properties can be easily understood in Wilsonian
renormalization, in which effective field theories are the low energy
renormalization group evolution of a more fundamental ---perhaps unknown or
unsolvable--- high energy theory. In nuclear physics they provide the
possibility of a theoretically sound derivation of nuclear forces without
having to solve quantum chromodynamics explicitly. However there is the problem
of how to organize calculations within nuclear effective field theory: the
traditional knowledge about power counting is perturbative but nuclear physics
is not. Yet power counting can be derived in Wilsonian renormalization and
there is already a fairly good understanding of how to apply these ideas to
non-perturbative phenomena and in particular to nuclear physics. Here we review
a few of these ideas, explain power counting in two-nucleon scattering and
reactions with external probes and hint at how to extend the present analysis
beyond the two-body problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04247</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>De-Chang</forenames></author></authors><title>Serious limitations of the strong equivalence principle</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A Vol. 32 (2017) 1750068</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500683</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that an accelerated charged particle radiates away energy.
However, whether an accelerated neutral composite particle radiates away energy
is unclear. We study decoherent Larmor radiation from an accelerated neutral
composite object. We find that the neutral object's long wavelength radiation
is highly suppressed because radiation from different charges is canceled out.
However, the neutral object radiates high energy or short wavelength radiation
without any suppression. In that case, radiation from each particle can be
treated independently, and it is called the decoherent radiation. We compare a
hydrogen atom's decoherent Larmor radiation with its gravitational radiation
while the atom is in a circular orbit around a star. Gravitational radiation is
stronger than the electromagnetic radiation if the orbital radius is larger
than some critical radius. Since the decoherent radiation is related to the
object's structure, this implies that the strong equivalence principle which
states that gravitational motion does not depend on an object's constitution
has severe limitations..
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06244</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pradhan</keyname><forenames>Parthapratim</forenames></author></authors><title>Circular Orbits in the Taub-NUT and mass-less Taub-NUT Space-time</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Version accepted in International Journal of Geometric Methods in
  Modern Physics</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Geometric Methods in Modern Physics, Vol.
  14 (2017) 1750101</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887817501018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the equatorial causal geodesics of the Taub-NUT (TN)
space-time in comparison with \emph{mass-less} TN space-time. We emphasized
both on the null circular geodesics and time-like circular geodesics. From the
effective potential diagram of null and time-like geodesics, we differentiate
the geodesics structure between TN spacetime and mass-less TN space-time. It
has been shown that there is a key role of the NUT parameter to changes the
shape of pattern of the potential well in the NUT spacetime in comparison with
\emph{mass-less} NUT space-time. We compared the ISCO (innermost stable
circular orbit), MBCO (marginally bound circular orbit) and CPO (circular
photon orbit) of the said space-time with graphically in comparison with
mass-less cases. Moreover, we compute the radius of ISCO, MBCO and CPO for
\emph{extreme} TN black hole (BH). Interestingly, we show that these
\emph{three radii} coincides with the Killing horizon i.e. the null geodesic
generators of the horizon. Finally in Appendix-A, we compute the center-of-mass
(CM) energy for TN BH and mass-less TN BH. We show that in both cases the CM
energy is finite. For \emph{extreme} NUT BH, we have found that the diverging
nature of CM energy. \emph{First}, we have observed that a non-asymptotic flat,
spherically symmetric and stationary extreme BH is showing such feature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05590</id><created>2016-06-17</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brax</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Anne-Christine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noller</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Energy and Doubly Coupled Bigravity</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>47 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav. 34 (2017) no.9, 095014</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6856</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the late time cosmology and the gravitational properties of doubly
coupled bigravity in the constrained vielbein formalism (equivalent to the
metric formalism) when the mass of the massive graviton is of the order of the
present Hubble rate. We focus on one of the two branches of background
cosmology where the ratio between the scale factors of the two metrics is
algebraically determined. The Universe evolves from a matter dominated epoch to
a dark energy dominated era where the equation of state of dark energy can
always be made close to -1 now by appropriately tuning the graviton mass. We
also analyse the perturbative spectrum of the theory in the quasi static
approximation well below the strong coupling scale where no instability is
present and we show that there are five scalar degrees of freedom, two vectors
and two gravitons. In a cosmological FRW background for both metrics, four of
the five scalars are Newtonian potentials which lead to a modification of
gravity on large scales. In this scalar sector, gravity is modified with
effects on both the growth of structure and the lensing potential. In
particular, we find that the $\Sigma$ parameter governing the Poisson equation
of the weak lensing potential can differ from one in the recent past of the
Universe. Overall, the nature of the modification of gravity at low energy,
which reveals itself in the growth of structure and the lensing potential, is
intrinsically dependent on the couplings to matter and the potential term of
the vielbeins. We also find that the time variation of Newton's constant in the
Jordan frame can easily satisfy the bound from solar system tests of gravity.
Finally we show that the two gravitons present in the spectrum have a
non-trivial mass matrix whose origin follows from the potential term of
bigravity. This mixing leads to gravitational birefringence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07936</id><created>2016-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>The uncertainty principle in terms of isoperimetric inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><journal-ref>Applied Mathematics, Vol. 8, 307-311 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/am.2017.83025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simultaneous measurements of position and momentum are considered in $n$
dimensions. We find, that for a particle whose position is strictly localized
in a compact domain $D\subset \mathbb{R}^n$ (spatial uncertainty) with
non-empty boundary, the standard deviation of its momentum is sharply bounded
by $\sigma_p \geq \lambda_1^{1/2}\hbar$, while $\lambda_1$ is the first
Dirichlet eigenvalue of the Laplacian on $D$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08465</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandkishore</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopalakrishnan</keyname><forenames>Sarang</forenames></author></authors><title>General theory of many body localized systems coupled to baths</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Updated references</comments><journal-ref>Annalen der Physik, 1521-3889 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201600181</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider what happens when a many body localized system is coupled to a
heat bath. Unlike previous works, we do not restrict ourselves to the limit
where the bath is large and effectively Markovian, nor to the limit where back
action on the bath is negligible. We identify limits where the effect of the
bath can be captured by classical noise, and limits where it cannot. We also
identify limits in which the bath delocalizes the system, as well as limits in
which the system localizes the bath. Using general arguments and dimensional
analysis, we constrain the overall phase diagram of the coupled system and
bath. Our analysis incorporates all the previously discussed regimes, and also
uncovers a new intrinsically quantum regime that has not hitherto been
discussed. We discuss baths that are themselves near a localization transition,
or are strongly disordered but protected against localization by symmetry or
topology. We also discuss situations where the system and bath have different
dimensionality (the case of `boundary MBL' and `boundary baths').
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03228</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanoda</keyname><forenames>Kazushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>Tai-Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Spin Liquid States</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Invited by RMP</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Mod. Phys. 89, 025003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/RevModPhys.89.025003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article is an introductory review of the physics of quantum spin liquid
(QSL) states. Quantum magnetism is a rapidly evolving field, and recent
developments reveal that the ground states and low-energy physics of frustrated
spin systems may develop many exotic behaviors once we leave the regime of
semi-classical approaches. The purpose of this article is to introduce these
developments. The article begins by explaining how semi-classical approaches
fail once quantum mechanics become important and then describes the alternative
approaches for addressing the problem. We discuss mainly spin $1/2$ systems,
and we spend most of our time in this article on one particular set of
plausible spin liquid states in which spins are represented by fermions. These
states are spin-singlet states and may be viewed as an extension of Fermi
liquid states to Mott insulators, and they are usually classified in the
category of so-called $SU(2)$, $U(1)$ or $Z_2$ spin liquid states. We review
the basic theory regarding these states and the extensions of these states to
include the effect of spin-orbit coupling and to higher spin ($S&gt;1/2$) systems.
Two other important approaches with strong influences on the understanding of
spin liquid states are also introduced: (i) matrix product states and projected
entangled pair states and (ii) the Kitaev honeycomb model. Experimental
progress concerning spin liquid states in realistic materials, including
anisotropic triangular lattice systems ($\kappa$-(ET)$_{2}$Cu$_{2}$(CN)$_{3}$
and EtMe$_{3}$Sb[(Pd(dmit)$_{2}$]$_{2}$), kagome lattice systems
(ZnCu$_{3}$(OH)$_{6}$Cl$_{2}$) and hyperkagome lattice systems
(Na$_{4}$Ir$_{3}$O$_{8}$), is reviewed and compared against the corresponding
theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06341</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monsivais</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Kunal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Asim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunbar</keyname><forenames>Robin I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaski</keyname><forenames>Kimmo</forenames></author></authors><title>Seasonal and geographical impact on human resting periods</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI q-bio.QM</categories><comments>This version substitutes the previous manuscript (with old title
  &quot;Seasonal and geographical influence on sleeping patterns inferred from
  mobile phone data&quot;), which now is split into two manuscripts due to its
  length and new investigations added. The current version includes the part
  related to seasonal variations of the resting periods</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the influence of seasonally and geographically related daily
dynamics of daylight and ambient temperature on human resting or sleeping
patterns using mobile phone data of a large number of individuals. We observe
two daily inactivity periods in the people's aggregated mobile phone calling
patterns and infer these to represent the resting times of the population. We
find that the nocturnal resting period is strongly influenced by the length of
daylight, and that its seasonal variation depends on the latitude, such that
for people living in two different cities separated by eight latitudinal
degrees, the difference in the resting period of people between the summer and
winter in southern cities is almost twice that in the northern cities. We also
observe that the duration of the afternoon resting period is influenced by the
temperature, and that there is a threshold from which this influence sets in.
Finally, we observe that the yearly dynamics of the afternoon and nocturnal
resting periods appear to be counterbalancing each other. This also lends
support to the notion that the total daily resting time of people is more or
less conserved across the year.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06445</id><created>2016-07-21</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hertzberg</keyname><forenames>Mark P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masoumi</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Astrophysical Constraints on Singlet Scalars at LHC</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures. V4: updated to version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 04 (2017) 028</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/04/028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the viability of new heavy gauge singlet scalar particles at
colliders such as the LHC. Our original motivation for this study came from the
possibility of a new heavy particle of mass ~ TeV decaying significantly into
two photons at colliders, such as LHC, but our analysis applies more broadly.
We show that there are significant constraints from astrophysics and cosmology
on the simplest UV complete models that incorporate such new particles and its
associated collider signal. The simplest and most obvious UV complete model
that incorporates such signals is that it arises from a new singlet scalar (or
pseudo-scalar) coupled to a new electrically charged and colored heavy fermion.
Here we show that these new fermions (and anti-fermions) would be produced in
the early universe, then form new color singlet heavy mesons with light quarks,
obtain a non-negligible freeze-out abundance, and remain in kinetic equilibrium
until decoupling. These heavy mesons possess interesting phenomenology,
dependent on their charge, including forming new bound states with electrons
and protons. We show that a significant number of these heavy states would
survive for the age of the universe and an appreciable number would eventually
be contained within the earth and solar system. We show that this leads to
detectable consequences, including the production of highly energetic events
from annihilations on earth, new spectral lines, and, spectacularly, the
destabilization of stars. The lack of detection of these consequences rules out
such simple UV completions, putting pressure on the viability of such new
particles at LHC. To incorporate such a scalar would require either much more
complicated UV completions or even further new physics that provides a decay
channel for the associated fermion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00344</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moustakidis</keyname><forenames>Ch. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaitanos</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margaritis</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lalazissis</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounds on the speed of sound in dense matter, and neutron star structure</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>17 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 045801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.045801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The accurate determination of the maximum mass of the neutron stars is one of
the most important tasks in astrophysics. It is directly related to the
identification of the black holes in the universe, the production of neutron
stars from the supernovae explosion, and the equation of state (EoS) of dense
matter. However, not only the EoS is directly connected with neutron star
masses, but also the speed of sound in dense matter is a crucial quantity which
characterizes the stiffness of the EoS. The upper bound of the speed of sound
imposes strong constraints on the maximum mass of neutron stars. However, this
upper bound remains still an open issue. Recent observations, of binary neutron
star systems, offer the possibility of measuring with high accuracy both the
mass and the tidal polarizability of the stars. We study possible effects of
the upper bound of the speed of sound on the upper bound of the mass and the
tidal polarizability. We conclude that these kinds of measurements, combined
with recent observations of neutron stars with masses close to $2 M_{\odot}$,
will provide robust constraints on the equation of state of hadronic matter at
high densities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00565</id><created>2016-07-30</created><updated>2016-12-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>A. M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coelho</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray powder diffraction of high-absorption materials at the XRD1
  beamline off the best conditions: Application to (Gd,Nd)5Si4 compounds</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Powder Diffraction, 32(1), 10-14 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0885715616000646</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Representative compounds of the new family of magnetic materials Gd5-xNdxSi4
were analyzed by X-ray diffraction at the XRD1 beamline at LNLS. To reduce
X-ray absorption, thin layers of the powder samples were mounted outside the
capillaries and measured in Debye-Scherrer geometry as usual. The X-ray
diffraction analyses and the magnetometry results indicate that the behavior of
the magnetic transition temperature as a function of Nd content may be directly
related to the average of the four smallest interatomic distances between
different rare earth sites of the majority phase of each compound. The quality
and consistency of the results show that the XRD1 beamline is able to perform
satisfactory X-ray diffraction experiments on high-absorption materials even
off the best conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04699</id><created>2016-08-16</created><updated>2017-03-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Acharya</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ekstr&#xf6;m</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odell</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papenbrock</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platter</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Corrections to nucleon capture cross sections computed in truncated
  Hilbert spaces</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 031301(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.031301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nucleon capture cross sections enter various astrophysical processes. The
measurement of proton capture on nuclei at astrophysically relevant low
energies is a challenge, and theoretical computations in this long-wavelength
regime are sensitive to the long-distance asymptotics of the wave functions. A
theoretical foundation for estimating and correcting errors introduced in
capture cross sections due to Hilbert space truncation has so far been lacking.
We derive extrapolation formulas that relate the infrared regularized capture
amplitudes to the infinite basis limit and demonstrate their efficacy for
proton-proton fusion. Our results are thus relevant to current calculations of
few-body capture reactions such as proton-proton fusion or proton capture on
the deuteron, and they also open the way for the use of {\it ab initio}
many-body wave functions represented in finite Hilbert spaces in precision
calculations of nucleon capture on heavier nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07037</id><created>2016-08-25</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cayron</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author></authors><title>Displacive model of deformation twinning in hexagonal close-packed
  metals. Case of the (90 deg, a) and (86 deg, a) extension twins in magnesium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>41 pages, 12 figures, 1 Appendix with 3 figures, 6 Suppl. Materials</comments><journal-ref>Materials and Design, 2017, vol. 119, p. 361-375</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.matdes.2017.01.047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A crystallographic displacive model is proposed for the extension twins in
magnesium. It is based on a hard-sphere assumption previously used for
martensitic transformations. The atomic displacements are established, and the
homogeneous lattice distortion is analytically expressed as a continuous
angular-distortive matrix that takes the usual form of shear when the
distortion is complete. The calculations prove that a volume change of 3
percents occurs for the intermediate states and that the twinning plane, even
if untilted and restored when the distortion is complete, is not fully
invariant during the transient states. The crystallographic calculations also
show that the (90 deg, a) twins observed in magnesium nano-pillars and the (86
deg, a) twins observed in bulk samples come from the same mechanism, the only
difference being the existence of a slight obliquity angle (+/- 3.4 deg)
required to reduce the strains in the latter case. Continuous features in the
pole figures between the low-misoriented (86 deg, a) twin variants are
expected; they are confirmed by EBSD maps acquired on a deformed magnesium
single crystal. As the continuous mechanism of extension twinning is not a
simple shear, a &quot;virtual work&quot; criterion using the value of the intermediate
distortion matrix at the maximum volume change is proposed in place of the
usual Schmid's law. It allows predicting the formation of extension twins for
crystal orientations associated with negative Schmid factors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07066</id><created>2016-08-25</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>Rampei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naruko</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Daisuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Extended vector-tensor theories</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>39 pages, 2 figures, v2: published in JCAP, v3: several references
  are added, v4: some typos are corrected</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/01/002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, several extensions of massive vector theory in curved space-time
have been proposed in many literatures. In this paper, we consider the most
general vector-tensor theories that contain up to two derivatives with respect
to metric and vector field. By imposing a degeneracy condition of the
Lagrangian in the context of ADM decomposition of space-time to eliminate an
unwanted mode, we construct a new class of massive vector theories where five
degrees of freedom can propagate, corresponding to three for massive vector
modes and two for massless tensor modes. We find that the generalized Proca and
the beyond generalized Proca theories up to the quartic Lagrangian, which
should be included in this formulation, are degenerate theories even in curved
space-time. Finally, introducing new metric and vector field transformations,
we investigate the properties of thus obtained theories under such
transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01551</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Fritsch</keyname><forenames>Veronika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucas</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huesges</keyname><forenames>Zita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Akito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kittler</keyname><forenames>Wolfram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taubenheim</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woitschach</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf8;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grube</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gegenwart</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockert</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;hneysen</keyname><forenames>Hilbert v.</forenames></author></authors><title>CePdAl - a Kondo lattice with partial frustration</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conf. Series 807 (2017) 032003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/807/3/032003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic frustration, which is well-defined in insulating systems with
localized magnetic moments, yields exotic ground states like spin ices, spin
glasses, or spin liquids. In metals magnetic frustration is less well defined
because of the incipient delocalization of magnetic moments by the interaction
with conduction electrons, viz., the Kondo effect. Hence, the Kondo effect and
magnetic frustration are antithetic phenomena. Here we present experimental
data of electrical resistivity, magnetization, specific heat and neutron
diffraction on CePdAl, which is one of the rare examples of a geometrically
frustrated Kondo lattice, demonstrating that the combination of Kondo effect
and magnetic frustration leads to an unusual ground state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02079</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-03-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parihar</keyname><forenames>Abhinav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>Nikhil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jerry</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Suman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raychowdhury</keyname><forenames>Arijit</forenames></author></authors><title>Vertex coloring of graphs via phase dynamics of coupled oscillatory
  networks</title><categories>cs.ET cond-mat.other math.DS</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7 (2017) 911</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-00825-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While Boolean logic has been the backbone of digital information processing,
there are classes of computationally hard problems wherein this conventional
paradigm is fundamentally inefficient. Vertex coloring of graphs, belonging to
the class of combinatorial optimization represents such a problem; and is well
studied for its wide spectrum of applications in data sciences, life sciences,
social sciences and engineering and technology. This motivates alternate, and
more efficient non-Boolean pathways to their solution. Here, we demonstrate a
coupled relaxation oscillator based dynamical system that exploits the
insulator-metal transition in vanadium dioxide (VO2), to efficiently solve the
vertex coloring of graphs. By harnessing the natural analogue between
optimization, pertinent to graph coloring solutions, and energy minimization
processes in highly parallel, interconnected dynamical systems, we harness the
physical manifestation of the latter process to approximate the optimal
coloring of k-partite graphs. We further indicate a fundamental connection
between the eigen properties of a linear dynamical system and the spectral
algorithms that can solve approximate graph coloring. Our work not only
elucidates a physics-based computing approach but also presents tantalizing
opportunities for building customized analog co-processors for solving hard
problems efficiently.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02282</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Xianxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Yefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Shengwang</forenames></author></authors><title>Bell inequality of frequency-bin entangled photon pairs with
  time-resolved detection</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Optica 4, 388 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000388</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement, describing the inseparability of a quantum multiparty system,
is one of the most intriguing features of quantum mechanics. Violation of Bell
inequality, for ruling out the possibility of local hidden variable theories,
is commonly used as a strong witness for quantum entanglement. In previous Bell
test experiments with photonic entanglement based on two-photon coincidence
measurement, the photon temporal wave packets are absorbed completely by the
detectors. That is, the photon coherence time is much shorter than the
detection time window. Here we demonstrate generation of frequency-bin
entangled narrowband biphotons, and for the first time, test the
Clauser-Horne-Shimony-Holt (CHSH) Bell inequality |S|&lt;= 2 for their nonlocal
temporal correlations with time-resolved detection. We obtain a maximum |S|
value of 2.52+/-0.48 that violates the CHSH inequality. Our result will have
applications in quantum information processing involving time-frequency
entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04329</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Underwood</keyname><forenames>T. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ackland</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Monteswitch: A package for evaluating solid-solid free energy
  differences via lattice-switch Monte Carlo</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>Computer Physics Communications 215 204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2017.02.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lattice-switch Monte Carlo (LSMC) is a method for evaluating the free energy
between two given solid phases. LSMC is a general method, being applicable to a
wide range of problems and interatomic potentials. Furthermore it is extremely
efficient, ostensibly more efficient than other existing general methods. Here
we introduce a package, monteswitch, which can be used to perform LSMC
simulations. The package can be used to evaluate the free energy differences
between pairs of solid phases, including multicomponent phases, via LSMC for
atomic (i.e., non-molecular) systems in the NVT and NPT ensembles. It could
also be used to evaluate the free energy cost associated with interfaces and
defects. Regarding interatomic potentials, monteswitch currently supports
various commonly-used pair potentials, including the hard-sphere,
Lennard-Jones, and Morse potentials, as well as the embedded atom model.
However the main strength of the package is its versatility: it is designed so
that users can easily implement their own potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07508</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agne</keyname><forenames>Sascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kauten</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Jeongwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer-Scott</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvail</keyname><forenames>Jeff Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamel</keyname><forenames>Deny R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Resch</keyname><forenames>Kevin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weihs</keyname><forenames>Gregor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jennewein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of genuine three-photon interference</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 153602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.153602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multiparticle quantum interference is critical for our understanding and
exploitation of quantum information, and for fundamental tests of quantum
mechanics. A remarkable example of multi-partite correlations is exhibited by
the Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) state. In a GHZ state, three particles
are correlated while no pairwise correlation is found. The manifestation of
these strong correlations in an interferometric setting has been studied
theoretically since 1990 but no three-photon GHZ interferometer has been
realized experimentally. Here we demonstrate three-photon interference that
does not originate from two-photon or single photon interference. We observe
phase-dependent variation of three-photon coincidences with 90.5 \pm 5.0 %
visibility in a generalized Franson interferometer using energy-time entangled
photon triplets. The demonstration of these strong correlations in an
interferometric setting provides new avenues for multiphoton interferometry,
fundamental tests of quantum mechanics and quantum information applications in
higher dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03636</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okuma</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic derivation of magnon spin current in a topological
  insulator/ferromagnet heterostructure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a spin-electricity conversion effect in a topological
insulator/ferromagnet heterostructure. In the spin-momentum-locked surface
state, an electric current generates nonequilibrium spin accumulation, which
causes a spin-orbit torque that acts on the ferromagnet. When spins in the
ferromagnet are completely parallel to the accumulated spin, this spin-orbit
torque is zero. In the presence of spin excitations, however, a coupling
between magnons and electrons enables us to obtain a nonvanishing torque. In
this paper, we consider a model of the heterostructure in which a
three-dimensional magnon gas is coupled with a two-dimensional massless Dirac
electron system at the interface. We calculate the torque induced by an
electric field, which can be interpreted as a magnon spin current, up to the
lowest order of the electron-magnon interaction. We derive the expressions for
high and low temperatures and estimate the order of magnitude of the induced
spin current for realistic materials at room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04619</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sumilan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Altman</keyname><forenames>Ehud</forenames></author></authors><title>Solvable model for a dynamical quantum phase transition from fast to
  slow scrambling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages, 12 figures, added the calculation for Lyapunov exponent
  away from the particle-hole symmetric situation</comments><msc-class>82B26, 81Q50, 82B44, 82C10</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an extension of the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev (SYK) model that exhibits a
quantum phase transition from the previously identified non-Fermi liquid fixed
point to a Fermi liquid like state, while still allowing an exact solution in a
suitable large $N$ limit. The extended model involves coupling the interacting
$N$-site SYK model to a new set of $pN$ peripheral sites with only quadratic
hopping terms between them. The conformal fixed point of the SYK model remains
a stable low energy phase below a critical ratio of peripheral sites $p&lt;p_c(n)$
that depends on the fermion filling $n$. The scrambling dynamics throughout the
non-Fermi liquid phase is characterized by a universal Lyapunov exponent
$\lambda_L\to 2\pi T$ in the low temperature limit, however the temperature
scale marking the crossover to the conformal regime vanishes continuously at
the critical point $p_c$. The residual entropy at $T\to 0$, non zero in the
NFL, also vanishes continuously at the critical point. For $p&gt;p_c$ the
quadratic sites effectively screen the SYK dynamics, leading to a quadratic
fixed point in the low temperature and frequency limit. The interactions have a
perturbative effect in this regime leading to scrambling with Lyapunov exponent
$\lambda_L\propto T^2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05105</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Waldorp</keyname><forenames>Lourens J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kossakowski</keyname><forenames>Jolanda J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mean field dynamics of graphs I: Evolution of probabilistic cellular
  automata for random and small-world graphs</title><categories>stat.AP nlin.CG physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  It was recently shown how graphs can be used to provide descriptions of
psychopathologies, where symptoms of, say, depression, affect each other and
certain configurations determine whether someone could fall into a sudden
depression. To analyse changes over time and characterise possible future
behaviour is rather difficult for large graphs. We describe the dynamics of
networks using one-dimensional discrete time dynamical systems theory obtained
from a mean field approach to (elementary) probabilistic cellular automata
(PCA). Often the mean field approach is used on a regular graph (a grid or
torus) where each node has the same number of edges and the same probability of
becoming active. We show that we can use variations of the mean field of the
grid to describe the dynamics of the PCA on a random and small-world graph.
Bifurcation diagrams for the mean field of the grid, random, and small-world
graphs indicate possible phase transitions for certain parameter settings.
Extensive simulations indicate for different graph sizes (number of nodes) that
the mean field approximation is accurate. The mean field approach allows us to
provide possible explanations of 'jumping' behaviour in depression.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00327</id><created>2016-11-01</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Antonov</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gulitskiy</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostenko</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu&#x10d;ivjansk&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulent compressible fluid: renormalization group analysis, scaling
  regimes, and anomalous scaling of advected scalar fields</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>28 pages, 6 figures. Version revisited by the journal and accepted
  for publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 033120 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.033120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a model of fully developed turbulence of a compressible fluid, based
on the stochastic Navier-Stokes equation, by means of the field theoretic
renormalization group. In this approach, scaling properties are related to the
fixed points of the renormalization group equations. Previous analysis of this
model near the real-world space dimension 3 identified some scaling regime
[Theor. Math. Phys., 110, 3 (1997)]. The aim of the present paper is to explore
the existence of additional regimes, that could not be found using the direct
perturbative approach of the previous work, and to analyze the crossover
between different regimes. It seems possible to determine them near the special
value of space dimension $4$ in the framework of double $y$ and $\varepsilon$
expansion, where $y$ is the exponent associated with the random force and
$\varepsilon=4-d$ is the deviation from the space dimension $4$. Our
calculations show that there exists an additional fixed point that governs
scaling behavior. Turbulent advection of a passive scalar (density) field by
this velocity ensemble is considered as well. We demonstrate that various
correlation functions of the scalar field exhibit anomalous scaling behavior in
the inertial-convective range. The corresponding anomalous exponents,
identified as scaling dimensions of certain composite fields, can be
systematically calculated as a series in $y$ and $\varepsilon$. All
calculations are performed in the leading one-loop approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03670</id><created>2016-11-11</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xurong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Global study of nuclear modifications on parton distribution functions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, minor modifications</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B 920 (2017) 1</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.04.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A global analysis of nuclear medium modifications of parton distributions is
presented using deeply inelastic scattering data of various nuclear targets.
Two obtained data sets are provided for quark and gluon nuclear modification
factors, referred as nIMParton16. One is from the global fit only to the
experimental data of isospin-scalar nuclei (Set A), and the other is from the
fit to all the measured nuclear data (Set B). The scale-dependence is described
by DGLAP equations with nonlinear corrections in this work. The Fermi motion
and off-shell effect, nucleon swelling, and parton-parton recombination are
taken into account together for modeling the complicated $x$-dependence of
nuclear modification. The nuclear gluon shadowing in this paper is dynamically
generated by the QCD evolution of parton splitting and recombination processes
with zero gluon density at the input scale. Sophisticated nuclear dependence of
nuclear medium effects is studied with only two free parameters. With the
obtained free parameters from the global analysis, the nuclear modifications of
parton distribution functions of unmeasured nuclei can be predicted in our
model. Nuclear modification of deuteron is also predicted and shown with recent
measurement at JLab.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06054</id><created>2016-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lauer</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braecher</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pirro</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Bjoern</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heussner</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laegel</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onbasli</keyname><forenames>Mehmet C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ross</keyname><forenames>Caroline A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillebrands</keyname><forenames>Burkard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chumak</keyname><forenames>Andrii V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal evolution of auto-oscillations in a YIG/Pt microdisc driven by
  pulsed spin Hall effect-induced spin-transfer torque</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Magn. Lett. 8, 3104304 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/LMAG.2017.2661243</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The temporal evolution of pulsed Spin Hall Effect - Spin Transfer Torque
(SHE-STT) driven auto-oscillations in a Yttrium Iron Garnet (YIG) / platinum
(Pt) microdisc is studied experimentally using time-resolved Brillouin Light
Scattering (BLS) spectroscopy. It is demonstrated that the frequency of the
auto-oscillations is different in the center and at the edge of the
investigated disc that is related to the simultaneous STT excitation of a
bullet and a non-localized spin-wave mode. Furthermore, the magnetization
precession intensity is found to saturate on a time scale of 20 ns or longer,
depending on the current density. For this reason, our findings suggest that a
proper ratio between the current and the pulse duration is of crucial
importance for future STT-based devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08332</id><created>2016-11-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Zhangru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Jingsi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Wanglin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Guojun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xianhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jixue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Chuanhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Deriving phosphorus atomic chain from few-layer black phosphorus</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1007/s12274-017-1456-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phosphorus atomic chains, the utmost-narrow nanostructures of black
phosphorus (BP), are highly relevant to the in-depth development of BP into
one-dimensional (1D) regime. In this contribution, we report a top-down route
to prepare atomic chains of BP via electron beam sculpting inside a
transmission electron microscope (TEM). The growth and dynamics (i.e. rupture
and edge migration) of 1D phosphorus chains are experimentally captured for the
first time. Furthermore, the dynamic behaviors and associated energetics of the
as-formed phosphorus chains are further corroborated by density functional
theory (DFT) calculations. The 1D counterpart of BP will serve as a novel
platform and inspire further exploration of the versatile properties of BP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09861</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iocco</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benito</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>An estimate of the DM profile in the Galactic bulge region</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><journal-ref>PDU 15, 90 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.dark.2016.12.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analysis of the mass distribution in the region of the Galactic
bulge, which leads to constraints on the total amount and distribution of Dark
Matter (DM) therein. Our results -based on the dynamical measurement of the
BRAVA collaboration- are quantitatively compatible with those of a recent
analysis, and generalised to a vaste sample of observationally inferred
morphologies of the stellar components in the region of the Galactic bulge. By
fitting the inferred DM mass to a generalised NFW profile, we find that cores
(index gamma smaller than 0.6) are forbidden only for very light configurations
of the bulge, and that cusps (index gamma bigger than 1.2) are allowed, but not
necessarily preferred. Interestingly, we find that the results for the bulge
region are compatible with those obtained with dynamical methods (based on the
rotation curve) applied to outer regions of the Milky Way, for all morphologies
adopted. We find that the uncertainty on the shape of the stellar morphology
heavily affects the determination of the DM distribution in the bulge region,
which is gravitationally dominated by baryons, adding up to the uncertainty on
its normalization. The combination of the two hinders the actual possibility to
infer sound conclusions about the distribution of DM in the region of the
Galactic bulge, and only future observations of the stellar census and dynamics
in this region will bring us closer to a quantitatively more definite answer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02597</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-03-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vorwerk</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cocchi</keyname><forenames>Caterina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draxl</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author></authors><title>Addressing electron-hole correlation in core excitations of solids: An
  all-electron many-body approach from first principles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>https://journals.aps.org/prb/accepted/51079O49M371532007297d377db6917b215a22721</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 155121 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an ab initio study of core excitations of solid-state materials
focussing on the role of electron-hole correlation. In the framework of an
all-electron implementation of many-body perturbation theory into the exciting
code, we investigate three different absorption edges of three materials,
spanning a broad energy window, with transition energies between a few hundred
to thousands of eV. Specifically, we consider excitations from the Ti $K$ edge
in rutile and anatase $\textrm{TiO}_2$, from the Pb $M_4$ edge in
$\textrm{PbI}_2$, and from the Ca $L_{2,3}$ edge in $\textrm{CaO}$. We show
that the electron-hole attraction rules x-ray absorption for deep core states,
when local fields play a minor role. On the other hand, the local-field effects
introduced by the exchange interaction between the excited electron and the
hole dominate excitation processes from shallower core levels, separated by a
spin-orbit splitting of a few eV. Our approach yields absorption spectra in
good agreement with available experimental data, and allows for an in-depth
analysis of the results, revealing the electronic contributions to the
excitations, as well as their spatial distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03509</id><created>2016-12-11</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Li-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Lin-Wan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Chun-Gui</forenames></author></authors><title>The energy loss effect of incoming quark in the Drell-Yan reaction off
  nuclei</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to need to add some
  new work</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of the analytic parameterizations of quenching weights based on
BDMPS formalism, the leading-order computations for nuclear Drell-Yan
differential cross section rations as a function of the quark momentum fraction
are performed with the nuclear geometry effect in Drell-Yan dimuon production.
The transport coefficient of the incoming quark energy loss in cold nuclear
matter is extracted with a global analysis of the experimental data from NA3
and E866 collaborations. The extracted transport coefficient with the analytic
parameterizations of BDMPS quenching weights is $\hat{q}=0.37\pm0.05$
GeV$^{2}$/fm. It is found that our predictions are in good agrement with the
experimental measurements, and especially the agreement of calculations with
NA3 experimental data has a significant improvement. The comparison of the
theoretical results and the corresponding experimental data demonstrates
intuitively that the energy loss effect of incoming quark is particularly
significant at lower incident proton energies. It is hoped that the obtained
results relevant to the NA3 experiment ($E_{beam}=150$ GeV) can provide useful
reference for the forthcoming E906 Sea Quest experiment ($E_{beam}=120$ GeV).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04055</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khamehchi</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Khalid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mossman</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yongping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busch</keyname><forenames>Th.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forbes</keyname><forenames>Michael McNeil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engels</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative mass hydrodynamics in a Spin-Orbit--Coupled Bose-Einstein
  Condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures: Minor updated bringing this in line with
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 155301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.155301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A negative effective mass can be realized in quantum systems by engineering
the dispersion relation. A powerful method is provided by spin-orbit coupling,
which is currently at the center of intense research efforts. Here we measure
an expanding spin-orbit coupled Bose-Einstein condensate whose dispersion
features a region of negative effective mass. We observe a range of dynamical
phenomena, including the breaking of parity and of Galilean covariance,
dynamical instabilities, and self-trapping. The experimental findings are
reproduced by a single-band Gross-Pitaevskii simulation, demonstrating that the
emerging features - shockwaves, soliton trains, self-trapping, etc. - originate
from a modified dispersion. Our work also sheds new light on related phenomena
in optical lattices, where the underlying periodic structure often complicates
their interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04475</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Bingchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Vy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Yujun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Qiushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaomu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cha</keyname><forenames>Judy J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Qiangfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Fengnian</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient Electrical Control of Thin-Film Black Phosphorus Bandgap</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 14474 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms14474</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently rediscovered black phosphorus is a layered semiconductor with
promising electronic and photonic properties. Dynamic control of its bandgap
can enable novel device applications and allow for the exploration of new
physical phenomena. However, theoretical investigations and photoemission
spectroscopy experiments performed on doped black phosphorus through potassium
adsorption indicate that in its few-layer form, an exceedingly large electric
field in the order of several volts per nanometer is required to effectively
tune its bandgap, making the direct electrical control unfeasible. Here we
demonstrate the tuning of bandgap in intrinsic black phosphorus using an
electric field directly and reveal the unique thickness-dependent bandgap
tuning properties, arising from the strong interlayer electronic-state
coupling. Furthermore, leveraging a 10-nm-thick black phosphorus in which the
field-induced potential difference across the film dominates over the
interlayer coupling, we continuously tune its bandgap from ~300 to below 50
milli-electron volts, using a moderate displacement field up to 1.1 volts per
nanometer. Such dynamic tuning of bandgap may not only extend the operational
wavelength range of tunable black phosphorus photonic devices, but also pave
the way for the investigation of electrically tunable topological insulators
and topological nodal semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05106</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-01-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nashed</keyname><forenames>G. G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanafy</keyname><forenames>W. El</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic rotating black hole solutions in $N$-dimensional $f(T)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages LaTex,Submitted to EPJC</comments><journal-ref>EPJC 77 (2017), 90</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4663-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A non-diagonal vielbein ansatz is applied to the $N$-dimension field
equations of $f(T)$ gravity. An analytical vacuum solution is derived for the
quadratic polynomial $f(T)=T+\epsilon T^2$ in the presence of a cosmological
constant $\Lambda$. Since the induced metric has off diagonal components, that
cannot be removed by a mere of a coordinate transformation, the solution has a
rotating parameter. The curvature and torsion scalars invariants are calculated
to study the singularities and horizons of the solution. In contrast to the
general relativity (GR), the Cauchy horizon is differ from the horizon which
shows the effect of the higher order torsion. The general expression of the
energy-momentum vector of $f(T)$ gravity is used to calculate the energy of the
system. Finally, we have shown that this kind of solution satisfies the first
law of thermodynamics in the framework of $f(T)$ gravitational theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05337</id><created>2016-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Dancheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Haibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Danhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asokan</keyname><forenames>Vijay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Omar</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Chuanhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Capture the growth kinetics of CVD growth of two-dimensional MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/s41699-017-0010-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the microscopic mechanism of chemical vapor deposition (CVD)
growth of two-dimensional molybdenum disulfide (2D MoS2) is a fundamental issue
towards the function-oriented controlled growth. In this work, we report
results on revealing the growth kinetics of 2D MoS2 via capturing the
nucleation seed, evolution morphology, edge structure and terminations at the
atomic scale during CVD growth using the transmission electron microscopy (TEM)
and scanning transmission electron microscopy (STEM) studies. The direct growth
of few- and mono-layer MoS2 onto graphene based TEM grids allow us to perform
the subsequent TEM characterization without any solution-based transfer. Two
forms of seeding centers are observed during characterizations: (i)
Mo-oxysulfide (MoOxS2-y) nanoparticles either in multi-shelled fullerene-like
structures or in compact nanocrystals for the growth of fewer-layer MoS2; (ii)
Mo-S atomic clusters in case of monolayer MoS2. In particular, for the
monolayer case, at the early stage growth, the morphology appears in irregular
polygon shape comprised with two primary edge terminations: S-Mo Klein edge and
Mo zigzag edge, approximately in equal numbers, while as the growth proceeds,
the morphology further evolves into near-triangle shape in which Mo zigzag edge
predominates. Results from density-functional theory calculations are also
consistent with the inferred growth kinetics, and thus supportive to the growth
mechanism we proposed. In general, the growth mechanisms found here should also
be applicable in other 2D materials, such as MoSe2, WS2 and WSe2 etc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05590</id><created>2016-12-16</created><updated>2017-04-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Junqueira</keyname><forenames>O. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadovski</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>T. R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreiro</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaz</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence between the Lovelock-Cartan action and a constrained gauge
  theory</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages. No figures. Final version accepted for publication at the
  EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.4, 249</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4820-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the four-dimensional Lovelock-Cartan action can be derived from
a massless gauge theory for the $SO(1,3)$ group with an additional BRST trivial
part. The model is originally composed by a topological sector and a BRST exact
piece and has no explicit dependence on the metric, the vierbein or a mass
parameter. The vierbein is introduced together with a mass parameter through
some BRST trivial constraints. The effect of the constraints is to identify the
vierbein with some of the additional fields, transforming the original action
into the Lovelock-Cartan one. In this scenario, the mass parameter is
identified with Newton's constant while the gauge field is identified with the
spin-connection. The symmetries of the model are also explored. Moreover, the
extension of the model to a quantum version is qualitatively discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06462</id><created>2016-12-19</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Escudero</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hooper</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witte</keyname><forenames>Samuel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Updated Collider and Direct Detection Constraints on Dark Matter Models
  for the Galactic Center Gamma-Ray Excess</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>v3: Footnote and reference added. v2: Published version, text and
  citations added. 19 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/02/038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Utilizing an exhaustive set of simplified models, we revisit dark matter
scenarios potentially capable of generating the observed Galactic Center
gamma-ray excess, updating constraints from the LUX and PandaX-II experiments,
as well as from the LHC and other colliders. We identify a variety of
pseudoscalar mediated models that remain consistent with all constraints. In
contrast, dark matter candidates which annihilate through a spin-1 mediator are
ruled out by direct detection constraints unless the mass of the mediator is
near an annihilation resonance, or the mediator has a purely vector coupling to
the dark matter and a purely axial coupling to Standard Model fermions. All
scenarios in which the dark matter annihilates through $t$-channel processes
are now ruled out by a combination of the constraints from LUX/PandaX-II and
the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06925</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sehmi</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langbein</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muljarov</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing the Drude-Lorentz model for material permittivity - method,
  program, and examples for gold, silver, and copper</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 115444 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.115444</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Approximating the frequency dispersion of the permittivity of materials with
simple analytical functions is of fundamental importance for understanding and
modeling the optical response of materials and resulting structures. In the
generalized Drude-Lorentz model, the permittivity is described in the complex
frequency plane by a number of simple poles having complex weights, which is a
physically relevant and mathematically simple approach: By construction, it
respects causality represents physical resonances of the material, and can be
implemented easily in numerical simulations. We report here an efficient method
of optimizing the fit of measured data with the Drude-Lorentz model having an
arbitrary number of poles. We show examples of such optimizations for gold,
silver, and copper, for different frequency ranges and up to four pairs of
Lorentz poles taken into account. We also provide a program implementing the
method for general use.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07004</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurements of top quark spin observables in $t\bar{t}$ events using
  dilepton final states in $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV $pp$ collisions with the ATLAS
  detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>50 pages in total, author list starting page 34, 8 figures, 7 tables,
  submitted to JHEP, All figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/TOPQ-2015-13</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-263</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 03 (2017) 113</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of top quark spin observables in $t\bar{t}$ events are presented
based on 20.2 fb$^{-1}$ of $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV proton-proton collisions recorded
with the ATLAS detector at the LHC. The analysis is performed in the dilepton
final state, characterised by the presence of two isolated leptons (electrons
or muons). There are 15 observables, each sensitive to a different coefficient
of the spin density matrix of $t\bar{t}$ production, which are measured
independently. Ten of these observables are measured for the first time. All of
them are corrected for detector resolution and acceptance effects back to the
parton and stable-particle levels. The measured values of the observables at
parton level are compared to Standard Model predictions at next-to-leading
order in QCD. The corrected distributions at stable-particle level are
presented and the means of the distributions are compared to Monte Carlo
predictions. No significant deviation from the Standard Model is observed for
any observable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04433</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>Maritza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aramon</keyname><forenames>Maliheh</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing Quantum Annealing Performance for the Molecular Similarity
  Problem</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DM q-bio.QM</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Information Processing, volume 16, number 5, May 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-017-1586-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum annealing is a promising technique which leverages quantum mechanics
to solve hard optimization problems. Considerable progress has been made in the
development of a physical quantum annealer, motivating the study of methods to
enhance the efficiency of such a solver. In this work, we present a quantum
annealing approach to measure similarity among molecular structures.
Implementing real-world problems on a quantum annealer is challenging due to
hardware limitations such as sparse connectivity, intrinsic control error, and
limited precision. In order to overcome the limited connectivity, a problem
must be reformulated using minor-embedding techniques. Using a real data set,
we investigate the performance of a quantum annealer in solving the molecular
similarity problem. We provide experimental evidence that common practices for
embedding can be replaced by new alternatives which mitigate some of the
hardware limitations and enhance its performance. Common practices for
embedding include minimizing either the number of qubits or the chain length,
and determining the strength of ferromagnetic couplers empirically. We show
that current criteria for selecting an embedding do not improve the hardware's
performance for the molecular similarity problem. Furthermore, we use a
theoretical approach to determine the strength of ferromagnetic couplers. Such
an approach removes the computational burden of the current empirical
approaches, and also results in hardware solutions that can benefit from simple
local classical improvement. Although our results are limited to the problems
considered here, they can be generalized to guide future benchmarking studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06498</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>McCormick</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Enk</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental demonstration of loop state-preparation-and-measurement
  tomography</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042329 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042329</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed an experiment demonstrating that loop
state-preparation-and-measurement (SPAM) tomography [C. Jackson and S. J. van
Enk, Phys. Rev. A 92, 042312 (2015)] is capable of detecting correlated errors
between the preparation and the measurement of a quantum system. Specifically,
we have prepared pure and mixed states of single qubits encoded in the
polarization of heralded individual photons. By performing measurements using
multiple state preparations and multiple measurement device settings we are
able to detect if there are any correlated errors between them, and are also
able to determine which state preparations are correlated with which
measurements. This is accomplished by going around a 'loop' in parameter space,
which allows us to check for self-consistency. No assumptions are made
concerning either the state preparations or the measurements, other than that
the dimensions of the states and the positive-operator-valued measures (POVM)
describing the detector are known. In cases where no correlations are found we
are able to perform quantum state tomography of the polarization qubits by
using knowledge of the detector POVMs, or quantum detector tomography by using
knowledge of the state preparations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06591</id><created>2017-01-23</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandbyge</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannestad</keyname><forenames>Steen</forenames></author></authors><title>Fourier imaging of non-linear structure formation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP04(2017)032</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/04/032</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a Fourier space decomposition of the dynamics of non-linear
cosmological structure formation in LCDM models. From N-body simulations
involving only cold dark matter we calculate 3-dimensional non-linear density,
velocity divergence and vorticity Fourier realizations, and use these to
calculate the fully non-linear mode coupling integrals in the corresponding
fluid equations. Our approach allows for a reconstruction of the amount of mode
coupling between any two wavenumbers as a function of redshift. With our
Fourier decomposition method we identify the transfer of power from larger to
smaller scales, the stable clustering regime, the scale where vorticity becomes
important, and the suppression of the non-linear divergence power spectrum as
compared to linear theory. Our results can be used to improve and calibrate
semi-analytical structure formation models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00228</id><created>2017-02-01</created><updated>2017-04-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dao</keyname><forenames>Vu Hung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fr&#xe9;sard</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective modes in the paramagnetic phase of the Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>17 pages, 15 figures with expanded discussion</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95. 165127 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.165127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The charge dynamical response function of the Hubbard model is investigated
on the square lattice in the thermodynamical limit. The obtained charge
excitation spectra consist of a continuum, a gapless collective mode with
anisotropic zero-sound velocity, and a correlation induced high-frequency mode
at $\omega\approx U$. The correlation function is calculated from Gaussian
fluctuations around the paramagnetic saddle-point within the Kotliar and
Ruckenstein slave-boson representation. Its dependence on the on-site Coulomb
repulsion $U$ and density is studied in detail. An approximate analytical
expression of the high frequency mode, that holds for any lattice with one atom
in the unit cell, is derived. Comparison with numerical simulations,
perturbation theory and the polarization potential theory is carried out. We
also show that magnetic instabilities tend to vanish for $T\gtrsim t/6$, and
finite temperature phase diagrams are established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00450</id><created>2017-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Stein</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiher</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Automated Identification of Relevant Frontier Orbitals for Chemical
  Compounds and Processes</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.str-el physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Chimia 71 (2017) 170-176</journal-ref><doi>10.2533/chimia.2017.170</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum-chemical multi-configurational methods are required for a proper
description of static electron correlation, a phenomenon inherent to the
electronic structure of molecules with multiple (near-)degenerate frontier
orbitals. Here, we review how a property of these frontier orbitals, namely the
entanglement entropy is related to static electron correlation. A subset of
orbitals, the so-called active orbital space, is an essential ingredient for
all multi-configurational methods. We proposed an automated selection of this
active orbital space, that would otherwise be a tedious and error prone manual
procedure, based on entanglement measures. Here, we extend this scheme to
demonstrate its capability for the selection of consistent active spaces for
several excited states and along reaction coordinates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00867</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00867</id><created>2017-02-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Simm</keyname><forenames>Gregor N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Proppe</keyname><forenames>Jonny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiher</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Error Assessment of Computational Models in Chemistry</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>21 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Chimia 71 (2017) 202-208</journal-ref><doi>10.2533/chimia.2017.202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Computational models in chemistry rely on a number of approximations. The
effect of such approximations on observables derived from them is often
unpredictable. Therefore, it is challenging to quantify the uncertainty of a
computational result, which, however, is necessary to assess the suitability of
a computational model. Common performance statistics such as the mean absolute
error are prone to failure as they do not distinguish the explainable
(systematic) part of the errors from their unexplainable (random) part. In this
paper, we discuss problems and solutions for performance assessment of
computational models based on several examples from the quantum chemistry
literature. For this purpose, we elucidate the different sources of
uncertainty, the elimination of systematic errors, and the combination of
individual uncertainty components to the uncertainty of a prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02924</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Chia-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tandean</keyname><forenames>Jusak</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Higgs-Doublet-Portal Dark-Matter Models in Light of Direct Search
  and LHC Data</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures, somewhat expanded, references added, main
  conclusions unchanged, matches publication</comments><report-no>NCTS-PH/1707</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 04 (2017) 107</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2017)107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore simple Higgs-portal models of dark matter (DM) with spin 1/2, 3/2,
and 1, respectively, applying to them constraints from the LUX and PandaX-II
direct detection experiments and from LHC measurements on the 125-GeV Higgs
boson. With only one Higgs doublet, we find that the spin-1/2 DM having a
purely scalar effective coupling to the doublet is viable only in a narrow
range of mass near the Higgs pole, whereas the vector DM is still allowed if
its mass is also close to the Higgs pole or exceeds 1.4 TeV, both in line with
earlier analyses. Moreover, the spin-3/2 DM is in a roughly similar situation
to the spin-1/2 DM, but has surviving parameter space which is even more
restricted. We also consider the two-Higgs-doublet extension of each of the
preceding models, assuming that the expanded Yukawa sector is that of the
two-Higgs-doublet model of type II. We show that in these
two-Higgs-doublet-portal models significant portions of the DM mass regions
excluded in the simplest scenarios by direct search bounds can be reclaimed due
to suppression of the effective DM interactions with nucleons at some ratios of
the $CP$-even Higgs bosons' couplings to the up and down quarks. The regained
parameter space contains areas which can yield a DM-nucleon scattering
cross-section that is far less than its current experimental limit or even goes
below the neutrino-background floor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02952</id><created>2017-02-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Prem</keyname><forenames>Abhinav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haah</keyname><forenames>Jeongwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandkishore</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author></authors><title>Glassy quantum dynamics in translation invariant fracton models</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 155133 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155133</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate relaxation in the recently discovered &quot;fracton&quot; models and
discover that these models naturally host glassy quantum dynamics in the
absence of quenched disorder. We begin with a discussion of &quot;type I&quot; fracton
models, in the taxonomy of Vijay, Haah, and Fu. We demonstrate that in these
systems, the mobility of charges is suppressed exponentially in the inverse
temperature. We further demonstrate that when a zero temperature type I fracton
model is placed in contact with a finite temperature heat bath, the approach to
equilibrium is a logarithmic function of time over an exponentially wide window
of time scales. Generalizing to the more complex &quot;type II&quot; fracton models, we
find that the charges exhibit subdiffusion upto a relaxation time that diverges
at low temperatures as a super-exponential function of inverse temperature.
This behaviour is reminiscent of &quot;nearly localized&quot; disordered systems, but
occurs with a translation invariant three-dimensional Hamiltonian. We also
conjecture that fracton models with conserved charge may support a phase which
is a thermal metal but a charge insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03506</id><created>2017-02-12</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iwahori</keyname><forenames>Koudai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawakami</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Stabilization of prethermal Floquet steady states in a periodically
  driven dissipative Bose-Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 043621 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.043621</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the effect of dissipation on heating which occurs in periodically
driven quantum many body systems. We especially focus on a periodically driven
Bose-Hubbard model coupled to an energy and particle reservoir. Without
dissipation, this model is known to undergo parametric instabilities which can
be considered as an initial stage of heating. By taking the weak on-site
interaction limit as well as the weak system-reservoir coupling limit, we find
that parametric instabilities are suppressed if the dissipation is stronger
than the on-site interaction strength and stable steady states appear. Our
results demonstrate that periodically-driven systems can emit energy, which is
absorbed from external drivings, to the reservoir so that they can avoid
heating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03834</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-02-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitsuka</keyname><forenames>Gaku</forenames></author></authors><title>Large single transverse spin asymmetry for forward neutrons in
  ultraperipheral polarized proton-nucleus collisions in explanation of
  measurements at RHIC-PHENIX</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 044908 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.044908</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The PHENIX experiment at BNL-RHIC recently reported the single transverse
spin asymmetry $A_N$ for forward neutrons measured in polarized proton-nucleus
collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}} = 200\,$GeV; $A_N$ in proton-aluminum and
proton-gold collisions are -0.015 and 0.18, respectively, which are clearly
different from $A_N=-0.08$ in proton-proton collisions. In this paper, we
propose large $A_N$ for forward neutrons in ultraperipheral polarized
proton-nucleus collisions as an explanation of the PHENIX measurements. The
proposed model is demonstrated using two Monte Carlo simulations organized as
follows. In the ultraperipheral collision simulation, we use the STARlight
event generator for the simulation of the virtual photon flux and then use the
MAID2007 unitary isobar model for the simulation of the neutron production in
the interactions of a virtual photon with a polarized proton. In the
proton-nucleus hadronic interaction simulation, the differential cross sections
of forward neutron production are predicted by a simple one-pion exchange model
and the Glauber model. The simulated $A_N$ values accumulating the both
contribution of ultraperipheral collisions and hadronic interactions are in
good agreement with the PHENIX results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05273</id><created>2017-02-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayaffre</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidiger</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheludev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horvati&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel Crossover in Coupled Spin Ladders</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 167206 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.167206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a novel crossover behavior in the long-range-ordered phase of a
prototypical spin-$1/2$ Heisenberg antiferromagnetic ladder compound
$\mathrm{(C_7H_{10}N)_2CuBr_4}$. The staggered order was previously evidenced
from a continuous and symmetric splitting of $^{14}$N NMR spectral lines on
lowering temperature below $T_c\simeq 330$ mK, with a saturation towards
$\simeq 150$ mK. Unexpectedly, the split lines begin to further separate away
below $T^*\sim 100$ mK while the line width and shape remain completely
invariable. This crossover behavior is further corroborated by the NMR
relaxation rate $T_1^{-1}$ measurements. A very strong suppression reflecting
the ordering, $T_1^{-1}\sim T^{5.5}$, observed above $T^*$, is replaced by
$T_1^{-1}\sim T$ below $T^*$. These original NMR features are indicative of
unconventional nature of the crossover, which may arise from a unique
arrangement of the ladders into a spatially anisotropic and frustrated coupling
network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05477</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cremers</keyname><forenames>Theo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chefdeville</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Niek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sweers</keyname><forenames>Edwin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koot</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claus</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>van de Meerakker</keyname><forenames>Sebastiaan Y. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new concept multi-stage Zeeman decelerator</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>Previously uploaded as two separate articles with arXiv:1702.04223,
  now merged into one</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.043415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new concept for a multi-stage Zeeman decelerator that is
optimized particularly for applications in molecular beam scattering
experiments. The decelerator consists of a series of alternating hexapoles and
solenoids, that effectively decouple the transverse focusing and longitudinal
deceleration properties of the decelerator. It can be operated in a
deceleration and acceleration mode, as well as in a hybrid mode that makes it
possible to guide a particle beam through the decelerator at constant speed.
The deceleration features phase stability, with a relatively large
six-dimensional phase-space acceptance. The separated focusing and deceleration
elements result in an unequal partitioning of this acceptance between the
longitudinal and transverse directions. This is ideal in scattering
experiments, which typically benefit from a large longitudinal acceptance
combined with narrow transverse distributions. We demonstrate the successful
experimental implementation of this concept using a Zeeman decelerator
consisting of an array of 25 hexapoles and 24 solenoids. The performance of the
decelerator in acceleration, deceleration and guiding modes is characterized
using beams of metastable Helium ($^3S$) atoms. Up to 60 % of the kinetic
energy was removed for He atoms that have an initial velocity of 520 m/s. The
hexapoles consist of permanent magnets, whereas the solenoids are produced from
a single hollow copper capillary through which cooling liquid is passed. The
solenoid design allows for excellent thermal properties, and enables the use of
readily available and cheap electronics components to pulse high currents
through the solenoids. The Zeeman decelerator demonstrated here is mechanically
easy to build, can be operated with cost-effective electronics, and can run at
repetition rates up to 10 Hz
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05822</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05822</id><created>2017-02-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Lillie</keyname><forenames>Scott E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broadway</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>James D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simpson</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stacey</keyname><forenames>Alastair</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tetienne</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollenberg</keyname><forenames>Lloyd C. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Environmentally mediated coherent control of a spin qubit in diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages including SI</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 167204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.167204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The coherent control of spin qubits forms the basis of many applications in
quantum information processing and nanoscale sensing, imaging and spectroscopy.
Such control is conventionally achieved by direct driving of the qubit
transition with a resonant global field, typically at microwave frequencies.
Here we introduce an approach that relies on the resonant driving of nearby
environment spins, whose localised magnetic field in turn drives the qubit when
the environmental spin Rabi frequency matches the qubit resonance. This concept
of environmentally mediated resonance (EMR) is explored experimentally using a
qubit based on a single nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centre in diamond, with nearby
electronic spins serving as the environmental mediators. We demonstrate EMR
driven coherent control of the NV spin-state, including the observation of Rabi
oscillations, free induction decay, and spin-echo. This technique also provides
a way to probe the nanoscale environment of spin qubits, which we illustrate by
acquisition of electron spin resonance spectra of single NV centres in various
settings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08472</id><created>2017-02-27</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimon</keyname><forenames>Meir</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology in Conformal Dilatonic Gravity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages, submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitation is described in the context of a dilatonic theory that is
conformally related to general relativity. All dimensionless ratios of
fundamental dimensional quantities, e.g. particle masses and the Planck mass,
as well as the relative strengths of the fundamental interactions, are fixed
constants. An interplay between the positive energy density associated with
relativistic matter (and possibly with negative spatial curvature) and the
negative energy associated with dynamical dilaton phase results in a
non-singular, flat cosmological model with no horizon, and -- as a direct
consequence of absence of phase transitions in the early universe -- with no
production of topological defects. The (logarithmic) time-derivative of the
field modulus is degenerate with the Hubble function, and all cosmological
epochs of the standard model are unchanged except at the very early universe.
We demonstrate that both linear order perturbation theory and the spherical
collapse model are equivalent to those in the standard model, up to
modifications caused by the phase of the (complex) scalar field and its
perturbations. Consequently, our alternative theory automatically passes the
main classical cosmological tests. Quantum excitations of the phase of the
scalar field generate a slightly red-tilted spectrum of adiabatic and gaussian
scalar perturbations on the largest scales. However, this framework does not
provide a similar mechanism for producing primordial gravitational waves on
these scales. A spherically symmetric vacuum solution that approximately
describes the exterior of gravitationally bound systems (e.g., stars and
galaxies) by a modified Schwarzschild-de Sitter metric, augmented with an
additional linear potential term, could possibly explain galactic rotation
curves and strong gravitational lensing with no recourse to dark matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00033</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miyahara</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grutter</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Force-gradient sensitive Kelvin probe force microscopy by dissipative
  electrostatic force modulation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, supplemental materials. arXiv admin note: text
  overlap with arXiv:1508.05866</comments><journal-ref>Appl.Phys.Lett. 110, 163103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981937</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) implementation using the
dissipation signal of a frequency modulation atomic force microscopy that is
capable of detecting the gradient of electrostatic force rather than
electrostatic force. It features a simple implementation and faster scanning as
it requires no low frequency modulation. We show that applying a coherent ac
voltage with two times the cantilever oscillation frequency induces the
dissipation signal proportional to the electrostatic force gradient which
depends on the effective dc bias voltage including the contact potential
difference. We demonstrate the KPFM images of a MoS$_2$ flake taken with the
present method is in quantitative agreement with that taken with the frequency
modulated Kelvin probe force microscopy technique.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00193</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiefer</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>Jamir</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal and nonthermal scaling of the Casimir-Polder interaction in a
  black hole spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc cond-mat.other quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 085014 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.085014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Casimir-Polder force arising between two identical two-level
atoms and mediated by a massless scalar field propagating in a black-hole
background. We study the interplay of Hawking radiation and Casimir-Polder
forces and find that, when the atoms are placed near the event horizon, the
scaling of the Casimir-Polder interaction energy as a function of interatomic
distance displays a transition from a thermallike character to a nonthermal
behavior. We corroborate our findings for a quantum field prepared in the
Boulware, Hartle-Hawking, and Unruh vacua. Our analysis is consistent with the
nonthermal character of the Casimir-Polder interaction of two-level atoms in a
relativistic accelerated frame [J. Marino et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 020403
(2014)], where a crossover from thermal scaling, consistent with the Unruh
effect, to a nonthermal scaling has been observed. The two crossovers are a
consequence of the noninertial character of the background where the field
mediating the Casimir interaction propagates. While in the former case the
characteristic crossover length scale is proportional to the inverse of the
surface gravity of the black hole, in the latter it is determined by the
inverse of the proper acceleration of the atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00480</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>Seyed Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momennia</keyname><forenames>Mehrab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>Behzad Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonsingular Universes in Gauss-Bonnet Gravity's Rainbow</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures. minor corrections included</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys. J. 827,153 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/827/2/153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we will study the rainbow deformation of the FRW cosmology in
both Einstein gravity and Gauss-Bonnet gravity. We will demonstrate that the
singularity in the FRW cosmology can be removed because of the rainbow
deformation of the FRW metric. We will obtain the general constraints required
for the FRW cosmology to be free from singularities. It will be observed that
the inclusion of Gauss-Bonnet gravity can significantly change the constraints
required to obtain a nonsingular universes. We will use a rainbow functions
motivated from the hard spectra of gamma-ray bursts to deform the FRW
cosmology, and it will be explicitly demonstrated that such a deformation
removes the singularity in the FRW cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00876</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xizhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jianfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Weixiong</forenames></author></authors><title>An efficient algorithm for finding all possible input nodes for
  controlling complex networks</title><categories>cs.DM cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding structural controllability of a complex network requires to
identify a Minimum Input nodes Set (MIS) of the network. It has been suggested
that finding an MIS is equivalent to computing a maximum matching of the
network, where the unmatched nodes constitute an MIS. However, maximum matching
of a network is often not unique, and finding all MISs may provide deep
insights to the controllability of the network. Finding all possible input
nodes, which form the union of all MISs, is computationally challenging for
large networks. Here we present an efficient enumerative algorithm for the
problem. The main idea is to modify a maximum matching algorithm to make it
efficient for finding all possible input nodes by computing only one MIS. We
rigorously proved the correctness of the new algorithm and evaluated its
performance on synthetic and large real networks. The experimental results
showed that the new algorithm ran several orders of magnitude faster than the
existing method on large real networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02634</id><created>2017-03-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lepori</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salasnich</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable zero and first sounds in ultracold Fermi gases with Rabi
  coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Accepted in Journal of Statistical Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 043107</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa6580</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a weakly-interacting fermionic gas of alkali-metal atoms
characterized by two hyper- fine states which are Rabi coupled. By using a
Hartree approximation for the repulsive interaction we determine the
zero-temperature equation of state of this Fermi gas in D spatial dimensions (D
= 1, 2, 3). Then, adopting the Landau-Vlasov equation and hydrodynamic
equations, we investi- gate the speed of first sound and zero sound. We show
that the two sounds, which occur respectively in collisional and collisionless
regimes, crucially depend on the interplay between interaction strength and
Rabi coupling. Finally, we discuss for some experimentally relevant cases the
effect of a trapping harmonic potential on the density profiles of the
fermionic system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05389</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-04-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Kang Sin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jihn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyae</keyname><forenames>Bumseok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Soonkeon</forenames></author></authors><title>Hairs of discrete symmetries and gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages,9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B769 (2017) 430-435</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gauge symmetries are known to be respected by gravity because gauge charges
carry flux lines, but global charges do not carry flux lines and are not
conserved by gravitational interaction. For discrete symmetries, they are
spontaneously broken in the Universe, forming domain walls. Since the
realization of discrete symmetries in the Universe must involve the vacuum
expectation values of Higgs fields, a string-like configuration (hair) at the
intersection of domain walls in the Higgs vacua can be realized. Therefore, we
argue that discrete charges are also respected by gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01600</id><created>2017-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Malmi-Kakkada</keyname><forenames>Abdul N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valls</keyname><forenames>Oriol T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Chandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Superfluid Field response to Edge dislocation motion</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>10 pages 7 figures. To appear in Phys. Rev B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134512 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamic response of a superfluid field to a moving edge
dislocation line to which the field is minimally coupled. We use a dissipative
Gross-Pitaevskii equation, and determine the initial conditions by solving the
equilibrium version of the model. We consider the subsequent time evolution of
the field for both glide and climb dislocation motion and analyze the results
for a range of values of the constant speed $V_D$ of the moving dislocation. We
find that the type of motion of the dislocation line is very important in
determining the time evolution of the superfluid field distribution associated
with it. Climb motion of the dislocation line induces increasing asymmetry, as
function of time, in the field profile, with part of the probability being, as
it were, left behind. On the other hand, glide motion has no effect on the
symmetry properties of the superfluid field distribution. Damping of the
superfluid field due to excitations associated with the moving dislocation line
occurs in both cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02849</id><created>2017-04-10</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sarlis</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christopoulos</keyname><forenames>S. -R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skordas</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Minima of the fluctuations of the order parameter of seismicity
  worldwide</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figure, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been shown [Phys. Rev. E 84, 022101 (2011); Chaos 22, 023123 (2012)]
that earthquakes of magnitude $M$ greater or equal to 7 are globally
correlated. Such correlations were identified by studying the variance
$\kappa_1$ of natural time which has been proposed as an order parameter for
seismicity. Here, we study the fluctuations of this order parameter using the
Global Centroid Moment Tensor catalog for a magnitude threshold $M_{thres}=5.0$
and focus on its behavior before major earthquakes. Natural time analysis
reveals that distinct minima of the fluctuations of the order parameter of
seismicity appear {within} almost five and a half months{-on average-} before
all major earthquakes of magnitude larger than 8.4. This phenomenon
corroborates the finding [Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 110, 13734 (2013)] that
similar minima of the seismicity order parameter fluctuations had preceded all
major shallow earthquakes in Japan. Moreover, on the basis of these minima a
statistically significant binary prediction method for earthquakes of magnitude
larger than 8.4 with hit rate 100\% and false alarm rate 6.67\% is suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05419</id><created>2017-04-18</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>Ishtiaq</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aslam</keyname><forenames>M. Jamil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rehman</keyname><forenames>Abdur</forenames></author></authors><title>Mass spectrum of spin-1/2 pentaquarks with a $c\bar{c}$ component and
  their anticipated discovery modes in $b$-baryon decays</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>1 figure, 11 tables</comments><report-no>DESY 17-057</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LHCb discovery of the two baryonic states $P_c^+(4380)$ and
$P_c^+(4450)$, having $J^{P}=3/2^-$ and $J^{P}=5/2^+$, respectively, in the
process $pp \to b \bar{b} \to \Lambda_b X$, followed by the decay $\Lambda_b
\to J/\psi\; p\; K^-$, has motivated a number of theoretical models.
Interpreting them as compact $\{\bar{c}\; [c u] \; [ud]; L_{\mathcal{P}}=0,1\}$
objects, the mass spectroscopy of the $J^P=3/2^-$ and $J^P=5/2^+$ pentaquarks
was worked out by us for the pentaquarks in the $SU(3)_F$ multiplets, using an
effective Hamiltonian based on constituent diquarks and quarks. Their possible
discovery modes in $b$-baryon decays were also given using the heavy quark spin
symmetry. In this paper, we calculate the mass spectrum of the hidden
$c\bar{c}$ pentaquarks having $J^{P}=\frac{1}{2}^\pm$ for the $SU(3)_F$
multiplets and their anticipated discovery modes in $b$-baryon decays. Some of
the $P_c^+(J^P=1/2^\pm$) pentaquarks, produced in the $\Lambda_{b}$ decays may
have their masses just below the $J/\psi\, p$ threshold, in which case they
should be searched for in the modes $ P_c^+(J^P=1/2^\pm) \to \eta_c\; p,\;\;
\mu^+ \mu^- \;p,\;\; e^+ e^-\; p$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05850</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bortolas</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mapelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spera</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supernova Kicks and Dynamics of Compact Remnants in the Galactic Centre</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables; accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><msc-class>85A05</msc-class><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx930</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Galactic Centre (GC) is a unique place to study the extreme dynamical
processes occurring near a super-massive black hole (SMBH). Here we investigate
the role of supernova (SN) explosions occurring in massive binary systems lying
in a disc-like structure within the innermost parsec. We use a regularized
algorithm to simulate 30,000 isolated three-body systems composed of a stellar
binary orbiting the SMBH. We start the integration when the primary member
undergoes a SN explosion, and we analyze the impact of SN kicks on the orbits
of stars and compact remnants. We find that SN explosions scatter the lighter
stars in the pair on completely different orbits, with higher eccentricity and
inclination. In contrast, stellar-mass black holes (BHs) and massive stars
retain memory of the orbit of their progenitor star. Our results suggest that
SN kicks are not sufficient to eject BHs from the GC. We thus predict that all
BHs that form in situ in the central parsec of our Galaxy remain in the GC,
building up a cluster of dark remnants. In addition, the change of NS orbits
induced by SNe may partially account for the observed dearth of NSs in the GC.
About 40 per cent of remnants stay bound to the stellar companion after the
kick; we expect up to 70 per cent of them might become X-ray binaries through
Roche-lobe filling. Finally, the eccentricity of some light stars becomes &gt; 0.7
as an effect of the SN kick, producing orbits similar to those of the G1 and G2
dusty objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05883</id><created>2017-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Duc Duy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Menglun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Guo-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Rigidity strengthening is a vital mechanism for protein-ligand binding</title><categories>q-bio.BM physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Protein-ligand binding is essential to almost all life processes. The
understanding of protein-ligand interactions is fundamentally important to
rational drug design and protein design. Based on large scale data sets, we
show that protein rigidity strengthening or flexibility reduction is a pivoting
mechanism in protein-ligand binding. Our approach based solely on rigidity is
able to unveil a surprisingly long range contribution of four residue layers to
protein-ligand binding, which has a ramification for drug and protein design.
Additionally, the present work reveals that among various pairwise
interactions, the short range ones within the distance of the van der Waals
diameter are most important. It is found that the present approach outperforms
all the other state-of-the-art scoring functions for protein-ligand binding
affinity predictions of two benchmark data sets
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05885</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Jubery</keyname><forenames>Talukder Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganapathysubramanian</keyname><forenames>Baskar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Matthew E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Attinger</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrating optimization with thermodynamics and plant physiology for
  crop ideotype design</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A computational framework integrating optimization algorithms, parallel
computing and plant physiology was developed to explore crop ideotype design.
The backbone of the framework is a plant physiology model that accurately
tracks water use (i.e. a plant hydraulic model) coupled with mass transport
(CO2 exchange and transport), energy conversion (leaf temperature due to
radiation, convection and mass transfer) and photosynthetic biochemistry of an
adult maize plant. For a given trait configuration, soil parameters and hourly
weather data, the model computes water use and photosynthetic output over the
life of an adult maize plant. We coupled this validated model with a parallel,
meta-heuristic optimization algorithm, specifically a genetic algorithm (GA),
to identify trait sets (ideotypes) that resulted in desired water use behavior
of the adult maize plant. We detail features of the model as well as the
implementation details of the coupling with the optimization framework and
deployment on high performance computing platforms. We illustrate a
representative result of this framework by identifying maize ideotypes with
optimized photosynthetic yields using weather and soil conditions corresponding
to Davis, CA. Finally, we show how the framework can be used to identify broad
ideotype trends that can inform breeding efforts. The developed presented tool
has the potential to inform the development of future climate-resilient crops.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05895</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Szenes</keyname><forenames>Andras</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banhelyi</keyname><forenames>Balazs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabo</keyname><forenames>Lorant Zs.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szabo</keyname><forenames>Gabor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csendes</keyname><forenames>Tibor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csete</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved emission of SiV diamond color centers embedded into concave
  plasmonic core-shell nanoresonators</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Configuration of three different concave silver core-shell nanoresonators was
numerically optimized to enhance the excitation and emission of embedded
silicon vacancy (SiV) diamond color centers simultaneously. According to the
tradeoff between the radiative rate enhancement and quantum efficiency (QE)
conditional optimization was performed to ensure ~2-3-4 and 5-fold apparent cQE
enhancement of SiV color centers with ~10% intrinsic QE. The enhancement
spectra, as well as the near-field and charge distribution were inspected to
uncover the physics underlying behind the optical responses. The conditionally
optimized coupled systems were qualified by the product of the radiative rate
enhancements at the excitation and emission, which is nominated as Px factor.
The optimized spherical core-shell nanoresonator containing a centralized
emitter is capable of enhancing considerably the emission via bonding dipolar
resonance. The Px factor is 529-fold with 49.7% cQE at the emission.
Decentralization of the emitter leads to appearance of higher order multipolar
modes, which is not advantageous caused by their nonradiative nature.
Transversal and longitudinal dipolar resonances of the optimized ellipsoidal
core-shell resonator were tuned to the excitation and emission, respectively.
The simultaneous enhancements result in 6.2x10^5 Px factor with 50.6% cQE at
the emission. Rod-shaped concave core-shell nanoresonators exploit similarly
transversal and longitudinal dipolar resonances, moreover they enhance the
fluorescence more significantly due to their antenna-like geometry. Px factor
of 8.34x10^5 enhancement is achievable while the cQE is 50.3% at the emission.
The enhancement can result in 2.03x10^6-fold Px factor, when the criterion
regarding the minimum QE is set to 20%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05901</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Sodoga</keyname><forenames>Komi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aremua</keyname><forenames>Isiaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hounkonnou</keyname><forenames>Mahouton Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape invariant potential formalism for photon-added coherent state
  construction</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An algebro-operator approach, called shape invariant potential method, of
constructing generalized coherent states for photon-added particle system is
presented. Illustration is given on Poschl-Teller potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05912</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Agaba</keyname><forenames>G. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyrychko</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blyuss</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-delayed SIS epidemic model with population awareness</title><categories>q-bio.PE nlin.CD q-bio.QM</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ecol. Compl. 31, 50-56 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ecocom.2017.03.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper analyses the dynamics of infectious disease with a concurrent
spread of disease awareness. The model includes local awareness due to contacts
with aware individuals, as well as global awareness due to reported cases of
infection and awareness campaigns. We investigate the effects of time delay in
response of unaware individuals to available information on the epidemic
dynamics by establishing conditions for the Hopf bifurcation of the endemic
steady state of the model. Analytical results are supported by numerical
bifurcation analysis and simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05920</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Pia</keyname><forenames>Maria Grazia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronchieri</keyname><forenames>Elisabetta</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of Econometric Data Analysis Methods to Physics Software</title><categories>cs.SE physics.data-an</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, IEEE NSS/MIC 2016</comments><acm-class>D.2.4; G.3</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an investigation of data analysis methods derived from other
disciplines, which we applied to physics software systems. They concern the
analysis of inequality, trend analysis and the analysis of diversity. The
analysis of inequality exploits statistical methods originating from
econometrics; trend analysis is typical of economics and environmental
sciences; the analysis of diversity is based on concepts derived from ecology
and treats software as an ecosystem. To the best of our knowledge, this is an
innovative exploration, as we could not find track of previous use of these
methods in the experimental physics domains within the scope of the IEEE
Nuclear Science Symposium. We applied these methods in the context of Geant4
physics validation and Geant4 maintainability assessment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05922</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>A multi model surface wind climatology for the Gulf of California</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Seven data sources are analyzed and combined to form a surface wind speed
climatology for the Gulf of California.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05951</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xingbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bi</keyname><forenames>Dapeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czajkowski</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkel</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manning</keyname><forenames>M. Lisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchetti</keyname><forenames>M. Cristina</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlating Cell Shape and Cellular Stress in Motile Confluent Tissues</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph q-bio.CB q-bio.TO</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Collective cell migration is a highly regulated process involved in wound
healing, cancer metastasis and morphogenesis. Mechanical interactions among
cells provide an important regulatory mechanism to coordinate such collective
motion. Using a Self-Propelled Voronoi (SPV) model that links cell mechanics to
cell shape and cell motility, we formulate a generalized mechanical inference
method to obtain the spatio-temporal distribution of cellular stresses from
measured traction forces in motile tissues and show that such traction-based
stresses match those calculated from instantaneous cell shapes. We additionally
use stress information to characterize the rheological properties of the
tissue. We identify a motility-induced swim stress that adds to the interaction
stress to determine the global contractility or extensibility of epithelia. We
further show that the temporal correlation of the interaction shear stress
determines an effective viscosity of the tissue that diverges at the
liquid-solid transition, suggesting the possibility of extracting rheological
information directly from traction data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05955</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Quanlong</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence of Local Complementation and Euler Decomposition in the
  Qutrit ZX-calculus</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we give a modified version of the qutrit ZX-calculus, by which
we represent qutrit graph states as diagrams and prove that the qutrit version
of local complementation property is true if and only if the qutrit Hadamard
gate $H$ has an Euler decomposition into $4\pi/3$-green and red rotations. This
paves the way for studying the completeness of qutrit ZX-calculus for qutrit
stabilizer quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05957</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Golla</keyname><forenames>Dheeraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brasington</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>LeRoy</keyname><forenames>Brian J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandhu</keyname><forenames>Arvinder</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast relaxation of hot phonons in Graphene-hBN Heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Pages 1-12: Main manuscript. Pages 13-18: Supplementary material</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fast carrier cooling is important for high power graphene based devices.
Strongly Coupled Optical Phonons (SCOPs) play a major role in the relaxation of
photoexcited carriers in graphene. Heterostructures of graphene and hexagonal
boron nitride (hBN) have shown exceptional mobility and high saturation
current, which makes them ideal for applications, but the effect of the hBN
substrate on carrier cooling mechanisms is not understood. We track the cooling
of hot photo-excited carriers in graphene-hBN heterostructures using ultrafast
pump-probe spectroscopy. We find that the carriers cool down four times faster
in the case of graphene on hBN than on a silicon oxide substrate thus
overcoming the hot phonon (HP) bottleneck that plagues cooling in graphene
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05970</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Jianyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Mingyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Liantuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Suotang</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced transmission capacity for laser communication at the
  single-photon level using the multi-channel frequency coding scheme</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>There are 11 pages, 9 figures in the paper. In this paper, we
  proposed a new MCFC coding scheme, which is specially designed for laser
  communication when the received signal is at the single-photon level</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The statistical properties of a radiation sources are commonly characterized
by second-order-correlation or Mandel parameter. Our research found that the
single photons modulation spectrum provides us another optional way which is
more sensitive to the high frequency information contained in the photon
sequence. In this paper, we present direct laser communication by using a
multi-channel frequency coding scheme based on the single photons modulation
spectrum in which the multi-frequency modulation makes the transmission
capacity efficiently enhanced. The modulation frequencies could be operated in
a wide band without frequency aliasing due to the inherent randomness of
photons arrival time of weak coherent light. The error rate less than 10-5 has
been achieved experimentally when the mean signal photon count is 80 kcps. The
modulated coherent light field shows nonlinear effects of single photons
modulation spectrum. The studies of statistical properties of the single
photons modulation spectrum, including the dependence of mean noise photon
count, integration time, channel spacing and the number of frequency component,
helped us to optimize the error rate and transmission capacity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05983</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Qinjian</forenames></author></authors><title>On the detection probability of neutron star glitches</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS
  https://academic.oup.com/mnras/article/468/3/3031/3089739/On-the-detection-probability-of-neutron-star?guestAccessKey=6271d3e2-a890-4950-91e8-372e14b40a57
  Your email for discussion is warmly welcome</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 468, 3031 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutron stars are observed to undergo small, abrupt rotational speed-up. This
phenomenon is known as glitch. In pulsar timing observations, detection of a
neutron star glitch is constrained by the time of occurrence of the event
relative to entire observing span and observing cadences, time of occurrence of
preceding/subsequent glitches relative to observing cadences and the strength
of timing noise. Using the Yu et al. (2013) data sets, in this paper, we
analyse the observational selection in terms of detection probability. We
define partial probabilities for the constraints and use Monte Carlo method
with assuming glitches distribute uniformly to solve the complete probability
formula for both group case involving 157 pulsars and individual cases for each
of the seven pulsars with glitch numbers $\geqslant 5$. In the simulations,
numerical Bayesian inference is used for glitch identification. With the
derived detection probability density and observed results, we uncover glitch
size probability distribution embedded in the data for both the group and
individual cases. We find the most prominent correction occurred for
PSR~J1341$-$6220, in which exponent of the power-law model varies from the
observed $+0.7^{+1.4}_{-0.7}$ to $-0.4^{+1.0}_{-0.4}$. We suggest observers
determine the detection probability for glitch theories, e.g. the
self-organised criticality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05989</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yamanouchi</keyname><forenames>Michihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyamada</keyname><forenames>Tatsuro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katase</keyname><forenames>Takayoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>Hiromichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Current-induced effective magnetic field in a half-metallic oxide
  La0.67Sr0.33MnO3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigated current-induced effective magnetic field Heff in
half-metallic oxide La0.67Sr0.33MnO3 (LSMO) films with various thicknesses by
using the planar Hall effect. Applying in-plane current to the LSMO films
exerted an in-plane Heff orthogonal to the current direction on magnetization.
The Heff magnitude increased with increasing current magnitude, and the
direction reversed when the applied current switched to opposite sign. Assuming
that a 6.5-u.c. insulating layer is created in the LSMO, the values of Heff
observed in devices with three different LSMO thicknesses were almost scaled
with current density, evaluated from the effective LSMO thickness excluding the
insulating layer, suggesting that Heff is induced in the LSMO bulk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06003</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Fumika</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractional Moment Methods for Anderson Localization with SAW
  Representation</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.dis-nn math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>This is an author-created, un-copyedited version of an article
  published in Journal of Physics A. IOP Publishing Ltd is not responsible for
  any errors or omissions in this version of the manuscript or any version
  derived from it. The Version of Record is available online at
  https://doi.org/10.1088/1751-8113/46/12/125008</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 46 125008 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/46/12/125008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Green's function contains much information about physical systems.
Mathematically, the fractional moment method (FMM) developed by Aizenman and
Molchanov connects the Green's function and the transport of electrons in the
Anderson model. Recently, it has been discovered that the Green's function on a
graph can be represented using self-avoiding walks on a graph, which allows us
to connect localization properties in the system and graph properties. We
discuss FMM in terms of the self-avoiding walks on a general graph, the only
general condition being that the graph has a uniform bound on the vertex
degree.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06006</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Fukusumi</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple Schramm-Loewner evolutions for coset Wess-Zumino-Witten models</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate multiple Schramm-Loewner evolutions (SLEs) for coset
Wess-Zumino-Witten (WZW) models. The resultant SLEs may describe the critical
behavior of multiple interfaces for the 2D statistical mechanics models whose
critical properties are classified by coset WZW models. The SLEs are
essentially characterized by multiple Brownian motions on a Lie group manifold
as well as those on the real axis. The drift terms of the Brownian motions,
which come from interactions of interfaces, are explicitly determined by
imposing a martingale condition on correlation functions among boundary
condition changing operators. As a concrete example, we formulate multiple SLE
on the $Z(n)$ parafermion model and calculate the crossing probability which is
closely related to 3-SLE drift terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06023</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Schaffernak</keyname><forenames>Gernot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruber</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krenn</keyname><forenames>Joachim R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krug</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ga&#x161;pari&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Marija</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belitsch</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hohenau</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluorescence coupling to plasmonic nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Photonics, Devices, and Systems VI, edited by Pavel Tom\'anek,
  Dagmar Sender\'akov\'a, Petr P\'ata, Proc. of SPIE Vol. 9450, 94501S (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2070333</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The combination of single photon emitters (quantum dots) and tailored metal
nanoparticles with defined size and shape allows a detailed study of the
interaction between light and matter. The enhanced optical near-field of the
nanoparticles can strongly influence the absorption and emission of nearby
fluorescent quantum dots. We show that a controlled spatial arrangement enables
the analysis and understanding of polarization dependent coupling between a
metal nanoparticle and few or single fluorescent quantum dots. Modifications in
the fluorescence spectrum and lifetime are analyzed and compare well with
simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06045</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Mengxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shizhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yachao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Weixing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Hailu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Shuangchun</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantized photonic spin Hall effect in graphene</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures. Some improvements have been made</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 95, 013809 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the photonic spin Hall effect (SHE) in a graphene-substrate system
with the presence of external magnetic field. In the quantum Hall regime, we
demonstrate that the in-plane and transverse spin-dependent splittings in
photonic SHE exhibit different quantized behaviors. The quantized SHE can be
described as a consequence of a quantized geometric phase (Berry phase), which
corresponds to the quantized spin-orbit interaction. Furthermore, an
experimental scheme based on quantum weak value amplification is proposed to
detect the quantized SHE in terahertz frequency regime. By incorporating the
quantum weak measurement techniques, the quantized photonic SHE holds great
promise for detecting quantized Hall conductivity and Berry phase. These
results may bridge the gap between the electronic SHE and photonic SHE in
graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06047</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06047</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Patil</keyname><forenames>M K</forenames></author></authors><title>Accretion powered AGN feedback in the cores of galaxy clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>National Conference on Signal Processing, Sustainable Energy
  Materials and Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics (NSSEMA 2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Detection of the copious amount of X-ray emission from the dilute hot plasma
in galaxy clusters suggests that a substantial fraction of the central
intracluster medium (ICM) is cooling radiatively on a time scale much faster
than the Hubble time. Theoretical models predict the cooling rate as high as
about few hundred to few thousand solar mass per year, which would be then made
available for the formation of new stars in the core of these clusters.
However, systematic studies of the cores of such clusters failed to detect the
expected reservoirs of cooled gas. Thus, the gas in the cores of galaxy
clusters is losing substantial amount of energy in the form of X-rays but is
not cooling. This in turn point towards the famous cooling flow paradox and
hence demands some intermittent heating to balance the cooling over such a long
period. Several sources have been suggested to counteract on the cooling of the
ICM, however, the AGN feedback appeared to be the most promising and enough
energetic source to resist cooling of the ICM in the cores of such clusters. In
this presentation I will provide a brief overview on the feedback processes
that are involved in the cores of the galaxy clusters with an emphasis on the
AGN feedback and its observable signatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06054</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ratha</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surendar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improvement of PolSAR Decomposition Scattering Powers Using a Relative
  Decorrelation Measure</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Remote Sensing Letters</comments><doi>10.1080/2150704X.2016.1271159</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, a methodology is proposed to improve the scattering powers
obtained from model-based decomposition using Polarimetric Synthetic Aperture
Radar (PolSAR) data. The novelty of this approach lies in utilizing the
intrinsic information in the off-diagonal elements of the 3$\times$3 coherency
matrix $\mathbf{T}$ represented in the form of complex correlation
coefficients. Two complex correlation coefficients are computed between
co-polarization and cross-polarization components of the Pauli scattering
vector. The difference between modulus of complex correlation coefficients
corresponding to $\mathbf{T}^{\mathrm{opt}}$ (i.e. the degree of polarization
(DOP) optimized coherency matrix), and $\mathbf{T}$ (original) matrices is
obtained. Then a suitable scaling is performed using fractions \emph{i.e.,}
$(T_{ii}^{\mathrm{opt}}/\sum\limits_{i=1}^{3}T_{ii}^{\mathrm{opt}})$ obtained
from the diagonal elements of the $\mathbf{T}^{\mathrm{opt}}$ matrix.
Thereafter, these new quantities are used in modifying the Yamaguchi
4-component scattering powers obtained from $\mathbf{T}^{\mathrm{opt}}$. To
corroborate the fact that these quantities have physical relevance, a
quantitative analysis of these for the L-band AIRSAR San Francisco and the
L-band Kyoto images is illustrated. Finally, the scattering powers obtained
from the proposed methodology are compared with the corresponding powers
obtained from the Yamaguchi \emph{et. al.,} 4-component (Y4O) decomposition and
the Yamaguchi \emph{et. al.,} 4-component Rotated (Y4R) decomposition for the
same data sets. The proportion of negative power pixels is also computed. The
results show an improvement on all these attributes by using the proposed
methodology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06059</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Beitia-Antero</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Castro</keyname><forenames>Ana I. G&#xf3;mez</forenames></author></authors><title>Interstellar extinction in Orion. Variation of the strength of the UV
  bump across the complex</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx881</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is growing observational evidence of dust coagulation in the dense
filaments within molecular clouds. Infrared observations show that the dust
grains size distribution gets shallower and the relative fraction of small to
large dust grains decreases as the local density increases. Ultraviolet (UV)
observations show that the strength of the 2175 {\AA} feature, the so-called UV
bump, also decreases with cloud density. In this work, we apply the technique
developed for the Taurus study to the Orion molecular cloud and confirm that
the UV bump decreases over the densest cores of the cloud as well as in the
heavily UV irradiated {\lambda} Orionis shell. The study has been extended to
the Rosette cloud with uncertain results given the distance (1.3 kpc).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06075</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>University of Vienna, Department of Astrophysics, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames><affiliation>Institut f&#xfc;r Astronomie und Astrophysik, Eberhard Karls Universit&#xe4;t T&#xfc;bingen, Germany</affiliation></author></authors><title>Applicability and limits of simple hydrodynamic scaling for collisions
  of water-rich bodies in different mass regimes</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Proceedings of the First Greek-Austrian Workshop on Extrasolar
  Planetary Systems, Ammouliani, Greece, Sept. 2016. Editors: Thomas I. Maindl,
  Harry Varvoglis, Rudolf Dvorak - 19 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the First Greek-Austrian Workshop on Extrasolar
  Planetary Systems, pages 63-81, March 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the outcome of collisions in very different mass regimes, but
an otherwise identical parameter setup, comprising the impact velocity
($v/v_\mathrm{esc}$), impact angle, mass ratio, and initial composition, w.r.t.
simple hydrodynamic scaling. The colliding bodies' masses range from $\simeq
10^{16}$ to $10^{24}$ kg, which includes km-sized planetesimals up to
planetary-sized objects. Our analysis of the results comprises the time
evolution of fragment masses, the fragments' water contents and fragment
dynamics, where we start with bodies consisting of basalt and water ice. The
usual assumption of hydrodynamic scaling over a wider range of masses is based
on material behavior similar to a fluid, or a rubble pile, respectively. All
our simulations are carried out once including full solid-body physics, and
once for strengthless - but otherwise identical - bodies, to test for the
influence of material strength.
  We find that scale-invariance over a wider range of masses is mostly only a
very crude approximation at best, but can be applied to constrained mass ranges
if tested carefully. For the chosen scenarios the outcomes of solid-body
objects compared to strengthless fluid bodies differ most for our intermediate
masses, but are similar for the lowest and highest masses. The most energetic,
planet-sized collisions produce considerably faster and more fragments, which
is also reflected in high water losses - above 50 percent in a single
collision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06082</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Man'ko</keyname><forenames>Margarita A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conditional information and hidden correlations in single-qudit states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the notions of mutual information and conditional information for
noncomposite systems, classical and quantum; both the mutual information and
the conditional information are associated with the presence of hidden
correlations in the state of a single qudit. We consider analogs of the
entanglement phenomena in the systems without subsystems related to strong
hidden quantum correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06083</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Zajnulina</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodenm&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blow</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boggio</keyname><forenames>J. M. Chavez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieznik</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characteristics and stability of soliton crystals in optical fibres for
  the purpose of optical frequency comb generation</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Opt Commun 393, pp 95 - 102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.optcom.2017.02.035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the properties of a soliton crystal, an bound state of several
optical pulses that propagate with a fixed temporal separation through the
optical fibres of the proposed approach for generation of optical frequency
combs (OFC) for astronomical spectrograph calibration. This approach - also
being suitable for subpicosecond pulse generation for other applications -
consists of a conventional single-mode fibre and a suitably pumped Erbium-doped
fibre. Two continuous-wave lasers are used as light source. The soliton crystal
arises out of the initial deeply modulated laser field at low input powers; for
higher input powers, it dissolves into free solitons. We study the soliton
crystal build-up in the first fibre stage with respect to different fibre
parameters (group-velocity dispersion, nonlinearity, and optical losses) and to
the light source characteristics (laser frequency separation and intensity
difference). We show that the soliton crystal can be described by two
quantities, its fundamental frequency and the laser power-threshold at which
the crystal dissolves into free solitons. The soliton crystal exhibits features
of a linear and nonlinear optical pattern at the same time and is insensitive
to the initial laser power fluctuations. We perform our studies using the
numerical technique called Soliton Radiation Beat Analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06085</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pourhassan</keyname><forenames>Behnam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sudhaker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hameeda</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering of Galaxies with Dynamical Dark Energy</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 468, 3166-3173 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx697</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study thermodynamics of the cluster of galaxies under the
effect of dynamical dark energy. We evaluate the configurational integral for
interacting system of galaxies in an expanding universe by including the
effects produced by the varying $\Lambda$. The gravitational partition function
is obtained using this configuration integral. We obtain thermodynamics
quantities in canonical ensemble which depend on time and investigate the
second law of thermodynamics. We also calculate the distribution function in
grand canonical ensemble. The time evolution of the clustering parameter of
galaxies is investigated for the time dependent (dynamical) dark energy. We
conclude that the second law of thermodynamics is valid for the total system of
cluster of galaxies and dynamical dark energy. We calculate correlation
function and show that our model is very close to Peebles's power law, in
agreement with the N-body simulation. It is observed that thermodynamics
quantities depend on the modified clustering parameter for this system of
galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06094</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>Frank G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Review on Cosmic-Ray Radio Detection (VULCANO 2016)</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Proceedings of VULCANO Workshop 2016, ISBN 978-88-86409-65-0</comments><journal-ref>Frascati Physics Series Vol. 64 (2016) 139</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extensive air showers still are our only access to the highest-energy
particles in the universe, namely cosmic-ray nuclei with energies up to several
100 EeV. Studying open questions in cosmic-ray physics, like their yet unknown
origin requires the reconstruction of the energy and mass of the primary
particles from the air-shower measurements. Great progress has been achieved
lately in the development of the radio detection technique for this purpose.
There now is a consistent picture of the mechanisms behind the radio emission,
which is in agreement with measurements. Several second-generation, digital
antenna arrays are operating in different parts of the world not only aiming at
the further development of the technique, but also contributing to cosmic-ray
physics at energies above 100 PeV. Recently it has been demonstrated
experimentally that radio detection can compete in precision with established
techniques for air showers, like the measurement of secondary particles on
ground, or fluorescence and Cherenkov light emitted by air showers.
Consequently, cosmic-ray observatories can benefit from radio extensions to
maximize their total measurement accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06106</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Benguria</keyname><forenames>Rafael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fournais</keyname><forenames>S&#xf8;ren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockmeyer</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosch</keyname><forenames>Hanne Van Den</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-adjointness of two-dimensional Dirac operators on domains</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages. Final published version, contains results that were
  previously in arXiv:1601.06607</comments><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincar\'e, 18(4), 1371-1383 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-017-0554-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider Dirac operators defined on planar domains. For a large class of
boundary conditions, we give a direct proof of their self-adjointness in the
Sobolev space $H^1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06108</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Takayama</keyname><forenames>Osamu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shkondin</keyname><forenames>Evgeniy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodganov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Esmail Aryaee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golenitskii</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dmitriev</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rep&#xe4;n</keyname><forenames>Taavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malureanu</keyname><forenames>Radu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belov</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jensen</keyname><forenames>Flemming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrinenko</keyname><forenames>Andrei V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mid-infrared directional surface waves on a high aspect ratio
  nano-trench platform</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical surface waves, highly localized modes bound to the surface of media,
enable manipulation of light at nanoscale, thus impacting a wide range of areas
in nanoscience. By applying metamaterials, artificially designed optical
materials, as contacting media at the interface, we can significantly
ameliorate surface wave propagation and even generate new types of waves. Here,
we demonstrate that high aspect ratio (1:20) grating structures with plasmonic
lamellas in deep nanoscale trenches function as a versatile platform supporting
both surface and volume infrared waves. The surface waves exhibit a unique
combination of properties, such as directionality, broadband existence (from 4
{\mu}m to at least 14 {\mu}m and beyond) and high localization, making them an
attractive tool for effective control of light in an extended range of infrared
frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06113</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sellier</keyname><forenames>Jean Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapanova</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Hydrogen Atom Beyond the Born-Oppenheimer Approximation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently a new formulation of quantum mechanics has been suggested which is
based on the concept of signed particles, that is, classical objects provided
with a position, a momentum and a sign simultaneously. In this paper, we
comment on the plausibility of simulating atomic systems beyond the
Born-Oppenheimer approximation by means of the signed particle formulation of
quantum mechanics. First, in order to show the new perspective offered by this
new formalism, we provide an example studying quantum tunnelling through a
simple Gaussian barrier in terms of the signed particle formulation. Then, we
perform a direct simulation of the hydrogen atom as a full quantum two-body
system, showing that the formalism can be a very promising tool for
first-principle-only quantum chemistry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06114</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zong-Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kedem</keyname><forenames>Yaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Jin-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zong-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hua</keyname><forenames>Yi-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guang-Can</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental observation of anomalous trajectories of single photons</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042121 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A century after its conception, quantum mechanics still hold surprises that
contradict many &quot;common sense&quot; notions. The contradiction is especially sharp
in case one consider trajectories of truly quantum objects such as single
photons. From a classical point of view, trajectories are well defined for
particles, but not for waves. The wave-particle duality forces a breakdown of
this dichotomy and quantum mechanics resolves this in a remarkable way:
Trajectories can be well defined, but they are utterly different from classical
trajectories. Here, we give an operational definition to the trajectory of a
single photon by introducing a novel technique to mark its path using its
spectral composition. The method demonstrates that the frequency degree of
freedom can be used as a bona fide quantum measurement device (meter). The
analysis of a number of setups, using our operational definition, leads to
anomalous trajectories which are non-continuous and in some cases do not even
connect the source of the photon to where it is detected. We carried out an
experimental demonstration of these anomalous trajectories using a nested
interferometer. We show that the Two-state vector formalism provides a simple
explanation for the results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06122</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Campana</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuschino</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labanti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marisaldi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amati</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uslenghi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldazzi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellutti</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evangelista</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elmi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feroci</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ficorella</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frontera</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picciotto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piemonte</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rachevski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashevskaya</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rignanese</keyname><forenames>L. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vacchi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zampa</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zampa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>A compact and modular X and gamma-ray detector with a CsI scintillator
  and double-readout Silicon Drift Detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures. Published in Proceeding of SPIE Astronomical
  Telescopes and Instrumentation 2016</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the SPIE, 9905, 99056I (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2232597</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A future compact and modular X and gamma-ray spectrometer (XGS) has been
designed and a series of prototypes have been developed and tested. The
experiment envisages the use of CsI scintillator bars read out at both ends by
single-cell 25 mm2 Silicon Drift Detectors. Digital algorithms are used to
discriminate between events absorbed in the Silicon layer (lower energy X rays)
and events absorbed in the scintillator crystal (higher energy X rays and
gamma-rays). The prototype characterization is shown and the modular design for
future experiments with possible astrophysical applications (e.g. for the
THESEUS mission proposed for the ESA M5 call) are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06128</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Marquet</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>The last paper &quot;On the theory of storm&quot; (Zur Sturmtheorie) published by
  Max Margules in 1906</title><categories>physics.hist-ph physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>18 pages / 3 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper &quot;On the theory of storm&quot; (Zur Sturmtheorie) is the last one Max
Margules has published in 1906, just before to &quot;bid farewell to Meteorology&quot;
(using his words). The lack of English translation of this paper might be
filled by this attempt which can be certainly improved, however.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06135</id><created>2017-04-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lade</keyname><forenames>Steven J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bodin</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;rjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donges</keyname><forenames>Jonathan F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kautsky</keyname><forenames>Elin Enfors</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galafassi</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsson</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schl&#xfc;ter</keyname><forenames>Maja</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling social-ecological transformations: an adaptive network
  proposal</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transformations to create more sustainable social-ecological systems are
urgently needed. Structural change is a feature of transformations of
social-ecological systems that is of critical importance but is little
understood. Here, we propose a framework for conceptualising and modelling
sustainability transformations based on adaptive networks. Adaptive networks
focus attention on the interplay between the structure of a social-ecological
system and the dynamics of individual entities. Adaptive networks could
progress transformations research by: 1) focusing research on changes in
structure; 2) providing a conceptual framework that clarifies the temporal
dynamics of social-ecological transformations compared to the most commonly
used heuristic in resilience studies, the ball-and-cup diagram; 3) providing
quantitative modelling tools in an area of study dominated by qualitative
methods. We illustrate the potential application of adaptive networks to
social-ecological transformations using a case study of illegal fishing in the
Southern Ocean and a theoretical model of socially networked resource users.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06136</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sitek</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>Miguel Urbaneja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torfason</keyname><forenames>Kristinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudmundsson</keyname><forenames>Vidar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manolescu</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlled Coulomb effects in core-shell quantum rings</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse theoretically the possibilities of contactless control of in-gap
states formed by a pair of electrons confined in a triangular quantum ring. The
in-gap states are corner-localized states associated with two electrons
occupying the same corner area, and thus shifted to much higher energies than
other corner states, but still they are below the energies of
corner-side-localized states. We show how the energies, degeneracy and
splittings between consecutive levels change with the orientation of an
external electric field relatively to the polygonal cross section. We also show
how absorption changes in the presence of external electric and magnetic
fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06144</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Rosa</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micciarelli</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laio</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baroni</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Sampling molecular conformers in solution with quantum mechanical
  accuracy at a nearly molecular mechanics cost</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Theory Comp. 12, 9 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a method to evaluate the relative populations of different
conformers of molecular species in solution, aiming at quantum mechanical
accuracy, while keeping the computational cost at a nearly molecular-mechanics
level. This goal is achieved by combining long classical molecular-dynamics
simulations to sample the free-energy landscape of the system, advanced
clustering techniques to identify the most relevant conformers, and
thermodynamic perturbation theory to correct the resulting populations, using
quantum-mechanical energies from density-functional theory. A quantitative
criterion for assessing the accuracy thus achieved is proposed. The resulting
methodology is demonstrated in the specific case of cyanin
(cyanidin-3-glucoside) in water solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06154</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Maldonado</keyname><forenames>Carlos Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Positive Affirmation of Non-Algorithmic Information Processing</title><categories>nlin.AO</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 table</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most compelling problems in science consists in understanding how
living systems process information. After all, the way they process information
defines their capacities to learning and adaptation. There is an increasing
consensus in that living systems are not machines in any sense. Biological
hyper-computation is the concept coined that expresses that living beings
process information non-algorithmically. Maldonado and Gomez (2015) have
brought up biological hyper-computation as a new problem within complexity
science. This paper aims at proving a positive understanding of non-algorithmic
processes. A number of arguments are brought that support the claim. This
fosters, it is argued, a brand new understanding of information processing
among living beings. Some conclusions are drawn at the end.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06166</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Parab</keyname><forenames>Pradnya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Deepak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muthurajan</keyname><forenames>Harries</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raychaudhuri</keyname><forenames>Pratap</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Sangita</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiband Superconductivity in the time reversal symmetry broken
  superconductor Re6Zr</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report point contact Andreev Reflection (PCAR) measurements on a
high-quality single crystal of the non-centrosymmetric superconductor Re6Zr. We
observe that the PCAR spectra can be fitted by taking two isotropic
superconducting gaps with Delta_1 ~ 0.79 meV and Delta_2 ~ 0.22 meV
respectively, suggesting that there are at least two bands which contribute to
superconductivity. Combined with the observation of time reversal symmetry
breaking at the superconducting transition from muon spin relaxation
measurements (Phys. Rev. Lett. 112, 107002 (2014)), our results imply an
unconventional superconducting order in this compound: A multiband singlet
state that breaks time reversal symmetry or a triplet state dominated by
interband pairing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06172</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Pieri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strinati</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Luttinger theorem and imbalanced Fermi systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 90, 68 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-80071-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The proof of the Luttinger theorem, which was originally given for a normal
Fermi liquid with equal spin populations formally described by the exact
many-body theory at zero temperature, is here extended to an approximate theory
given in terms of a &quot;conserving&quot; approximation also with spin imbalanced
populations. The need for this extended proof, whose underlying assumptions are
here spelled out in detail, stems from the recent interest in superfluid
trapped Fermi atoms with attractive inter-particle interaction, for which the
difference between two spin populations can be made large enough that
superfluidity is destroyed and the system remains normal even at zero
temperature. In this context, we will demonstrate the validity of the Luttinger
theorem separately for the two spin populations for any &quot;$\Phi$-derivable&quot;
approximation, and illustrate it in particular for the self-consistent
$t$-matrix approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06193</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>Andres</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kebschull</keyname><forenames>Udo</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Intrusion Prevention and Detection in Grid Computing - The ALICE Case</title><categories>cs.DC cs.AI cs.CR hep-ex</categories><comments>Journal of Physics: Conference Series, Volume 664</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 664 062017 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/664/6/062017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Grids allow users flexible on-demand usage of computing resources through
remote communication networks. A remarkable example of a Grid in High Energy
Physics (HEP) research is used in the ALICE experiment at European Organization
for Nuclear Research CERN. Physicists can submit jobs used to process the huge
amount of particle collision data produced by the Large Hadron Collider (LHC).
Grids face complex security challenges. They are interesting targets for
attackers seeking for huge computational resources. Since users can execute
arbitrary code in the worker nodes on the Grid sites, special care should be
put in this environment. Automatic tools to harden and monitor this scenario
are required. Currently, there is no integrated solution for such requirement.
This paper describes a new security framework to allow execution of job
payloads in a sandboxed context. It also allows process behavior monitoring to
detect intrusions, even when new attack methods or zero day vulnerabilities are
exploited, by a Machine Learning approach. We plan to implement the proposed
framework as a software prototype that will be tested as a component of the
ALICE Grid middleware.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06197</id><created>2017-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Ota</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Reproduction of Interstellar Infrared Spectrum of Reflection Nebula
  NGC2023 By A Hydrocarbon Pentagon-Hexagon Combined Molecule</title><categories>physics.atom-ph astro-ph.GA physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reflection Nebula NGC2023 shows specific interstellar infrared spectrum due
to polycyclic aromatic hydrocarbon (PAH) in a wide wavelength range from 5 to
20 micrometer. By our previous quantum chemistry calculation, it was suggested
that a molecule group having hydrocarbon pentagon-hexagon combined skeleton
could reproduce ubiquitous interstellar infrared spectrum. In this paper,
observed NGC2023 spectrum was compared in detail with such carrier candidates.
First model molecule was di-cation (C23H12)2+ with two hydrocarbon pentagons
combined with five hexagons. Observed strong infrared bands were 6.2, 7.7, 8.6,
and 11.2 micrometer. Whereas, calculated strong peaks were 6.4, 7.5, 7.7, 8.5,
and 11.2 micrometer. Observed weaker bands from 10 to 15 micrometer were 11.0,
12.0, 12.7, 13.5, and 14.2 micrometer, which were reproduced well by computed
bands as 10.9, 12.0, 12.6, 13.6, and 14.0 micrometer. From 15 to 20 micrometer,
observed 15.8, 16.4, 17.4, 17.8, and 19.0 micrometer were correlated with
calculated 15.6, 16.5, 17.2, 18.2, and 18.8 micrometer. It should be noted that
we could successfully reproduce interstellar infrared spectrum by applying a
single molecule. Second model molecule was (C12H8)3+ with one pentagon combined
with two hexagons. Again, observed strong bands at 6.2, 7.7, 8.6, 11.2 and 12.7
micrometer were successfully computed as 6.3, 7.4, 7.7, 8.6, 11.1, and 12.8
micrometer. It was concluded that by introducing hydrocarbon pentagon-hexagon
combined ionized molecules, interstellar PAH oriented infrared spectrum could
be successfully reproduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06207</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Samanta</keyname><forenames>Nairhita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Rajarshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion of self-propelled Janus tracer in polymeric environment</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Artificially synthesized Janus particles have tremendous prospective as
in-vivo drug-delivery agents due to the possibility of self-propulsion by
external stimuli. Here we report the first ever computational study of
translational and rotational motion of self-propelled Janus tracers in a het-
erogeneous polymeric environment. The presence of polymers makes the
translational mean square displacement (MSD) of the Janus tracer to grow very
slowly as compared to that of a free Janus tracer, but surprisingly the mean
square angular displacement (MSAD) is significantly increased as observed in a
recent experiment. Moreover, with the increasing propulsion velocity, MSAD
grows even faster. However, when the repulsive polymers are replaced with
polymers with sticky zones, MSD and MSAD both show sharp decline.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-04-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06238</id><created>2017-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Vafafard</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum Induced Coherence in Cavity Quantum Electrodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Vacuum induced coherence in a strongly coupled cavity consisting of a
three-level system is studied theoretically. The effects of the strong coupling
to electromagnetic field vacuum are examined by solution of an open-system
quantum master equation. The numerical results show that the system exhibits
population trapping, and the numerical results are interpreted with analytical
expressions derived from a new basis in the weak excitation regime. We further
show that the generated effects can be probed with weak external fields.
Moreover, it is shown that the induced coherence can be controlled by the
applied field parameters like field detuning. Finally, we study the trapping
dynamics in the strong field excitation regime, and also demonstrate that a
recently proposed asymmetric pumping regime (limited to the weak coupling
regime) can remove the radiative decay of coherent Rabi oscillations, with both
weak and strong excitation fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
