<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:52:36Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-01" from="2017-05-01" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1001.1847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1001.1847</id><created>2010-01-12</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dasari</keyname><forenames>Sanjay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>Anindya Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>An Economic analogy to Electrodynamics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph q-fin.GN</categories><comments>19 pages, duality aspect added, expanded, to comply with journal
  version</comments><journal-ref>Modern Economy, 2013, 4, 723-732</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note, we would like to find the laws of electrodynamics in simple
economic systems. In this direction, we identify the chief economic variables
and parameters, scalar and vector, which are amenable to be put directly into
the crouch of the laws of electrodynamics, namely Maxwell's equations.
Moreover, we obtain Phillp's curve, recession and Black-Scholes formula, as
sample applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1005.2533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1005.2533</id><created>2010-05-14</created><updated>2010-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yeung</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cimini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>C. -H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics underlying Box-office: Movie Competition on Recommender Systems</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.IR</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 83, 016105 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.83.016105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a simple model to study movie competition in the recommender
systems. Movies of heterogeneous quality compete against each other through
viewers' reviews and generate interesting dynamics of box-office. By assuming
mean-field interactions between the competing movies, we show that run-away
effect of popularity spreading is triggered by defeating the average review
score, leading to hits in box-office. The average review score thus
characterizes the critical movie quality necessary for transition from
box-office bombs to blockbusters. The major factors affecting the critical
review score are examined. By iterating the mean-field dynamical equations, we
obtain qualitative agreements with simulations and real systems in the
dynamical forms of box-office, revealing the significant role of competition in
understanding box-office dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1106.6198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1106.6198</id><created>2011-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Shklovskij</keyname><forenames>Valerij A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency-dependent ratchet effect in superconducting films with a
  tilted washboard pinning potential</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys Rev. B 84 (2011) 054515</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.84.054515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of an ac current of arbitrary amplitude and frequency on the
mixed-state dc-voltage-ac-drive ratchet response of a superconducting film with
a dc current-tilted uniaxial cosine pinning potential at finite temperature is
theoretically investigated. The results are obtained in the single-vortex
approximation, i.e., for non-interacting vortices, within the frame of an exact
solution of the appropriate Langevin equation in terms of a matrix continued
fraction. Formulas for the dc voltage ratchet response and absorbed power in ac
response are discussed as functions of ac current amplitude and frequency as
well as dc current induced tilt in a wide range of corresponding dimensionless
parameters. Special attention is paid to the physical interpretation of the
obtained results in adiabatic and high-frequency ratchet responses taking into
account both running and localized states of the (ac+dc)-driven vortex motion
in a washboard pinning potential. Our theoretical results are discussed in
comparison with recent experimental work on the high-frequency ratchet response
in nanostructured superconducting films [B. B. Jin et al., Phys. Rev. B 81
(2010) 174505].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.5297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.5297</id><created>2011-09-24</created><updated>2012-10-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Olla</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE, INRIA Paris - Rocquencourt</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sasada</keyname><forenames>Makiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Macroscopic energy diffusion for a chain of anharmonic oscillators</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>Accepted for the publication in Probability Theory and Related Fields</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Probability Theory and Related Fields, 2013, Volume 157, Issue 3,
  721-775</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00440-012-0469-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the energy diffusion in a chain of anharmonic oscillators where the
Hamiltonian dynamics is perturbed by a local energy conserving noise. We prove
that under diffusive rescaling of space-time, energy fluctuations diffuse and
evolve following an infinite dimensional linear stochastic differential
equation driven by the linearized heat equation. We also give variational
expressions for the thermal diffusivity and some upper and lower bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.1189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.1189</id><created>2012-04-05</created><updated>2012-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khlystova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Horizontal Component of Photospheric Plasma Flows During the
  Emergence of Active Regions on the Sun</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures, 3 tables. The results of article were presented
  at the ESPM-13 (12-16 September 2011, Rhodes, Greece, Abstract Book p. 102,
  P.4.12,
  http://astro.academyofathens.gr/espm13/documents/ESPM13_abstract_programme_book.pdf)</comments><journal-ref>Solar Physics, 2013, Volume 284, Issue 2, pp.343-361</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11207-012-0181-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of horizontal plasma flows during the first hours of the
emergence of active region magnetic flux in the solar photosphere have been
analyzed using SOHO/MDI data. Four active regions emerging near the solar limb
have been considered. It has been found that extended regions of Doppler
velocities with different signs are formed in the first hours of the magnetic
flux emergence in the horizontal velocity field. The flows observed are
directly connected with the emerging magnetic flux; they form at the beginning
of the emergence of active regions and are present for a few hours. The Doppler
velocities of flows observed increase gradually and reach their peak values
4-12 hours after the start of the magnetic flux emergence. The peak values of
the mean (inside the +/-500 m/s isolines) and maximum Doppler velocities are
800-970 m/s and 1410-1700 m/s, respectively. The Doppler velocities observed
substantially exceed the separation velocities of the photospheric magnetic
flux outer boundaries. The asymmetry was detected between velocity structures
of leading and following polarities. Doppler velocity structures located in a
region of leading magnetic polarity are more powerful and exist longer than
those in regions of following polarity. The Doppler velocity asymmetry between
the velocity structures of opposite sign reaches its peak values soon after the
emergence begins and then gradually drops within 7-12 hours. The peak values of
asymmetry for the mean and maximal Doppler velocities reach 240-460 m/s and
710-940 m/s, respectively. An interpretation of the observable flow of
photospheric plasma is given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.4536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.4536</id><created>2012-04-20</created><updated>2012-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khlystova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Relationship Between Plasma Flow Doppler Velocities and Magnetic
  Field Parameters During the Emergence of Active Regions at the Solar
  Photospheric Level</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures. The results of article were presented at the
  ESPM-13 (12-16 September 2011, Rhodes, Greece, Abstract Book p. 102-103,
  P.4.13,
  http://astro.academyofathens.gr/espm13/documents/ESPM13_abstract_programme_book.pdf)</comments><journal-ref>Solar Physics, 2013, Volume 284, Issue 2, pp.329-341</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11207-012-0193-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A statistical study has been carried out of the relationship between plasma
flow Doppler velocities and magnetic field parameters during the emergence of
active regions at the solar photospheric level with data acquired by the
Michelson Doppler Imager (MDI) onboard the Solar and Heliospheric Observatory
(SOHO). We have investigated 224 emerging active regions with different spatial
scales and positions on the solar disc. The following relationships for the
first hours of the emergence of active regions have been analysed: i) of peak
negative Doppler velocities with the position of the emerging active regions on
the solar disc; ii) of peak plasma upflow and downflow Doppler velocities with
the magnetic flux growth rate and magnetic field strength for the active
regions emerging near the solar disc centre (the vertical component of plasma
flows); iii) of peak positive and negative Doppler velocities with the magnetic
flux growth rate and magnetic field strength for the active regions emerging
near the limb (the horizontal component of plasma flows); iv) of the magnetic
flux growth rate with the density of emerging magnetic flux; v) of the Doppler
velocities and magnetic field parameters for the first hours of the appearance
of active regions with the total unsigned magnetic flux at the maximum of their
development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.1877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.1877</id><created>2013-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Shklovskij</keyname><forenames>Valerij A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosedkin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex ratchet reversal in an asymmetric washboard pinning potential
  subject to combined dc and ac stimuli</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 26 (2014) 025703</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/26/2/025703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mixed-state resistive response of a superconductor thin film with an
asymmetric washboard pinning potential subject to superimposed dc and ac
currents of arbitrary amplitudes and frequency at finite temperature is
theoretically investigated. The problem is considered in the single-vortex
approximation, relying upon the exact solution of the Langevin equation in
terms of a matrix continued fraction. The dc voltage response and the absorbed
power in ac response are analyzed as functions of dc bias, ac current amplitude
and frequency, in a wide range of corresponding dimensionless parameters.
Predictions are made of (i) a reversal of the rectified voltage at small dc
biases and strong ac drives and (ii) a non-monotonic enhancement of the
absorbed power in the nonlinear ac response at far sub-depinning frequencies.
It is elucidated how and why both these effects appear due to the competition
of the fixed internal and the tunable, dc bias-induced external asymmetry of
the potential as the only reason. This is distinct from other scenarios used
for explaining the vortex ratchet reversal effect so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.2303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.2303</id><created>2014-03-10</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fashami</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Salehi</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Souza</keyname><forenames>Noel</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring Performance, Coherence, and Clocking of Magnetization in
  Multiferroic Four-State Nanomagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2017.02.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanomagnetic memory and logic are currently seen as promising candidates to
replace current digital computing architectures due to its superior
energy-efficiency, non-volatility and propensity for highly dense and low-power
applications. In this work, we investigate the use of shape engineering
(concave and diamond shape) to introduce biaxial anisotropy in single domain
nanomagnets, giving rise to multiple easy and hard axes. Such nanomagnets, with
dimensions of 100 nm x 100 nm, double the logic density of conventional
two-state nanomagnetic devices by encoding more information (four binary
bits:00,11,10,01) per nanomagnet and can be used in memory and logic devices as
well as in higher order information processing applications. We study
reliability, magnetization switching coherence, and show, for the first time,
the use of voltage-induced strain for the clocking of magnetization in these
four-state nanomagnets. Critical parameters such as size, thickness, concavity,
and geometry of two types of four-state nanomagnets are also investigated. This
analytical study provides important insights into achieving reliable and
coherent single domain nanomagnets and low-energy magnetization clocking in
four-state nanomagnets, paving the way for potential applications in advanced
technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1536</id><created>2014-10-06</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>The HAWC collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abeysekara</keyname><forenames>A. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alfaro</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xc1;lvarez</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arceo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arteaga-Vel&#xe1;zquez</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solares</keyname><forenames>H. A. Ayala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baughman</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bautista-Elivar</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>BenZvi</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosales</keyname><forenames>M. Bonilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caballero-Mora</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrami&#xf1;ana</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotti</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cotzomi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Fuente</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Le&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeYoung</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez</keyname><forenames>R. Diaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dingus</keyname><forenames>B. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DuVernois</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ellsworth</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorino</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraija</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galindo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garfias</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodman</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gussert</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hampel-Arias</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harding</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;ntemeyer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imran</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iriarte</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karn</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieda</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunde</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauer</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lennarz</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vargas</keyname><forenames>H. Le&#xf3;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnemann</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luna-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malone</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Castro</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>E. Mendoza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miranda-Romagnoli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mostaf&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nellen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newbold</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noriega-Papaqui</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oceguera-Becerra</keyname><forenames>T. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patricelli</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelayo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-P&#xe9;rez</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pretz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivi&#xe8;re</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosa-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salazar</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greus</keyname><forenames>F. Salesa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandoval</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinnis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodle</keyname><forenames>K. Sparks</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springer</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taboada</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tollefson</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ukwatta</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villase&#xf1;or</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weisgarber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westerhoff</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wisher</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yodh</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Younk</keyname><forenames>P. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaborov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zepeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for gamma-rays from the unusually bright GRB 130427A with the
  HAWC Gamma-ray Observatory</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 2015, 800, 78</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/800/2/78</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first limits on the prompt emission from the long gamma-ray burst (GRB)
130427A in the $&gt;100\nobreakspace\rm{GeV}$ energy band are reported. GRB
130427A was the most powerful burst ever detected with a redshift
$z\lesssim0.5$ and featured the longest lasting emission above
$100\nobreakspace\rm{MeV}$. The energy spectrum extends at least up to
$95\nobreakspace\rm{GeV}$, clearly in the range observable by the High Altitude
Water Cherenkov (HAWC) Gamma-ray Observatory, a new extensive air shower
detector currently under construction in central Mexico. The burst occurred
under unfavourable observation conditions, low in the sky and when HAWC was
running 10% of the final detector. Based on the observed light curve at MeV-GeV
energies, eight different time periods have been searched for prompt and
delayed emission from this GRB. In all cases, no statistically significant
excess of counts has been found and upper limits have been placed. It is shown
that a similar GRB close to zenith would be easily detected by the full HAWC
detector, which will be completed soon. The detection rate of the full HAWC
detector may be as high as one to two GRBs per year. A detection could provide
important information regarding the high energy processes at work and the
observation of a possible cut-off beyond the $\mathit{Fermi}$-LAT energy range
could be the signature of gamma-ray absorption, either in the GRB or along the
line of sight due to the extragalactic background light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00685</id><created>2015-02-02</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wijtmans</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manning</keyname><forenames>M. Lisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Disentangling defects and sound modes in disordered solids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a new method to isolate localized defects from extended
vibrational modes in disordered solids. This method augments particle
interactions with an artificial potential that acts as a high-pass filter: it
preserves small-scale structures while pushing extended vibrational modes to
higher frequencies. The low-frequency modes that remain are &quot;bare&quot; defects;
they are exponentially localized without the quadrupolar tails associated with
elastic interactions. We demonstrate that these localized excitations are
excellent predictors of plastic rearrangements in the solid. We characterize
several of the properties of these defects that appear in mesoscopic theory of
plasticity, including their distribution of energy barriers, number density,
and size, which is a first step in testing and revising continuum models for
plasticity in disordered solids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01936</id><created>2015-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franke</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>$^4$He sample probe for combined microwave and dc transport measurements</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Meas. Sci. Technol. 26 (2015) 035502</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-0233/26/3/035502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combined microwave and dc electrical transport measurements at low
temperatures represent a valuable experimental method in many research areas.
In particular, when samples are conventional superconductors, a typical
experiment requires a combination of helium temperatures, a wide range of
magnetic fields, and the utilization of coaxial lines along with the usual dc
wiring. We report on the general design features and the microwave performance
of a custom-made low-temperature sample probe, with a measurement bandwidth
tested from dc to 20 GHz. Equipped with 6 coaxial cables, a heater, Hall and
temperature sensors, the probe fits into a d32 mm shaft. We present our setup,
analyze its microwave performance, and describe two representative experiments
enabled by this system. The proposed setup will be essential for a systematic
study of the dc and ac response of the vortex dynamics in nanopatterned
superconductors subject to combined dc and microwave stimuli. Besides, it will
be valuable for the investigation of a broad class of nonlinear stochastic
systems where a combination of dc and high-frequency ac driving in a wide
temperature range is necessary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01937</id><created>2015-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual cut-off dc-tunable microwave low-pass filter on superconducting Nb
  microstrips with asymmetric nanogrooves</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 106, 142601 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4917229</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a dual cut-off, dc-tunable low-pass microwave filter on a
superconducting Nb microstrip with uniaxial asymmetric nanogrooves. The
frequency response of the device was measured in the range $300$\,KHz to
$14$\,GHz at different temperatures, magnetic fields, and dc current values.
The microwave loss is most effectively reduced when the Abrikosov vortex
lattice spatially matches the underlying washboard pinning landscape. The
forward transmission coefficient $S_{21}(f)$ of the microstrip has a dc-tunable
cut-off frequency $f_d$ which notably changes under dc bias reversal, due to
the two different slope steepnesses of the pinning landscape. The device's
operation principle relies upon a crossover from the weakly dissipative
response of vortices at low frequencies when they are driven over the grooves,
to the strongly dissipative response at high frequencies when the vortices are
oscillating within one groove. The filter's cut-off frequency is the vortex
depinning frequency tunable by the dc bias as it diminishes the pinning effect
induced by the nanopattern. The reported results unveil an advanced microwave
functionality of superconducting films with asymmetric (ratchet) pinning
landscapes and are relevant for tuning the microwave loss in superconducting
planar transmission lines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01943</id><created>2015-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kompaniiets</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sachser</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porrati</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gspan</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plank</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable magnetism on the lateral mesoscale by post-processing of Co/Pt
  heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Beilstein J. Nanotechnol</comments><journal-ref>Beilstein J. Nanotechnol. 6 (2015) 1082</journal-ref><doi>10.3762/bjnano.6.109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Controlling magnetic properties on the nm-scale is essential for basic
research in micro-magnetism and spin-dependent transport, as well as for
various applications such as magnetic recording, imaging and sensing. This has
been accomplished to a very high degree by means of layered heterostructures in
the vertical dimension. Here we present a complementary approach that allows
for a controlled tuning of the magnetic properties of Co/Pt heterostructures on
the lateral mesoscale. By means of in-situ post-processing of Pt- and Co-based
nano-stripes prepared by focused electron beam induced deposition (FEBID) we
are able to locally tune their coercive field and remanent magnetization.
Whereas single Co-FEBID nano-stripes show no hysteresis, we find hard-magnetic
behavior for post-processed Co/Pt nano-stripes with coercive fields up to 850
Oe. We attribute the observed effects to the locally controlled formation of
the CoPt L1$_{0}$ phase, whose presence has been revealed by transmission
electron microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01945</id><created>2015-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Begun</keyname><forenames>Evgeniya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kompaniiets</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sachser</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gspan</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plank</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Post-growth purification of Co nanostructures prepared by focused
  electron beam induced deposition</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 26 (2015) 075301</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/26/7/075301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the majority of cases nanostructures prepared by focused electron beam
induced deposition (FEBID) employing an organometallic precursor contain
predominantly carbon-based ligand dissociation products. This is unfortunate
with regard to using this high-resolution direct-write approach for the
preparation of nanostructures for various fields, such as mesoscopic physics,
micromagnetism, electronic correlations, spin-dependent transport and numerous
applications. Here we present an in-situ cleaning approach to obtain pure
Co-FEBID nanostructures. The purification procedure lies in the exposure of
heated samples to a H$_2$ atmosphere in conjunction with the irradiation by
low-energy electrons. The key finding is that the combination of annealing at
$300^\circ$C, H$_2$ exposure and electron irradiation leads to compact, carbon-
and oxygen free Co layers down to a thickness of about 20\,nm starting from
as-deposited Co-FEBID structures. In addition to this, in temperature-dependent
electrical resistance measurements on post-processed samples we find a typical
metallic behavior. In low-temperature magneto-resistance and Hall effect
measurements we observe ferromagnetic behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06046</id><created>2015-04-23</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ching-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Runyao</forenames></author></authors><title>On the One-Shot Zero-Error Classical Capacity of Classical-Quantum
  Channels Assisted by Quantum Non-signalling Correlations</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quant. Inf. and Comp., vol.17, no. 5&amp;6, pp. 0380-0398, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Duan and Winter studied the one-shot zero-error classical capacity of a
quantum channel assisted by quantum non-signalling correlations, and formulated
this problem as a semidefinite program depending only on the Kraus operator
space of the channel. For the class of classical-quantum channels, they showed
that the asymptotic zero-error classical capacity assisted by quantum
non-signalling correlations, minimized over all classical-quantum channels with
a confusability graph $G$, is exactly $\log \vartheta(G)$, where $\vartheta(G)$
is the celebrated Lov\'{a}sz theta function. In this paper, we show that the
one-shot capacity for a classical-quantum channel, induced from a circulant
graph $G$ defined by equal-sized cyclotomic cosets, is $\log \lfloor
\vartheta(G) \rfloor$, which further implies that its asymptotic capacity is
$\log \vartheta(G)$. This type of graphs include the cycle graphs of odd
length, the Paley graphs of prime vertices, and the cubit residue graphs of
prime vertices. Examples of other graphs are also discussed. This endows the
Lov\'{a}sz $\theta$ function with a more straightforward operational meaning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01557</id><created>2015-05-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sokoloff</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khlystova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solar small-scale dynamo and polarity of sunspot groups</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, 2015, Volume
  451, Issue 2, p.1522-1527</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to clarify a possible role of small-scale dynamo in formation of
solar magnetic field, we suggest an observational test for small-scale dynamo
action based on statistics of anti-Hale sunspot groups. As we have shown,
according to theoretical expectations the small-scale dynamo action has to
provide a population of sunspot groups which do not follow the Hale polarity
law, and the density of such groups on the time-latitude diagram is expected to
be independent on the phase of the solar cycle. Correspondingly, a percentage
of the anti-Hale groups is expected to reach its maximum values during solar
minima. For several solar cycles, we considered statistics of anti-Hale groups
obtained by several scientific teams, including ours, to find that the
percentage of anti-Hale groups becomes indeed maximal during a solar minimum.
Our interpretation is that this fact may be explained by the small-scale dynamo
action inside the solar convective zone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01248</id><created>2015-10-05</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Repko</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kvasil</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesterenko</keyname><forenames>V. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinhard</keyname><forenames>P. -G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Skyrme RPA for spherical and axially symmetric nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, published version, see
  http://www.fu.sav.sk/fileadmin/user_upload/oddelenia/ojf/nph/events/ISTROS/2015/ISTROS_2015_Proceedings.pdf</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the ISTROS 2015 International Conference,
  Casta-Papiernicka, Slovakia, May 1-6, 2015, pages 41-50 (Bratislava 2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random Phase Approximation (RPA) is the basic method for calculation of
excited states of nuclei over the Hartree-Fock ground state, suitable also for
energy density functionals (EDF or DFT). We developed a convenient formalism
for expressing densities and currents in a form of reduced matrix elements,
which allows fast calculation of spectra for spherical nuclei. All terms of
Skyrme functional were taken into account, so it is possible to calculate
electric, magnetic and vortical/toroidal/compression transitions and strength
functions of any multipolarity. Time-odd (spin) terms in Skyrme functional
become important for magnetic M1 and isovector toroidal E1 transitions. It was
also found that transition currents in pygmy region (low-lying part of E1
resonance) exhibit isoscalar toroidal flow, so the previously assumed picture
of neutron-skin vibration is not the only mechanism present in pygmy
transitions.
  RPA calculations with heavy axially-symmetric nuclei now become feasible on
ordinary PC. Detailed formulae for axial Skyrme RPA are given. Some numerical
results are shown in comparison with the approximate approach of separable RPA,
previously developed in our group for fast calculation of strength functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02432</id><created>2015-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huth</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shklovskij</keyname><forenames>Valerij A.</forenames></author></authors><title>AC-driven microwave loss modulation in a fluxonic metamaterial</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 107 (2015) 162603</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4934487</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a fluxonic metamaterial on the basis of nanopatterned
superconducting Nb microstrips and employ it for modulation and synthesis of
quantized loss levels in the lower GHz range by a sine-wave quasistatic ac
drive. The nanopatterns are uniaxial nanogrooves with identical and different
slope steepness, which induce a pinning potential of the washboard type for
Abrikosov vortices. For the fundamental matching field, when the location of
vortex rows geometrically matches the nanogrooves, the following effects are
observed: The forward transmission coefficient $S_{21}(f)$ of the microstrips
can be controllably modulated within a range of about $3$\,dB by the ac
current. For the sample with symmetric grooves, depending on the choice of the
operation point in the current-voltage curve, the shape and the duty cycle of
the output signal can be tuned. For the sample with asymmetric grooves,
depending on the ac amplitude, a sine-to-triangular or a sine-to-rectangular
pulse shape conversion is observed. The possibility of synthesizing quantized
loss levels by a serial connection of the two samples with different
nanopatterns is exemplified and can be used for the development of multilevel
excess-loss-based fluxonic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02518</id><created>2015-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ilic</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Douspis</keyname><forenames>Marian</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray galaxy clusters abundance and mass temperature scaling</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 582, A79 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526793</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The abundance of clusters of galaxies is known to be a potential source of
cosmological constraints through their mass function. In the present work, we
examine the information that can be obtained from the temperature distribution
function of X-ray clusters. For this purpose, the mass-temperature ($M$-$T$)
relation and its statistical properties are critical ingredients. Using a
combination of cosmic microwave background (CMB) data from Planck and our
estimations of X-ray cluster abundances, we use Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC)
techniques to estimate the $\Lambda$CDM cosmological parameters and the mass to
X-ray temperature scaling relation simultaneously. We determine the integrated
X-ray temperature function of local clusters using flux-limited surveys. A
local comprehensive sample was build from the BAX X-ray cluster database,
allowing us to estimate the local temperature distribution function above
$\sim$1 keV. We model the expected temperature function from the mass function
and the $M$-$T$ scaling relation. We then estimate the cosmological parameters
and the parameters of the $M$-$T$ relation (calibration and slope)
simultaneously. The measured temperature function of local clusters in the
range $\sim\!\!1$-$10$ keV is well reproduced once the calibration of the
$M$-$T$ relation is treated as a free parameter, and therefore is
self-consistent with respect to the $\Lambda$CDM cosmology. The best-fit values
of the standard cosmological parameters as well as their uncertainties are
unchanged by the addition of clusters data. The calibration of the mass
temperature relation, as well as its slope, are determined with $\sim10\%$
statistical uncertainties. This calibration leads to masses that are
$\sim\!\!75\%$ larger than X-ray masses used in Planck.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06872</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06872</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Dobrovolskiy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Abrikosov fluxonics in washboard nanolandscapes</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Brief review on the basis of an invited lecture delivered at the 9th
  international conference in school format on Vortex Matter in Nanostructured
  Suprconductors (12-17 September 2015, Rhodes, Greece); 20 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica C 533 (2017) 80</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physc.2016.07.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Abrikosov fluxonics, a domain of science and engineering at the interface of
superconductivity research and nanotechnology, is concerned with the study of
properties and dynamics of Abrikosov vortices in nanopatterned superconductors,
with particular focus on their confinement, manipulation, and exploitation for
emerging functionalities. Vortex pinning, guided vortex motion, and the ratchet
effect are three main fluxonic ``tools'' which allow for the dynamical (pinned
or moving), the directional (angle-dependent), and the orientational (current
polarity-sensitive) control over the fluxons, respectively. Thanks to the
periodicity of the vortex lattice, several groups of effects emerge when the
vortices move in a periodic pinning landscape: Spatial commensurability of the
location of vortices with the underlying pinning nanolandscape leads to a
reduction of the dc resistance and the microwave loss at the so-called matching
fields. Temporal synchronization of the displacement of vortices with the
number of pinning sites visited during one half ac cycle manifests itself as
Shapiro steps in the current-voltage curves. Delocalization of vortices
oscillating under the action of a high-frequency ac drive can be tuned by a
superimposed dc bias. In this short review a choice of experimental results on
the vortex dynamics in the presence of periodic pinning in Nb thin films is
presented. The consideration is limited to one particular type of artificial
pinning structures --- directly written nanolandscapes of the washboard type,
which are fabricated by focused ion beam milling and focused electron beam
induced deposition. The reported results are relevant for the development of
fluxonic devices and the reduction of microwave losses in superconducting
planar transmission lines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02519</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coumbe</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum gravity without vacuum dispersion</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>Version published in International Journal of Modern Physics D. 13
  pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D, 0, 1750119 (2017) [22 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021827181750119X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generic prediction of quantum gravity is the vacuum dispersion of light,
and hence that a photon's speed depends on its energy. We present further
numerical evidence for a scale dependent speed of light in the causal dynamical
triangulation (CDT) approach to quantum gravity. We show that the observed
scale dependent speed of light in CDT can be accounted for by a scale dependent
transformation of geodesic distance, whose specific functional form implies a
discrete equidistant area spectrum. We make two non-trivial tests of the
proposed scale transformation: a comparison with the leading order quantum
correction to the gravitational potential and a comparison with the generalised
uncertainty principle. In both cases, we obtain the same functional form.
However, contrary to the widespread prediction of vacuum dispersion in quantum
gravity, numerous experiments have now definitively ruled out linear vacuum
dispersion beyond Planckian energy scales, and have now even constrained
quadratic dispersion. Motivated by these experimental constraints we seek to
reconcile quantum gravity with the absence of vacuum dispersion. We point out
that given a scale dependent geodesic distance, a scale dependent time interval
becomes essential to maintaining an invariant speed of light. We show how a
particular scale dependent time interval allows a photon's speed to remain
independent of its energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06849</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piegsa</keyname><forenames>Florian M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaestner</keyname><forenames>Anders P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antognini</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggenberger</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirch</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wichmann</keyname><forenames>Gunther</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Uncertainty in Quantitative Neutron Radiography</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Appl. Phys. (2017) 78: 10702</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjap/2017160336</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a novel procedure to calibrate neutron detection systems
commonly used in standard neutron radiography. This calibration allows
determining the uncertainties due to Poisson-like neutron counting statistics
for each individual pixel of a radiographic image. The obtained statistical
errors are necessary in order to perform a correct quantitative analysis. This
fast and convenient method is applied to data measured at the cold neutron
radiography facility ICON at the Paul Scherrer Institute. Moreover, from the
results the effective neutron flux at the beam line is determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08665</id><created>2016-03-29</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Zhiqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Dongfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Qing-yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalar and tensor perturbation in vacuum inflation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 105013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa6b9c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, it was proposed that a small true vacuum universe can inflate
spontaneously, in principle. Furthermore, there should be matter creation in
vacuum inflation due to quantum fluctuations, and the matter created will
influence the inflation simultaneously. In this paper, scalar and tensor
perturbations in this model are analyzed and confronted with recent
observations. These perturbations are derived and expressed with Hubble
flow-functions. By comparing our calculations with experimental results, we can
determine all the parameters in this model. Finally, with the determined
parameters, we compute the evolution of the matter density and show that the
matter produced in inflation roughly fits the observations at present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05306</id><created>2016-04-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zubair</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kousar</keyname><forenames>Farzana</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological reconstruction and energy bounds in $f(R,R_{\alpha
  \beta}R^{\alpha\beta},\phi)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>27 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76: 254</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4104-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the cosmological reconstruction of
$f(R,R_{\alpha\beta}R^{\alpha\beta},\phi)$ (where $R$,
$R_{\alpha\beta}R^{\alpha\beta}$ and $\phi$ represents the Ricci scalar, Ricci
invariant and scalar field) corresponding to power law and de Sitter evolution
in the framework of FRW universe model. We derive the energy conditions for
this modified theory which seem to be more general and can be reduced to some
known forms of these conditions in general relativity, $f(R)$ and $f(R,\phi)$
theories. We have presented the general constraints in terms of recent values
of snap, jerk, deceleration and Hubble parameters. The energy bounds are
analyzed for reconstructed as well as known models in this theory. Finally, the
free parameters are analyzed comprehensively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05742</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2017-01-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berglund</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Ges&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Hendrik</forenames></author></authors><title>An Eyring-Kramers law for the stochastic Allen-Cahn equation in
  dimension two</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>28 pages, 1 Figure. Revised version with expanded discussion</comments><msc-class>60H15, 35K57 (primary), 81S20, 82C28 (secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Electron. J. Probab. 22 (2017), no. 41, 27 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/17-EJP60</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study spectral Galerkin approximations of an Allen--Cahn equation over the
two-dimensional torus perturbed by weak space-time white noise of strength
$\sqrt{\varepsilon}$. We introduce a Wick renormalisation of the equation in
order to have a system that is well-defined as the regularisation is removed.
We show sharp upper and lower bounds on the transition times from a
neighbourhood of the stable configuration $-1$ to the stable configuration $1$
in the asymptotic regime $\varepsilon \to 0$. These estimates are uniform in
the discretisation parameter $N$, suggesting an Eyring-Kramers formula for the
limiting renormalised stochastic PDE. The effect of the &quot;infinite
renormalisation&quot; is to modify the prefactor and to replace the ratio of
determinants in the finite-dimensional Eyring-Kramers law by a renormalised
Carleman-Fredholm determinant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01351</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takita</keyname><forenames>Maika</forenames></author><author><keyname>C&#xf3;rcoles</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magesan</keyname><forenames>Easwar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdo</keyname><forenames>Baleegh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brink</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cross</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chow</keyname><forenames>Jerry M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gambetta</keyname><forenames>Jay M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Demonstration of weight-four parity measurements in the surface code
  architecture</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 210505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.210505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present parity measurements on a five-qubit lattice with connectivity
amenable to the surface code quantum error correction architecture. Using
all-microwave controls of superconducting qubits coupled via resonators, we
encode the parities of four data qubit states in either the $X$- or the
$Z$-basis. Given the connectivity of the lattice, we perform full
characterization of the static $Z$-interactions within the set of five qubits,
as well as dynamical $Z$-interactions brought along by single- and two-qubit
microwave drives. The parity measurements are significantly improved by
modifying the microwave two-qubit gates to dynamically remove non-ideal $Z$
errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02747</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2017-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fillion-Gourdeau</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacLean</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laflamme</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient state initialization by a quantum spectral filtering algorithm</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, revised version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042331 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042331</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An algorithm that initializes a quantum register to a state with a specified
energy range is given, corresponding to a quantum implementation of the
celebrated Feit-Fleck method. This is performed by introducing a
nondeterministic quantum implementation of a standard spectral filtering
procedure combined with an apodization technique, allowing for accurate state
initialization. It is shown that the implementation requires only two ancilla
qubits. A lower bound for the total probability of success of this algorithm is
derived, showing that this scheme can be realized using a finite, relatively
low number of trials. Assuming the time evolution can be performed efficiently
and using a trial state polynomially close to the desired states, it is
demonstrated that the number of operations required scales polynomially with
the number of qubits. Tradeoffs between accuracy and performance are
demonstrated in a simple example: the harmonic oscillator. This algorithm would
be useful for the initialization phase of the simulation of quantum systems on
digital quantum computers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07602</id><created>2016-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>Fergus J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ball</keyname><forenames>Caleb J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry-broken local-density approximation for one-dimensional systems</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, ,accepted for publication in Phys Rev B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 235114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.235114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within density-functional theory, the local-density approximation (LDA)
correlation functional is typically built by fitting the difference between the
near-exact and Hartree-Fock (HF) energies of the uniform electron gas (UEG),
together with analytic perturbative results from the high- and low-density
regimes. Near-exact energies are obtained by performing accurate diffusion
Monte Carlo calculations, while HF energies are usually assumed to be the Fermi
fluid HF energy. However, it has been known since the seminal work of
Overhauser that one can obtain lower, symmetry-broken (SB) HF energies at any
density. Here, we have computed the SBHF energies of the one-dimensional UEG
and constructed a SB version of the LDA (SBLDA) from the results. We compare
the performance of the LDA and SBLDA functionals when applied to
one-dimensional systems, including atoms and molecules. Generalization to
higher dimensions is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08456</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margetis</keyname><forenames>Dionisios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luskin</keyname><forenames>Mitchell</forenames></author></authors><title>Dipole excitation of surface plasmon on a conducting sheet: finite
  element approximation and validation</title><categories>math.NA math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>65N30, 78M10, 78M30, 78A45</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Comput. Phys. 339 (2017) 126-145</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2017.03.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate and validate a finite element approach to the propagation of a
slowly decaying electromagnetic wave, called surface plasmon-polariton, excited
along a conducting sheet, e.g., a single-layer graphene sheet, by an electric
Hertzian dipole. By using a suitably rescaled form of time-harmonic Maxwell's
equations, we derive a variational formulation that enables a direct numerical
treatment of the associated class of boundary value problems by appropriate
curl-conforming finite elements. The conducting sheet is modeled as an
idealized hypersurface with an effective electric conductivity. The requisite
weak discontinuity for the tangential magnetic field across the hypersurface
can be incorporated naturally into the variational formulation. We carry out
numerical simulations for an infinite sheet with constant isotropic
conductivity embedded in two spatial dimensions; and validate our numerics
against the closed-form exact solution obtained by the Fourier transform in the
tangential coordinate. Numerical aspects of our treatment such as an absorbing
perfectly matched layer, as well as local refinement and a-posteriori error
control are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03355</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blender</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badin</keyname><forenames>Gualtiero</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of Hamiltonian and Nambu forms for the shallow water
  equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP physics.ao-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A systematic method to derive the Hamiltonian and Nambu form for the shallow
water equations, using the conservation for energy and potential enstrophy, is
presented. Different mechanisms, such as vortical flows and emission of gravity
waves, emerge from different conservation laws (CLs) for total energy and
potential enstrophy. The equations are constructed using exterior differential
forms and self-adjoint operators and result in the sum of two Nambu brackets,
one for the vortical flow and one for the wave-mean flow interaction, and a
Poisson bracket representing the interaction between divergence and geostrophic
imbalance. The advantage of this approach is that the Hamiltonian and Nambu
forms can be here written in a coordinate independent form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09387</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Disertori</keyname><forenames>Margherita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lager</keyname><forenames>Mareike</forenames></author></authors><title>Density of States for Random Band Matrices in two dimensions</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages, 2 figures</comments><msc-class>82B44 (primary), 82B20 (secondary)</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s00023-017-0572-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a two dimensional random band matrix ensemble, in the limit of
infinite volume and fixed but large band width $W$. For this model we
rigorously prove smoothness of the averaged density of states. We also prove
that the resulting expression coincides with Wigner's semicircle law with a
precision $W^{-2+\delta },$ where $\delta\to 0$ when $W\to \infty.$ The proof
uses the supersymmetric approach and extends results by Disertori, Pinson and
Spencer from three to two dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01447</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>STAR Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Direct virtual photon production in Au+Au collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$
  = 200 GeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the direct virtual photon invariant yields in the transverse
momentum ranges $1\!&lt;\!p_{T}\!&lt;\!3$ GeV/$c$ and $5\!&lt;\!p_T\!&lt;\!10$ GeV/$c$ at
mid-rapidity derived from the dielectron invariant mass continuum region
$0.10&lt;M_{ee}&lt;0.28$ GeV/$c^{2}$ for 0-80\% minimum-bias Au+Au collisions at
$\sqrt{s_{NN}}=200$ GeV. A clear excess in the invariant yield compared to the
number-of-binary-collisions ($N_{bin}$) scaled $p+p$ reference is observed in
the $p_T$ range $1\!&lt;\!p_{T}\!&lt;\!3$ GeV/$c$. For $p_T\!&gt;6$ GeV/$c$ the
production follows $N_{bin}$ scaling. Model calculations with contributions
from thermal radiation and initial hard parton scattering are consistent within
uncertainties with the direct virtual photon invariant yield.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03072</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parnovski</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shterenberg</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbation theory for spectral gap edges of 2D periodic Schr\&quot;odinger
  operators</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>25 pages; several typos are fixed and comments are added; subsection
  3.2 is expanded to include more detailed proof of Theorem 3.9</comments><msc-class>35P20, 35J10, 47A55, 81Q10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a two-dimensional periodic Schr\&quot;odinger operator $H=-\Delta+W$
with $\Gamma$ being the lattice of periods. We investigate the structure of the
edges of open gaps in the spectrum of $H$. We show that under arbitrary small
perturbation $V$ periodic with respect to $N\Gamma$ where $N=N(W)$ is some
integer, all edges of the gaps in the spectrum of $H+V$ which are perturbation
of the gaps of $H$ become non-degenerate, i.e. are attained at finitely many
points by one band function only and have non-degenerate quadratic
minimum/maximum. We also discuss this problem in the discrete setting and show
that changing the lattice of periods may indeed be unavoidable to achieve the
non-degeneracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04242</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Nilanjana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pautrat</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouze</keyname><forenames>Cambyse</forenames></author></authors><title>Contractivity properties of a quantum diffusion semigroup</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>The results of this paper were presented at the &quot;48th Symposium on
  Mathematical Physics; Gorini-Kossakowski-Lindblad-Sudarshan Master Equation -
  40 Years After&quot;, held in Torun, Poland (June 10-12, 2016). v2: minor typos
  and proof of Theorem 7 corrected. v3, v4: minor typos corrected and overall
  presentation improved. v5: Published version. v6: metadata modified</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 58, 012205 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4974223</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a quantum generalization of the classical heat equation, and
study contractivity properties of its associated semigroup. We prove a Nash
inequality and a logarithmic Sobolev inequality. The former leads to an
ultracontractivity result. This in turn implies that the largest eigenvalue and
the purity of a state with positive Wigner function, evolving under the action
of the semigroup, decrease at least inverse polynomially in time, while its
entropy increases at least logarithmically in time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05405</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Pratik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Yogesh K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Virmani</keyname><forenames>Amitabh</forenames></author></authors><title>Hair on non-extremal D1-D5 bound states</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>24 pages, no figures; v2: footnotes added; v3: JHEP version; v4:
  results unchanged, app B removed, a footnote added, supersedes published
  version</comments><report-no>IP-BBSR-2016-7</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2016) 145</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)145</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a truncation of type IIB supergravity on four-torus where in
addition to the Ramond-Ramond 2-form field, the Ramond-Ramond axion (w) and the
NS-NS 2-form field (B) are also retained. In the (w, B) sector we construct a
linearised perturbation carrying only left moving momentum on two-charge
non-extremal D1-D5 geometries of Jejjala, Madden, Ross and Titchener. The
perturbation is found to be smooth everywhere and normalizable. It is
constructed by matching to leading order solutions of the perturbation
equations in the inner and outer regions of the geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03558</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hosseinpour</keyname><forenames>Mansoureh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>Fabiano M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Edilberto O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanabadi</keyname><forenames>Hassan</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering and bound states of Dirac Equation in presence of cosmic
  string for Hulth\'en potential</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures, v2: some parts of the text were rewritten,
  matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 77, 270 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4834-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the Dirac equation with vector and scalar potentials in
the spacetime generated by a cosmic string. Using an approximation for the
centrifugal term, a solution for the radial differential equation is obtained.
We consider the scattering states under the Hulth\'{e}n potential and obtain
the phase shifts. From the poles of the scattering $S$-matrix the states
energies are determined as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03581</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Rongting</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear quantitative photoacoustic tomography with two-photon
  absorption</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.NA physics.comp-ph</categories><msc-class>35R30, 49N45, 65M32, 74J25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-photon photoacoustic tomography (TP-PAT) is a non-invasive optical
molecular imaging modality that aims at inferring two-photon absorption
property of heterogeneous media from photoacoustic measurements. In this work,
we analyze an inverse problem in quantitative TP-PAT where we intend to
reconstruct optical coefficients in a semilinear elliptic PDE, the mathematical
model for the propagation of near infra-red photons in tissue-like optical
media with two-photon absorption, from the internal absorbed energy data. We
derive uniqueness and stability results on the reconstructions of single and
multiple optical coefficients, and present some numerical reconstruction
results based on synthetic data to complement the theoretical analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03736</id><created>2016-08-12</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bufetov</keyname><forenames>Alexander I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Yanqi</forenames></author></authors><title>Conditional measures of generalized Ginibre point processes</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>Accepted version in Journal of Functional Analysis</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The main result of this paper is that conditional measures of generalized
Ginibre point processes, with respect to the configuration in the complement of
a bounded open subset on $\mathbb{C}$, are orthogonal polynomial ensembles with
weights found explicitly. An especially simple formula for conditional measures
is obtained in the particular case of radially-symmetric determinantal point
processes, including the classical Ginibre point process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04370</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04370</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heinemann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klapp</keyname><forenames>Sabine H. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coarse-graining strategy for molecular pair interactions: A reaction
  coordinate study for two- and three-dimensional systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>29 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 164107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4981207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate and provide optimal sets of reaction coordinates for mixed
pairs of molecules displaying polar, uniaxial, or spherical symmetry in two and
three dimensions. These coordinates are non-redundant, i.e., they implicitly
involve the molecules' symmetries. By tabulating pair interactions in these
coordinates, resulting tables are thus minimal in length and require a minimal
memory space. The intended fields of application are computer simulations of
large ensembles of molecules or colloids with rather complex interactions in a
fluid or liquid crystalline phase at low densities. Using effective
interactions directly in the form of tables can help bridging the time and
length scales without introducing errors stemming from any modeling procedure.
Finally, we outline an exemplary computational methodology for gaining an
effective pair potential in these coordinates, based on the Boltzmann inversion
principle, by providing a step-by-step recipe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06504</id><created>2016-08-23</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marboe</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volin</keyname><forenames>Dmytro</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast analytic solver of rational Bethe equations</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures. v2: minor changes, added discussion in
  Mathematica notebook</comments><report-no>TCDMATH 16-11</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 204002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6b88</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we propose an approach for a fast analytic determination of all
possible eigenstates of rational GL(N|M) integrable spin chains of given not
too large length, in terms of Baxter Q-functions. We observe that all
exceptional solutions, if any, are automatically correctly accounted.
  The key intuition behind the approach is that the equations on the
Q-functions are determined solely by the Young diagram, and not by the choice
of the rank of the GL symmetry. Hence we can choose arbitrary N and M that
accommodate the desired representation. Then we consider all distinguished
Q-functions at once, not only those following a certain Kac-Dynkin path.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03911</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yanbao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lutkenhaus</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement verification with detection-efficiency mismatch</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042319 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042319</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The security analysis of quantum key distribution is difficult to perform
when there is efficiency mismatch between various threshold detectors involved
in an experimental setup. Even the verification that the device actually
performs in the quantum domain, referred to as the task of entanglement
verification, is hard to perform. In this article we provide such an
entanglement-verification method for characterized detection-efficiency
mismatch. Our method does not rely on a cut-off of photon numbers in the
optical signal. It can be applied independently of the degrees of freedom
involved, thus covering, for example, efficiency mismatch in polarization and
time-bin modes, but also in spatial modes. The evaluation of typical
experimental scenarios suggests that an increase of detection-efficiency
mismatch will drive the performance of a given setup out of the quantum domain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05288</id><created>2016-09-17</created><updated>2017-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harikumar</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuhair</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking radiation in the kappa-spacetime</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 1 figure, reference added</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 32 (2017) 1750072</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500725</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we analyze the Hawking radiation of a kappa-deformed
Schwarzchild black hole and obtain the deformed Hawking temperature. For this,
we first derive deformed metric for the kappa-spacetime, which in the generic
case, is not a symmetric tensor and also has a momentum dependence. We show
that the Schwarzchild metric obtained in the kappa-deformed spacetime has a
dependence on energy. We use the fact that the deformed metric is conformally
flat in the 1+1 dimensions, to solve the kappa-deformed Klein-Gordon equation
in the background of the Schwarzchild metric. The method of Boguliobov
coefficients is then used to calculate the thermal spectrum of
kappa-deformed-Schwarzchild black hole and show that the Hawking temperature is
modified by the non-commutativity of the kappa-spacetime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06672</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fanfarillo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovannetti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capone</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bascones</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nematicity at the Hund's metal crossover in iron superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>The title, the text and the figures have been modified with respect
  to the first version. 8 pages (6 pages + references), 3 pdf figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 144511 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.144511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theoretical understanding of the nematic state of iron-based
superconductors and especially of FeSe is still a puzzling problem. Although a
number of experiments calls for a prominent role of local correlations and
place iron superconductors at the entrance of a Hund metal state, the effect of
the electronic correlations on the nematic state has been theoretically poorly
investigated. In this work we study the nematic phase of iron superconductors
accounting for local correlations, including the effect of the Hund's coupling.
We show that Hund's physics strongly affects the nematic properties of the
system. It severely constraints the precise nature of the feasible
orbital-ordered state and induces a differentiation in the effective masses of
the zx=yz orbitals in the nematic phase. The latter effect leads to distinctive
signatures in different experimental probes, so far overlooked in the
interpretation of experiments. As notable examples the splittings between zx
and yz bands at Gamma and M points are modified, with important consequences
for ARPES measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07383</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07383</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Chandra</keyname><forenames>Hirak Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guang-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Anomalous Hall and Half-metallic Phases in Ferromagnetic (111)
  Bilayers of 4d and 5d Transition Metal Perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This is almost the completely rewritten preprint of arXiv: 1512.08843
  (2015) with significant new results as well as several new figures and one
  new table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134448 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134448</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extraordinary electronic phases can form in artificial oxide
heterostructures, which will provide a fertile ground for new physics and also
give rise to novel device functions. Based on a systematic first-principles
density functional theory study of the magnetic and electronic properties of
the (111) superlattices (ABO3)2/(AB'O3)10 of 4d and 5d transition metal
perovskite (B = Ru, Rh, Ag, Re, Os, Ir, Au; AB'O3 = LaAlO3, SrTiO3), we
demonstrate that due to quantum confinement, bilayers (LaBO3)2 (B = Ru, Re, Os)
and (SrBO3)2 (B = Rh, Os, Ir) are ferromagnetic with ordering temperatures up
to room temperature. In particular, bilayer (LaOsO3)2 is an exotic
spin-polarized quantum anomalous Hall insulator, while the other ferromagnetic
bilayers are metallic with large Hall conductances comparable to the
conductance quantum. Furthermore, bilayers (LaRuO3)2 and (SrRhO3)2 are
half-metallic, while bilayer (SrIrO3)2 exhibits peculiar colossal magnetic
anisotropy. Our findings thus show that 4d and 5d metal perovskite (111)
bilayers are a class of quasi-two-dimensional materials for exploring exotic
quantum phases and also for advanced applications such as low-power
nanoelectronics and oxide spintronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08185</id><created>2016-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasselov</keyname><forenames>Dimitar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podolak</keyname><forenames>Morris</forenames></author></authors><title>The Abundance of Atmospheric CO2 in Ocean Exoplanets: A Novel CO2
  Deposition Mechanism</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>114 pages, 55 figures, submitted to the astrophysical journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 838 Number 1, page 24, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa5cfe</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider super-Earth sized planets which have a water mass fraction that
is large enough to form an external mantle composed of high pressure water ice
polymorphs and that lack a substantial H/He atmosphere. We consider such
planets in their habitable zone so that their outermost condensed mantle is a
global deep liquid ocean. For these ocean planets we investigate potential
internal reservoirs of CO2; the amount of CO2 dissolved in the ocean for the
various saturation conditions encountered, and the ocean-atmosphere exchange
flux of CO2. We find that in steady state the abundance of CO2 in the
atmosphere has two possible states. When the wind-driven circulation is the
dominant CO2 exchange mechanism, an atmosphere of tens of bars of CO2 results,
where the exact value depends on the subtropical ocean surface temperature and
the deep ocean temperature. When sea-ice formation, acting on these planets as
a CO2 deposition mechanism, is the dominant exchange mechanism, an atmosphere
of a few bars of CO2 is established. The exact value depends on the subpolar
surface temperature. Our results suggest the possibility of a negative feedback
mechanism, unique to water planets, where a reduction in the subpolar
temperature drives more CO2 into the atmosphere to increase the greenhouse
effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08840</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stanghellini</keyname><forenames>Letizia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bucciarelli</keyname><forenames>Beatrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lattanzi</keyname><forenames>Mario G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morbidelli</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Tests of the Galactic planetary nebula distance scale with the initial
  Gaia parallax distances of their central stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>IAU Symposium 323, Planetary Nebulae: Multi-Wavelength Probes of
  Stellar and Galactic Evolution (in press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We used the &quot;primary dataset&quot; of Gaia Data Release 1 (DR1) to search for
parallax measurements of central stars (CSs) of Galactic planetary nebulae
(PNe), to determine PN distances. We found that a trigonometric parallax is
available for 16 CSs, seven of which with relative uncertainty below 80%. The
limited comparison of these trigonometric distances to other reliable
individual determinations discloses good correlation between the two sets, with
the Gaia parallax distances being lower by a factor of ~0.1 dex in the
logarithmic distances. We tested with the Gaia parallaxes the most popular
Galactic PN distance scales, namely, the physical radius vs. surface
brightness, and the ionized mass vs. inverse optical thickness scales. While
the number of available calibrators may still be too low, and their relative
uncertainties too high, to derive a working distance scale, we were able to
assess the current sample and to reveal the very promising potential of the
future Gaia releases for a recalibration of the distance scale of Galactic PNe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09779</id><created>2016-09-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Saumya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sunandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics and emergent universe</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages Latex</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A 32 (2017) 1750089</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317500894</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that in the isentropic scenario the first order thermodynamical
particle creation model gives an emergent universe solution even when the
chemical potential is non-zero. However there exists no emergent universe
scenario in the second order non-equilibrium theory for the particle creation
model. We then point out a correspondence between the particle creation model
with barotropic equation of state and the equation of state giving rise to an
emergent universe without particle creation in spatially flat FRW cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01072</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keshtgar</keyname><forenames>Hedyeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Streib</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamra</keyname><forenames>Akashdeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanter</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>Gerrit E. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetomechanical coupling and ferromagnetic resonance in magnetic
  nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134447 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134447</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the theory of the coupled lattice and magnetization dynamics of
freely suspended single-domain nanoparticles. Magnetic anisotropy generates
low-frequency satellite peaks in the microwave absorption spectrum and a
blueshift of the ferromagnetic resonance (FMR) frequency. The low-frequency
resonances are very sharp with maxima exceeding that of the FMR, because their
magnetic and mechanical precessions are locked, thereby suppressing Gilbert
damping. Magnetic nanoparticles can operate as nearly ideal motors that convert
electromagnetic into mechanical energy. The Barnett/Einstein-de Haas effect is
significant even in the absence of a net rotation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01917</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rains</keyname><forenames>Eric M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Affine Macdonald conjectures and special values of Felder-Varchenko
  functions</title><categories>math.RT math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>26 pages. v3: minor edits for published version</comments><msc-class>17B37 (primary), 17B67, 33C75, 33D80, 81R12 (secondary)</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s00029-017-0328-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We refine the statement of the denominator and evaluation conjectures for
affine Macdonald polynomials proposed by Etingof-Kirillov Jr. and prove the
first non-trivial cases of these conjectures. Our results provide a
q-deformation of the computation of genus 1 conformal blocks via elliptic
Selberg integrals by Felder-Stevens-Varchenko. They allow us to give precise
formulations for the affine Macdonald conjectures in the general case which are
consistent with computer computations.
  Our method applies recent work of the second named author to relate these
conjectures in the case of $U_q(\widehat{\mathfrak{sl}}_2)$ to evaluations of
certain theta hypergeometric integrals defined by Felder-Varchenko. We then
evaluate the resulting integrals, which may be of independent interest, by
well-chosen applications of the elliptic beta integral introduced by
Spiridonov.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04413</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Landsteiner</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on Anomaly Induced Transport</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.other</categories><comments>Based on lectures presented at 56. Cracow School on Theoretical
  Physics, May 24 - June 1 2016, Zakopane, Poland and the APCTP focus workshop
  on Holography and Topology of Quantum Matter, August 22 - August 29, 2016,
  Pohang, Korea, v2: typos corrected, references added, v3: some text
  improvements, typos corrected and references added, v4: improved LLL
  discussion</comments><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-16-103</report-no><doi>10.5506/APhysPolB.47.2617</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chiral anomalies give rise to dissipationless transport phenomena such as the
chiral magnetic and vortical effects. In these notes I review the theory from a
quantum field theoretic, hydrodynamic and holographic perspective. A physical
interpretation of the otherwise somewhat obscure concepts of consistent and
covariant anomalies will be given. Vanishing of the CME in strict equilibrium
will be connected to the boundary conditions in momentum space imposed by the
regularization. The role of the gravitational anomaly will be explained. That
it contributes to transport in an unexpectedly low order in the derivative
expansion can be easiest understood via holography. Anomalous transport is
supposed to play also a key role in understanding the electronics of advanced
materials, the Dirac- and Weyl (semi)metals. Anomaly related phenomena such as
negative magnetoresistivity, anomalous Hall effect, thermal anomalous Hall
effect and Fermi arcs can be understood via anomalous transport. Finally I
briefly review a holographic model of Weyl semimetal which allows to infer a
new phenomenon related to the gravitational anomaly: the presence of odd
viscosity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08978</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Siemens</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Elvira</keyname><forenames>J. Ruiz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Epelbaum</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoferichter</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krebs</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubis</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei&#xdf;ner</keyname><forenames>U. -G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reconciling threshold and subthreshold expansions for pion-nucleon
  scattering</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 tables, Mathematica notebook with the analytic
  expressions for threshold and subthreshold parameters included as
  supplementary material; journal version</comments><report-no>INT-PUB-16-035, NSF-KITP-16-158</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B770: 27-34, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.04.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heavy-baryon chiral perturbation theory (ChPT) at one loop fails in relating
the pion-nucleon amplitude in the physical region and for subthreshold
kinematics due to loop effects enhanced by large low-energy constants. Studying
the chiral convergence of threshold and subthreshold parameters up to fourth
order in the small-scale expansion, we address the question to what extent this
tension can be mitigated by including the $\Delta(1232)$ as an explicit degree
of freedom and/or using a covariant formulation of baryon ChPT. We find that
the inclusion of the $\Delta$ indeed reduces the low-energy constants to more
natural values and thereby improves consistency between threshold and
subthreshold kinematics. In addition, even in the $\Delta$-less theory the
resummation of $1/m_N$ corrections in the covariant scheme improves the results
markedly over the heavy-baryon formulation, in line with previous observations
in the single-baryon sector of ChPT that so far have evaded a profound
theoretical explanation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09367</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Rogers</keyname><forenames>Fergus J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Excited-State Wigner Crystals in One Dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 044114 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4974839</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wigner crystals (WC) are electronic phases peculiar to low-density systems,
particularly in the uniform electron gas. Since its introduction in the early
twentieth century, this model has remained essential to many aspects of
electronic structure theory and condensed-matter physics. Although the
(lowest-energy) ground-state WC (GSWC) has been thoroughly studied, the
properties of excited-state WCs (ESWCs) are basically unknown. To bridge this
gap, we present a well-defined procedure to obtain an entire family of ESWCs in
a one-dimensional electron gas using a symmetry-broken mean-field approach.
While the GSWC is a commensurate crystal (i.e.~the number of density maxima
equals the number of electrons), these ESWCs are incommensurate crystals
exhibiting more or less maxima. Interestingly, they are lower in energy than
the (uniform) Fermi fluid state. For some of these ESWCs we have found
asymmetrical band gaps, which would lead to anisotropic conductivity. These
properties are associated to unusual characteristics in their electronic
structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09098</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harland</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michel</keyname><forenames>Manon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampmann</keyname><forenames>Tobias A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kierfeld</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Event-chain Monte Carlo algorithms for three- and many-particle
  interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>EPL 117, 30001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/30001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We generalize the rejection-free event-chain Monte Carlo algorithm from many
particle systems with pairwise interactions to systems with arbitrary three- or
many-particle interactions. We introduce generalized lifting probabilities
between particles and obtain a general set of equations for lifting
probabilities, the solution of which guarantees maximal global balance. We
validate the resulting three-particle event-chain Monte Carlo algorithms on
three different systems by comparison with conventional local Monte Carlo
simulations: (i) a test system of three particles with a three-particle
interaction that depends on the enclosed triangle area; (ii) a hard-needle
system in two dimensions, where needle interactions constitute three-particle
interactions of the needle end points; (iii) a semiflexible polymer chain with
a bending energy, which constitutes a three-particle interaction of neighboring
chain beads. The examples demonstrate that the generalization to many-particle
interactions broadens the applicability of event-chain algorithms considerably.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01839</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Houston</keyname><forenames>Alexander J H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradhand</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>Mark R</forenames></author></authors><title>A random wave model for the Aharonov-Bohm effect</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J Phys A 50 205101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa660f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study an ensemble of random waves subject to the Aharonov-Bohm effect. The
introduction of a point with a magnetic flux of arbitrary strength into a
random wave ensemble gives a family of wavefunctions whose distribution of
vortices (complex zeros) are responsible for the topological phase associated
with the Aharonov-Bohm effect. Analytical expressions are found for the vortex
number and topological charge densities as functions of distance from the flux
point. Comparison is made with the distribution of vortices in the isotropic
random wave model. The results indicate that as the flux approaches
half-integer values, a vortex with the same sign as the fractional part of the
flux is attracted to the flux point, merging with it at half-integer flux.
Other features of the Aharonov-Bohm vortex distribution are also explored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02253</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02253</id><created>2016-12-07</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Claydon</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gieles</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zocchi</keyname><forenames>Alice</forenames></author></authors><title>The properties of energetically unbound stars in stellar clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 17 figures, MNRAS, updated to match final journal style</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. R. Astron. Soc. 466, 3937-3950 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several Milky Way star clusters show a roughly flat velocity dispersion
profile at large radii, which is not expected from models with a tidal cut-off
energy. Possible explanations for this excess velocity include: the effects of
a dark matter halo, modified gravity theories and energetically unbound stars
inside of clusters. These stars are known as potential escapers (PEs) and can
exist indefinitely within clusters which are on circular orbits. Through a
series of N-body simulations of star cluster systems, where we vary the
galactic potential, orbital eccentricity and stellar mass function, we
investigate the properties of the PEs and their effects on the kinematics. We
derive a prediction for the scaling of the velocity dispersion at the Jacobi
surface due to PEs, as a function of cluster mass, angular velocity of the
cluster orbit, and slope of the mass profile of the host galaxy. We see a
tentative signal of the mass and orbital velocity dependence in kinematic data
of globular clusters from literature. We also find that the fraction of PEs
depends sensitively on the galactic mass profile, reaching as high as 40% in
the cusp of a Navarro-Frenk-White profile and as the velocity anisotropy also
depends on the slope of the galactic mass profile, we conclude that PEs provide
an independent way of inferring the properties of the dark matter mass profile
at the galactic radius of (globular) clusters in the Gaia era.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02451</id><created>2016-11-15</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horsley</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Philbin</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Perfect Transmission through Disordered Media</title><categories>physics.class-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 163201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.163201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transmission of a wave through a randomly chosen `pile of plates'
typically decreases exponentially with the number of plates, a phenomenon
closely related to Anderson localisation. In apparent contradiction we
construct disordered planar permittivity profiles which are complex-valued
(i.e. have reactive and dissipative properties) that appear to vary randomly
with position, yet are one-way reflectionless for all angles of incidence and
exhibit a transmission coefficient of unity. We contrast these complex-valued
'random' planar permittivity profiles with a family of real-valued, two-way
reflectionless and perfectly transmitting disordered permittivity profiles that
function only for a single angle of incidence and frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03740</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nava</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuliano</keyname><forenames>Rosa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campagnano</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuliano</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author></authors><title>Persistent current and zero-energy Majorana modes in a p-wave disordered
  superconducting ring</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>22 pages, 12 .eps figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 155449 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the emergence of zero-energy Majorana modes in a disordered
finite-length p-wave one-dimensional superconducting ring, pierced by a
magnetic flux $\Phi$ tuned at an appropriate value $\Phi=\Phi_*$. In the
absence of fermion parity conservation, we evidence the emergence of the
Majorana modes by looking at the discontinuities in the persistent current
$I[\Phi]$ at $\Phi=\Phi_*$. By monitoring the discontinuities in $I[\Phi]$, we
map out the region in parameter space characterized by the emergence of
Majorana modes in the disordered ring.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05421</id><created>2016-12-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Balz</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lake</keyname><forenames>Bella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reehuis</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>A. T. M. Nazmul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Yogesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokhnenko</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pattison</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toth</keyname><forenames>Sandor</forenames></author></authors><title>Crystal growth, structure and magnetic properties of Ca10Cr7O28</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29 (2017) 225802 (10pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa68eb</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed diffraction study of Ca10Cr7O28 is presented which adds
significant new insights into the structural and magnetic properties of this
compound. A new crystal structure type was used where the a and b axes are
doubled compared to previous models providing a more plausible structure where
all crystallographic sites are fully occupied. The presence of two different
valences of chromium was verified and the locations of the magnetic Cr5+ and
non-magnetic Cr6+ ions were identified. The Cr5+ ions have spin-1/2 and form
distorted kagome bilayers which are stacked in an ABC arrangement along the c
axis. These results lay the foundation for understanding of the quantum spin
liquid behavior in Ca10Cr7O28 which has recently been reported in [C. Balz et
al., Nature Physics, 12, 942 (2016)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06022</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2017-02-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchange functionals based on finite uniform electron gases</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 figures and 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 146, 114108 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4978409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how one can construct \alert{a simple} exchange functional by
extending the well-know local-density approximation (LDA) to finite uniform
electron gases. This new generalized local-density approximation (GLDA)
functional uses only two quantities: the electron density $\rho$ and the
curvature of the Fermi hole $\alpha$. This alternative &quot;rung 2&quot; functional can
be easily coupled with generalized-gradient approximation (GGA) functionals to
form a new family of &quot;rung 3&quot; meta-GGA (MGGA) functionals that we have named
factorizable MGGAs (FMGGAs). Comparisons are made with various LDA, GGA and
MGGA functionals for atoms and molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06824</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Miguel A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>Mark R</forenames></author></authors><title>A ray-optical Poincar\'e sphere for structured Gaussian beams</title><categories>physics.optics math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Main article 12 pages 10 figures; supplementary material (appendices)
  7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optica 4 pp476-86 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000476</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general family of structured Gaussian beams naturally emerges from a
consideration of families of rays. These ray families, with the property that
their transverse profile is invariant upon propagation (except for cycling of
the rays and a global rescaling), have two parameters, the first giving a
position on an ellipse naturally represented by a point on the Poincar\'e
sphere (familiar from polarization optics), and the other determining the
position of a curve traced out on this Poincar\'e sphere. This construction
naturally accounts for the familiar families of Gaussian beams, including
Hermite-Gauss, Laguerre-Gauss and Generalized Hermite-Laguerre-Gauss beams, but
is far more general. The conformal mapping between a projection of the
Poincar\'e sphere and the physical space of the transverse plane of a Gaussian
beam naturally involves caustics. In addition to providing new insight into the
physics of propagating Gaussian beams, the ray-based approach allows effective
approximation of the propagating amplitude without explicit diffraction
calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07401</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cang</keyname><forenames>Ruijin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yaopengxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shaohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yongming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Max Yi</forenames></author></authors><title>Microstructure Representation and Reconstruction of Heterogeneous
  Materials via Deep Belief Network for Computational Material Design</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cs.LG stat.ML</categories><comments>27 pages, 17 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Integrated Computational Materials Engineering (ICME) aims to accelerate
optimal design of complex material systems by integrating material science and
design automation. For tractable ICME, it is required that (1) a structural
feature space be identified to allow reconstruction of new designs, and (2) the
reconstruction process be property-preserving. The majority of existing
structural presentation schemes rely on the designer's understanding of
specific material systems to identify geometric and statistical features, which
could be biased and insufficient for reconstructing physically meaningful
microstructures of complex material systems. In this paper, we develop a
feature learning mechanism based on convolutional deep belief network to
automate a two-way conversion between microstructures and their
lower-dimensional feature representations, and to achieves a 1000-fold
dimension reduction from the microstructure space. The proposed model is
applied to a wide spectrum of heterogeneous material systems with distinct
microstructural features including Ti-6Al-4V alloy, Pb63-Sn37 alloy,
Fontainebleau sandstone, and Spherical colloids, to produce material
reconstructions that are close to the original samples with respect to 2-point
correlation functions and mean critical fracture strength. This capability is
not achieved by existing synthesis methods that rely on the Markovian
assumption of material microstructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07499</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abhinav</keyname><forenames>Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guha</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-Integrability of The KdV System</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>22 pages, extended results</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quasi-integrable KdV equation has been obtained from the corresponding
deformation of the Hamiltonian for the usual KdV system. Following suitable
gauge-fixing, it has been found that the quasi-conservation condition is
satisfied and an infinite number of anomalous conservation laws are obtained,
with some containing possible conserved charges. Judicious choice of
deformation of the Hamiltonian clearly leads to a conserved charge, manifesting
quasi-integrability, but also creates a hierarchy of higher-derivative
equations with at least one conserved charge. A particular quasi-deformation
parameterization of the Hamiltonian is found to complement the same of the NLS
system, following an approximate equivalence of the two systems obtained
earlier, in the weak coupling limit. Single-soliton solutions for all these
cases are obtained, with manifest scaling due to the quasi-integrable
deformation. Finally, quasi-conservation formulation for the complex coupled
generalized KdV system is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02391</id><created>2017-01-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ball</keyname><forenames>Caleb J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gill</keyname><forenames>P. M. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular electronic structure in one-dimensional Coulomb systems</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 8 figures, 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 19, 3987 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP06801D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following two recent papers [Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys. 2015, \textbf{17}, 3196;
Mol. Phys. 2015, \textbf{113}, 1843], we perform a larger-scale study of
chemical structure in one dimension (1D). We identify a wide, and occasionally
surprising, variety of stable 1D compounds (from diatomics to tetra-atomics) as
well as a small collection of stable polymeric structures. We define the
exclusion potential, a 1D analogue of the electrostatic potential, and show
that it can be used to rationalise the nature of bonding within molecules. This
allows us to construct a small set of simple rules which can predict whether a
putative 1D molecule should be stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04327</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Ryuhei</forenames></author></authors><title>Better Protocol for XOR Game using Communication Protocol and Nonlocal
  Boxes</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages + the title page</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Buhrman showed that an efficient communication protocol implies a reliable
XOR game protocol. This idea rederives Linial and Shraibman's lower bounds of
communication complexity, which was derived by using factorization norms, with
worse constant factor in much more intuitive way. In this work, we improve and
generalize Buhrman's idea, and obtain a class of lower bounds for classical
communication complexity including an exact Linial and Shraibman's lower bound
as a special case. In the proof, we explicitly construct a protocol for XOR
game from a classical communication protocol by using a concept of nonlocal
boxes and Paw{\l}owski et al.'s elegant protocol, which was used for showing
the violation of information causality in superquantum theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04554</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Bhagya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naesby</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dantan</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author></authors><title>Optomechanical characterization of silicon nitride membrane arrays</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 42, 1341 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.42.001341</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the optical and mechanical characterization of arrays of
parallel micromechanical membranes. Pairs of high-tensile stress, 100 nm-thick
silicon nitride membranes are assembled parallel with each other with
separations ranging from 8.5 to 200 $\mu$m. Their optical properties are
accurately determined using a combination of broadband and monochromatic
illuminations and the lowest vibrational mode frequencies and mechanical
quality factors are determined interferometrically. The results and techniques
demonstrated are promising for investigations of collective phenomena in
optomechanical arrays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05373</id><created>2017-01-19</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Genes</keyname><forenames>Claudiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dantan</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-matter interactions in multi-element resonators</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. B 50, 105502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa6a74</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate structural resonances in multi-element optical resonators and
provide a roadmap for the description of the interaction of single extended
cavity modes with quantum emitters or mechanical resonators. Using a first
principle approach based on the transfer matrix formalism we analyze, both
numerically and analytically, the static and dynamical properties of three- and
four-mirror cavities. We investigate in particular conditions under which the
confinement of the field in specific subcavities allows for enhanced
light-matter interactions in the context of cavity quantum electrodynamics and
cavity optomechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01849</id><created>2017-02-06</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Kazufumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motohashi</keyname><forenames>Hayato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suyama</keyname><forenames>Teruaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Tsutomu</forenames></author></authors><title>General invertible transformation and physical degrees of freedom</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th physics.class-ph</categories><comments>14 pages; matches published version</comments><report-no>RESCEU-1/17, RUP-17-2</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 084053 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.084053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An invertible field transformation is such that the old field variables
correspond one-to-one to the new variables. As such, one may think that two
systems that are related by an invertible transformation are physically
equivalent. However, if the transformation depends on field derivatives, the
equivalence between the two systems is nontrivial due to the appearance of
higher derivative terms in the equations of motion. To address this problem, we
prove the following theorem on the relation between an invertible
transformation and Euler-Lagrange equations: If the field transformation is
invertible, then any solution of the original set of Euler-Lagrange equations
is mapped to a solution of the new set of Euler-Lagrange equations, and vice
versa. We also present applications of the theorem to scalar-tensor theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02703</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faber</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozovic</keyname><forenames>Dolores</forenames></author></authors><title>Chaotic Dynamics of Inner Ear Hair Cells</title><categories>physics.bio-ph nlin.CD q-bio.NC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental records of active bundle motility are used to demonstrate the
presence of a low-dimensional chaotic attractor in hair cell dynamics.
Dimensionality tests from dynamic systems theory are applied to estimate the
number of independent variables sufficient for modeling the hair cell response.
Poincare maps are constructed to observe a quasiperiodic transition from chaos
to order with increasing amplitudes of mechanical forcing. The onset of this
transition is accompanied by a reduction of Kolmogorov entropy in the system
and an increase in mutual information between the stimulus and the hair bundle,
indicative of signal detection. A simple theoretical model is used to describe
the observed chaotic dynamics. The model exhibits an enhancement of sensitivity
to weak stimuli when the system is poised in the chaotic regime. We propose
that chaos may play a role in the hair cell's ability to detect low-amplitude
sounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03940</id><created>2017-02-13</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Difu</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Baojiu</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jiaxin</forenames><affiliation>Kavli, U Tokyo and ICC, Durham</affiliation></author></authors><title>Environmental screening of dark matter haloes in $f(R)$ gravity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables. Published in MNRAS after minor
  correction</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx865</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In certain theories of modified gravity, solar system constraints on
deviations from general relativity (GR) are satisfied by virtue of a so-called
screening mechanism, which enables the theory to revert to GR in regions where
the matter density is high or the gravitational potential is deep. In the case
of chameleon theories, the screening has two contributions -- self-screening,
which is due to the mass of an object itself, and environmental screening,
which is caused by the surrounding matter -- which are often entangled, with
the second contribution being more crucial for less massive objects. A
quantitative understanding of the effect of the environment on the screening
can prove critical in observational tests of such theories using systems such
as the Local Group and dwarf galaxies, for which the environment may be
inferred in various ways. We use the high-resolution {\sc liminality}
simulation of Shi et al. (2015) to test the fidelity of different definitions
of environment. We find that, although the different ways to define environment
in practice do not agree with one another perfectly, they can provide useful
guidance, and cross checks about how well a dark matter halo is screened. In
addition, the screening of subhaloes in dark matter haloes is primarily
determined by the environment, with the subhalo mass playing a minor role,
which means that lower-resolution simulations where subhaloes are not well
resolved can still be useful for understanding the modification of gravity
inside subhaloes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05132</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carollo</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carini</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyler</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gould</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stwalley</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Resolution Spectroscopy of {R}ydberg Molecular States of
  $^{85}${R}b$_2$ Near the $5s+7p$ Asymptote</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 042516 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.042516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rydberg molecules, often exemplified by long-range &quot;trilobite&quot; molecules, are
a subject of much recent interest at high principal quantum number $n$. States
that use the same bonding mechanism can exist at much lower $n$ and
less-extreme internuclear separations that are still quite long range. We use a
high-resolution pulsed amplifier to study previously-detected transitions to a
low-$n$ Rydberg molecular state near the $5s+7p$ asymptote in $^{85}$Rb$_2$.
The observed line structure is modeled using precise ground-state positions and
a lower bound of $\tau &gt; 1.1 \times 10^{-9}$ s is set on the excited-state
autoionization lifetime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05559</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-03-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jounghun</forenames><affiliation>Seoul National University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Independent Measurements of the Dynamical Masses of Six Galaxy Clusters
  in the Local Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>accepted for publication in ApJ, revised version, minor changes, 10
  figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 839 (2017) 29</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6895</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present independent measurements of the masses of the galaxy clusters in
the local universe by employing the Dynamical Mass Estimator (DME) originally
developed by Falco et al in 2014. In the catalog of the galaxy groups/clusters
constructed by Tempel et al. from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 10,
we search for those as the targets around which the neighbor galaxies
constitute thin straight filamentary structures in the configuration space
spanned by the redshifts and the projected distances. Out of the $29$ Sloan
clusters that have $100$ or more member galaxies, a total of six targets are
found to have filamentary structures in their bound zones. For each of the six
targets, we construct the profile of the recession velocities of the filament
galaxies, which depends on the cluster mass and the angle of the filament
relative the line of the sight direction. Fitting the constructed profile to
the universal formula with constant amplitude and slope, we statistically
determine the dynamical mass of each cluster and compare it with the previous
estimates made by a conventional method. The weak and strong points of the DME
as well as its prospect for the measurements of the dynamical masses of the
high-$z$ clusters are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00138</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Su</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Xiaoling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Fulde-Ferrell states in alkaline-earth-metal-like atoms near
  an orbital Feshbach resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 043634 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.043634</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of synthetic spin-orbit coupling on the pairing physics
in quasi-one-dimensional ultracold Fermi gases of alkaline-earth-metal-like
atoms near an orbital Feshbach resonance (OFR). The interplay between
spin-orbit coupling and pairing interactions near the OFR leads to an
interesting topological Fulde-Ferrell state, where the nontrivial topology of
the state is solely encoded in the closed channel with a topologically trivial
Fulde-Ferrell pairing in the open channel. We confirm the topological property
of the system by characterizing the Zak phase and the edge states. The
topological Fulde-Ferrell state can be identified by the momentum-space density
distribution obtained from time-of-flight images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01359</id><created>2017-03-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Jo</keyname><forenames>Na Hyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaluarachchi</keyname><forenames>Udhara S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masters</keyname><forenames>Morgan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neilson</keyname><forenames>Kathryn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Downing</keyname><forenames>Savannah S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canfield</keyname><forenames>Paul C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bud'ko</keyname><forenames>Sergey L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure induced change in the electronic state of Ta$_4$Pd$_3$Te$_{16}$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 134516 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of superconducting transition temperature,
resistivity, magnetoresistivity and temperature dependence of the upper
critical field of Ta$_4$Pd$_3$Te$_{16}$ under pressures up to 16.4 kbar. All
measured properties have an anomaly at $\sim 2 - 4$ kbar pressure range, in
particular there is a maximum in $T_c$ and upper critical field, $H_{c2}(0)$,
and minimum in low temperature, normal state resistivity. Qualitatively, the
data can be explained considering the density of state at the Fermi level as a
dominant parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04581</id><created>2017-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Giunti</keyname><forenames>Barbara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perri</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical systems on graphs through the signless Laplacian matrix</title><categories>math.CO physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures, 1 table</comments><doi>10.1007/s11587-017-0326-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is a deep and interesting connection between the topological properties
of a graph and the behaviour of the dynamical system defined on it. We analyse
various kind of graphs, with different contrasting connectivity or degree
characteristics, using the signless Laplacian matrix. We expose the theoretical
results about the eigenvalue of the matrix and how they are related to the
dynamical system. Then, we perform numerical computations on real-like graphs
and observe the resulting system. Comparing the theoretical and numerical
results we found a perfect consistency. Furthermore, we define a metric which
takes in account the &quot;rigidity&quot; of the graph and enables us to relate all
together the topological properties of the graph, the signless Laplacian matrix
and the dynamical system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00400</id><created>2017-04-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenyon</keyname><forenames>Scott J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Podolak</keyname><forenames>Morris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prialnik</keyname><forenames>Dina</forenames></author></authors><title>H-Atmospheres of Icy Super-Earths Formed in situ in the Outer Solar
  System: An Application to a Possible Planet Nine</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>32 pages, 11 figures, accepted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 839 Number 2, page 111, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6ba6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the possibility that icy super-Earth mass planets, formed over
long time scales (0.1--1~Gyr) at large distances ($\sim$ 200--1000~AU) from
their host stars, will develop massive H-rich atmospheres. Within the interior
of these planets, high pressure converts CH$_4$ into ethane, butane, or diamond
and releases H$_2$. Using simplified models which capture the basic physics of
the internal structure, we show that the physical properties of the atmosphere
depend on the outflux of H$_2$ from the mantle. When this outflux is $\lesssim
10^{10}$ [molec cm$^{-2}$ s$^{-1}$], the outgassed atmosphere has base pressure
$\lesssim$ 1 bar. Larger outflows result in a substantial atmosphere where the
base pressure may approach $10^3 - 10^4$ bar. For any pressure, the mean
density of these planets, 2.4--3 [g cm$^{-3}$], is much larger than the mean
density of Uranus and Neptune, 1.3--1.6 [g cm$^{-3}$]. Thus, observations can
distinguish between a Planet Nine with a primordial H/He-rich atmosphere
accreted from the protosolar nebula and one with an atmosphere outgassed from
the core.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01263</id><created>2017-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yonemitsu</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Frequency Analysis of Effective Interactions and Bandwidth for
  Transient States after Monocycle Pulse Excitation of Extended Hubbard Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 064702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.064702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a high-frequency expansion in periodically driven extended Hubbard
models, where the strengths and ranges of density-density interactions are
arbitrary, we obtain the effective interactions and bandwidth, which depend
sensitively on the polarization of the driving field. Then, we numerically
calculate modulations of correlation functions in a quarter-filled extended
Hubbard model with nearest-neighbor interactions on a triangular lattice with
trimers after monocycle pulse excitation. We discuss how the resultant
modulations are compatible with the effective interactions and bandwidth
derived above on the basis of their dependence on the polarization of
photoexcitation, which is easily accessible by experiments. Some correlation
functions after monocycle pulse excitation are consistent with the effective
interactions, which are weaker or stronger than the original ones. However, the
photoinduced enhancement of anisotropic charge correlations previously
discussed for the three-quarter-filled organic conductor
$\alpha$-(bis[ethylenedithio]-tetrathiafulvalene)$_2$I$_3$
[$\alpha$-(BEDT-TTF)$_2$I$_3$] in the metallic phase is not fully explained by
the effective interactions or bandwidth, which are derived independently of the
filling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01970</id><created>2017-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Factor</keyname><forenames>Samuel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaherty</keyname><forenames>Kevin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Rita K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Francesco</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Jonathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>Brenda C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bally</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>Doug</forenames></author></authors><title>ALMA Observations of Asymmetric Molecular Gas Emission from a
  Protoplanetary Disk in the Orion Nebula</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 12 figures, accepted for publication in AJ</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/aa6c2c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) observations
of molecular line emission from d216-0939, one of the largest and most massive
protoplanetary disks in the Orion Nebula Cluster (ONC). We model the spectrally
resolved HCO$^+$ (4--3), CO (3--2), and HCN (4--3) lines observed at 0\farcs5
resolution to fit the temperature and density structure of the disk. We also
weakly detect and spectrally resolve the CS (7--6) line but do not model it.
The abundances we derive for CO and HCO$^+$ are generally consistent with
expected values from chemical modeling of protoplanetary disks, while the HCN
abundance is higher than expected. We dynamically measure the mass of the
central star to be $2.17\pm0.07\,M_\odot$ which is inconsistent with the
previously determined spectral type of K5. We also report the detection of a
spatially unresolved high-velocity blue-shifted excess emission feature with a
measurable positional offset from the central star, consistent with a Keplerian
orbit at $60\pm20\,\mathrm{au}$. Using the integrated flux of the feature in
HCO$^+$ (4--3), we estimate the total H$_2$ gas mass of this feature to be at
least $1.8-8\,M_\mathrm{Jupiter}$, depending on the assumed temperature. The
feature is due to a local temperature and/or density enhancement consistent
with either a hydrodynamic vortex or the expected signature of the envelope of
a forming protoplanet within the disk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02482</id><created>2017-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Khlystova</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toriumi</keyname><forenames>Shin</forenames></author></authors><title>Photospheric Velocity Structures during the Emergence of Small Active
  Regions on the Sun</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures, 3 table, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 2017, Volume 839, Issue 1, article id.
  63, 12 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa688f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the plasma flows in the solar photosphere during the emergence of
two small active regions, NOAA 9021 and 10768. Using SOHO/MDI data, we find
that the strong plasma upflows appear at the initial stage of active region
formation, with maximum upflow velocities of -1650 and -1320 m/s. The
structures with enhanced upflows have size about 8 Mm in diameter, and they
exist for 1-2 hr. The parameters of the enhanced upflows are consistent with
those of the large active region NOAA 10488, which may suggest the possibility
that the elementary emerging magnetic loops that appear at the earliest phase
of active region formation have similar properties, irrespective of scales of
active regions. Comparison between the observations and a numerical simulation
of magnetic flux emergence shows a striking consistency. We find that the
driving force of the plasma upflow is at first the gas pressure gradient and
later the magnetic pressure gradient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06670</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Status of the SuperNEMO 0$\nu\beta\beta$ experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Poster presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 4
  pages, LaTeX, 8 png figures</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Patrick</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SuperNEMO is an ultra-low-background tracker-calorimeter experiment designed
to look for the neutrinoless double-beta decay of various isotopes. We present
the current state of the experiment's Demonstrator Module, which is currently
being installed and and commissioned in the LSM in France.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08043</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ciuffoli</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Methods for the Neutrino Mass Hierarchy</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages,
  LaTeX, 8 figures. v2: Refs added</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Ciuffoli</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the next decade several experiments will attempt to determine the neutrino
mass hierarchy, i.e. the sign of $\Delta m_{31}^2$. In the last years it was
noticed that the two hierarchies are disjoint hypotheses and, for this reason,
Wilks' theorem cannot be applied: this means that
$\Delta\chi^2=\chi^2_{IH}-\chi^2_{NH}$ does not follow a one-degree-of-freedom
chi-square distribution. It was proven that, under certain assumptions, it
follows instead a Gaussian distribution with $\sigma=2\sqrt{\mu}$. I will
present several possible definition of sensitivity and review the approaches
proposed in the literature, both within the Bayesian and the frequentist
framework, examining advantages and disadvantages and discussing how they
should be modified if the conditions for Gaussianity are not fulfilled. I will
also discuss the possibility of introducing a new pull parameter in order to
avoid the issue related to the non-nested hypotheses and the differences
between marginalization and minimization, showing under which conditions the
two procedures yield the same $\Delta\chi^2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08169</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Quntao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zheshen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noisy entanglement-assisted classical capacity as a security framework
  for two-way quantum key distribution protocols</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures, typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the noisy entanglement-assisted classical capacity formula
[arXiv:1609.08592] to create a coherent-attack security framework for Gaussian
two-way quantum key distribution protocols in the asymptotic region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08182</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-04-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belovs</keyname><forenames>Aleksandrs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brassard</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoyer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaplan</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laplante</keyname><forenames>Sophie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvail</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>Provably secure key establishment against quantum adversaries</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, no figures, fixes a problem with arXiv:1108.2316v2. Will
  appear in the Proceedings of the 12th Conference on Theory of Quantum
  Computation, Communication and Cryptography (TQC), Paris, June 2017. The only
  change in v2 is that there was a problem with the affiliations in v1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At Crypto 2011, some of us had proposed a family of cryptographic protocols
for key establishment capable of protecting quantum and classical legitimate
parties unconditionally against a quantum eavesdropper in the query complexity
model. Unfortunately, our security proofs were unsatisfactory from a
cryptographically meaningful perspective because they were sound only in a
worst-case scenario. Here, we extend our results and prove that for any e &gt; 0,
there is a classical protocol that allows the legitimate parties to establish a
common key after O(N) expected queries to a random oracle, yet any quantum
eavesdropper will have a vanishing probability of learning their key after
O(N^{1.5-e}) queries to the same oracle. The vanishing probability applies to a
typical run of the protocol. If we allow the legitimate parties to use a
quantum computer as well, their advantage over the quantum eavesdropper becomes
arbitrarily close to the quadratic advantage that classical legitimate parties
enjoyed over classical eavesdroppers in the seminal 1974 work of Ralph Merkle.
Along the way, we develop new tools to give lower bounds on the number of
quantum queries required to distinguish two probability distributions. This
method in itself could have multiple applications in cryptography. We use it
here to study average-case quantum query complexity, for which we develop a new
composition theorem of independent interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08681</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08681</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Moschidis</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author></authors><title>A proof of the instability of AdS for the Einstein--null dust system
  with an inner mirror</title><categories>gr-qc math.AP</categories><comments>78 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2006, Dafermos and Holzegel formulated the so-called AdS instability
conjecture, stating that there exist arbitrarily small perturbations to AdS
initial data which, under evolution by the Einstein vacuum equations for
$\Lambda&lt;0$ with reflecting boundary conditions on conformal infinity, lead to
the formation of black holes. The numerical study of this conjecture in the
simpler setting of the spherically symmetric Einstein--scalar field system was
initiated by Bizon and Rostworowski, followed by a vast number of numerical and
heuristic works by several authors.
  In this paper, we provide the first rigorous proof of the AdS instability
conjecture in the simplest possible setting, namely for the spherically
symmetric Einstein--massless Vlasov system, in the case when the Vlasov field
is moreover supported only on radial geodesics. This system is equivalent to
the Einstein--null dust system, allowing for both ingoing and outgoing dust. In
order to overcome the break down of this system occuring once the null dust
reaches the centre $r=0$, we place an inner mirror at $r=r_{0}&gt;0$ and study the
evolution of this system on the exterior domain $\{r\ge r_{0}\}$. The structure
of the maximal development and the Cauchy stability properties of general
initial data in this setting are studied in our companion paper.
  The statement of the main theorem is as follows: We construct a family of
mirror radii $r_{0\epsilon}&gt;0$ and initial data $\mathcal{S}_{\epsilon}$,
$\epsilon\in(0,1]$, converging to the AdS initial data in a suitable norm, such
that, for any $\epsilon&gt;0$, the maximal development
$(\mathcal{M}_{\epsilon},g_{\epsilon})$ of $\mathcal{S}_{\epsilon}$ contains a
black hole region. Our proof is based on purely physical space arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08685</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Moschidis</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author></authors><title>The Einstein--null dust system in spherical symmetry with an inner
  mirror: structure of the maximal development and Cauchy stability</title><categories>gr-qc math.AP</categories><comments>80 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the evolution of asymptotically AdS initial data for
the spherically symmetric Einstein--massless Vlasov system for $\Lambda&lt;0$,
with reflecting boundary conditions imposed on timelike infinity $\mathcal{I}$,
in the case when the Vlasov field is supported only on radial geodesics. This
system is equivalent to the spherically symmetric Einstein--null dust system,
allowing for both ingoing and outgoing dust. In general, solutions to this
system break down in finite time (independent of the size of the initial data);
we highlight this fact by showing that, at the first point where the ingoing
dust reaches the axis of symmetry, solutions become $C^{0}$ inextendible,
although the spacetime metric remains regular up to that point.
  One way to overcome this trivial obstacle to well-posedness is to place an
inner mirror on a timelike hypersurface of the form $\{r=r_{0}\}$, $r_{0}&gt;0$,
and study the evolution on the exterior domain $\{r\ge r_{0}\}$. In this
setting, we prove the existence and uniqueness of maximal developments for
general smooth and asymptotically AdS initial data sets, and study the basic
geometric properties of these developments. Furthermore, we establish the
well-posedness and Cauchy stabilty of solutions with respect to a rough initial
data norm, measuring the concentration of energy at scales proportional to the
mirror radius $r_{0}$.
  The above well-posedness and Cauchy stability estimates are used in our
companion paper for the proof of the AdS instability conjecture for the
Einstein--null dust system. However, the results of the present paper might
also be of independent interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08689</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Reifarth</keyname><forenames>Ren&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;bel</keyname><forenames>Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heftrich</keyname><forenames>Tanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weigand</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurado</keyname><forenames>Beatriz</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;ppeler</keyname><forenames>Franz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Litvinov</keyname><forenames>Yuri A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A spallation-based neutron target for direct studies of neutron-induced
  reactions in inverse kinematics</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Accelerators and Beams 20, 044701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.20.044701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the possibility to build a neutron target for nuclear reaction
studies in inverse kinematics utilizing a storage ring and radioactive ion
beams. The proposed neutron target is a specially designed spallation target
surrounded by a large moderator of heavy water (D$_2$O). We present the
resulting neutron spectra and their properties as a target. We discuss possible
realizations at different experimental facilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08706</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08706</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Mor</keyname><forenames>Ilan</forenames></author></authors><title>High Spatial-Resolution Fast Neutron Detectors for Imaging and
  Spectrometry</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>PhD thesis, Ben-Gurion University (2013)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two detection systems based on optical readout were developed:
  a. Integrative optical detector A 2nd generation of Time-Resolved Integrative
Optical Neutron (TRION) detector was developed. It is based on an integrative
optical technique, which permits fast-neutron energy-resolved imaging via
time-gated optical readout. This mode of operation allows loss-free operation
at very high neutron-flux intensities. The TRION neutron imaging system can be
regarded as a stroboscopic photography of neutrons arriving at the detector on
a few-ns time scale. As this spectroscopic capability is based on the
Time-of-Flight (TOF) technique, it has to be operated in conjunction with a
pulsed neutron source, such as an ion accelerator producing 1-2 ns wide beam
pulses at MHz repetition rates. TRION is capable of capturing 4 simultaneous
TOF frames within a single accelerator pulse and accumulating them over all
pulses contained within a finite acquisition time. The detector principle of
operation, simulations and experimental results are described.
  b. Fibrous optical detector A fast neutron imaging detector based on
micrometric glass capillaries loaded with high- refractive-index liquid
scintillator has been developed. Neutron energy spectrometry is based on
event-by-event detection and reconstruction of neutron energy from the
measurement of the recoil proton track projection length and the amount of
light produced in the track. In addition, the detector can provide fast-neutron
imaging with position resolution of tens of microns. The detector principle of
operation, simulations and experimental results obtained with a small detector
prototype are described. Track-imaging of individual recoil protons from
incident neutrons in the range of 2-14 MeV are demonstrated as well as
preliminary results of detector spectroscopic capabilities.
  Keywords: Fast neutron resonance radiography; Time-of-Flight; Fast neutron
imaging; Energy-resolved imaging; Neutron spectrometry; Capillary array; Liquid
scintillator
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08707</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Oi</keyname><forenames>Daniel KL</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallone</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villoresi</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenland</keyname><forenames>Steve</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kerr</keyname><forenames>Emma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macdonald</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinfurter</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuiper</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charbon</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ursin</keyname><forenames>Rupert</forenames></author></authors><title>CubeSat quantum communications mission</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Quantum Technol. (2017) 4: 6</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjqt/s40507-017-0060-1</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum communication is a prime space technology application and offers
near-term possibilities for long-distance quantum key distribution (QKD) and
experimental tests of quantum entanglement. However, there exists considerable
developmental risks and subsequent costs and time required to raise the
technological readiness level of terrestrial quantum technologies and to adapt
them for space operations. The small-space revolution is a promising route by
which synergistic advances in miniaturization of both satellite systems and
quantum technologies can be combined to leap-frog conventional space systems
development. Here, we outline a recent proposal to perform orbit-to-ground
transmission of entanglement and QKD using a CubeSat platform deployed from the
International Space Station (ISS). This ambitious mission exploits advances in
nanosatellite attitude determination and control systems (ADCS), miniaturised
target acquisition and tracking sensors, compact and robust sources of single
and entangled photons, and high-speed classical communications systems, all to
be incorporated within a 10 kg 6 litre mass-volume envelope. The CubeSat
Quantum Communications Mission (CQuCoM) would be a pathfinder for advanced
nanosatellite payloads and operations, and would establish the basis for a
constellation of low-Earth orbit trusted-nodes for QKD service provision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08710</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bainbridge</keyname><forenames>Matthew B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>John K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluating the New Automatic Method for the Analysis of Absorption
  Spectra Using Synthetic Spectra</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, published on 5 April 2017 in Universe</comments><journal-ref>Universe 2017, 3(2), 34</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/universe3020034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recently presented a new &quot;artificial intelligence&quot; method for the analysis
of high-resolution absorption spectra (Bainbridge and Webb, Mon. Not. R.
Astron. Soc. 2017, 468,1639-1670). This new method unifies three established
numerical methods: a genetic algorithm (GVPFIT); non-linear least-squares
optimisation with parameter constraints (VPFIT); and Bayesian Model Averaging
(BMA). In this work, we investigate the performance of GVPFIT and BMA over a
broad range of velocity structures using synthetic spectra. We found that this
new method recovers the velocity structures of the absorption systems and
accurately estimates variation in the fine structure constant. Studies such as
this one are required to evaluate this new method before it can be applied to
the analysis of large sets of absorption spectra. This is the first time that a
sample of synthetic spectra has been utilised to investigate the analysis of
absorption spectra. Probing the variation of nature's fundamental constants
(such as the fine structure constant), through the analysis of absorption
spectra, is one of the most direct ways of testing the universality of physical
laws. This &quot;artificial intelligence&quot; method provides a way to avoid the main
limiting factor, i.e., human interaction, in the analysis of absorption
spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08714</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Riordan</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warnke</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author></authors><title>The phase transition in bounded-size Achlioptas processes</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math.CO</categories><comments>95 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>05C80, 60C05, 90B15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Perhaps the best understood phase transition is that in the component
structure of the uniform random graph process introduced by Erd\H{o}s and
R\'enyi around 1960. Since the model is so fundamental, it is very interesting
to know which features of this phase transition are specific to the model, and
which are `universal', at least within some larger class of processes (a
`universality class'). Achlioptas process, a class of variants of the
Erd\H{o}s--R\'enyi process that are easy to define but difficult to analyze,
have been extensively studied from this point of view. Here, settling a number
of conjectures and open problems, we show that all `bounded-size' Achlioptas
processes share (in a strong sense) all the key features of the
Erd\H{o}s--R\'enyi phase transition. We do not expect this to hold for
Achlioptas processes in general.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08728</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Alves</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>C. J. A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leite</keyname><forenames>A. C. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fisher matrix forecasts for astrophysical tests of the stability of the
  fine-structure constant</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Phys. Lett. B (in press)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.03.053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use Fisher Matrix analysis techniques to forecast the cosmological impact
of astrophysical tests of the stability of the fine-structure constant to be
carried out by the forthcoming ESPRESSO spectrograph at the VLT (due for
commissioning in late 2017), as well by the planned high-resolution
spectrograph (currently in Phase A) for the European Extremely Large Telescope.
Assuming a fiducial model without $\alpha$ variations, we show that ESPRESSO
can improve current bounds on the E\&quot;{o}tv\&quot;{o}s parameter---which quantifies
Weak Equivalence Principle violations---by up to two orders of magnitude,
leading to stronger bounds than those expected from the ongoing tests with the
MICROSCOPE satellite, while constraints from the E-ELT should be competitive
with those of the proposed STEP satellite. Should an $\alpha$ variation be
detected, these measurements will further constrain cosmological parameters,
being particularly sensitive to the dynamics of dark energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08745</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>Marco C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximizing Survey Volume for Large-Area Multi-Epoch Surveys with Voronoi
  Tessellation</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 tables, 8 figures, accepted by MNRAS on 10 April 2017</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The survey volume of a proper motion-limited sample is typically much smaller
than a magnitude-limited sample. This is because of the noisy astrometric
measurements from detectors that are not dedicated for astrometric missions. In
order to apply an empirical completeness correction, existing works limit the
survey depth to the shallower parts of the sky that hamper the maximum
potential of a survey. The number of epoch of measurement is a discrete
quantity that cannot be interpolated across the projected plane of observation,
so that the survey properties change in discrete steps across the sky. This
work proposes a method to dissect the survey into small parts with Voronoi
tessellation using candidate objects as generating points, such that each part
defines a `mini-survey' that has its own properties. Coupling with a maximum
volume density estimator, the new method is demonstrated to be unbiased and
recovered {\sim}20% more objects than the existing method in a mock catalogue
of a white dwarf-only solar neighbourhood with Pan--STARRS 1-like
characteristics. Towards the end of this work, we demonstrate one way to
increase the tessellation resolution with artificial generating points, which
would be useful for analysis of rare objects with small number counts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08751</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08751</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Dae-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Min-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Yong-Keun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Joo-Sung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Yoon-Seok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Duck-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Je</keyname><forenames>Soong-Geun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>Byoung-Chul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choe</keyname><forenames>Sug-Bong</forenames></author></authors><title>Chirality-induced Antisymmetry in Magnetic Domain-Wall Speed</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In chiral magnetic materials, numerous intriguing phenomena such as built in
chiral magnetic domain walls (DWs) and skyrmions are generated by the
Dzyaloshinskii Moriya interaction (DMI). The DMI also results in asymmetric DW
speed under in plane magnetic field, which provides a useful scheme to measure
the DMI strengths. However, recent findings of additional asymmetries such as
chiral damping have disenabled unambiguous DMI determination and the underlying
mechanism of overall asymmetries becomes under debate. By extracting the
DMI-induced symmetric contribution, here we experimentally investigated the
nature of the additional asymmetry. The results revealed that the additional
asymmetry has a truly antisymmetric nature with the typical behavior governed
by the DW chirality. In addition, the antisymmetric contribution changes the DW
speed more than 100 times, which cannot be solely explained by the chiral
damping scenario. By calibrating such antisymmetric contributions, experimental
inaccuracies can be largely removed, enabling again the DMI measurement scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08753</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Yangzheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Zhisheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strobel</keyname><forenames>Timothy A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interpenetrating Graphene Networks: Three-dimensional Node-line
  Semimetals with Massive Negative Linear Compressibilities</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245422 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245422</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigated the stability and mechanical and electronic properties of
fifteen metastable mixed $sp^2$-$sp^3$ carbon allotropes in the family of
interpenetrating graphene networks (IGNs) using density functional theory (DFT)
within the generalized gradient approximation (GGA). IGN allotropes exhibit
non-monotonic bulk and linear compressibilities before their structures
irreversibly transform into new configurations under large hydrostatic
compression. The maximum bulk compressibilities vary widely between structures
and range from 3.6 to 306 TPa$^{-1}$. We find all the IGN allotropes have
negative linear compressibilities with maximum values varying from -0.74 to
-133 TPa$^{-1}$. The maximal negative linear compressibility of Z33 (-133
TPa$^{-1}$ at 3.4 GPa) exceeds previously reported values at pressures higher
than 1.0 GPa. IGN allotropes can be classified as either armchair- or
zigzag-type, and these two types of IGNs exhibit different electronic
properties. Zigzag-type IGNs are node-line semimetals, while armchair-type IGNs
are either semiconductors or node-loop or node-line semimetals. Experimental
synthesis of these IGN allotropes might be realized since their formation
enthalpies relative to graphite are only 0.1 - 0.5 eV/atom (that of C$_{60}$
fullerene is about 0.4 eV/atom), and energetically feasible binary compound
pathways are possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08764</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenxu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ying-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebogi</keyname><forenames>Celso</forenames></author></authors><title>Data Based Identification and Prediction of Nonlinear and Complex
  Dynamical Systems</title><categories>physics.data-an nlin.CD physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>138 pages, 37 figures, Review Article</comments><journal-ref>Physics Reports 644, 1-76 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2016.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of reconstructing nonlinear and complex dynamical systems from
measured data or time series is central to many scientific disciplines
including physical, biological, computer, and social sciences, as well as
engineering and economics. In this paper, we review the recent advances in this
forefront and rapidly evolving field, aiming to cover topics such as
compressive sensing (a novel optimization paradigm for sparse-signal
reconstruction), noised-induced dynamical mapping, perturbations, reverse
engineering, synchronization, inner composition alignment, global silencing,
Granger Causality and alternative optimization algorithms. Often, these rely on
various concepts from statistical and nonlinear physics such as phase
transitions, bifurcation, stabilities, and robustness. The methodologies have
the potential to significantly improve our ability to understand a variety of
complex dynamical systems ranging from gene regulatory systems to social
networks towards the ultimate goal of controlling such systems. Despite recent
progress, many challenges remain. A purpose of this Review is then to point out
the specific difficulties as they arise from different contexts, so as to
stimulate further efforts in this interdisciplinary field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08766</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Castro-Mar&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castro-Olvera</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ru&#xed;z</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardu&#xf1;o-Mej&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosete-Aguilar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruce</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Z-scan confocal method for indirect focusing location</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>submitted to Review of Scientific Instruments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new technique that we have defined as the z-scan confocal method
to determine the absolute location and size of the focal spot in a tight
focused ultrashort laser pulse. The method permits to accurately position a
target in the focal spot with a fast response. The technique is designed to
help to automatize the location of an overdense target in focus in a laser
plasma experiment. The method allows for a fast localization of the focal
position and the relative motion of the target with respect to it. As an
example of the capacities we measure the defocusing of a fast rotating disc in
several radius to reconstruct the motion of the disc at focus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08779</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Mazilu</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Mie scattering eigenmodes for optical trapping</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Presented at the Bremen Workshop on Light Scattering 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Mie scattering theory enables the exact determination of the scattered
field as a function of the incident field. Here, we use this approach to
calculate the Hermitian relationship between the incident field and the optical
forces acting on the scattering objects. This Hermitian relationship defines
also a set of orthogonal optical eigenmodes which deliver a natural basis to
describe momentum transfer in light-matter interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08794</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Jiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Songbai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Qiyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jieci</forenames></author></authors><title>Detect black holes using photons for coupling model of electromagnetic
  and gravitational fields</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a model of the electromagnetic field coupled to Weyl tensor, Maxwell
equations are modified and photons at low frequencies no longer propagate along
light cone. If we detect a black hole using these photons, some difficulties
appear because we can not determine the position of event horizon which is
defined by null surface. To overcome these difficulties, the simplest way may
be an effective description by introducing an effective spacetime in which the
photons propagate along the light cone. Then, we find, comparing the results
with those of the original spacetime, that the event horizon and temperature do
not change, but the area of the event horizon and Bekenstein-Hawking entropy
become different. We show that the total entropy for this system, which is
still the same as that of original spacetime, consists of two parts, one is the
Bekenstein-Hawking entropy and the other is the entropy arising from the
coupling of electromagnetic field and Weyl tensor. We also present the
effective descriptions for the Smarr relation and first law of thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08801</id><created>2017-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Sarita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jindal</keyname><forenames>V. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative Thermal expansion of pure and doped Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>21 pages, 11 figures and 44 references. arXiv admin note: substantial
  text overlap with arXiv:1606.07656</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene and its derivatives distinguish themselves for their large negative
thermal expansion even at temperatures as high as 1000K. The linear thermal
expansion coefficients (LTEC) of two-dimensional honeycomb structured pure
graphene and B/N doped graphene are analyzed using ab initio density functional
perturbation theory (DFPT) employed in VASP software under quasiharmonic
approximation. One of the essential ingredients required is the phonon
frequencies for a set of points in the Brillouin zone and their volume
dependence. These were obtained from the dynamical matrix which was calculated
using VASP code in interface with phonopy code. In particular, the transverse
acoustic modes (ZA) behave drastically differently as compared to planer modes
and so also their volume dependence. Using this approach firstly thermal
expansion for pure graphene is calculated. The results agree with earlier
calculations using similar approach. Thereafter we have studied the effect of
boron and nitrogen doping on LTEC. The LTEC of graphene is found to be negative
in the entire range of temperature under study (0-1000K) and its value at room
temperature (RT) is around -3.26X10-6K-1. The value of LTEC at RT becomes more
negative with B/N doping in graphene. In order to get an insight into the cause
of negative thermal expansion, we have computed the contribution of individual
phonon modes of vibration. We notice that it is principally the ZA modes which
are responsible for negative thermal expansion. It has been concluded that
transverse mode in 2D hexagonal lattices have an important role to play in many
of the thermodynamical properties of 2D structures. We have extended the study
to calculate the LTEC of h-BN sheet also.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08811</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Deepak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiti</keyname><forenames>Moumita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahiri</keyname><forenames>Susanta</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental probe on the production of $^{97}$Ru from
  $^{7}$Li+$^{93}$Nb reaction: A study on the precompound emissions</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>20, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.C 94, 044603 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.044603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: Interaction of weakly bound heavy-ions with an intermediate or
heavy target is not yet understood completely due to the scarcity of
experimental data. In order to develop a clear understanding of breakup fusion
or preequilibrium emission even at low energy range, 3--10 MeV/nucleon, more
experimental investigations are necessary. Purpose: Study of reaction
mechanisms involved in the weakly bound heavy-ion induced reaction, $^7$Li +
$^{93}$Nb, at low energies by measuring the production cross sections of the
residual radionuclides. Method: Natural niobium ($^{93}$Nb) foil, backed by
aluminium (Al) catcher, arranged in a stack was bombarded by $^{7}$Li ions of
20-45 MeV energy. Activity of the residues produced in each $^{93}$Nb target
was measured by off-line $\gamma$-ray spectrometry after the end of bombardment
(EOB) and cross sections were calculated. Experimental cross sections were
compared with those computed using compound and precompound models. Results: In
general, measured excitation functions of all residues produced in $^{7}$Li +
$^{93}$Nb reaction showed good agreement with the model calculations based on
Hauser-Feshbach formalism and exciton model for compound and precompound
processes, respectively. Significant preequilibrium emission of neutrons was
observed at the relatively high energy tail of the excitation function of
$^{97}$Ru. Conclusions: Preequilibrium process played an important role for the
enhancement of cross-section in $xn$ reaction channel over the compound
reaction mechanism at higher energies for $^{7}$Li + $^{93}$Nb reaction.
Additionally, indirect evidence of incomplete or breakup fusion was also
perceived.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08816</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Kiratidis</keyname><forenames>Adrian L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamleh</keyname><forenames>Waseem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leinweber</keyname><forenames>Derek B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhan-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stokes</keyname><forenames>Finn M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Anthony W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopy with Local Multi-hadron Interpolators in Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>INPC 2016 Conference proceedings; 7 pages, 2 Figures, 1 Table</comments><report-no>ADP-17-15/T1021</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The positive-parity nucleon spectrum is studied in 2 + 1 flavour lattice QCD
in an attempt to discover novel low-lying energy eigenstates in the region of
the Roper resonance. In this work, we employ standard three-quark interpolating
fields and introduce new local five-quark meson-baryon operators that hold the
possibility of revealing new states that have been missed in previous studies.
Motivated by phenomenological arguments, five-quark interpolators based on the
$\sigma{N}$, $\pi{N}$ and $a_0{N}$ channels are constructed. Despite the
introduction of qualitatively different operators, no novel energy levels are
extracted near the regime of the Roper resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08870</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bora</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Delineating site response from microtremors: A case study</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report estimation of site response in the form of fundamental frequency.
Towards this objective, we deploy widely established receiver function
technique. Taking locally recorded events as inputs, we implement this
technique to estimate resonance frequency in three receiver sites,
characterized by varying lithology underneath. It is observed that resonance
frequencies varies from 3 to 7 Hz, which is also confirmed by our previous
studies of estimates from ambient noise recordings with reference to identical
sites. Variation of frequency implies existence of heterogeneity in the study
area.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08872</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08872</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Burdyuzha</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charugin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>L{\alpha} line of dark positronium as nongravitational detection of dark
  matter</title><categories>physics.gen-ph astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 0 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Modern Physics, 2015, N6, p. 1833-1839</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jmp.2015.613187</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An attempt to predict the new atomic dark matter lines is done on the example
of a dark lepton atom - positronium. Its Layman-alpha line with the energy near
3 GeV may be observable if the appropriate conditions realize. For this we have
studied a {\gamma}-ray excess in the Center of our Galaxy. In principle, this
excess may be produced by the L{\alpha} line of a dark positronium in the
medium with Compton scattering. The possibility of observations of an
annihilation line (E~300 TeV) of dark positronium is also predicted. Other
proposals to observe the atomic dark matter are shortly described. Besides,
H{\alpha} line (1.3{\mu}) of usual positronum must be observable in the
direction on the Center of our Galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08885</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Buck</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Sterile Neutrinos: Reactor Experiments</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Buck</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nuclear reactors are strong, pure and well localized sources of electron
antineutrinos with energies in the few MeV range. Therefore they provide a
suitable environment to study neutrino properties, in particular neutrino
oscillation parameters. Recent predictions of the expected antineutrino flux at
nuclear reactors are about 6% higher than the average rate measured in
different experiments. This discrepancy, known as the reactor antineutrino
anomaly, is significant at the 2.5{\sigma} level.
  Several new experiments are searching for the origin of this observed
neutrino deficit. One hypothesis to be tested is an oscillation to another
neutrino state. In a three flavor model reactor neutrinos do not oscillate at
baselines below 100 m. Hence, if such an oscillation is observed, it would
imply the existence of at least one light sterile neutrino state not
participating in weak interactions. Such a discovery would open the gate for
new physics beyond the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08898</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Cowan</keyname><forenames>Greig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drakopoulou</keyname><forenames>Evangelia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Needham</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taani</keyname><forenames>Mahdi</forenames></author></authors><title>Machine Learning-based Energy Reconstruction for Water-Cherenkov
  detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hyper-Kamiokande (Hyper-K) is a proposed next generation underground water
Cherenkov (WCh) experiment. The far detector will measure the oscillated
neutrino flux from the long-baseline neutrino experiment using 0.6 GeV
neutrinos produced by a 1.3 MW proton beam at J-PARC. It has a broad program of
physics and astrophysics mainly focusing on the precise measurement of the
lepton neutrino mixing matrix and the CP asymmetry. The unoscillated neutrino
flux will be measured by an intermediate WCh detector. One of the proposed
designs is the Tokai Intermediate Tank for the Unoscillated Spectrum (TITUS).
WCh detectors are instrumented with photomultipliers to detect the Cherenkov
light emitted from charged particles which are produced by neutrino
interactions. The detection of light is used to measure the energy, position
and direction of the charged particles. We propose machine learning-based
methods to reconstruct the energy of charged particles in WCh detectors and
present our results for the TITUS configuration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08903</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Status and challenges of neutrino cross sections</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>Talk presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 8 pages,
  LaTeX, 1 eps figure</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Martini</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutrino oscillations physics entered in the precision era. In this context
accelerator-based neutrino experiments need a reduction of systematic errors to
the level of a few percent. Today one of the most important sources of
systematic errors are the neutrino-nucleus cross sections. The status of our
knowledge of these cross sections in the different open channels in the few-GeV
region, i.e. the quasielastic, the pion production and the multinucleon
emission, is reviewed. Special emphasis is devoted to the multinucleon emission
channel, which attracted a lot of attention in the last few years. It is
crucial to properly reconstruct the neutrino energy which enters the expression
of the oscillation probability. This channel was not included in the generators
used for the analyses of the neutrino cross sections and oscillations
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08915</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yiting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beam-Size Invariant Spectropolarimeters Using Gap-Plasmon Metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metasurfaces enable exceptional control over the light with surface-confined
planar components, offering the fascinating possibility of very dense
integration and miniaturization in photonics. Here, we design, fabricate and
experimentally demonstrate chip-size plasmonic spectropolarimeters for
simultaneous polarization state and wavelength determination.
Spectropolarimeters, consisting of three gap-plasmon phase-gradient
metasurfaces that occupy 120{\deg} circular sectors each, diffract normally
incident light to six predesigned directions, whose azimuthal angles are
proportional to the light wavelength, while contrasts in the corresponding
diffraction intensities provide a direct measure of the incident polarization
state through retrieval of the associated Stokes parameters. The
proof-of-concept 96-{\mu}m-diameter spectropolarimeter operating in the
wavelength range of 750-950nm exhibits the expected polarization selectivity
and high angular dispersion. Moreover, we show that, due to the circular-sector
design, polarization analysis can be conducted for optical beams of different
diameters without prior calibration, demonstrating thereby the beam-size
invariant functionality. The proposed spectropolarimeters are compact,
cost-effective, robust, and promise high-performance real-time polarization and
spectral measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08917</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Antonova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asfandiyarov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayes</keyname><forenames>R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benoit</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blondel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogomilov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bross</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cadoux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chikuma</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dudarev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ekel&#xf6;f</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Favre</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedotov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hallsj&#xf6;</keyname><forenames>S-P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmaylov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karadzhov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khabibullin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khotyantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleymenova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koga</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudenko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Likhacheva</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matev</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medvedeva</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mefodiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mineev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nessi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicola</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noah</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovsiannikova</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Da Silva</keyname><forenames>H. Pais</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parsa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rayner</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolando</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaykhiev</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simion</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soler</keyname><forenames>F. J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suvorov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsenov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kate</keyname><forenames>H. Ten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vankova-Kirilova</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yershov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Baby MIND Experiment Construction Status</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Poster presented at NuPhys2016 (London, 12-14 December 2016). 4
  pages, LaTeX, 7 figures</comments><report-no>NuPhys2016-Parsa</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Baby MIND is a magnetized iron neutrino detector, with novel design features,
and is planned to serve as a downstream magnetized muon spectrometer for the
WAGASCI experiment on the T2K neutrino beam line in Japan. One of the main
goals of this experiment is to reduce systematic uncertainties relevant to
CP-violation searches, by measuring the neutrino contamination in the
anti-neutrino beam mode of T2K. Baby MIND is currently being constructed at
CERN, and is planned to be operational in Japan in October 2017.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08940</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Koo</keyname><forenames>Hyun-Joo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>Elijah E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whangbo</keyname><forenames>Myung-Hwan</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-domain ferromagnet of noncentrosymmetric uniaxial magnetic ions
  and magnetoelectric interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures, supporting information</comments><doi>10.1002/anie.201701699</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The feasibility of a single-domain ferromagnet based on uniaxial magnetic
ions was examined. For a noncentrosymmetric uniaxial magnetic ion of magnetic
moment at a site of local electric dipole moment p, it is unknown to date
whether the magnetic moment prefers to be parallel or antiparallel to the
electric dipole moment. The nature of this magnetoelectric interaction was
probed in terms of analogical reasoning based on the Rashba effect and density
functional calculations. We show that the magnetic and electric dipole moments
prefer an antiparallel arrangement, predict that Fe-doped CaZnOS is a
single-domain ferromagnet like a bar magnet, and find the probable cause for
the ferromagnetism and weak magnetization hysteresis in Fe-doped hexagonal ZnO
and ZnS at very low dopant concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08945</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bogod</keyname><forenames>Ilana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahav</keyname><forenames>Saar</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic discrimination of a polymerase in the presence of obstacles</title><categories>q-bio.SC cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E, v95, 042408 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.042408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the causes of high fidelity of copying in biological systems is
kinetic discrimination. In this mechanism larger dissipation and copying
velocity result in improved copying accuracy. We consider a model of a
polymerase which simultaneously copies a single stranded RNA and opens a
single- to double-stranded junction serving as an obstacle. The presence of the
obstacle slows down the motor, resulting in a change of its fidelity, which can
be used to gain information about the motor and junction dynamics. We find that
the motor's fidelity does not depend on details of the motor-junction
interaction, such as whether the interaction is passive or active. Analysis of
the copying fidelity can still be used as a tool for investigating the junction
kinetics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08946</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oguri</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silveira</keyname><forenames>Felipe</forenames></author></authors><title>Specific heats of degenerate ideal gases</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, in Portuguese, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From arguments based on Heisenberg's uncertainty principle and Pauli's
exclusion principle, the molar specific heats of degenerate ideal gases at low
temperatures are estimated, giving rise to values consistent with the
Nerst-Planck Principle (third law of Thermodynamics). The Bose-Einstein
condensation phenomenon based on the behavior of specific heat of massive and
non-relativistic boson gases is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08947</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Saad</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nouh</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaker</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamel</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Approximate Analytical Solutions to the Relativistic Isothermal Gas
  Spheres</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we introduce a novel analytical solution to
Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff (TOV) equation, which is ultimately a hydrostatic
equilibrium equation derived from the general relativity in the framework of
relativistic isothermal spheres. Application of the traditional power series
expansions on solving TOV equation results in a limited physical range to the
convergent power series solution. To improve the convergence radii of the
obtained series solutions, a combination of the two techniques of Euler-Abel
transformation and Pade approximation has done. The solutions are given in
\exi-\theta and \exi-\mu phase planes taking into account the general
relativistic effects \sigma= 0.1, 0.2 and 0.3. An Application to a neutron star
has done. A Comparison between the results obtained by the suggested approach
in the present paper and the numerical one indicates a good agreement with a
maximum relative error of order 10-3, which establishes the validity and
accuracy of the method. The procedure we have applied accelerated the power
series solution with about ten times than of traditional one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08948</id><created>2017-04-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sajjadi</keyname><forenames>Shahrdad G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanal</keyname><forenames>Harihar</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction of Tollmien-Schlichting Waves in the Air with the Sea
  Surface</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>29 pages and 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Advances and Applications in Fluid Mechanics, Volume 5, Issue 1
  (January 2009)</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  Linear stability of fully developed flows of air over water is carried out in
order to study non-linear effects in the generation of solitons by wind. A
linear stability analysis of the basic flow is made and the conditions at which
solitons first begin to grow is determined. Then, following [10], the
non-linear stability of the flow is examined and the quintic non-linear
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation is derived for the amplitude of disturbances. The
coefficients of the non-linear Schr\&quot;odinger equation are calculated from the
eigenvalue problem which determines the stability of air-water interface. An
asymptotic and a numerical stability analysis is carried out to determine the
neutrally stable flow conditions for air-sea interface. Four different profiles
are considered for the airflow blowing over the surface of the sea, namely,
plane Couette flow (pCf), plane Poiseuille flow (pPf), laminar and turbulent
boundary layer (L,TBL) profiles. For each of the above cases the shear flow
counterpart in the water is assumed to be a pPf. It is shown that the above
amplitude equation produces `snake' solitons [9] for pCf, pPf and LBL profiles,
with striking similarities. On the other hand, for TBL we observe a very
violent surface motion. For cases of pCf and LBL remarkable similarity is
observed with observations made at sea. We conclude that the effect of
nonlinearity in the airflow over the sea surface is much larger than nonlinear
interactions in the water, and hence it is not possible to decouple the motion
in the air and the water for finite amplitude wind-wave interactions,
particularly in the case of wind-generated solitons in shallow waters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08962</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08962</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Chin-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Paul. T. P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirano</keyname><forenames>Naomi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>Hsien</forenames></author></authors><title>First Detection of Equatorial Dark Dust Lane in a Protostellar Disk at
  Submillimeter Wavelength</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>24 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Advances 3, e1602935 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the earliest (so-called &quot;Class 0&quot;) phase of sunlike (low-mass) star
formation, circumstellar disks are expected to form, feeding the protostars.
However, such disks are difficult to resolve spatially because of their small
sizes. Moreover, there are theoretical difficulties in producing such disks in
the earliest phase, due to the retarding effects of magnetic fields on the
rotating, collapsing material (so-called &quot;magnetic braking&quot;). With the Atacama
Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA), it becomes possible to uncover
such disks and study them in detail. HH 212 is a very young protostellar
system. With ALMA, we not only detect but also spatially resolve its disk in
dust emission at submillimeter wavelength. The disk is nearly edge-on and has a
radius of ~ 60 AU. Interestingly, it shows a prominent equatorial dark lane
sandwiched between two brighter features, due to relatively low temperature and
high optical depth near the disk midplane. For the first time, this dark lane
is seen at submillimeter wavelength, producing a &quot;hamburger&quot;-shaped appearance
that is reminiscent of the scattered-light image of an edge-on disk in optical
and near infrared. Our observations open up an exciting possibility of directly
detecting and characterizing small disks around the youngest protostars through
high-resolution imaging with ALMA, which provides strong constraints on
theories of disk formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08969</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Machado</keyname><forenames>Ronalton Evandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>Lubienska Cristina Lucas Jaqui&#xea;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>Milena</forenames></author></authors><title>Does forest replacement increase water suply in watersheds? Analysis
  through hydrological simulation</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 16 figures, 5 tables, search results</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The forest plays an important role in a watershed hydrology, regulating the
transfer of water within the system. The forest role in maintaining watersheds
hydrological regime is still a controversial issue. Consequently, we use the
Soil and Water Assessment Tool (SWAT) model to simulate scenarios of land use
in a watershed. In one of these scenarios we identified, through GIS
techniques, Environmentally Sensitive Areas (ESAs) which have watershed been
degraded and we considered these areas protected by forest cover. This scenario
was then compared to current usage scenario regarding watershed sediment yield
and hydrological regime. The results showed a reduction in sediment yield of
54% among different scenarios, at the same time that the watershed water yield
was reduced by 19.3%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08983</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Mulargia</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Galactic hum</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.EP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A number of earth's tremor spectral peaks show a persistent narrow bandwidth
incompatible with any geophysical or instrumental origin. These peaks, located
at frequencies lower than a few mHz, are in principle consistent with the earth
strain waves induced by monochromatic gravitational waves. Exploring this
hypothesis under the current cosmological constraints yields that the tremor
peaks below 2 mHz are in apparently significant coincidence with the
theoretical emission of two binary systems each consisting of a small main
sequence star with mass $\sim 10^{-1} M_{\odot}$, captured by Sgr A* in a close
orbit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08989</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gil</keyname><forenames>J. A. Celis</forenames></author><author><keyname>P.</keyname><forenames>S. Gomez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>William J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise cross-correlation and Cooper pair splitting efficiency in
  multi-teminal superconductor junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Solid State Communications, Volume 258, May 2017, Pages 25-32</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2017.04.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the non-local shot noise in a multi-terminal junction formed by
two Normal metal leads con- nected to one superconductor. Using the cross Fano
factor and the shot noise, we calculate the efficiency of the Cooper pair
splitting. The method is applied to d-wave and iron based superconductors. We
de- termine that the contributions to the noise cross-correlation are due to
crossed Andreev reflections (CAR), elastic cotunneling, quasiparticles
transmission and local Andreev reflections. In the tunneling limit, the CAR
contribute positively to the noise cross-correlation whereas the other
processes contribute negatively. Depending on the pair potential symmetry, the
CAR are the dominant processes, giving as a result a high efficiency for Cooper
pair split. We propose the use of the Fano factor to test the efficiency of a
Cooper pair splitter device.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.09014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.09014</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Jarret</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lackey</keyname><forenames>Brad</forenames></author></authors><title>Substochastic Monte Carlo Algorithms</title><categories>cs.DS quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce and formalize Substochastic Monte Carlo (SSMC)
algorithms. These algorithms, originally intended to be a better classical foil
to quantum annealing than simulated annealing, prove to be worthy optimization
algorithms in their own right. In SSMC, a population of walkers is initialized
according to a known distribution on an arbitrary search space and varied into
the solution of some optimization problem of interest. The first argument of
this paper shows how an existing classical algorithm, &quot;Go-With-The-Winners&quot;
(GWW), is a limiting case of SSMC when restricted to binary search and
particular driving dynamics.
  Although limiting to GWW, SSMC is more general. We show that (1) GWW can be
efficiently simulated within the SSMC framework, (2) SSMC can be exponentially
faster than GWW, (3) by naturally incorporating structural information, SSMC
can exponentially outperform the quantum algorithm that first inspired it, and
(4) SSMC exhibits desirable search features in general spaces. Our approach
combines ideas from genetic algorithms (GWW), theoretical probability
(Fleming-Viot processes), and quantum computing. Not only do we demonstrate
that SSMC is often more efficient than competing algorithms, but we also hope
that our results connecting these disciplines will impact each independently.
An implemented version of SSMC has previously enjoyed some success as a
competitive optimization algorithm for Max-$k$-SAT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.09020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.09020</id><created>2017-04-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Neukirch</keyname><forenames>Maik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galiana</keyname><forenames>Savitri</forenames></author></authors><title>Appraisal of the Magnetotelluric Galvanic Electric Distortion by
  Optimisation of the Relation between Amplitude and Phase Tensors</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 5 color figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The introduction of the Phase Tensor marked a major breakthrough in the
understanding, analysis and treatment of galvanic distortion of the electric
field in the Magnetotelluric (MT) method. We build upon a recently formulated
impedance tensor decomposition into the known Phase Tensor and an Amplitude
Tensor that is shown to be complementary and algebraically independent of the
Phase Tensor. This recent decomposition demonstrates that the Amplitude Tensor
contains inductive and galvanic information of the subsurface and that the
inductive information is physically coupled to the one contained in the Phase
Tensor. In this work we present an algorithm that employs this last finding to
show that the MT galvanic electric distortion tensor can be separated from the
inductive Amplitude Tensor and hence, that this distortion can be recovered for
any given data up to a single constant usually denoted as galvanic shift.
Firstly, to illustrate distortion effects on the Amplitude Tensor, we manually
apply distortion by matrix multiplication to synthetic impedance tensor data.
Then, we use the observations of that analysis to define an objective function,
which minimises when there is no distortion present in the Amplitude Tensor.
Secondly, we describe our algorithm that employs a genetic algorithm to find
the optimal distortion tensor needed to correct the Amplitude Tensor, and
therewith the impedance tensor. Lastly, we test the performance of the proposed
methodology on synthetic data of known distortion and random distortion, and on
four real data sets. The real data sets, lit007/lit008 and lit901/lit902,
demonstrate the utility of the proposed algorithm by revealing geological
expected results in the impedance data for the first time, which could not be
achieved before by alternative methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
