<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T10:58:18Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-05-08" from="2017-05-08" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0706.3682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0706.3682</id><created>2007-06-25</created><updated>2008-08-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mathar</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Orthogonal Set of Basis Functions over the Binocular Pupil</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Added chapters V and VI on interferometric signal and Fourier
  representation</comments><journal-ref>Baltic Astronomy 19 (2010) 121-141</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/astro-2017-0416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sets of orthogonal basis functions over two-dimensional circular areas--most
often representing pupils in optical applications--are known in the literature
for the full circle (Zernike or Jacobi polynomials) and the annulus. This work
proposes an orthogonal set if the area is two non-overlapping circular pupils
of same size. The major free parameter is the ratio of the pupil radii over the
distance between both circles. Increasingly higher order aberrations--as
defined for a virtual larger pupil in which both pupils are embedded--are fed
into a Gram-Schmidt orthogonalization to implement one unique set of basis
functions. The key element is to work out the overlap integrals between a full
set of primitive basis functions (products of powers of the distance from the
mid-point between both pupils by azimuthal functions of the Fourier type).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.8422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.8422</id><created>2014-09-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Varignon</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bristowe</keyname><forenames>Nicholas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bousquet</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosez</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling and Electrical Control of Structural, Orbital and Magnetic
  Orders in Perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>The first two authors contributed equally</comments><doi>10.1038/srep15364</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Perovskite oxides are already widely used in industry and have huge potential
for novel device applications thanks to the rich physical behaviour displayed
in these materials. The key to the functional electronic properties exhibited
by perovskites is often the so-called Jahn-Teller distortion. For applications,
an electrical control of the Jahn-Teller distortions, which is so far out of
reach, would therefore be highly desirable. Based on universal symmetry
arguments, we determine new lattice mode couplings that can provide exactly
this paradigm, and exemplify the effect from first-principles calculations. The
proposed mechanism is completely general, however for illustrative purposes, we
demonstrate the concept on vanadium based perovskites where we reveal an
unprecedented orbital ordering and Jahn-Teller induced ferroelectricity. Thanks
to the intimate coupling between Jahn-Teller distortions and electronic degrees
of freedom, the electric field control of Jahn-Teller distortions is of general
relevance and may find broad interest in various functional devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04890</id><created>2015-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gambino</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupo</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sammartino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of cross-diffusion on Turing patterns in a reaction-diffusion
  Schnakenberg model</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><journal-ref>Ricerche di Matematica Volume 65, Issue 2, 1 November 2016, Pages
  449-467</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11587-016-0267-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the Turing pattern formation mechanism of a two component
reaction-diffusion system modeling the Schnakenberg chemical reaction coupled
to linear cross-diffusion terms is studied. The linear cross-diffusion terms
favors the destabilization of the constant steady state and the mechanism of
pattern formation with respect to the standard linear diffusion case, as shown
in Madzvamuse et al. (J. Math. Biol. 2014). Since the subcritical Turing
bifurcations of reaction-diffusion systems lead to spontaneous onset of robust,
finite-amplitude localized patterns, here a detailed investigation of the
Turing pattern forming region is performed to show how the diffusion
coefficients for both species (the activator and the inhibitor) influence the
occurrence of supercritical or subcritical bifurcations. The weakly nonlinear
(WNL) multiple scales analysis is employed to derive the equations for the
amplitude of the Turing patterns and to distinguish the supercritical and the
subcritical pattern region, both in 1D and 2D domains. Numerical simulations
are employed to confirm the WNL theoretical predictions through which a
classification of the patterns (squares, rhombi, rectangle and hexagons) is
obtained. In particular, due to the hysteretic nature of the subcritical
bifurcation, we observe the phenomenon of pattern transition from rolls to
hexagons, in agreement with the bifurcation diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07148</id><created>2015-07-25</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vaccario</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomasello</keyname><forenames>Mario Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tessone</keyname><forenames>Claudio Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schweitzer</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying knowledge exchange in R&amp;D networks: A data-driven model</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>35 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a model that reflects two important processes in R&amp;D activities of
firms, the formation of R&amp;D alliances and the exchange of knowledge as a result
of these collaborations. In a data-driven approach, we analyze two large-scale
data sets extracting unique information about 7500 R&amp;D alliances and 5200
patent portfolios of firms. This data is used to calibrate the model parameters
for network formation and knowledge exchange. We obtain probabilities for
incumbent and newcomer firms to link to other incumbents or newcomers which are
able to reproduce the topology of the empirical R&amp;D network. The position of
firms in a knowledge space is obtained from their patents using two different
classification schemes, IPC in 8 dimensions and ISI-OST-INPI in 35 dimensions.
Our dynamics of knowledge exchange assumes that collaborating firms approach
each other in knowledge space at a rate $\mu$ for an alliance duration $\tau$.
Both parameters are obtained in two different ways, by comparing knowledge
distances from simulations and empirics and by analyzing the collaboration
efficiency $\mathcal{\hat{C}}_{n}$. This is a new measure, that takes also in
account the effort of firms to maintain concurrent alliances, and is evaluated
via extensive computer simulations. We find that R&amp;D alliances have a duration
of around two years and that the subsequent knowledge exchange occurs at a very
low rate. Hence, a firm's position in the knowledge space is rather a
determinant than a consequence of its R&amp;D alliances. From our data-driven
approach we also find model configurations that can be both realistic and
optimized with respect to the collaboration efficiency $\mathcal{\hat{C}}_{n}$.
Effective policies, as suggested by our model, would incentivize shorter R&amp;D
alliances and higher knowledge exchange rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05730</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05730</id><created>2015-08-24</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Elise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mongin</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasparian</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Remote electrical arc suppression by laser filamentation</title><categories>physics.optics physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express Vol. 23, Issue 22, pp. 28640-28648 (2015); Erratum
  in Optics Express vol. 25, issue 10, pp. 11210 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.23.028640</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the interaction of narrow plasma channels formed in the
filamentation of ultrashort laser pulses, with a DC high voltage. The laser
filaments prevent electrical arcs by triggering corona that neutralize the
high-voltage electrodes. This phenomenon, due to the electric field modulation
and free electron release around the filament, opens new prospects to lightning
and over-voltage mitigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07312</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marochnik</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Energy and Inflation in a Gravitational Wave Dominated Universe</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, misprints are fixed</comments><journal-ref>Gravitation and Cosmology, 22, 10, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0202289316010126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The empty space (with no matter fields) is not really empty because of
natural metric fluctuations, quantum and classical. We show that gravitons as
well as classical gravitational waves of super-horizon wavelengths are able to
form the de Sitter state of the empty homogeneous isotropic Universe. This
state is the exact solution to the self-consistent equations of one-loop
quantum gravity for gravitons in the empty FLRW space. It also is the exact
solution to the self-consistent equations of back reaction for classical
gravitational waves. Technically, to get this de Sitter solution in both
quantum and classical cases, it is necessary to make the transition to
imaginary time and then come back to real time which is possible because this
de Sitter state is invariant with respect to Wick rotation. Such a procedure
means that the time was used as a complex variable, and this fact has a deep
but still not understood meaning. De Sitter accelerated expansion of the empty
Universe naturally explains the origin of dark energy and inflation because the
Universe is empty at the start and by the end of its evolution. This theory is
consistent with the existing observational data. The CMB anisotropy of the
order of 10^-5 is produced by fluctuations in the number of gravitons. The
existence of a threshold and unique coincidence of topologically impenetrable
barriers for tunneling takes place for the matter-dominated epoch and De Sitter
State only. These facts provide a solution to the coincidence problem. The
theoretical prediction that the equation-of-state parameter should be w&gt;-1 for
inflation and w&lt;-1 for dark energy is consistent with observational data. To
provide the reader with a complete picture, this paper gather together new and
some published results of the graviton theory of the origin of inflation and
dark energy
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04031</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lind&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x106;uri&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boucharin</keyname><forenames>Alexis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fange</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elf</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulated single molecule microscopy with SMeagol</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>v2: 14 pages including supplementary text. Pre-copyedited,
  author-produced version of an application note published in Bioinformatics
  following peer review. The version of record, and additional supplementary
  material is available online at:
  https://academic.oup.com/bioinformatics/article-lookup/doi/10.1093/bioinformatics/btw109</comments><journal-ref>Bioinformatics 2016; 32 (15): 2394-2395</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/bioinformatics/btw109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  SMeagol is a software tool to simulate highly realistic microscopy data based
on spatial systems biology models, in order to facilitate development,
validation, and optimization of advanced analysis methods for live cell single
molecule microscopy data. Availability and Implementation: SMeagol runs on
Matlab R2014 and later, and uses compiled binaries in C for reaction-diffusion
simulations. Documentation, source code, and binaries for recent versions of
Mac OS, Windows, and Ubuntu Linux can be downloaded from
http://smeagol.sourceforge.net.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00188</id><created>2015-10-01</created><updated>2017-02-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oksanen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bufalo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>BRST Quantization of Unimodular Gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>26 pages, minor modification in texts</comments><journal-ref>Braz. J. Phys. 47, 350 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s13538-017-0500-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantization of two versions of unimodular gravity, namely,
fully diffeomorphism-invariant unimodular gravity and unimodular gravity with
fixed metric determinant utilizing standard path integral approach. We derive
the BRST symmetry of effective actions corresponding to several relevant gauge
conditions. We observe that for some gauge conditions, the restricted gauge
structure may complicate the formulation and effective actions, in particular,
if the chosen gauge conditions involve the canonical momentum conjugate to the
induced metric on the spatial hypersurface. The BRST symmetry is extended
further to the finite field-dependent BRST transformation, in order to
establish the mapping between different gauge conditions in each of the two
versions of unimodular gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06198</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical Cap Packing Asymptotics and Rank-Extreme Detection</title><categories>math.ST cs.IT math.IT physics.data-an stat.ME stat.ML stat.TH</categories><comments>14 pages; 1 figure. Accepted Jan 31, 2017 by IEEE Transactions on
  Information Theory</comments><doi>10.1109/TIT.2017.2700202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spherical cap packing problem with a probabilistic approach.
Such probabilistic considerations result in an asymptotic sharp universal
uniform bound on the maximal inner product between any set of unit vectors and
a stochastically independent uniformly distributed unit vector. When the set of
unit vectors are themselves independently uniformly distributed, we further
develop the extreme value distribution limit of the maximal inner product,
which characterizes its uncertainty around the bound.
  As applications of the above asymptotic results, we derive (1) an asymptotic
sharp universal uniform bound on the maximal spurious correlation, as well as
its uniform convergence in distribution when the explanatory variables are
independently Gaussian distributed; and (2) an asymptotic sharp universal bound
on the maximum norm of a low-rank elliptically distributed vector, as well as
related limiting distributions. With these results, we develop a fast detection
method for a low-rank structure in high-dimensional Gaussian data without using
the spectrum information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02304</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bains</keyname><forenames>Jasdeep S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hertzberg</keyname><forenames>Mark P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilczek</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillatory Attractors: A New Cosmological Phase</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 15 figures. V2: Updated to version published in JCAP</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP-4745</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 05 (2017) 011</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/05/011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In expanding FRW spacetimes, it is usually the case that homogeneous scalar
fields redshift and their amplitudes approach limiting values: Hubble friction
usually ensures that the field relaxes to its minimum energy configuration,
which is usually a static configuration. Here we discover a class of
relativistic scalar field models in which the attractor behavior is the field
oscillating indefinitely, with finite amplitude, in an expanding FRW spacetime,
despite the presence of Hubble friction. This is an example of spontaneous
breaking of time translation symmetry. We find that the effective equation of
state of the field has average value $\langle w\rangle=-1$, implying that the
field itself could drive an inflationary or dark energy dominated phase. This
behavior is reminiscent of ghost condensate models, but in the new models,
unlike in the ghost condensate models, the energy-momentum tensor is time
dependent, so that these new models embody a more definitive breaking of time
translation symmetry. We explore (quantum) fluctuations around the homogeneous
background solution, and find that low $k$-modes can be stable, while high
$k$-modes are typically unstable. We discuss possible interpretations and
implications of that instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07843</id><created>2015-12-24</created><updated>2017-04-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arsenijevic</keyname><forenames>Momir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeknic-Dugic</keyname><forenames>Jasmina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dugic</keyname><forenames>Miroljub</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Kraus operators for the one-qubit depolarizing quantum
  channel</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures, aaccepted for publication in Brazilian Journal
  of Physics, in press</comments><journal-ref>Braz J Phys (2017) 47: 339-349</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s13538-017-0502-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microscopic Hamiltonian models of the composite system &quot;open system +
environment&quot; typically do not provide the operator-sum Kraus form of the open
system's dynamical map. With the use of a recently de- veloped method [16], we
derive the Kraus operators starting from the mi- croscopic Hamiltonian model,
i.e. from the proper master equation, of the one-qubit depolarizing channel.
Those Kraus operators generalize the stan- dard counterparts, which are widely
used in the literature. Comparison of the standard and the here obtained Kraus
operators is performed via inves- tigating dynamical change of the Bloch sphere
volume, entropy production and the open system's state trace distance. We find
that the standard depo- larizing channel is more deteriorating than the
generalized one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00686</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>University of Vienna, Department of Astrophysics, Austria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kuchner</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Trieste,</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ziegler</keyname><forenames>B. L.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Trieste,</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Verdugo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Trieste,</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Balestra</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Trieste,</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Girardi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Napoli</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mercurio</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Napoli</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rosati</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>University Ferrara, Italy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fritz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>INAF, Milano</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grillo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Dark Cosmology Center, Copenhagen</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nonino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sartoris</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>CLASH-VLT: Strangulation of cluster galaxies in MACSJ0416.1-2403 as seen
  from their chemical enrichment</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Version better matched to the published version, including table with
  observed and derived quantities for the 76 cluster galaxies</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 590, A108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628223</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  (abridged) We explore the Frontier Fields cluster MACS J0416.1-2403 at
z=0.3972 with VIMOS/VLT spectroscopy from the CLASH-VLT survey covering a
region which corresponds to almost three virial radii. We measure fluxes of 5
emission lines of 76 cluster members enabling us to unambiguously derive O/H
gas metallicities, and also SFRs from Halpha. For intermediate massses we find
a similar distribution of cluster and field galaxies in the MZR and mass vs.
sSFR diagrams. Bulge-dominated cluster galaxies have on average lower sSFRs and
higher O/Hs compared to their disk-dominated counterparts. We use the location
of galaxies in the projected velocity vs. position phase-space to separate our
cluster sample into a region of objects accreted longer time ago and a region
of recently accreted and infalling galaxies. We find a higher fraction of
accreted metal-rich galaxies (63%) compared to the fraction of 28% of
metal-rich galaxies in the infalling regions. Intermediate mass galaxies
falling into the cluster for the first time are found to be in agreement with
predictions of the fundamental metallicity relation. In contrast, for already
accreted star-forming galaxies of similar masses, we find on average
metallicities higher than predicted by the models. This trend is intensified
for accreted cluster galaxies of the lowest mass bin, that display
metallicities 2-3 times higher than predicted by models with primordial gas
inflow. Environmental effects therefore strongly influence gas regulations and
control gas metallicities of log(M/Msun)&lt;10.2 (Salpeter IMF) cluster galaxies.
We also investigate chemical evolutionary paths of model galaxies with and
without inflow of gas showing that strangulation is needed to explain the
higher metallicities of accreted cluster galaxies. Our results favor a
strangulation scenario in which gas inflow stops for log(M/Msun)&lt;10.2 galaxies
when accreted by the cluster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01996</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armaitis</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duine</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superfluidity and spin superfluidity in spinor Bose gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053607 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053607</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that spinor Bose gases subject to a quadratic Zeeman effect exhibit
coexisting superfluidity and spin superfluidity, and study the interplay
between these two distinct types of superfluidity. To illustrate that the basic
principles governing these two types of superfluidity are the same, we describe
the magnetization and particle-density dynamics in a single hydrodynamic
framework. In this description spin and mass supercurrents are driven by their
respective chemical potential gradients. As an application, we propose an
experimentally accessible stationary state, where the two types of
supercurrents counterflow and cancel each other, thus resulting in no mass
transport. Furthermore, we propose a straightforward setup to probe spin
superfluidity by measuring the in-plane magnetization angle of the whole cloud
of atoms. We verify the robustness of these findings by evaluating the
four-magnon collision time, and find that the time scale for coherent
(superfluid) dynamics is separated from that of the slower incoherent dynamics
by one order of magnitude. Comparing the atom and magnon kinetics reveals that
while the former can be hydrodynamic, the latter is typically collisionless
under most experimental conditions. This implies that, while our
zero-temperature hydrodynamic equations are a valid description of spin
transport in Bose gases, a hydrodynamic description that treats both mass and
spin transport at finite temperatures may not be readily feasible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02033</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Chih-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krasnov</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author></authors><title>Colour-Kinematics duality and the Drinfeld double of the Lie algebra of
  diffeomorphisms</title><categories>hep-th math.QA</categories><comments>v2: published version, appendix on numerator identities at 5 points
  added, 34 pages, many feynmf diagrams</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1701 (2017) 075</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colour-kinematics duality suggests that Yang-Mills (YM) theory possesses some
hidden Lie algebraic structure. So far this structure has resisted
understanding, apart from some progress in the self-dual sector. We show that
there is indeed a Lie algebra behind the YM Feynman rules. The Lie algebra we
uncover is the Drinfeld double of the Lie algebra of vector fields. More
specifically, we show that the kinematic numerators following from the YM
Feynman rules satisfy a version of the Jacobi identity, in that the Jacobiator
of the bracket defined by the YM cubic vertex is cancelled by the contribution
of the YM quartic vertex. We then show that this Jacobi-like identity is in
fact the Jacobi identity of the Drinfeld double. All our considerations are
off-shell. Our construction explains why numerators computed using the Feynman
rules satisfy the colour-kinematics at four but not at higher numbers of
points. It also suggests a way of modifying the Feynman rules so that the
duality can continue to hold for an arbitrary number of gluons. Our
construction stops short of producing explicit higher point numerators because
of an absence of a certain property at four points. We comment on possible ways
of correcting this, but leave the next word in the story to future work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05411</id><created>2016-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wenxuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotsis</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparative Density Functional Theory and Density Functional Tight
  Binding Study of Arginine and Arginine-Rich Cell-Penetrating Peptide TAT
  Adsorption on Anatase TiO2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>38 pages, 11 figures, 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 18, 19902-19917 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP02671K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparative Density Functional Theory (DFT) and Density
Functional Tight Binding (DFTB) study of geometries and electronic structures
of arginine (Arg), arginine adsorbed on the anatase (101) surface of titania in
several adsorption configurations, and of an arginine-rich cell penetrating
peptide TAT and its adsorption on the surface of TiO2. Two DFTB
parameterizations are considered, tiorg-0-1/mio-1-1 and matsci-0-3. While there
is good agreement in the structures and relative energies of Arg and peptide
conformers between DFT and DFTB, both adsorption geometries and energies are
noticeably different for Arg adsorbed on TiO2. The tiorg-0-1/mio-1-1
parameterization performs better than matsci-0-3. We relate this difference to
the difference in electronic structures resulting from the two methods (DFT and
DFTB) and specifically to the band alignment between the molecule and the
oxide. We show that the band alignment of TAT and of TiO2 modeled with DFTB is
qualitatively correct but that with DFT using the PBE functional is not. This
is specific to the modeling of large molecules where the HOMO is close to the
conduction band of the oxide. We therefore report a case where the approximate
DFT-based method - DFTB (with which the correct band structure can be
effectively obtained) - performs better than the DFT itself with a functional
approximation feasible for the modeling of large bio-inorganic interfaces, i.e.
GGA (as opposed to hybrid functionals which are impractical at such a scale).
Our results highlight the utility of the DFTB method for the modeling of
bioinorganic interfaces not only from the CPU cost perspective but also from
the accuracy point of view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05480</id><created>2016-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Varignon</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grisolia</keyname><forenames>Mathieu N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xcd;&#xf1;iguez</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barth&#xe9;l&#xe9;my</keyname><forenames>Agn&#xe8;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bibes</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Reconciling the ionic and covalent pictures in rare-earth nickelates</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1038/s41535-017-0024-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The properties of AMO3 perovskite oxides, where M is a 3d transition metal,
depend strongly on the level of covalency between the metal d and oxygen p
orbitals. With their complex spin orders and metal-insulator transition,
rare-earth nickelates verge between dominantly ionic and covalent characters.
Accordingly, the nature of their ground state is highly debated. Here, we
reconcile the ionic and covalent visions of the insulating state of nickelates.
Through first-principles calculations, we show that it is reminiscent of the
ionic charge disproportionation picture (with strictly low-spin 4+ and
high-spin 2+ Ni sites) while exhibiting strong covalence effects with oxygen
electrons shifted toward the depleted Ni cations, mimicking a configuration
with identical Ni sites. Our results further hint at strategies to control
electronic and magnetic phases of transition metal oxide perovskites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08060</id><created>2016-03-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Peizhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac Fermions in Antiferromagnetic Semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 1100 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3839</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The analogues of elementary particles have been extensively searched for in
condensed matter systems because of both scientific interests and technological
applications. Recently massless Dirac fermions were found to emerge as low
energy excitations in the materials named Dirac semimetals. All the currently
known Dirac semimetals are nonmagnetic with both time-reversal symmetry
$\mathcal{T}$ and inversion symmetry $\mathcal{P}$. Here we show that Dirac
fermions can exist in one type of antiferromagnetic systems, where
$\mathcal{T}$ and $\mathcal{P}$ are broken but their combination $\mathcal{PT}$
is respected. We propose orthorhombic antiferromagnet CuMnAs as a candidate,
analyze the robustness of the Dirac points with symmetry protections, and
demonstrate its distinctive bulk dispersions as well as the corresponding
surface states by \emph{ab initio} calculations. Our results give a new route
towards the realization of Dirac materials, and provide a possible platform to
study the interplay of Dirac fermion physics and magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02737</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Becher</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neubert</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rothen</keyname><forenames>Lorena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Ding Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Factorization and Resummation for Jet Processes</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>59 pages, 15 figures. v2: journal version; v3: corrected sign of
  (5.11) and a few other typos</comments><report-no>DESY 16-052, MITP/16-042</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2016)019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From a detailed analysis of cone-jet cross sections in effective field
theory, we obtain novel factorization theorems which separate the physics
associated with different energy scales present in such processes. The relevant
low-energy physics is encoded in Wilson lines along the directions of the
energetic particles inside the jets. This multi-Wilson-line structure is
present even for narrow-cone jets due to the relevance of small-angle soft
radiation. We discuss the renormalization-group equations satisfied by these
operators. Their solution resums all logarithmically enhanced contributions to
such processes, including non-global logarithms. Such logarithms arise in many
observables, in particular whenever hard phase-space constraints are imposed,
and are not captured with standard resummation techniques. Our formalism
provides the basis for higher-order logarithmic resummations of jet and other
non-global observables. As a nontrivial consistency check, we use it to obtain
explicit two-loop results for all logarithmically enhanced terms in cone-jet
cross sections and verify those against numerical fixed-order computations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06553</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06553</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Riedinger</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Florian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mule</keyname><forenames>Aniket</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzotti</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knuesel</keyname><forenames>Philippe N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kress</keyname><forenames>Stephan J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prins</keyname><forenames>Ferry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erwin</keyname><forenames>Steven C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>How semiconductor nanoplatelets form</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>57 pages, 23 figures (main text and supporting information merged),
  submitted</comments><doi>10.1038/nmat4889</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Colloidal nanoplatelets - quasi-two-dimensional sheets of semiconductor
exhibiting efficient, spectrally pure fluorescence - form when liquid-phase
syntheses of spherical quantum dots are modified. Despite intense interest in
their properties, the mechanism behind their anisotropic shape and precise
atomic-scale thickness remains unclear, and even counterintuitive when their
crystal structure is isotropic. One commonly accepted explanation is that
nanoclusters nucleate within molecular templates and then fuse. Here, we test
this mechanism for zincblende nanoplatelets and show that they form instead due
to an intrinsic instability in growth kinetics. We synthesize CdSe and
CdS1-xSex nanoplatelets in template- and solvent-free isotropic melts
containing only cadmium carboxylate and chalcogen, a finding incompatible with
previous explanations. Our model, based on theoretical results showing enhanced
growth on narrow surface facets, rationalizes nanoplatelet formation and
experimental dependencies on temperature, time, and carboxylate length. Such
understanding should lead to improved syntheses, controlled growth on surfaces,
and broader libraries of nanoplatelet materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07510</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Herfray</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krasnov</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarinci</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>6D Interpretation of 3D Gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math.DG</categories><comments>v2: published version, minor changes, 37 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 045007, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa5727</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that 3D gravity, in its pure connection formulation, admits a natural
6D interpretation. The 3D field equations for the connection are equivalent to
6D Hitchin equations for the Chern-Simons 3-form in the total space of the
principal bundle over the 3-dimensional base. Turning this construction around
one gets an explanation of why the pure connection formulation of 3D gravity
exists. More generally, we interpret 3D gravity as the dimensional reduction of
the 6D Hitchin theory. To this end, we show that any SU(2) invariant closed
3-form in the total space of the principal SU(2) bundle can be parametrised by
a connection together with a 2-form field on the base. The dimensional
reduction of the 6D Hitchin theory then gives rise to 3D gravity coupled to a
topological 2-form field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07633</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bordone</keyname><forenames>Marzia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isidori</keyname><forenames>Gino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pattori</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Standard Model predictions for $R_K$ and $R_{K^*}$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages [v3: Added Note on SM predictions for RK* in the low q2
  region]</comments><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4274-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate the impact of radiative corrections in the ratios $\Gamma[B\to M
\mu^+\mu^-]/\Gamma[B\to M e^+e^-]$ when the meson $M$ is a $K$ or a $K^*$.
Employing the cuts on $m^2_{\ell\ell}$ and the reconstructed $B$-meson mass
presently applied by the LHCb Collaboration, such corrections do not exceed a
few $\%$. Moreover, their effect is well described (and corrected for) by
existing Montecarlo codes. Our analysis reinforces the interest of these
observables as clean probe of physics beyond the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09712</id><created>2016-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Korkmaz</keyname><forenames>Alper</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ersoy</keyname><forenames>Ozlem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dag</keyname><forenames>Idiris</forenames></author></authors><title>Motion of Patterns Modeled by the Gray-Scott Autocatalysis System in One
  Dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math.NA nlin.PS</categories><comments>23 pages, 11 figures (including sub figures)</comments><journal-ref>MATCH Communications in Mathematical and in Computer Chemistry,
  77(2), 507-526 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Occupation of an interval by self-replicating initial pulses is studied
numerically. Two different approximates in different categories are proposed
for the numerical solutions of some initial-boundary value problems. The sinc
differential quadrature combined with third-fourth order implicit Rosenbrock
and exponential B-spline collocation methods are setup to obtain the numerical
solutions of the mentioned problems. The numerical simulations containing
occupation of single initial pulse, non or slow occupation model and covering
the domain with two initial pulses are demonstrated by using both proposed
methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00327</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00327</id><created>2016-06-01</created><updated>2016-11-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cristinziani</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulders</keyname><forenames>Martijn</forenames></author></authors><title>Top-quark physics at the Large Hadron Collider</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>54 pages, 42 figures, 2 tables. Accepted for publication in J. Phys.
  G</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G: Nucl. Part. Phys. 44 (2017) 063001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/44/6/063001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This experimental review gives an overview of top-quark measurements
performed by the two general purpose-detectors ATLAS and CMS during the first
few years of running of the Large Hadron Collider. In the years 2010 - 2012
each experiment collected 5 fb$^{-1}$ of pp collision data at $\sqrt{s} = 7$
TeV and 20 fb$^{-1}$ at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV, allowing detailed studies of
top-quark production and decays, and measurements of the properties of the top
quark with unprecedented precision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01520</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Myasnikova</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gileeva</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moseykin</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation of strongly coupled electron and phonon fields after
  photoemission and high-energy part of ARPES spectra of cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, submitted to PRB</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider photoemission from cuprate high-temperature superconductors
taking into account joint relaxation of strongly coupled fields: a field of
correlated electrons and phonon field. Such relaxation occurs in systems with
predominantly long-range electron-phonon interaction at sufficiently high
carrier concentration due to coexistence of autolocalized and delocalized
carriers. A simple method to calculate analytically a high-energy part of the
ARPES spectrum arising is proposed. The approach suggested yields all the
high-energy spectral features like broad bands of Gaussian shape and vertical
dispersion patterns being in good quantitative agreement with the experiments
at any doping with both types of carriers. Demonstrated coexistence of
autolocalized and delocalized carriers in cuprate superconductors is important
for understanding their transport and magnetic properties. Presence of
large-radius autolocalized carriers shown may be helpful in explanation of
charge ordering in doped cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04304</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Englert</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nordstrom</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Liam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russell</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Giving top quark effective operators a boost</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Published version</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.10.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the prospects to systematically improve generic effective
field theory-based searches for new physics in the top sector during LHC run 2
as well as the high luminosity phase. In particular, we assess the benefits of
high momentum transfer final states on top EFT-fit as a function of systematic
uncertainties in comparison with sensitivity expected from fully-resolved
analyses focusing on $t\bar t$ production. We find that constraints are
typically driven by fully-resolved selections, while boosted top quarks can
serve to break degeneracies in the global fit. This demystifies and clarifies
the importance of high momentum transfer final states for global fits to new
interactions in the top sector from direct measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04675</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Lind&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x106;uri&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amselem</keyname><forenames>Elias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elf</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author></authors><title>Certain uncertainty: using pointwise error estimates in super-resolution
  microscopy</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.data-an physics.optics q-bio.QM</categories><comments>Accompanying software available at
  https://github.com/bmelinden/uncertainSPT</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15115 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Point-wise localization of individual fluorophores is a critical step in
super-resolution microscopy and single particle tracking. Although the methods
are limited by the accuracy in localizing individual flourophores, this
point-wise accuracy has so far only been estimated by theoretical best case
approximations, disregarding for example motional blur, out of focus broadening
of the point spread function and time varying changes in the fluorescence
background. Here, we show that pointwise localization uncertainty can be
accurately estimated directly from imaging data using a Laplace approximation
constrained by simple mircoscope properties. We further demonstrate that the
estimated localization uncertainty can be used to improve downstream
quantitative analysis, such as estimation of diffusion constants and detection
of changes in molecular motion patterns. Most importantly, the accuracy of
actual point localizations in live cell super-resolution microscopy can be
improved beyond the information theoretic lower bound for localization errors
in individual images, by modeling the fluorophores' movement and accounting for
their point-wise localization uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06858</id><created>2016-07-22</created><updated>2016-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sasankan</keyname><forenames>Nishanth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Mayukh R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathews</keyname><forenames>Grant J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kusakabe</keyname><forenames>Motohiko</forenames></author></authors><title>New observational limits on dark radiation in brane-world cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>6 Pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 083516 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.083516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A dark radiation term arises as a correction to the energy momentum tensor in
the simplest five-dimensional RS-II brane-world cosmology. In this paper we
revisit the constraints on dark radiation based upon the newest results for
light-element nuclear reaction rates, observed light-element abundances and the
power spectrum of the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB). Adding dark radiation
during big bang nucleosynthesis alters the Friedmann expansion rate causing the
nuclear reactions to freeze out at a different temperature. This changes the
final light element abundances at the end of BBN. Its influence on the CMB is
to change the effective expansion rate at the surface of last scattering. We
find that our adopted BBN constraints reduce the allowed range for dark
radiation to between $-12.1\%$ and $+6.2\%$ of the ambient background energy
density. Combining this result with fits to the CMB power spectrum, the range
decreases to $-6.0\%$ to $+6.2\%$. Thus, we find, that the ratio of dark
radiation to the background total relativistic mass energy density $\rho_{\rm
DR}/\rho$ is consistent with zero although in the BBN analysis there could be a
slight preference for a negative contribution. However, the BBN constraint
depends strongly upon the adopted primordial helium abundance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01579</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2017-01-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Efstathiou</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacobbe</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marde&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugny</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rotation Forms and Local Hamiltonian Monodromy</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><msc-class>37Jxx</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys., 58(2), 022902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4975215</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The monodromy of torus bundles associated to completely integrable systems
can be computed using geometric techniques (constructing homology cycles) or
analytic arguments (computing discontinuities of abelian integrals). In this
article we give a general approach to the computation of monodromy that
resembles the analytical one, reducing the problem to the computation of
residues of polar 1-forms. We apply our technique to three celebrated examples
of systems with monodromy (the champagne bottle, the spherical pendulum, the
hydrogen atom) and to the case of non degenerate focus-focus singularities,
re-obtaining the classical results. An advantage of this approach is that the
residue-like formula can be shown to be local in a neighborhood of a
singularity, hence allowing the definition of monodromy also in the case of
non-compact fibers. This idea has been introduced in the literature under the
name of scattering monodromy. We prove the coincidence of the two definitions
with the monodromy of an appropriately chosen compactification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02238</id><created>2016-08-07</created><updated>2017-03-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dyatlov</keyname><forenames>Semyon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Long</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonances for open quantum maps and a fractal uncertainty principle</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP nlin.CD</categories><comments>53 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables. Simplified the proof of Lemma 2.2 and
  revised according to referee's comments. To appear in Communications in
  Mathematical Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2892-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study eigenvalues of quantum open baker's maps with trapped sets given by
linear arithmetic Cantor sets of dimensions $\delta\in (0,1)$. We show that the
size of the spectral gap is strictly greater than the standard bound
$\max(0,{1\over 2}-\delta)$ for all values of $\delta$, which is the first
result of this kind. The size of the improvement is determined from a fractal
uncertainty principle and can be computed for any given Cantor set. We next
show a fractal Weyl upper bound for the number of eigenvalues in annuli, with
exponent which depends on the inner radius of the annulus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05469</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramachandra</keyname><forenames>Nesar S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shandarin</keyname><forenames>Sergei F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topology and geometry of the dark matter web: a multistream view</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 13 figures. Matches version accepted by MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society (2017) 467 (2):
  1748-1762</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx183</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological connections in the single-streaming voids and multistreaming
filaments and walls reveal a cosmic web structure different from traditional
mass density fields. A single void structure not only percolates the
multistream field in all the directions, but also occupies over 99 per cent of
all the single-streaming regions. Sub-grid analyses on scales smaller than
simulation resolution reveal tiny pockets of voids that are isolated by
membranes of the structure. For the multistreaming excursion sets, the
percolating structure is significantly thinner than the filaments in
over-density excursion approach.
  Hessian eigenvalues of the multistream field are used as local geometrical
indicators of dark matter structures. Single-streaming regions have most of the
zero eigenvalues. Parameter-free conditions on the eigenvalues in the
multistream region may be used to delineate primitive geometries with
concavities corresponding to filaments, walls and haloes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07118</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Podolsky</keyname><forenames>Jiri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svarc</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Algebraic classification of Robinson-Trautman spacetimes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages, no figures, slightly extended version of the Phys. Rev. D
  paper</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064043 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a general class of four-dimensional geometries admitting a null
vector field that has no twist and no shear but has an arbitrary expansion. We
explicitly present the Petrov classification of such Robinson-Trautman (and
Kundt) gravitational fields, based on the algebraic properties of the Weyl
tensor. In particular, we determine all algebraically special subcases when the
optically privileged null vector field is a multiple principal null direction
(PND), as well as all the cases when it remains a single PND. No field
equations are a priori applied, so that our classification scheme can be used
in any metric theory of gravity in four dimensions. In the classic Einstein
theory this reproduces previous results for vacuum spacetimes, possibly with a
cosmological constant, pure radiation and electromagnetic field, but can be
applied to an arbitrary matter content. As non-trivial explicit examples we
investigate specific algebraic properties of the Robinson-Trautman spacetimes
with a free scalar field, and also black hole spacetimes in the pure
Einstein-Weyl gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07940</id><created>2016-08-29</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Troshin</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyurin</keyname><forenames>N. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin measurements in strangeness production at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures. updated version with account for QGP detection/.
  arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:hep-ph/0509238,
  arXiv:hep-ph/0501004</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We briefly recollect the problem of significant hyperon polarization
emphasizing the role of spin in dynamics of hadron interactions. We provide
also some model predictions based on chiral dynamics and the impact parameter
picture for illustration. The old, but yet unsolved problem of hyperon
polarization, can obtain a new insight from the measurements at the LHC
energies and, in combination with other measurements, can be used for tagging
QGP formation in $pp$--collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04617</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chrzaszcz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przedzinski</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Was</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaremba</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>TAUOLA of tau lepton decays-- framework for hadronic currens, matrix
  elements and anomalous decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>1 figure 1+34 pages, updates for FCC project added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an update of the Monte Carlo event generator TAUOLA for tau lepton
decays, with substantially increased list of decay channels and new
initialization options. The core of the program remains written in FORTRAN but
necessary arrangements have been made to allow handling of the user-provided
hadronic currents and matrix elements at the execution time. Such solution may
simplify preparation of new hadronic currents and may be useful for fitting to
the experimental data as well.
  We have implemented as default for TAUOLA a set of hadronic currents, which
is compatible with the default initialization used by BaBar collaboration.
Options for currents available in previous releases are still stored in the
code, sometimes left defunct or activated by internal flags only. The new
version of the program, includes also implementation of Lepton Flavour
Violating tau decays.
  Finally, we present, as an example, a set of C++ methods for handling
user-provided currents, matrix elements or complete new decay channels
initialization which can be performed at the program execution time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06078</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2016-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dan&#x10d;o</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hnati&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komarova</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu&#x10d;ivjansk&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nalimov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization group calculation of dynamic exponent in the models E
  and F with hydrodynamic fluctuations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, presented at 16th Czech and Slovak Conference on Magnetism
  (CSMAG'16) in Kosice, Slovakia</comments><journal-ref>Acta Physica Polonica A 131(4), 651 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.12693/APhysPolA.131.651</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The renormalization group method is applied in order to analyze models E and
F of critical dynamics in the presence of velocity fluctuations generated by
the stochastic Navier-Stokes equation. Results are given to the one-loop
approximation for the anomalous dimension $\gamma_\lambda$ and fixed-points'
structure. The dynamic exponent $z$ is calculated in the turbulent regime and
stability of the fixed points for the standard model E is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06114</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2017-04-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hirsch</keyname><forenames>Flavien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quintino</keyname><forenames>Marco T&#xfa;lio</forenames></author><author><keyname>V&#xe9;rtesi</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navascu&#xe9;s</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunner</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Better local hidden variable models for two-qubit Werner states and an
  upper bound on the Grothendieck constant $K_G(3)$</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages, typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Quantum 1, 3 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-04-25-3</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of reproducing the correlations obtained by arbitrary
local projective measurements on the two-qubit Werner state $\rho = v |\psi_- &gt;
&lt;\psi_- | + (1- v ) \frac{1}{4}$ via a local hidden variable (LHV) model, where
$|\psi_- &gt;$ denotes the singlet state. We show analytically that these
correlations are local for $ v = 999\times689\times{10^{-6}}$ $\cos^4(\pi/50)
\simeq 0.6829$. In turn, as this problem is closely related to a purely
mathematical one formulated by Grothendieck, our result implies a new bound on
the Grothendieck constant $K_G(3) \leq 1/v \simeq 1.4644$. We also present a
LHV model for reproducing the statistics of arbitrary POVMs on the Werner state
for $v \simeq 0.4553$. The techniques we develop can be adapted to construct
LHV models for other entangled states, as well as bounding other Grothendieck
constants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08284</id><created>2016-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Legrain</keyname><forenames>Fleur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>A First-Principles Comparative Study of Lithium, Sodium, and Magnesium
  Storage in Pure and Gallium-Doped Germanium: Competition between Interstitial
  and Substitutional Sites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys., 146, 034706 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973841</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermodynamics and kinetics of Li, Na, and Mg storage in Ge is studied ab
initio. The most stable configurations can consist of tetrahedral,
substitutional, or a combination of the two types of sites. In the dilute
limit, Li, Na prefer interstitial, while Mg prefers substitutional sites. At
higher concentrations of Li, Na, and Mg, there is a combination of interstitial
and substitutional sites. This is an important finding, as previous ab initio
studies of alloying type electrode materials ignored substitutional sites.
Insertion energies computed at dilute concentration (x = 1/64) show that Na and
Mg insertion are not thermodynamically favored in Ge vs formation of bulk Na
and Mg, as opposed to Li insertion which is favored. We investigate the effect
of p-doping of Ge (with Ga) on the thermodynamics and find that it considerably
lowers the defect formation energies associated with the insertion of Li/Na/Mg
at tetrahedral sites. On the other hand, the energetics associated with
Li/Na/Mg insertion at substitutional sites are not significantly affected. In
addition, we compute the migration energy barriers for Li/Na/Mg diffusion
between two tetrahedral sites (0.38/0.79/0.66 eV), between two substitutional
sites (0.77/0.93/1.83 eV), and between two sites of different type
(2.15/1.75/0.85 eV).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01399</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2017-03-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lipunova</keyname><forenames>G. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malanchev</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the turbulent parameter in the accretion disks: effects
  of self-irradiation in 4U 1543-47 during the 2002 outburst</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. Code Freddi
  is publicly available at http://xray.sai.msu.ru/~malanchev/freddi/</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2017) 468 (4): 4735-4747</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx768</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the viscous evolution of the accretion disk in 4U 1543-47, a
black hole binary system, during the first 30 days after the peak of the 2002
burst by comparing the observed and theoretical accretion rate evolution $\dot
M(t)$. The observed $\dot M(t)$ is obtained from spectral modelling of the
archival RXTE/PCA data. Different scenarios of disk decay evolution are
possible depending on a degree of self-irradiation of the disk by the emission
from its centre. If the self-irradiation, which is parametrized by factor
$C_\mathrm{irr}$, had been as high as $\sim 5\times10^{-3}$, then the disk
would have been completely ionized up to the tidal radius and the short time of
the decay would have required the turbulent parameter $\alpha\sim 3$. We find
that the shape of the $\dot M(t)$ curve is much better explained in a model
with a shrinking high-viscosity zone. If $C_\mathrm{irr}\approx(2-3)\times
10^{-4}$, the resulting $\alpha$ lie in the interval $0.5-1.5$ for the black
hole masses in the range $6-10~\mathrm{M}_\odot$, while the radius of the
ionized disk is variable and controlled by irradiation. For very weak
irradiation, $C_\mathrm{irr} &lt; 1.5 \times10^{-4}$, the burst decline develops
as in normal outbursts of dwarf novae with $\alpha \sim 0.08-0.32$. The optical
data indicate that $C_\mathrm{irr}$ in 4U 1543-47 (2002) was not greater than
approximately $(3-6)\times10^{-4}$. Generally, modelling of an X-ray nova burst
allows one to estimate $\alpha$ that depends on the black hole parameters. We
present the public 1-D code Freddi to model the viscous evolution of an
accretion disk. Analytic approximations are derived to estimate $\alpha$ in
X-ray novae using $\dot M(t)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01457</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Krasnov</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Dual Gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>v2: published version, minor changes, 28 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 095001, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa65e5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-dual gravity is a diffeomorphism invariant theory in four dimensions
that describes two propagating polarisations of the graviton and has a negative
mass dimension coupling constant. Nevertheless, this theory is not only
renormalisable but quantum finite, as we explain. We also collect various facts
about self-dual gravity that are scattered across the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05090</id><created>2016-10-17</created><updated>2017-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Run-Qiu</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong energy condition and complexity growth bound in holography</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Changed title, improved expressions and proofs</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 086017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.086017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proves that if eternal neutral black holes satisfy some general
conditions and matter fields only appear in the outside of the Killing horizon,
the strong energy condition is a sufficient condition to insure that the vacuum
Schwarzschild black hole has the fastest action growth of the same total
energy. This result is consistent with the bound of computational complexity
growth rate and gives a strong evidence for the holographic complexity-action
conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08669</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandner</keyname><forenames>Kay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maisi</keyname><forenames>Ville F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pekola</keyname><forenames>Jukka P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrahan</keyname><forenames>Juan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flindt</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Determination of Dynamical Lee-Yang Zeros</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, final version as published in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 180601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.180601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Statistical physics provides the concepts and methods to explain the phase
behavior of interacting many-body systems. Investigations of Lee-Yang zeros ---
complex singularities of the free energy in systems of finite size --- have led
to a unified understanding of equilibrium phase transitions. The ideas of Lee
and Yang, however, are not restricted to equilibrium phenomena. Recently,
Lee-Yang zeros have been used to characterize non-equilibrium processes such as
dynamical phase transitions in quantum systems after a quench or dynamic
order-disorder transitions in glasses. Here, we experimentally realize a scheme
for determining Lee-Yang zeros in such non-equilibrium settings. We extract the
dynamical Lee-Yang zeros of a stochastic process involving Andreev tunneling
between a normal-state island and two superconducting leads from measurements
of the dynamical activity along a trajectory. From the short-time behavior of
the Lee-Yang zeros, we predict the large-deviation statistics of the activity
which is typically difficult to measure. Our method paves the way for further
experiments on the statistical mechanics of many-body systems out of
equilibrium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08958</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clarke</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sau</keyname><forenames>Jay D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Sankar Das</forenames></author></authors><title>Probability and (Braiding) Statistics in Majorana nanowires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, Updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 155451 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.155451</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given recent progress in the realization of Majorana zero modes in
semiconducting nanowires with proximity-induced superconductivity, a crucial
next step is to attempt an experimental demonstration of the predicted braiding
statistics associated with the Majorana mode. Such a demonstration should, in
principle, confirm that observed zero-bias anomalies are indeed indicative of
the presence of anyonic Majorana zero modes. Moreover, such a demonstration
would be a breakthrough at the level of fundamental physics: the first clear
demonstration of a non-Abelian excitation. It is therefore important to clarify
the expected signals of Majorana physics in the braiding context, and to
differentiate these signals from those that might also arise in non-topological
variants of the same system. A definitive and critical distinction between
signals expected in topological (i.e. anyonic) and non-topological (i.e.
trivial) situations is therefore essential for future progress in the field. In
this manuscript, we carefully examine the expected signals of braiding and
fusion experiments in topological and non-topological variants of the
experimental nanowire systems in which Majoranas are predicted to occur. We
point out situations where `trivial' and `anyonic' signatures may be similar
experimentally, necessitating a certain level of caution in the interpretation
of various proposed fusion and braiding experiments. We find in particular that
braiding experiments consisting of full braids (two Majorana exchanges) are
better at distinguishing between topological and non-topological systems than
fusion experiments or experiments with an odd number of Majorana exchanges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09382</id><created>2016-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Fontecilla</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuadra</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author></authors><title>A Second Decoupling Between Merging Binary Black Holes and the Inner
  Disc--Impact on the Electromagnetic Counterpart</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>Submitted. Comments welcome!</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 468, L50 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw258</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The coalescence of two supermassive black holes (SMBHs) produces powerful
gravitational-wave (GW) radiation and, if gas is present in the vicinity, also
an electromagnetic (EM) counterpart. In the standard picture, an EM outburst
will be produced when the binary &quot;decouples&quot; from the circum-binary disc and
starts &quot;squeezing&quot; the disc inside the secondary orbit, resulting in its quick
accretion on to the primary black hole. Here we use analytical arguments and
numerical simulations to show that the disc within about $20~R_S$ of a SMBH
survives the merger without being depleted. The reason is a &quot;second
decoupling&quot;: the inner disc thickens due to tidal heating and inefficient
cooling, effectively decoupling from the interaction of the binary. We show
that this second decoupling quenches the heating sources in the disc ${\cal
O}(10^2)$ days before coalescence. This will render the peak UV/X-ray
luminosity significantly weaker than previously thought. After the merger, the
residual disc cools down and expands, merging with the outer disc rather than
being completely accreted. This results in continuous EM emission, hindering
the detection of the cut-off and re-brightening proposed in earlier studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06586</id><created>2016-11-20</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>High-$E_{\rm T}$ isolated-photon plus jets production in $pp$ collisions
  at $\sqrt s=$ 8 TeV with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>59 pages in total, author list starting page 43, 16 figures, 5
  tables, submitted to Nuclear Physics B, All figures including auxiliary
  figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2015-11/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-252</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B 918 (2017) 257</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.03.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of isolated-photon plus one-, two- and three-jet production in
$pp$ collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV are studied with the ATLAS
detector at the LHC using a data set with an integrated luminosity of 20.2
fb$^{-1}$. Measurements of isolated-photon plus jets cross sections are
presented as functions of the photon and jet transverse momenta. The cross
sections as functions of the azimuthal angle between the photon and the jets,
the azimuthal angle between the jets, the photon-jet invariant mass and the
scattering angle in the photon-jet centre-of-mass system are presented. The
pattern of QCD radiation around the photon and the leading jet is investigated
by measuring jet production in an annular region centred on each object;
enhancements are observed around the leading jet with respect to the photon in
the directions towards the beams. The experimental measurements are compared to
several different theoretical calculations, and overall a good description of
the data is found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08684</id><created>2016-11-26</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hadronically decaying heavy dark matter and high-energy neutrino limits</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, minor corrections in text, results unchanged,
  published in JETP Letters</comments><report-no>INR-TH-2016-042</report-no><doi>10.1134/S0021364017090028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider dark matter consisting of long--living particles with masses
$10^{7}~\lesssim~M~\lesssim~10^{16}$ GeV decaying through hadronic channel as a
source of high energy neutrino. Using recent data on high energy neutrino from
IceCube and Pierre Auger experiments we derive the upper-limits on neutrino
flux from dark matter decay and constraints on dark matter parameter space. For
the dark matter masses of order $10^8$ GeV the constraints derived are slightly
stronger than those obtained for the same dark matter model using the high
energy gamma-ray limits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06416</id><created>2016-12-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Shepard</keyname><forenames>Gabriella D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ajayi</keyname><forenames>Obafunso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiangzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hone</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strauf</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanobubble induced formation of quantum emitters in monolayer
  semiconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4, 021019 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/aa629d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent discovery of exciton quantum emitters in transition metal
dichalcogenides (TMDCs) has triggered renewed interest of localized excitons in
low-dimensional systems. Open questions remain about the microscopic origin
previously attributed to dopants and/or defects as well as strain potentials.
Here we show that the quantum emitters can be deliberately induced by
nanobubble formation in WSe2 and BN/WSe2 heterostructures. Correlations of
atomic-force microscope and hyperspectral photoluminescence images reveal that
the origin of quantum emitters and trion disorder is extrinsic and related to
10 nm tall nanobubbles and 70 nm tall wrinkles, respectively. We further
demonstrate that hot stamping results in the absence of 0D quantum emitters and
trion disorder. The demonstrated technique is useful for advances in nanolasers
and deterministic formation of cavity-QED systems in monolayer materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06814</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-03-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shekhter</keyname><forenames>Arkady</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modic</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDonald</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramshaw</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic constraints on the amplitude of quantum oscillations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>PRB Rapid commun. (2017)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 121106 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.121106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magneto-quantum oscillation experiments in high temperature superconductors
show a strong thermally-induced suppression of the oscillation amplitude
approaching critical dopings---in support of a quantum critical origin of their
phase diagrams. We suggest that, in addition to a thermodynamic mass
enhancement, these experiments may directly indicate the increasing role of
quantum fluctuations that suppress the oscillation amplitude through inelastic
scattering. We show that the traditional theoretical approaches beyond
Lifshitz-Kosevich to calculate the oscillation amplitude in correlated metals
result in a contradiction with the third law of thermodynamics and suggest a
way to rectify this problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07827</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07827</id><created>2016-12-22</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Camporeale</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agnihotri</keyname><forenames>Ashutosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rutjes</keyname><forenames>Casper</forenames></author></authors><title>Adaptive selection of sampling points for Uncertainty Quantification</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 15 figures; to appear in Int. J. Uncertainty Quantification</comments><doi>10.1615/Int.J.UncertaintyQuantification.2017020027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple and robust strategy for the selection of sampling points
in Uncertainty Quantification. The goal is to achieve the fastest possible
convergence in the cumulative distribution function of a stochastic output of
interest. We assume that the output of interest is the outcome of a
computationally expensive nonlinear mapping of an input random variable, whose
probability density function is known. We use a radial function basis to
construct an accurate interpolant of the mapping. This strategy enables adding
new sampling points one at a time, adaptively. This takes into full account the
previous evaluations of the target nonlinear function. We present comparisons
with a stochastic collocation method based on the Clenshaw-Curtis quadrature
rule, and with an adaptive method based on hierarchical surplus, showing that
the new method often results in a large computational saving.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08782</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08782</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Ching-Hwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Chuanhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct identification of monolayer rhenium diselenide by an individual
  diffraction pattern</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s12274-017-1639-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the current extensive studies of transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs),
compared to hexagonal layered materials, like graphene, hBN and MoS2, low
symmetry layered 2D crystals showed great potential for applications in
anisotropic devices. Rhenium diselenide (ReSe2) has the bulk space group P1 and
belongs to triclinic crystal system with a deformed cadmium iodide type
structure. Here we unambiguously determined monolayer and its vertical
orientation of rhenium diselenide membrane with an individual electron
diffraction pattern, which could be applicable to low symmetry crystal systems,
including both triclinic and monoclinic lattices, as long as their third
unit-cell basis vector is not perpendicular to basal plane. Atomically resolved
image from probe corrected annular dark field scanning transmission electron
microscope (ADF-STEM) was employed to validate layer number. Finally,
experimental results were well explained by kinematical electron diffraction
theory and corresponding simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01524</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Brian Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagenbreth</keyname><forenames>Gene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Mayor</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hen</keyname><forenames>Itay</forenames></author></authors><title>Advantages of Unfair Quantum Ground-State Sampling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 1044 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-01096-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The debate around the potential superiority of quantum annealers over their
classical counterparts has been ongoing since the inception of the field by
Kadowaki and Nishimori close to two decades ago. Recent technological
breakthroughs in the field, which have led to the manufacture of experimental
prototypes of quantum annealing optimizers with sizes approaching the practical
regime, have reignited this discussion. However, the demonstration of quantum
annealing speedups remains to this day an elusive albeit coveted goal. Here, we
examine the power of quantum annealers to provide a different type of quantum
enhancement of practical relevance, namely, their ability to serve as useful
samplers from the ground-state manifolds of combinatorial optimization
problems. We study, both numerically by simulating ideal stoquastic and
non-stoquastic quantum annealing processes, and experimentally, using a
commercially available quantum annealing processor, the ability of quantum
annealers to sample the ground-states of spin glasses differently than
classical thermal samplers. We demonstrate that i) quantum annealers in general
sample the ground-state manifolds of spin glasses very differently than thermal
optimizers, ii) the nature of the quantum fluctuations driving the annealing
process has a decisive effect on the final distribution over ground-states, and
iii) the experimental quantum annealer samples ground-state manifolds
significantly differently than thermal and ideal quantum annealers. We
illustrate how quantum annealers may serve as powerful tools when complementing
standard sampling algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01855</id><created>2017-01-07</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malinowski</keyname><forenames>Filip K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>Frederico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cywi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;ukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudner</keyname><forenames>Mark S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nissen</keyname><forenames>Peter D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallahi</keyname><forenames>Saeed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardner</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfra</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcus</keyname><forenames>Charles M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuemmeth</keyname><forenames>Ferdinand</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectrum of the Nuclear Environment for GaAs Spin Qubits</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 8 pages of supplementary material, 5
  supplementary figures</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV CMT 2017</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 177702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.177702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a singlet-triplet spin qubit as a sensitive spectrometer of the GaAs
nuclear spin bath, we demonstrate that the spectrum of Overhauser noise agrees
with a classical spin diffusion model over six orders of magnitude in
frequency, from 1 mHz to 1 kHz, is flat below 10 mHz, and falls as $1/f^2$ for
frequency $f \! \gtrsim \! 1$ Hz. Increasing the applied magnetic field from
0.1 T to 0.75 T suppresses electron-mediated spin diffusion, which decreases
spectral content in the $1/f^2$ region and lowers the saturation frequency,
each by an order of magnitude, consistent with a numerical model. Spectral
content at megahertz frequencies is accessed using dynamical decoupling, which
shows a crossover from the few-pulse regime ($\lesssim \! 16$ $\pi$-pulses),
where transverse Overhauser fluctuations dominate dephasing, to the many-pulse
regime ($\gtrsim \! 32$ $\pi$-pulses), where longitudinal Overhauser
fluctuations with a $1/f$ spectrum dominate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04138</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schmidtt</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable Lambda Models And Chern-Simons Theories</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages. Published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2017)012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we reveal a connection between the phase space of lambda models
on $S^{1}\times \mathbb{R}$ and the phase space of double Chern-Simons theories
on $D\times \mathbb{R}$ and explain in the process the origin of the
non-ultralocality of the Maillet bracket, which emerges as a boundary algebra.
In particular, this means that the (classical) $AdS_{5}\times S^{5}$ lambda
model can be understood as a double Chern-Simons theory defined on the Lie
superalgebra $\mathfrak{psu}(2,2|4)$ after a proper dependence of the spectral
parameter is introduced. This offers a possibility for avoiding the use of the
problematic non-ultralocal Poisson algebras that preclude the introduction of
lattice regularizations and the application of the QISM to string sigma models.
The utility of the equivalence at the quantum level is, however, still to be
explored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04761</id><created>2017-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Pace</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Said</keyname><forenames>Jackson Levi</forenames></author></authors><title>Quark Stars in $f(T, \mathcal{T})-$Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><report-no>EPJC-16-10-080.R1</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 62</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4637-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a working model for the Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff equation for
quark star systems within the modified $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity class of
models. We consider $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity for a static spherically
symmetric space-time. In this instance the metric is built from a more
fundamental tetrad vierbein from which the metric tensor can be derived. We
impose a linear $f(T)$ parameter parameter, namely taking $f=\alpha T(r) +
\beta \mathcal{T}(r) + \varphi$ and investigate the behavior of a linear
energy-momentum tensor trace, $\mathcal{T}$. We also outline the restrictions
which modified $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity imposes upon the coupling
parameters. Finally we incorporate the MIT bag model in order to derive the
mass-radius and mass-central density relations of the quark star within $f(T,
\mathcal{T})$-gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06615</id><created>2017-01-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Altrock</keyname><forenames>Philipp M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traulsen</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>Martin A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolutionary games on cycles with strong selection</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>5 Figures. Accepted for publication (Physical Review E)</comments><msc-class>60J10, 92D25</msc-class><journal-ref>Physical Review E 95, 022407 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.022407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Evolutionary games on graphs describe how strategic interactions and
population structure determine evolutionary success, quantified by the
probability that a single mutant takes over a population. Graph structures,
compared to the well-mixed case, can act as amplifiers or suppressors of
selection by increasing or decreasing the fixation probability of a beneficial
mutant. Properties of the associated mean fixation times can be more intricate,
especially when selection is strong. The intuition is that fixation of a
beneficial mutant happens fast (in a dominance game), that fixation takes very
long (in a coexistence game), and that strong selection eliminates demographic
noise. Here we show that these intuitions can be misleading in structured
populations. We analyze mean fixation times on the cycle graph under strong
frequency-dependent selection for two different microscopic evolutionary update
rules (death-birth and birth-death). We establish exact analytical results for
fixation times under strong selection, and show that there are coexistence
games in which fixation occurs in time polynomial in population size. Depending
on the underlying game, we observe inherence of demographic noise even under
strong selection, if the process is driven by random death before selection for
birth of an offspring (death-birth update). In contrast, if selection for an
offspring occurs before random removal (birth-death update), strong selection
can remove demographic noise almost entirely.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07049</id><created>2017-01-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>Paul C</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Sandeep</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin mediated enhanced negative magnetoresistance in Ni80Fe20 and
  p-silicon bilayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages 4 main figures and 2 supplementary figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2017.05.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present an experimental study of spin mediated enhanced
negative magnetoresistance in Ni80Fe20 (50 nm)/p-Si (350 nm) bilayer. The
resistance measurement shows a reduction of ~2.5% for the bilayer specimen as
compared to 1.3% for Ni80Fe20 (50 nm) on oxide specimen for an out-of-plane
applied magnetic field of 3T. In the Ni80Fe20-only film, the negative
magnetoresistance behavior is attributed to anisotropic magnetoresistance. We
propose that spin polarization due to spin-Hall effect is the underlying cause
of the enhanced negative magnetoresistance observed in the bilayer. Silicon has
weak spin orbit coupling so spin Hall magnetoresistance measurement is not
feasible. We use V2{\omega} and V3{\omega} measurement as a function of
magnetic field and angular rotation of magnetic field in direction normal to
electric current to elucidate the spin-Hall effect. The angular rotation of
magnetic field shows a sinusoidal behavior for both V2{\omega} and V3{\omega},
which is attributed to the spin phonon interactions resulting from the
spin-Hall effect mediated spin polarization. We propose that the spin
polarization leads to a decrease in hole-phonon scattering resulting in
enhanced negative magnetoresistance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01555</id><created>2017-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzhos</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>On the oxidation state of titanium in titanium dioxide</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. Lett., 2017, 8, pp 1593-1598</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b00313</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The oxidation state of titanium in titanium dioxide is commonly assumed to be
+4. This assumption is used ubiquitously to rationalize phenomena observed with
TiO2. We present a comprehensive electronic structure investigation of Ti ions,
TiO2 molecules and TiO2 bulk crystals, using different density functional
theory and wave function-based approaches, which suggests a lower oxidation
state (+3). Specifically, there is evidence of a significant remaining
contribution from valence s and d electrons of Ti, including the presence of a
nuclear cusp around the Ti core. The charge corresponding to valence s and d
states of Ti amounts to 1 e. The commonly assumed picture may therefore have to
be revised.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05820</id><created>2017-02-19</created><updated>2017-02-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vicent</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochoa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guinea</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin relaxation in corrugated graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 + epsilon pages; 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 195402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In graphene, out-of-plane (flexural) vibrations and static ripples imposed by
the substrate relax the electron spin, intrinsically protected by mirror
symmetry. We calculate the relaxation times in different scenarios, accounting
for all the possible spin-phonon couplings allowed by the hexagonal symmetry of
the lattice. Scattering by flexural phonons imposes the ultimate bound to the
spin lifetimes, in the ballpark of hundreds of nano-seconds at room
temperature. This estimate and the behavior as a function of the carrier
concentration are substantially altered by the presence of tensions or the
pinning with the substrate. Static ripples also influence the spin transport in
the diffusive regime, dominated by motional narrowing. We find that the
D'yakonov-Perel' mechanism saturates when the mean free path is comparable to
the correlation length of the heights profile. In this regime, the
spin-relaxation times are exclusively determined by the geometry of the
corrugations. Simple models for typical corrugations lead to lifetimes of the
order of tens of micro-seconds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.07512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.07512</id><created>2017-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Hayatsu</keyname><forenames>N. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umehata</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smail</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swinbank</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivison</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohno</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iono</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsukade</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakanishi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabe</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagao</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inoue</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>T. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujimoto</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izumi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikarashi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>ALMA Deep Field in SSA22: Blindly Detected CO Emitters and [CII] Emitter
  Candidates</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures. Accepted to PASJ</comments><doi>10.1093/pasj/psx018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the identification of four millimeter line emitting galaxies with
the Atacama Large Milli/submillimeter Array (ALMA) in SSA22 Field (ADF22). We
analyze the ALMA 1.1 mm survey data, with an effective survey area of 5
arcmin$^2$, a frequency range of 253.1--256.8 and 269.1--272.8 GHz, angular
resolution of 0&quot;.7 and RMS noise of 0.8 mJy beam$^{-1}$ at 36 km s$^{-1}$
velocity resolution. We detect four line emitter candidates with significance
levels above $6 \sigma$. We identify one of the four sources as a CO(9-8)
emitter at $z = 3.1$ in a member of the proto-cluster known in this field.
Another line emitter with an optical counterpart is likely a CO(4-3) emitter at
$z = 0.7$. The other two sources without any millimeter continuum or
optical/near-infrared counterpart are likely to be [CII] emitter candidates at
$z = 6.0$ and $6.5$. The equivalent widths of the [CII] candidates are
consistent with those of confirmed high-redshift [CII] emitters and candidates,
and are a factor of 10 times larger than that of the CO(9-8) emitter detected
in this search. The [CII] luminosity of the candidates are $4-7 \times 10^8~\rm
L_\odot$. The star formation rates (SFRs) of these sources are estimated to be
$10-20~\rm M_{\odot}~yr^{-1}$ if we adopt an empirical [CII] luminosity - SFR
relation. One of them has a relatively low-S/N ratio, but shows features
characteristic of emission lines. Assuming that at least one of the two
candidates is a [CII] emitter, we derive a lower limit of [CII]-based star
formation rate density (SFRD) at $z~\sim~6$. The resulting value of $&gt; 10^{-2}$
$\rm M_\odot yr^{-1} Mpc^{-3}$ is consistent with the dust-uncorrected UV-based
SFRD. Future millimeter/submillimeter surveys can be used to detect a number of
high redshift line emitters, with which to study the star formation history in
the early Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00809</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hurst</keyname><forenames>Hilary M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efimkin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spielman</keyname><forenames>I. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galitski</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic theory of dark solitons with tunable friction</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 figures, 14 pages incl. appendices</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053604 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study controllable friction in a system consisting of a dark soliton in a
one-dimensional Bose-Einstein condensate coupled to a non-interacting Fermi
gas. The fermions act as impurity atoms, not part of the original condensate,
that scatter off of the soliton. We study semi-classical dynamics of the dark
soliton, a particle-like object with negative mass, and calculate its friction
coefficient. Surprisingly, it depends periodically on the ratio of interspecies
(impurity-condensate) to intraspecies (condensate-condensate) interaction
strengths. By tuning this ratio, one can access a regime where the friction
coefficient vanishes. We develop a general theory of stochastic dynamics for
negative mass objects and find that their dynamics are drastically different
from their positive mass counterparts - they do not undergo Brownian motion.
From the exact phase space probability distribution function (i.e. in position
and velocity), we find that both the trajectory and lifetime of the soliton are
altered by friction, and the soliton can only undergo Brownian motion in the
presence of friction and a confining potential. These results agree
qualitatively with experimental observations by Aycock, et. al. (PNAS, 2017) in
a similar system with bosonic impurity scatterers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01154</id><created>2017-03-03</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xueyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>De-Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Xing-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ya-Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Hai-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>New zirconium hydrides predicted by structure search method based on
  first principles calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation of precipitated zirconium (Zr) hydrides is closely related to
the hydrogen embrittlement problem for the cladding materials of pressured
water reactors (PWR). In this work, we systematically investigated the crystal
structures of zirconium hydride (ZrHx) with different hydrogen concentrations
(x = 0~2, atomic ratio) by combining the basin hopping algorithm with first
principles calculations. We conclude that the P3m1 {\zeta}-ZrH0.5 is
dynamically unstable, while a novel dynamically stable P3m1 ZrH0.5 structure
was discovered in the structure search. The stability of bistable P42/nnm
ZrH1.5 structures and I4/mmm ZrH2 structures are also revisited. We find that
the P42/nnm (c/a &gt; 1) ZrH1.5 is dynamically unstable, while the I4/mmm (c/a =
1.57) ZrH2 is dynamically stable.The P42/nnm (c/a &lt; 1) ZrH1.5 might be a key
intermediate phase for the transition of {\gamma}-&gt;{\delta}-&gt;{\epsilon} phases.
Additionally, by using the thermal dynamic simulations, we find that
{\delta}-ZrH1.5 is the most stable structure at high temperature while ZrH2 is
the most stable hydride at low temperature. Slow cooling process will promote
the formation of {\delta}-ZrH1.5, and fast cooling process will promote the
formation of {\gamma}-ZrH. These results may help to understand the phase
transitions of zirconium hydrides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01667</id><created>2017-03-05</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramirez</keyname><forenames>Marlon David Gonzalez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falaye</keyname><forenames>Babatunde James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Guo-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cruz-Irisson</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum teleportation and information splitting via four-qubit cluster
  state and a Bell state</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Front. Phys. 12(5), 120306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11467-017-0684-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum teleportation provides a `bodiless' way of transmitting the quantum
state from one object to another, at a distant location, using a classical
communication channel and a previously shared entangled state. In this paper,
we present a tripartite scheme for probabilistic teleportation of an arbitrary
single qubit state, without losing the information of the state being
teleported, via a four-qubit cluster state of the form
$\left.|{\phi}\right\rangle_{1234}=\left.\alpha|0000\right\rangle+\left.\beta|1010\right\rangle+\left.\gamma|0101\right\rangle-\eta\left.|1111\right\rangle$,
as the quantum channel, where the nonzero real numbers $\alpha$, $\beta$,
$\gamma$, and $\eta$ satisfy the relation
$|\alpha|^2+|\beta|^2+|\gamma|^2+|\eta|^2=1$. With the introduction of an
auxiliary qubit with state $\left|0\right\rangle$, using a suitable unitary
transformation and a positive-operator valued measure (POVM), the receiver can
recreate the state of the original qubit. An important advantage of the
teleportation scheme demonstrated here is that, if the teleportation fails, it
can be repeated without teleporting copies of the unknown quantum state, if the
concerned parties share another pair of entangled qubit. We also present a
protocol for quantum information splitting of an arbitrary two-particle system
via the aforementioned cluster state and a Bell-state as the quantum channel.
Problems related to security attacks were examined for both the cases and it
was found that this protocol is secure. This protocol is highly efficient and
easy to implement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01998</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Madeira</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gandolfi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Kevin E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Core structure of two-dimensional Fermi gas vortices in the BEC-BCS
  crossover region</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>LA-UR-17-21896</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 053603 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.053603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report $T=0$ diffusion Monte Carlo results for the ground-state and vortex
excitation of unpolarized spin-1/2 fermions in a two-dimensional disk. We
investigate how vortex core structure properties behave over the BEC-BCS
crossover. We calculate the vortex excitation energy, density profiles, and
vortex core properties related to the current. We find a density suppression at
the vortex core on the BCS side of the crossover, and a depleted core on the
BEC limit. Size-effect dependencies in the disk geometry were carefully
studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06010</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aguar</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>Charles C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beltran</keyname><forenames>Diego Boada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Safaei</keyname><forenames>Saeid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asefi</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portes</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arabnia</keyname><forenames>Hamid R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>Juan B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Considerations on Interdisciplinary Instruction and Design Influenced by
  Adaptive Learning. A Case Study Involving Biology, Computer Science,
  Mathematics, and Statistics</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures. Version 2 of this document had a minor change in
  the title</comments><msc-class>97A99, 97P99</msc-class><acm-class>K.3.1</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ALICE (Adaptive Learning for Interdisciplinary Collaborative Environments) is
an open-source web based adaptive learning system designed for
interdisciplinary instruction. ALICE has the potential to transform education
by empowering transdisciplinary knowledge acquisition. This is particularly
important in fields that accept newcomers with diverse scholastic backgrounds,
e.g. Systems Biology. With traditional interdisciplinary instruction, the
instructor must cover pre-requisite information from multiple disciplines to
ensure all students begin at a common baseline - slowing the learning process.
With ALICE, students follow a personalized syllabus based on their previous
knowledge and work towards individual goals. Implementing an adaptive learning
system in an interdisciplinary course requires careful considerations of the
instructional design. Structuring material, formulating assessments, and other
instructional design aspects must be carefully considered. These considerations
are detailed through the exploration of a case study implementing ALICE in a
graduate level Systems Biology course.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10865</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Skenderis</keyname><forenames>Kostas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Withers</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Robinson-Trautman spacetimes and gauge/gravity duality</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Proceedings prepared for the &quot;Workshop on Geometry and Physics&quot; in
  memoriam of Ioannis Bakas, November 2016, Ringberg Castle, Germany. v2: Minor
  changes, added discussion of isotropisation time</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study far-from-equilibrium field theory dynamics using gauge/gravity
duality applied to the Robinson-Trautman (RT) class of spacetimes and we
present a number of new results. First, we assess the applicability of the
hydrodynamic approximation to inhomogeneous plasma dynamics dual to RT
spacetimes. We prove that to any order in a late time expansion it is possible
to identify variables corresponding to the local energy density and fluid
velocity. However, we show using numerical examples that this does not hold at
the non-perturbative level; for sufficiently inhomogeneous initial data a local
rest frame does not exist. Second, we preset a new class of holographic
inhomogeneous plasma flows on the plane. The corresponding spacetimes are not
of the RT type but they can be obtained from RT spacetimes with spatially
compact boundaries by coordinate transformations which generate Poincar\'e
patch-like coordinates with planar boundaries. We demonstrate the application
of this procedure using numerical examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00548</id><created>2017-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Schweiner</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Main</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wunner</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uihlein</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>The even exciton series in Cu$_2$O</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 195201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.195201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In $\mathrm{Cu_{2}O}$ parity is a good quantum number and thus the exciton
spectrum falls into two parts: The dipole-active exciton states of negative
parity and odd angular momentum, which can be observed in one-photon absorption
($\Gamma_4^-$ symmetry) and the exciton states of positive parity and even
angular momentum, which can be observed in two-photon absorption ($\Gamma_5^+$
symmetry). The unexpected observation of $D$ excitons in two-photon absorption
and of $F$ excitons in one-photon absorption has given evidence that the
dispersion properties of the $\Gamma_5^+$ orbital valence band is giving rise
to a coupling of the yellow and green exciton series. In this paper we show
that the even and odd parity exciton system can be consistently described
within the same theoretical approach. However, the Hamiltonian of the even
parity system needs, in comparison to the odd exciton case, modifications to
account for the very small radius of the $1S$ exciton. In the presented
treatment we take special care of the central-cell corrections, which comprise
a reduced screening of the Coulomb potential at distances comparable to the
polaron radius, the exchange interaction being responsible for the exciton
splitting into ortho and para states, and the inclusion of terms in the fourth
power of $p$ in the kinetic energy. Since the yellow $1S$ exciton state is
coupled to all other states of positive parity, we show how the central-cell
corrections affect the whole even exciton series. The close resonance of the
$1S$ green exciton with states of the yellow exciton series has a strong impact
on the energies and oscillator strengths of all implied states. The consistency
between theory and experiment with respect to energies and oscillator strengths
for the even and odd exciton system in $\mathrm{Cu_{2}O}$ is a convincing proof
for the validity of the applied theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01789</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gr&#xe4;ser</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knopp</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szwargulski</keyname><forenames>Patryk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Gladiss</keyname><forenames>Anselm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaul</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krishnan</keyname><forenames>Kannan M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ittrich</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adam</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzug</keyname><forenames>Thorsten M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Picogram Detection of Superparamagnetic Iron-Oxide Particles
  Using a Gradiometric Receive Coil</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>15 Pages, 7 Figures, V2: Changed the initials of Author Kannan M
  Krishnan, added two citations, corrected typos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superparamagnetic iron-oxide nanoparticles can be used in a variety of
medical applications like vascular or targeted imaging. Magnetic particle
imaging (MPI) is a promising tomographic imaging technique that allows
visualizing the 3D nanoparticle distribution concentration in a non-invasive
manner. The two main strengths of MPI are high temporal resolution and high
sensitivity. While the first has been proven in the assessment of dynamic
processes like cardiac imaging, it is unknown how far the detection limit of
MPI can be lowered. Within this work, we will present a highly sensitive
gradiometric receive-coil unit combined with a noise-matching network tailored
for the measurement of mice. The setup is capable of detecting 5 ng of iron in
vitro at 2.14 sec acquisition time. In terms of iron concentration we are able
to detect 156 {\mu}g/L marking the lowest value that has been reported for an
MPI scanner so far. In vivo MPI mouse images of a 512 ng bolus at 21.5 ms
acquisition time allow for capturing the flow of an intravenously injected
tracer through the heart of a mouse. Since it has been rather difficult to
compare detection limits across MPI publications we propose guidelines
improving the comparability of future MPI studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01986</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>De-Chang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stojkovic</keyname><forenames>Dejan</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal temperature of the gas in AdS space-time</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Published in Phys.Rev. D95 (2017) no.8, 085015</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D95 (2017) no.8, 085015</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.085015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assuming only statistical mechanics and general relativity, we calculate the
maximal temperature of gas of particles placed in AdS space-time. If two
particles with a given center of mass energy come close enough, according to
classical gravity they will form a black hole. We focus only on the black holes
with Hawking temperature lower than the environment, because they do not
disappear. The number density of such black holes grows with the temperature in
the system. At a certain finite temperature, the thermodynamical system will be
dominated by black holes. This critical temperature is lower than the Planck
temperature for the values of the AdS vacuum energy density below the Planck
density. This result might be interesting from the AdS/CFT correspondence point
of view, since it is different from the Hawking-Page phase transition, and it
is not immediately clear what effect dynamically limits the maximal temperature
of the thermal state on the CFT side of the correspondence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02326</id><created>2017-04-07</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ngo</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>Heather A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bryan</keyname><forenames>Marta L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blunt</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Eric L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batygin</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowler</keyname><forenames>Brendan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crepp</keyname><forenames>Justin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinkley</keyname><forenames>Sasha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howard</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mawet</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames></author></authors><title>No difference in orbital parameters of RV-detected giant planets between
  0.1 and 5 au in single vs multi-stellar systems</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>34 pages, 10 figures, 16 tables, including 4 tables in machine
  readable format and 7 tables with online supplemental data</comments><journal-ref>The Astronomical Journal, 153, 242 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/aa6cac</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our Keck/NIRC2 imaging survey searches for stellar companions around 144
systems with radial velocity (RV) detected giant planets to determine whether
stellar binaries influence the planets' orbital parameters. This survey, the
largest of its kind to date, finds eight confirmed binary systems and three
confirmed triple systems. These include three new multi-stellar systems (HD
30856, HD 86081, and HD 207832) and three multi-stellar systems with newly
confirmed common proper motion (HD 43691, HD 116029, and HD 164509). We combine
these systems with seven RV planet-hosting multi-stellar systems from the
literature in order to test for differences in the properties of planets with
semimajor axes ranging between 0.1-5 au in single vs multi-stellar systems. We
find no evidence that the presence or absence of stellar companions alters the
distribution of planet properties in these systems. Although the observed
stellar companions might influence the orbits of more distant planetary
companions in these systems, our RV observations currently provide only weak
constraints on the masses and orbital properties of planets beyond 5 au. In
order to aid future efforts to characterize long period RV companions in these
systems, we publish our contrast curves for all 144 targets. Using four years
of astrometry for six hierarchical triple star systems hosting giant planets,
we fit the orbits of the stellar companions in order to characterize the
orbital architecture in these systems. We find that the orbital plane of the
secondary and tertiary companions are inconsistent with an edge-on orbit in
four out of six cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03343</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03343</id><created>2017-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Pace</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Said</keyname><forenames>Jackson Levi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Perturbative Approach to Neutron Stars in $f(T, \mathcal{T})-$Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1701.04761</comments><report-no>EPJC-17-02-113.R1</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77:283</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4838-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff equation in neutron star systems
within the modified $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity class of models using a
perturbative approach. In our approach $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity is
considered to be a static spherically symmetric space-time. In this instance
the metric is built from a more fundamental tetrad vierbein which can be used
to relate inertial and global coordinates. A linear function $f = T(r) +
\mathcal{T}(r) + \chi h(T, \mathcal{T}) + \mathcal{O}(\chi^{2})$ is taken as
the Lagrangian density for the gravitational action. Finally we impose the
polytropic equation of state of neutron star upon the derived equations in
order to derive the mass profile and mass-central density relations of the
neutron star in $f(T, \mathcal{T})$-gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04411</id><created>2017-04-14</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iwamoto</keyname><forenames>Masanori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amano</keyname><forenames>Takanobu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoshino</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Persistence of precursor waves in two-dimensional relativistic shocks</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 16 figures, Revised Figure 15, results unchanged</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 840 (2017) 52</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6d6f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigated the efficiency of coherent upstream large-amplitude
electromagnetic wave emission via synchrotron maser instability at relativistic
magnetized shocks by using two-dimensional particle-in-cell simulations. We
considered the purely perpendicular shock in an electron-positron plasma. The
coherent wave emission efficiency was measured as a function of the
magnetization parameter {\sigma}, which is defined by the ratio of the Poynting
flux to the kinetic energy flux. The wave amplitude was systematically smaller
than that observed in one-dimensional simulations. However, it continued to
persist, even at a considerably low magnetization rate, where the Weibel
instability dominated the shock transition. The emitted electromagnetic waves
were sufficiently strong to disturb the upstream medium, and transverse
filamentary density structures of substantial amplitude were produced. Based on
this result, we discuss the possibility of the wakefield acceleration model for
the production of non-thermal electrons in a relativistic magnetized
ion-electron shock.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04835</id><created>2017-04-16</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Sumei</forenames></author></authors><title>A novel design to realize deterministic switching of perpendicularly
  magnetic layers by spin orbital torque through antiferromagnetic coupling</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>I just found a paper published last year in Nature Nanotechnology has
  used the idea I presented in the paper. I am truly sorry for all the trouble</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We proposed a novel and simple multilayer structure to realize the
deterministic switching of perpendicularly magnetized layers (Co in our work)
by spin orbital torque from the spin Hall Effect in this paper. A pinned layer
is introduced, antiferromagnetically coupled to the magnetic Co layer. We have
confirmed the deterministic switching of perpendicularly magnetized layers from
perspectives of switching loops, trajectories and switching properties under
periodic spin currents through micromagnetic simulation. The antiferromagnetic
interaction accounts for the deterministic switching exhibited in the structure
and the reversal ultimate state of the magnetic layer is predictable when the
applied spin current density is above 60MA/cm2. In our design, the
antiferromagnetic coupling is easily tunable and no external magnetic field is
needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05140</id><created>2017-04-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokol</keyname><forenames>Alexey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buckeridge</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scanlon</keyname><forenames>David O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catlow</keyname><forenames>C. Richard A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron counting in solids: oxidation states, partial charges and
  ionicity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 8, 2074 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b00809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this short viewpoint, we discuss the assignment of ionic charges in
solids. We argue that formal oxidation states serve a useful function, and that
absolute values of partial charges should be interpreted and applied with
caution; the charge assigned can never be definitive and depends on the type of
property studied and the type of analysis performed. Careful analysis can be
used to avoid unphysical conclusions such as a recent report on the Ti(III)
nature of Ti in stoichiometric TiO$_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06588</id><created>2017-04-20</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Golovko</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A tentative view on hadrons</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Numerical estimate and extra comment added in the first paragraph of
  the concluding section</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present paper is based upon ideas and results obtained in an earlier
paper by the author devoted to a new formulation of quantum electrodynamics.
The equations derived in that paper depict the structure and properties of the
electron as well as of other leptons including neutrinos. Since in nature there
are only two stable charged elementary particles, the electron and proton (with
their antiparticles), it is logical to suppose that in nature there is a
protonic field too whose description is analogous with the one of the
electronic field. The equations obtained in the paper and describing the proton
and other baryons differ in some detail from the ones for the electronic field.
A section of the paper is devoted to nuclei where the electronic and protonic
fields are present simultaneously without neutrons. The neutron itself consists
of an electron and a proton. Mesons are short-lived combinations of the
electronic and protonic fields. The theory contains three dimensionless
constants whose value can be calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07171</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Orman</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nce Keziban</forenames><affiliation>LIA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Labatut</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames><affiliation>LIA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Naskali</keyname><forenames>Ahmet Teoman</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the Evolution of Node Neighborhoods in Dynamic Networks</title><categories>cs.SI cs.IR physics.soc-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physica A, Elsevier, 482, pp.375-391 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2017.04.084</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamic Networks are a popular way of modeling and studying the behavior of
evolving systems. However, their analysis constitutes a relatively recent
subfield of Network Science, and the number of available tools is consequently
much smaller than for static networks. In this work, we propose a method
specifically designed to take advantage of the longitudinal nature of dynamic
networks. It characterizes each individual node by studying the evolution of
its direct neighborhood, based on the assumption that the way this neighborhood
changes reflects the role and position of the node in the whole network. For
this purpose, we define the concept of \textit{neighborhood event}, which
corresponds to the various transformations such groups of nodes can undergo,
and describe an algorithm for detecting such events. We demonstrate the
interest of our method on three real-world networks: DBLP, LastFM and Enron. We
apply frequent pattern mining to extract meaningful information from temporal
sequences of neighborhood events. This results in the identification of
behavioral trends emerging in the whole network, as well as the individual
characterization of specific nodes. We also perform a cluster analysis, which
reveals that, in all three networks, one can distinguish two types of nodes
exhibiting different behaviors: a very small group of active nodes, whose
neighborhood undergo diverse and frequent events, and a very large group of
stable nodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00409</id><created>2017-04-30</created><updated>2017-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashemi</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Guangsha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kioupakis</keyname><forenames>Emmanouil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieffer</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Predictive Simulations for Tuning Electronic and Optical Properties of
  SubPc Derivatives</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boron subphthalocyanine chloride is an electron donor material used in small
molecule organic photovoltaics with an unusually large molecular dipole moment.
Using first-principles calculations, we investigate enhancing the electronic
and optical properties of boron subphthalocyanine chloride, by substituting the
boron and chlorine atoms with other trivalent and halogen atoms in order to
modify the molecular dipole moment. Gas phase molecular structures and
properties are predicted with hybrid functionals. Using positions and
orientations of the known compounds as the starting coordinates for these
molecules, stable crystalline structures are derived following a procedure that
involves perturbation and accurate total energy minimization. Electronic
structure and photonic properties of the predicted crystals are computed using
the GW method and the Bethe-Salpeter equation, respectively. Finally, a simple
transport model is use to demonstrate the importance of molecular dipole
moments on device performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00792</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00792</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sobacchi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Granot</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bromberg</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Why Are We Not Detecting Any Type Ib Supernova Associated with Long
  Gamma Ray Bursts?</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>We realised that eq. 4 and 5 are not appropriate if a large amount of
  energy is deposited directly into the envelope. We are trying to fix this
  issue, but this is not immediate and can affect the conclusions. Hence, we
  prefer to withdraw the paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Core-collapse supernovae (SNe) of Types Ib and Ic arise from
hydrogen-stripped stars, while the latter are also stripped of their helium.
Both SN types have a similar temporal evolution, suggesting broadly similar
progenitors. However, while some Ic SNe are associated with relativistic jets
of gamma-ray bursts (GRBs), no GRB has yet been found in association with Type
Ib SNe. Here we find that, even if GRB-like central engines operate in both SNe
Ib and Ic, different properties of their envelopes may accommodate this
potential tension. In particular, we focus on the case of a low-mass, extended
envelope surrounding the progenitor star (as produced, for example, by strong
mass losses prior to explosion). If the envelopes of Type Ib SNe are
sufficiently massive ($M_{\rm ext}\sim(0.3-1)M_\odot$) and extended ($R_{\rm
ext}\sim 10^{13}\text{ cm}$), we show that (i) GRB-like jets cannot break out
of the star; (ii) the SN light curve is compatible with current observations.
Different envelope properties of Type Ib SNe with respect to (at least some)
Type Ic SNe may be connected to the presence of a helium layer surrounding the
star.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01455</id><created>2017-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruglov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation of universe due to nonlinear electrodynamics</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures, to appear in IJMPA</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A, Vol. 32 (2017) 1750071</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500713</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model of nonlinear electrodynamics with a dimensional parameter $\beta$ is
considered. Electromagnetic fields are the source of the gravitation field and
inflation of the universe. We imply that the universe is filled by stochastic
magnetic fields. It is demonstrated that after the universe inflation the
universe decelerates approaching the Minkowski spacetime. We evaluate the
spectral index, the tensor-to-scalar ratio, and the running of the spectral
index which approximately agree with the PLANK and WMAP data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01579</id><created>2017-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichl</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riedi</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faelt</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegscheider</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical probing of the intrinsic spin Hall effect in a high mobility
  GaAs p-doped quantum well</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the detection of the intrinsic spin Hall effect in a modulation
doped Al-GaAs/GaAs/AlGaAs heterostructure bounded by a self-aligned
pn-junction, fabricated by the cleaved edge overgrowth method. Light emission
due to the recombination of electrons and spin-polarized holes was generated
and mapped with a spatial resolution of one micrometer. An edge accumulated
spin polarization of up to 11% was measured, induced solely by application of
an electric Field perpendicular to the pn-junction. Using a quantum dot
structure as light source, a linear dependence of the effective spin
polarization, and with that the dominance of the spin Hall effect, with the
electric field is seen. Spatially resolved spectroscopy from an epitaxially
fabricated LED is demonstrated to be a valuable tool to probe the edge states
of electron and hole gases in reduced dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01643</id><created>2017-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Haley D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinsberg</keyname><forenames>Stefan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moiseenko</keyname><forenames>Vitali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jonn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Steven D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prefer Nested Segmentation to Compound Segmentation</title><categories>q-bio.QM physics.med-ph q-bio.TO</categories><comments>7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Introduction: Intra-organ radiation dose sensitivity is becoming increasingly
relevant in clinical radiotherapy. One method for assessment involves
partitioning delineated regions of interest and comparing the relative
contributions or importance to clinical outcomes. We show that an intuitive
method for dividing organ contours, compound (sub-)segmentation, can
unintentionally lead to sub-segments with inconsistent volumes, which will bias
relative importance assessment. An improved technique, nested segmentation, is
introduced and compared. Methods: Clinical radiotherapy planning parotid
contours from 510 patients were segmented. Counts of radiotherapy dose matrix
voxels interior to sub-segments were used to determine the equivalency of
sub-segment volumes. The distribution of voxel counts within sub-segments were
compared using Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests and characterized by their dispersion.
Analytical solutions for 2D/3D analogues were derived and sub-segment
area/volume were compared directly. Results: Both parotid and 2D/3D region of
interest analogue segmentation confirmed compound segmentation intrinsically
produces sub-segments with volumes that depend on the region of interest shape
and selection location. Significant volume differences were observed when
sub-segmenting parotid contours into 18ths, and vanishingly small sub-segments
were observed when sub-segmenting into 96ths. Central sub-segments were
considerably smaller than sub-segments on the periphery. Nested segmentation
did not exhibit these shortcomings and produced sub-segments with equivalent
volumes when dose grid and contour collinearity was addressed, even when
dividing the parotid into 96ths. Nested segmentation was always faster or
equivalent in runtime to compound segmentation. Conclusions: Nested
segmentation is more suited than compound segmentation for analyses requiring
equal weighting of sub-segments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01798</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Nilles</keyname><forenames>Hans Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Stringy Origin of Discrete R-symmetries</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Proceedings of the Corfu Summer Institute 2016 &quot;School and Workshops
  on Elementary Particle Physics and Gravity&quot;,31 August - 23 September, 2016,
  Corfu, Greece</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discrete symmetries play a crucial role in particle physics. They appear
abundantly in string model constructions. We focus here on the case of discrete
$R$-symmetries which are intrinsically connected to the Lorentz group in extra
dimensions and the appearance of $N$-extended supersymmetry. In that sense,
discrete $R$-symmetries can be understood as &quot;fractionally&quot; extended
supersymmetry. These symmetries reveal insight about the location of fields in
extra dimensions (in particular the Higgs boson). Applications can be found in
the solution of the $\mu$-problem, suppression of proton decay and the
structure of the soft terms of broken supersymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01941</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Troiano</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kriplani</keyname><forenames>Pravesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author></authors><title>Regression Driven F--Transform and Application to Smoothing of Financial
  Time Series</title><categories>physics.data-an cs.CE cs.DM</categories><comments>IFSA-SCIS 2017, 5 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we propose to extend the definition of fuzzy transform in order
to consider an interpolation of models that are richer than the standard fuzzy
transform. We focus on polynomial models, linear in particular, although the
approach can be easily applied to other classes of models. As an example of
application, we consider the smoothing of time series in finance. A comparison
with moving averages is performed using NIFTY 50 stock market index.
Experimental results show that a regression driven fuzzy transform (RDFT)
provides a smoothing approximation of time series, similar to moving average,
but with a smaller delay. This is an important feature for finance and other
application, where time plays a key role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01942</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Dorband</keyname><forenames>John E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving the Accuracy of an Adiabatic Quantum Computer</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of the D-Wave adiabatic quantum computer is to find a set of
qubit values that minimize its objective function. For various reasons, the set
of qubit values returned by the D-Wave has errors. This paper presents a method
of improving the results returned by the D-Wave. The method individually
modifies the qubit values returned by the D-Wave to find a set of values which
is a minimum of the objective function. That set however is not necessarily
guaranteed to be a global minimum. The method is simple and easily incorporated
into any algorithm that has direct access to the sets of values returned by the
D-Wave. Examples are also presented that demonstrate the merit of using such a
sample improvement method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01958</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Miatto</keyname><forenames>Filippo M</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant weak value amplification with chirped waveforms</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weak value amplification is a classical phenomenon that can enhance the
sensitivity of a measurement through clever use of interference. The most
well-known paradigm of weak value amplification makes use of a Gaussian pulse,
which is typical of pulsed laser systems. In this Letter we show that chirped
pulses have a great advantage over Gaussians at detecting frequency shifts
thanks to the large phase space area that they cover. As an example, we show
that within the typical operative parameters of a radar, we can achieve two
orders of magnitude amplification of small frequency shifts \emph{on top of the
weak value amplification}. This idea could lead to new metrological avenues in
the microwave optics domain, and to Doppler radar technology with unprecedented
sensitivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01980</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Borodin</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corwin</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic ASEP, duality and continuous $q^{-1}$-Hermite polynomials</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a Markov duality between the dynamic ASEP and the standard
ASEP. We then apply this to step initial data, as well as a half-stationary
initial data (which we introduce). While investigating the duality for
half-stationary initial data, we uncover and utilize connections to continuous
$q^{-1}$-Hermite polynomials. Finally, we introduce a family of stationary
initial data which are related to the indeterminate moment problem associated
with these $q^{-1}$-Hermite polynomials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01982</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Zhiyue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Mudi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>Lorin S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hyde</keyname><forenames>Truell W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of interaction between a dust particle pair in complex
  plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>CASPER-17-1</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A non-intrusive method to measure particle interaction using only the thermal
motion of the particles is applied to a vertically aligned dust particle pair
in a complex plasma. The scanning mode spectra (SMS) are obtained by tracking
the thermal motion of the grains, with the interaction strength then determined
from the frequencies and the eigenvector configuration of the normal modes. The
interaction of the bottom particle acting on the top particle is shown to be
Yukawa-like with the screening length suppressed against the ion flow. The
interaction of the top particle acting on the bottom particle is repulsive in
the vertical direction and attractive in the horizontal direction. The vertical
interaction from the top to bottom particle is stronger than that from the
bottom to top particle, agreeing with an extended ion wake tail as predicted by
the inhomogeneous ion wake theory. Determination of the horizontal attraction
strength serves as a direct verification and quantification of the ion wake
effect. Heating of the lower particle in both the vertical and horizontal
directions is observed and quantitatively related to the nonreciprocity of the
interaction. The in situ confinement strength at the position of the bottom
particle is found to be consistently lower than at the position of the top
particle, caused by decharging of the lower particle by 10-30% while inside the
ion wake of the top particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01983</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Shin</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames><affiliation>NICADD, DeKalb and Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lumpkin</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thangaraj</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thurman-Keup</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shiltsev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>TeV/m Nano-Accelerator: Current Status of CNT-Channeling Acceleration
  Experiment</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>5 pp. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1502.02073</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-14-340-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Crystal channeling technology has offered various opportunities in the
accelerator community with a viability of ultrahigh gradient (TV/m)
acceleration for future HEP collider. The major challenge of channeling
acceleration is that ultimate acceleration gradients might require a high power
driver in the hard x-ray regime (~ 40 keV). This x-ray energy exceeds those for
x-rays as of today, although x-ray lasers can efficiently excite solid plasma
and accelerate particles inside a crystal channel. Moreover, only disposable
crystal accelerators are possible at such high externally excited fields which
would exceed the ionization thresholds destroying the atomic structure, so
acceleration will take place only in a short time before full dissociation of
the lattice. Carbon-based nanostructures have great potential with a wide range
of flexibility and superior physical strength, which can be applied to
channeling acceleration. This paper presents a beam-driven channeling
acceleration concept with CNTs and discusses feasible experiments with the
Advanced Superconducting Test Accelerator (ASTA) in Fermilab.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01988</id><created>2017-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>McCullagh</keyname><forenames>Nuala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norberg</keyname><forenames>Peder</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Shaun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez-Perez</keyname><forenames>Violeta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baugh</keyname><forenames>Carlton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helly</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting HOD model assumptions: the impact of AGN feedback and
  assembly bias</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 13 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The standard Halo Occupation Distribution (HOD) models were originally
developed based on results from semi-analytic and hydrodynamical galaxy
formation models. Those models have since progressed, in particular to include
AGN feedback to match the galaxy luminosity function in a universe with the
observed baryon fraction. AGN feedback affects the relationship between galaxy
stellar mass and luminosity, in particular making the relationship
non-monotonic. For matched number density samples, galaxies in
luminosity-threshold samples occupy a different range of halo masses from those
in stellar-mass-threshold samples. We find that the shapes of the HODs of
luminosity-threshold samples are slightly more complicated in semi-analytic
galaxy formation models that include AGN feedback than are assumed by standard
HOD models. We also find that subhalo abundance matching (SHAM) does not
preserve these non-standard shapes. We show that catalogues created using SHAM
and the semi-analytic model Galform that have the same large-scale 2-point
clustering by construction have different void probability functions (VPFs) in
both real and redshift space. We find that these differences arise from the
different HOD shapes, as opposed to assembly bias, which indicates that the VPF
could be used to test the suitability of an HOD model with real data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01994</id><created>2017-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Dale</keyname><forenames>Matthew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morley</keyname><forenames>Gavin W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Medical applications of diamond magnetometry: commercial viability</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.ins-det physics.med-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sensing of magnetic fields has important applications in medicine,
particularly to the sensing of signals in the heart and brain. The fields
associated with biomagnetism are exceptionally weak, being many orders of
magnitude smaller than the Earth's magnetic field. To measure them requires
that we use the most sensitive detection techniques, however, to be
commercially viable this must be done at an affordable cost. The current state
of the art uses costly SQUID magnetometers, although they will likely be
superseded by less costly, but otherwise limited, alkali vapour magnetometers.
Here, we discuss the application of diamond magnetometers to medical
applications. Diamond magnetometers are robust, solid state devices that work
in a broad range of environments, with the potential for sensitivity comparable
to the leading technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01995</id><created>2017-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Yaremko</keyname><forenames>Yurij</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic shifts of eigenfrequencies in an ideal Penning trap</title><categories>physics.class-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>70K43 83A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Mass Spectrom. 405 64 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ijms.2016.05.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First-order perturbative calculation of the frequency-shifts caused by
special relativity is performed for a charged particle confined in a Penning
trap. The perturbed motion is approximated by the Jacobian elliptic functions
which describe the periodic orbit repeating itself sinuously with a period that
exceeds $2\pi$. We find relativistic corrections to amplitudes of oscillating
modes as well as shifts of eigenfrequencies which depend on amplitudes. Besides
we find the relativistic contributions to modular angles. In the low-energy
limit the deformed orbit simplifies to the well-known combination of axial
oscillation and in-plane motion consisting of two circular modes. We compare
the results with the model of relativistic frequency-shifts developed by J.
Ketter {\em et al.}
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02006</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Morissona</keyname><forenames>Marietta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szopa</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>Nathalie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buch</keyname><forenames>Arnaud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gautier</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Titan organic aerosols: molecular composition and structure of
  laboratory analogues inferred from systematic pyrolysis gas chromatography
  mass spectrometry analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Icarus, Elsevier, 2016, 277, pp.442-454</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.05.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerous studies have been carried out to characterize the chemical
composition of laboratory analogues of Titan aerosols (tholins), but their
molecular composition as well as their structure are still poorly known. If
pyrolysis gas chromatography mass spectrometry (pyr-GCMS) has been used for
years to give clues about this composition, the highly disparate results
obtained can be attributed to the analytical conditions used and/or to
differences in the nature of the analogues studied. In order to have a better
description of Titan tholins molecular composition, we led a systematic
analysis of these materials using pyr-GCMS with two major objectives: (i)
exploring the analytical parameters to estimate the biases this technique can
induce and to find an optimum for analyses allowing the detection of a wide
range of compounds and thus a characterization of the tholins composition as
comprehensive as possible, and (ii) highlighting the role of the CH4 ratio in
the gaseous reactive medium on the tholins molecular structure. With this aim,
we used a radio-frequency plasma discharge to synthetize tholins with different
concentrations of CH4 diluted in N2. The samples were systematically pyrolyzed
from 200 to 600{\deg}C. The extracted gases were then analyzed by GCMS for
their molecular identification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02011</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiltsev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>Considerations On Energy Frontier Colliders After LHC</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>4 pp. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1511.01934,
  arXiv:1509.08369</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-536-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Since 1960's, particle colliders have been in the forefront of particle
physics, 29 total have been built and operated, 7 are in operation now. At
present the near term US, European and international strategies of the particle
physics community are centered on full exploitation of the physics potential of
the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) through its high-luminosity upgrade (HL-LHC).
The future of the world-wide HEP community critically depends on the
feasibility of possible post-LHC colliders. The concept of the feasibility is
complex and includes at least three factors: feasibility of energy, feasibility
of luminosity and feasibility of cost. Here we overview all current options for
post-LHC colliders from such perspective (ILC, CLIC, Muon Collider, plasma
colliders, CEPC, FCC, HE-LHC) and discuss major challenges and accelerator R&amp;D
required to demonstrate feasibility of an energy frontier accelerator facility
following the LHC. We conclude by taking a look into ultimate energy reach
accelerators based on plasmas and crystals, and discussion on the perspectives
for the far future of the accelerator-based particle physics. This paper
largely follows previous study and the presentation given at the ICHEP'2016
conference in Chicago.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02013</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Strazzullo</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosetti</keyname><forenames>Renzo</forenames></author></authors><title>FEniCS Application to a Finite Element Quasi-Geostrophic Model. Linear
  and non-linear analysis of Munk-like Solutions and Data Assimilation
  Implementation Through Adjoint Method</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first aim of this work is to construct a Finite Elements model for
quasi-geostrophic equation. This model is analyzed through FEniCS interface. As
a second purpose, it shows the potential of the control theory to treat Data
Assimilation large scale problems. In section one the finite element
approximation of the quasi-geostrophic model is described. In section two some
numerical results on different domains are shown. In section three a comparison
between Navier Stokes model and quasi-geostrophic one is discussed. Last
section is dedicated to a more complex data assimilation/control problem based
on quasi-geostrophic equations, to test possible developments and improvements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02014</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Minkov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drenska</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yotov</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent quadrupole-octupole states from a SUSY-QM Hamiltonian hierarchy
  and shape invariance</title><categories>nucl-th quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures, Proceedings of the 33-rd International Workshop
  on Nuclear Theory (Rila Mountains, Bulgaria 2014)</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Theory, vol. 33, (Heron Press, Sofia), p. 32 (2014)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the potential in the radial equation in the model of coherent
quadrupole-octupole motion (CQOM) in nuclei generates a sequence of
superpotentials and subsequent series of effective potentials which satisfy the
shape-invariance condition and correspond to a SUSY-QM hierarchy of
Hamiltonians. On this basis we suggest that the original CQOM level scheme
possesses a generic supersymmetric structure of the spectrum inherent for the
coherent quadrupole-octupole mode. We outline the mechanism in which the real
quadrupole-octupole spectra in even-even and odd-even nuclei deviate from the
genuine symmetry. By using it we illustrate the possibilities to identify the
signs of supersymmetry in the alternating-parity spectra of even-even nuclei
and the quasi-parity-doublet levels of odd-mass nuclei described within the
CQOM model approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02016</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Trevor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindwall</keyname><forenames>Greta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Supriyo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lane</keyname><forenames>Brandon M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kattner</keyname><forenames>Ursula R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lass</keyname><forenames>Eric A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heigel</keyname><forenames>Jarred C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Idell</keyname><forenames>Yaakov</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Maureen E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guyer</keyname><forenames>Jonathan E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Lyle E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of Finite Element, Phase-field, and CALPHAD-based Methods to
  Additive Manufacturing of Ni-based Superalloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Acta Materialia on May 1, 2017</comments><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.05.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical simulations are used in this work to investigate aspects of
microstructure and microsegregation during rapid solidification of a Ni-based
superalloy in a laser powder bed fusion additive manufacturing process. Thermal
modeling by finite element analysis simulates the laser melt pool, with surface
temperatures in agreement with in situ thermographic measurements on Inconel
625. Geometric and thermal features of the simulated melt pools are extracted
and used in subsequent mesoscale simulations. Solidification in the melt pool
is simulated on two length scales. For the multicomponent alloy Inconel 625,
microsegregation between dendrite arms is calculated using the Scheil-Gulliver
solidification model and DICTRA software. Phase-field simulations, using Ni-Nb
as a binary analogue to Inconel 625, produced microstructures with primary
cellular/dendritic arm spacings in agreement with measured spacings in
experimentally observed microstructures and a lesser extent of microsegregation
than predicted by DICTRA simulations. The composition profiles are used to
compare thermodynamic driving forces for nucleation against experimentally
observed precipitates identified by electron and X-ray diffraction analyses.
Our analysis lists the precipitates that may form from FCC phase of enriched
interdendritic compositions and compares these against experimentally observed
phases from 1 h heat treatments at two temperatures: stress relief at 1143 K
(870{\deg}C) or homogenization at 1423 K (1150{\deg}C).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02022</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Mokhov</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eidelman</keyname><forenames>Yu. I.</forenames><affiliation>Euclid Techlabs, Solon</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rakhno</keyname><forenames>I. L.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tchelidze</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>ESS, Lund</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tropin</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author></authors><title>MARS15 Simulation Of Radiation Environment At The ESS Linac</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>15 pp. Presented paper at the 13th Meeting of the task-force on
  Shielding aspects of Accelerators, Targets and Irradiation Facilities
  (SATIF-13), HZDR, October 10-12, 2016, Dresden, Germany</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-543-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Comprehensive studies with the MARS15(2016) Monte-Carlo code are described on
evaluation of prompt and residual radiation levels induced by nominal and
accidental beam losses in the 5-MW, 2-GeV European Spallation Source (ESS)
Linac. These are to provide a basis for radiation shielding design verification
through the accelerator complex. The calculation model is based on the latest
engineering design and includes a sophisticated algorithm for particle tracking
in the machine RF cavities as well as a well-established model of the beam
loss. Substantial efforts were put in solving the deep-penetration problem for
the thick shielding around the tunnel with numerous complex penetrations. It
allowed us to study in detail not only the prompt dose, but also component and
air activation, radiation loads on the soil outside the tunnel, and skyshine
studies for the complicated 3-D surface above the machine. Among the other
things, the newest features in MARS15 (2016), such as a ROOT-based beamline
builder and a TENDL-based event generator for nuclear interactions below 100
MeV, were very useful in this challenging application.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02024</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Svalgaard</keyname><forenames>Leif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schatten</keyname><forenames>Kenneth H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sunspot Group Numbers Since 1900 and Implications for the Long-term
  Record of Solar Activity</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent work on improving and revising estimates of solar activity [Clette et
al., 2014] has resulted in renewed interest in what has been called the longest
running 'Science Experiment'. We compare four reconstructions of solar activity
as reflected in the number of sunspot groups ('active regions') constructed by
different authors using very different methods. We concentrate on the period
since AD 1900 where the underlying solar and geomagnetic data are plentiful and
of sufficient quality and find that all four methods yield essentially the same
Sunspot Group Number series. We take that as indicating that protracted and
pernicious criticisms of the individual methods are neither fruitful nor
helpful and we suggest that future efforts be directed towards understanding
the specific reasons why the methods give discordant results for centuries
prior to the 20th. The main area of disagreement occurs during the last 25
years of the 19th century and feeds back into the time prior to that. The solar
Extreme Ultraviolet flux can be reconstructed since the 1740s [Svalgaard, 2016]
and with suitable scaling fits the Svalgaard &amp; Schatten [2016] Sunspot Group
Number series since 1865 very well, so we argue that the discordant group
series have problems once we move out of the 20th century, and that the
community should concentrate on finding out what those are, so a true and
useful consensus can emerge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02030</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Kun-Ta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hishamunda</keyname><forenames>Jean Bernard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Daniel T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeCamp</keyname><forenames>Stephen J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Ya-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez-Nieves</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraden</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dogic</keyname><forenames>Zvonimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Transition from turbulent to coherent flows in confined
  three-dimensional active fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.bio-ph</categories><journal-ref>Science 355, eaal1979 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aal1979</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transport of fluid through a pipe is essential for the operation of
macroscale machines and microfluidic devices. Conventional fluids only flow in
response to external pressure. We demonstrate that an active isotropic fluid,
comprised of microtubules and molecular motors, autonomously flows through
meter-long three-dimensional channels. We establish control over the magnitude,
velocity profile and direction of the self-organized flows, and correlate these
to the structure of the extensile microtubule bundles. The inherently
three-dimensional transition from bulk-turbulent to confined-coherent flows
occurs concomitantly with a transition in the bundle orientational order near
the surface, and is controlled by a scale-invariant criterion related to the
channel profile. The non-equilibrium transition of confined isotropic active
fluids can be used to engineer self-organized soft machines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02049</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Teimouri</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic f(R) Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this short paper we follow the entropic gravity approach and demonstrate
how \(f(R)\) theories of gravity can be emergent. This is done by introducing
an effective gravitational constant which is naturally arising from the
\(f(R)\)'s equations of motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02052</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashemi</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kieffer</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Semiclassical Model for Calculating Exciton and Polaron Pair Energetics
  at Interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>37 Pages, 14 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exciton and polaron pair dissociation is a key functional aspect of
photovoltaic devices. To improve upon the current state of interfacial
transport models, we augment the existing classical models of dielectric
interfaces by incorporating results from ab initio calculations, allowing us to
calculate exciton and polaron binding energies more accurately. We demonstrate
the predictive capabilities of this new model using two interfaces: (i) the
boron subphthalocyanine chloride (SubPc) and C60 interface, which is an
archetype for many organic photovoltaic devices; and (ii) pentacene and silicon
(100), which represents a hybrid between organic and inorganic semiconductors.
Our calculations predict that the insertion of molecular dipoles at interfaces
can be used for improving polaron pair dissociation and that sharp transitions
in dielectric permittivity can have a stronger effect on the polaron pair
dissociation than even the electron-hole Coulomb interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02067</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Edwards</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalev</keyname><forenames>Y. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ojha</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bignall</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carpenter</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hovatta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voytsik</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrianov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hase</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horiuchi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jauncey</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadler</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisakov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lovell</keyname><forenames>J. E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCallum</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ploetz</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quick</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolovsky</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzioumis</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuga</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>PKS 1954-388: RadioAstron Detection on 80,000 km Baselines and
  Multiwavelength Observations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>PASA, 34, e21 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/pasa.2017.16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from a multiwavelength study of the blazar PKS 1954-388 at
radio, UV, X-ray, and gamma-ray energies. A RadioAstron observation at 1.66 GHz
in June 2012 resulted in the detection of interferometric fringes on baselines
of 6.2 Earth-diameters. This suggests a source frame brightness temperature of
greater than 2x10^12 K, well in excess of both equipartition and inverse
Compton limits and implying the existence of Doppler boosting in the core. An
8.4 GHz TANAMI VLBI image, made less than a month after the RadioAstron
observations, is consistent with a previously reported superluminal motion for
a jet component. Flux density monitoring with the Australia Telescope Compact
Array confirms previous evidence for long-term variability that increases with
observing frequency. A search for more rapid variability revealed no evidence
for significant day-scale flux density variation. The ATCA light-curve reveals
a strong radio flare beginning in late 2013 which peaks higher, and earlier, at
higher frequencies. Comparison with the Fermi gamma-ray light-curve indicates
this followed ~9 months after the start of a prolonged gamma-ray high-state --
a radio lag comparable to that seen in other blazars. The multiwavelength data
are combined to derive a Spectral Energy Distribution, which is fitted by a
one-zone synchrotron-self-Compton (SSC) model with the addition of external
Compton (EC) emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02074</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Javaid</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drumm</keyname><forenames>Daniel W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Russo</keyname><forenames>Salvy P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greentree</keyname><forenames>Andrew D.</forenames></author></authors><title>A study of size-dependent properties of MoS2 monolayer nanoflakes using
  density-functional theory</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novel physical phenomena emerge in ultra-small sized nanomaterials. We study
the limiting small-size-dependent properties of MoS$_{2}$ monolayer rhombic
nanoflakes using density-functional theory on structures of size up to
Mo$_{35}$S$_{70}$ (1.74~nm). We investigate the structural and electronic
properties as functions of the lateral size of the nanoflakes, finding zigzag
is the most stable edge configuration, and that increasing size is accompanied
by greater stability. We also investigate passivation of the structures to
explore realistic settings, finding increased HOMO-LUMO gaps and energetic
stability. Understanding the size-dependent properties will inform efforts to
engineer electronic structures at the nano-scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02084</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Zhongrui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Haotong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Hailong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carlin</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guangwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yongheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Zihuang</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Ray Removal in Fiber Spectroscopic Image</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>PASP, V129, I972, pp. 024004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1538-3873/129/972/024004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-exposure spectra in large spectral surveys are valuable for time
domain studies such as stellar variability, but there is no available method to
eliminate cosmic rays for single-exposure, multi-fiber spectral images. In this
paper, we describe a new method to detect and remove cosmic rays in multi-fiber
spectroscopic single exposures. Through the use of two-dimensional profile
fitting and a noise model that considers the position-dependent errors, we
successfully detect as many as 80% of the cosmic rays and correct the cosmic
ray polluted pixels to an average accuracy of 97.8%. Multiple tests and
comparisons with both simulated data and real LAMOST data show that the method
works properly in detection rate, false detection rate, and validity of cosmic
ray correction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02086</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Callen</keyname><forenames>Benjamin D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified Dark Matter from a Simple Gauge Group on a Domain-Wall Brane</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>50 pages, 32 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some models of asymmetric dark matter commonly employ a gauge group structure
of the form $G_{V}\times{}G_{D}$ where $G_{V}$ is the visible gauge group
containing the Standard Model and $G_{D}$ is the gauge group responsible for
self-interactions amongst components of dark matter. In some models, there is
also an additional spontaneously broken $U(1)$ gauge symmetry coupling the
visible and dark sectors at high energies. One theoretical problem is how to
unify the visible and dark sectors by inducing the spontaneous breaking
$G\rightarrow{}G_{V}\times{}G_{D}$ for some large gauge group $G$. In this
paper, we discuss how to generate such a structure at low energies, in the
context of 4+1-dimensional domain-wall brane model, by employing a
generalization of the Dvali-Shifman mechanism, used to localized gauge bosons
on domain walls, called the clash-of-symmetries mechanism. In one model, we
describe a clash-of-symmetries domain wall solution in a theory with two scalar
fields in the adjoint representation which breaks the group $SU(12)$ to two
differently embedded copies of $SU(6)\times{}SU(6)\times{}U(1)$, leading to a
an effective $SU(5)_{V}\times{}SU(5)_{D}\times{}U(1)_{X}$-invariant field
theory on the wall. We find that fermions in the mixed representations of
$SU(5)_{V}\times{}SU(5)_{D}$ do not couple to the domain wall and thus remain
5D vector-like Dirac fermions, attaining masses of order $M_{GUT}$ when we
perform the breaking
$SU(5)_{V}\rightarrow{}SU(3)_{c}\times{}SU(2)_{I}\times{}U(1)_{Y}$, thus being
removed from the spectrum. We also outline how to build a few alternative
models, one based on the group $SU(9)$, and a couple more based on
non-clash-of-symmetries domain wall solutions in $SU(12)$ and $SU(10)$ models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02089</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>D. Sam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gautham</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>iMOLSDOCK : induced-fit docking using mutually orthogonal Latin squares
  (MOLS)</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><journal-ref>J.Mol.Graph.Model. 74 (2017) 89-99</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmgm.2017.03.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have earlier reported the MOLSDOCK technique to perform rigid
receptor/flexible ligand docking. The method uses the MOLS method, developed in
our laboratory. In this paper we report iMOLSDOCK, the 'flexible receptor'
extension we have carried out to the algorithm MOLSDOCK. iMOLSDOCK uses
mutually orthogonal Latin squares (MOLS) to sample the conformation and the
docking pose of the ligand and also the flexible residues of the receptor
protein. The method then uses a variant of the mean field technique to analyze
the sample to arrive at the optimum. We have benchmarked and validated
iMOLSDOCK with a dataset of 44 peptide-protein complexes with peptides. We have
also compared iMOLSDOCK with other flexible receptor docking tools GOLD v5.2.1
and AutoDock Vina. The results obtained show that the method works better than
these two algorithms, though it consumes more computer time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02099</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Chuan-Cun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Daoyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petersen</keyname><forenames>Ian R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henriksen</keyname><forenames>Niels E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete elimination of nonlinear light-matter interactions with
  broadband ultrafast laser pulses</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 95, 033809 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.033809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The absorption of a single photon that excites a quantum system from a low to
a high energy level is an elementary process of light-matter interaction, and a
route towards realizing pure single-photon absorption has both fundamental and
practical implications in quantum technology. Due to nonlinear optical effects,
however, the probability of pure single-photon absorption is usually very low,
which is particularly pertinent in the case of strong ultrafast laser pulses
with broad bandwidth. Here we demonstrate theoretically a counterintuitive
coherent single-photon absorption scheme by eliminating nonlinear interactions
of ultrafast laser pulses with quantum systems. That is, a completely linear
response of the system with respect to the spectral energy density of the
incident light at the transition frequency can be obtained for all transition
probabilities between 0 and 100% in a multi-level quantum systems. To that end,
a new multi-objective optimization algorithm is developed to find an optimal
spectral phase of an ultrafast laser pulse, which is capable of eliminating all
possible nonlinear optical responses while maximizing the probability of
single-photon absorption between quantum states. This work not only deepens our
understanding of light-matter interactions, but also offers a new way to study
photophysical and photochemical processes in the &quot;absence&quot; of nonlinear optical
effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02107</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Bhuwan</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames><affiliation>Osmania Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>Upendra</forenames><affiliation>USO/PRL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Yong-Jae</forenames><affiliation>SSR/KHU</affiliation></author></authors><title>Evolutionary aspects and north-south asymmetry of soft X-ray flare index
  during solar cycles 21, 22, and 23</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, 2015, Volume 582, id. A4</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526369</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aims. In this paper, we investigate the temporal evolution and north-south
(N-S) asymmetry in the occurrence of solar flares during cycle 21, 22, and 23,
and compare the results with traditional solar activity indices. Methods. The
flare activity is characterized by a soft X-ray (SXR) flare index, which
incorporates information about flare occurrences during a selected interval
along with the peak intensity of individual events. Results. The SXR flare
index correlates well with other conventional parameters of solar activity.
Further, it exhibits a significantly higher correlation with sunspot area over
sunspot number, which suggests the variations in sunspot area to be more
closely linked with the transient energy release in the solar corona. The
cumulative plots of the flare index indicate a slight excess of activity in the
northern hemisphere during cycle 21, while a southern excess clearly prevails
for cycles 22 and 23. The study reveals a significant N-S asymmetry, which
exhibits variations with the phases of solar cycle. The reliability and
persistency of this asymmetry significantly increases when the data is averaged
over longer periods, while an optimal level is achieved when data is binned for
13 Carrington rotations. The time evolution of the flare index further confirms
evolution of dual peaks in solar cycles during the solar maxima and violation
of Gnevyshev-Ohl rule for the pair of solar cycles 22 and 23. Conclusions. The
SXR flare index in the northern and the southern hemispheres of the Sun
exhibits significant asymmetry during the evolutionary phases of the solar
cycle, which implies that N-S asymmetry of solar flares is manifested in terms
of the flare counts as well as the intensity of flare events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02119</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Nampoothiri</keyname><forenames>Sankaran</forenames><affiliation>IISER-TVM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Medhi</keyname><forenames>Amal</forenames><affiliation>IISER-TVM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Role of curvature and domain shape on Turing patterns</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider pattern formation using reaction-diffusion equation on various
non-uniformly curved surfaces. We explore how, in general, curvature and, in
particular the domain shape would affect the pattern formation in these
geometries. As examples, we study stripe and spot patterns on a torus, and on
an ellipsoid. Our results show that the curvature and domain shape can control
the orientation of stripe pattern as well as the size and number of spots. Our
results also indicate that by controlling the curvature and shape, one can
drive the chemicals to a preferred region. Specifically on a torus, curvature
and shape can guide the chemicals more on to outer side than inner side. This
result may prove important in the studies of self-organization of molecules in
biological membranes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02157</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Gavilan</keyname><forenames>Lisseth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Remusat</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roskosz</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popescu</keyname><forenames>Horia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaouen</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandt</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jager</keyname><forenames>Cornelia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simionovici</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemaire</keyname><forenames>Jean Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mangin</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>Nathalie</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray induced deuterium enrichment on N-rich organics in protoplanetary
  disks: an experimental investigation using synchrotron light</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>14 pages, 23 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 840, Number 1, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6bfc</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The deuterium enrichment of organics in the interstellar medium,
protoplanetary disks and meteorites has been proposed to be the result of
ionizing radiation. The goal of this study is to quantify the effects of soft
X-rays (0.1 - 2 keV), a component of stellar radiation fields illuminating
protoplanetary disks, on the refractory organics present in the disks. We
prepared tholins, nitrogen-rich complex organics, via plasma deposition and
used synchrotron radiation to simulate X-ray fluences in protoplanetary disks.
Controlled irradiation experiments at 0.5 and 1.3 keV were performed at the
SEXTANTS beam line of the SOLEIL synchrotron, and were followed by ex-situ
infrared, Raman and isotopic diagnostics. Infrared spectroscopy revealed the
loss of singly-bonded groups (N-H, C-H and R-N$\equiv$C) and the formation of
sp$^3$ carbon defects. Raman analysis revealed the introduction of defects and
structural amorphization. Finally, tholins were measured via secondary ion mass
spectrometry (SIMS), revealing that significant D-enrichment is induced by
X-ray irradiation. Our results are compared to previous experimental studies
involving the thermal degradation and electron irradiation of organics. The
penetration depth of soft X-rays in $\mu$m-sized tholins leads to volume rather
than surface modifications: lower energy X-rays (0.5 keV) induce a larger
D-enrichment than 1.3 keV X-rays, reaching a plateau for doses larger than 5
$\times$ 10$^{27}$ eV cm$^{-3}$. Our work provides experimental evidence of a
new non-thermal pathway to deuterium fractionation of organic matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02180</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Orioli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beccara</keyname><forenames>S. A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faccioli</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self Consistent Path Sampling: Making Accurate All-Atom Protein Folding
  Simulations Possible on Small Computer Clusters</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.BM</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a powerful iterative algorithm to compute protein folding
pathways, with realistic all-atom force fields. Using the path integral
formalism, we explicitly derive a modified Langevin equation which samples
directly the ensemble of reactive pathways, exponentially reducing the cost of
simulating thermally activated transitions. The algorithm also yields a
rigorous stochastic estimate of the reaction coordinate. After illustrating
this approach on a simple toy model, we successfully validate it against the
results of ultra-long plain MD protein folding simulations for a fast folding
protein (Fip35), which were performed on the Anton supercomputer. Using our
algorithm, computing a folding trajectory for this protein requires only 1000
core hours, a computational load which could be even carried out on a desktop
workstation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02182</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Arancibia</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godoy</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dur&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling and simulation of an acoustic well stimulation method</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a mathematical model and a numerical procedure to
simulate an acoustic well stimulation (AWS) method for enhancing the
permeability of the rock formation surrounding oil and gas wells. The AWS
method considered herein aims to exploit the well-known permeability-enhancing
effect of mechanical vibrations in acoustically porous materials, by
transmitting time-harmonic sound waves from a sound source device---placed
inside the well---to the well perforations made into the formation. The
efficiency of the AWS is assessed by quantifying the amount of acoustic energy
transmitted from the source device to the rock formation in terms of the
emission frequency and the well configuration. A simple methodology to find
optimal emission frequencies for a given well configuration is presented. The
proposed model is based on the Helmholtz equation and an impedance boundary
condition that effectively accounts for the porous solid-fluid interaction at
the interface between the rock formation and the well perforations. Exact
non-reflecting boundary conditions derived from Dirichlet-to-Neumann maps are
utilized to truncate the circular cylindrical waveguides considered in the
model. The resulting boundary value problem is then numerically solved by means
of the finite element method. A variety of numerical examples are presented in
order to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed procedure for finding
optimal emission frequencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02196</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mackain</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cottura</keyname><forenames>Maeva</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rodney</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>ILM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Clouet</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames><affiliation>SRMP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Atomic-scale modeling of twinning disconnections in zirconium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physical Review B : Condensed matter and materials physics,
  American Physical Society, 2017, 95, pp.13402</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.134102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Twin growth in hexagonal close-packed zirconium is investigated at the atomic
scale by modeling the various disconnections that can exist on twin boundaries.
Thanks to a coupling with elasticity theory, core energies are extracted from
atomistic simulations and the formation energy of isolated disconnection
dipoles is defined. For twin systems where several disconnections can exist,
because of this core contribution, the most stable disconnection is not always
the one with the smallest Burgers vector. Crystallographic parameters of the
disconnection with the lowest formation energy correlate well with twin modes
observed experimentally. On the other hand, disconnection migration,
characterized here by computing their migration energy and Peierls stress, does
not appear critical for twin mode selection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02199</id><created>2017-03-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Mingyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Zong-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidmer</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Hidden space reconstruction inspires link prediction in complex networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.data-an physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As a fundamental challenge in vast disciplines, link prediction aims to
identify potential links in a network based on the incomplete observed
information, which has broad applications ranging from uncovering missing
protein-protein interaction to predicting the evolution of networks. One of the
most influential methods rely on similarity indices characterized by the common
neighbors or its variations. We construct a hidden space mapping a network into
Euclidean space based solely on the connection structures of a network.
Compared with real geographical locations of nodes, our reconstructed locations
are in conformity with those real ones. The distances between nodes in our
hidden space could serve as a novel similarity metric in link prediction. In
addition, we hybrid our hidden space method with other state-of-the-art
similarity methods which substantially outperforms the existing methods on the
prediction accuracy. Hence, our hidden space reconstruction model provides a
fresh perspective to understand the network structure, which in particular
casts a new light on link prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02204</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author></authors><title>Computer simulation of detecting system of compact positron-emission
  tomograph based on scintillator-photodiode detectors</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Bachelor thesis supervised by Dr. N.I. Maslov</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the original computer code for the simulation of multi-element
detection system of the compact positron-emission tomograph based on a
scintillator-photodiode type of detection elements. The use of such type of
detection elements allows obtaining a high spatial resolution at a relatively
small total size of the tomograph. This program gives an opportunity to choose
the optimal geometry of detection system depending on the parameters of its
elements, and analyze the efficiency of different image reconstruction
algorithms. The handy interface for the designed compact positron-emission
tomograph operation has been created.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02206</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Piotrovich</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnedin</keyname><forenames>Yu. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natsvlishvili</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buliga</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining Recoiling Velocities of Black Holes Ejected by
  Gravitational Radiation in Galaxy Mergers</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figures, 2 tables. Accepted for publication in
  Astrophysics and Space Sciences</comments><doi>10.1007/s10509-017-3095-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent general relativistic simulations have shown that the coalescence of
two spinning black holes (BH) can lead to recoiling speeds of the BH remnant of
up to thousands of km/s as a result of the gravitational radiation emission. It
is important that the accretion disc remains bound to ejected BH within the
region where the gas orbital velocity is larger than the ejection speed. We
considered the situation when the recoiling kick radius coincides with the
radius of the broad line region (BLR). We show that in this situation the
observed polarization data of accretion disk emission allow to determine the
value of the recoil velocity. We present the estimates of the kick velocity for
AGN with determined polarization data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02207</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Hanna</keyname><forenames>Taku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiramatsu</keyname><forenames>Hidenori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakaguchi</keyname><forenames>Isao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosono</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly hydrogen-sensitive thermal desorption spectroscopy system for
  quantitative analysis of low hydrogen concentration (~1 x 10^16 atoms/cm3) in
  thin-film samples</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 88, 053103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4982255</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We developed a highly hydrogen-sensitive thermal desorption spectroscopy
(HHS-TDS) system to detect and quantitatively analyze low hydrogen
concentrations in thin films. The system was connected to an in situ
sample-transfer chamber system, manipulators, and an rf magnetron sputtering
thin-film deposition chamber under an ultra-high-vacuum (UHV) atmosphere of
~10^-8 Pa. The following key requirements were proposed in developing the
HHS-TDS: (i) a low hydrogen residual partial pressure, (ii) a low hydrogen
exhaust velocity, and (iii) minimization of hydrogen thermal desorption except
from the bulk region of the thin films. To satisfy these requirements,
appropriate materials and components were selected, and the system was
constructed to extract the maximum performance from each component.
Consequently, ~2000 times higher sensitivity to hydrogen than that of a
commercially available UHV-TDS system was achieved using H+-implanted Si
samples. Quantitative analysis of an amorphous oxide semiconductor InGaZnO4
thin film (1 cm x 1 cm x 1um thickness, hydrogen concentration of 4.5 x 10^17
atoms/cm3) was demonstrated using the HHS-TDS system. This concentration level
cannot be detected using UHV-TDS or secondary ion mass spectroscopy (SIMS)
systems. The hydrogen detection limit of the HHS-TDS system was estimated to be
~1 x 10^16 atoms/cm3, which implies ~2 orders of magnitude higher sensitivity
than that of SIMS and resonance nuclear reaction systems (~10^18 atoms/cm3).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02213</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yan-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Ying-Mao</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced quantum teleportation in the background of Schwarzschild
  spacetime by weak measurements</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is commonly believed that the fidelity of quantum teleportation in the
gravitational field would be degraded due to the heat up by the Hawking
radiation. In this paper, we point out that the Hawking effect could be
eliminated by the combined action of pre- and post-weak measurements, and thus
the teleportation fidelity is almost completely protected. It is intriguing to
notice that the enhancement of fidelity could not be attributed to the
improvement of entanglement, but rather to the probabilistic nature of weak
measurements. Our work extends the ability of weak measurements as a quantum
technique to battle against gravitational decoherence in relativistic quantum
information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02218</id><created>2017-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Arraut</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous symmetry breaking as a triangular relation between pairs of
  Goldstone bosons and the degenerate vacuum: Interactions of D-branes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate the Nambu-Goldstone theorem as a triangular relation between
pairs of Goldstone bosons with the degenerate vacuum. The vacuum degeneracy is
then a natural consequence of this relation. Inside the scenario of String
Theory, we then find that there is a correspondence between the way how the
$D$-branes interact and the properties of the Goldstone bosons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02222</id><created>2017-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Ashish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diwaker</keyname></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Anirudhha</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact solution of long-range electron transfer through conjugated
  molecular bridge</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intermolecular electron transfer reaction often occurs over long range
distances (i.e. up to several tens of angstroms) and plays a key role in
various physical, chemical and biological processes. In these reactions the
rate constant of long range electron transfer depends upon electronic coupling
between the donor and acceptor. The coupling between donor and acceptor may
increases by the atoms located between them which form a kind of bridge for
electron tunneling. By using exact analytical method we calculated the value of
electronic coupling for the above said processes in which the interaction of an
electron with the donor, acceptor are represented as Dirac delta functions and
conjugated bridge is represented by finite square well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02248</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Dolores</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Osa</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo Alcaraz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>Juan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saiz</keyname><forenames>Jose M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluation of effective medium theories for spherical nano-shells</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current effective medium theories for nano-shells are reviewed. A new method
for calculating the effective dielectric function of a core-shell nanoparticle
is presented and compared with existing theories showing clear advantages in
most conditions. It consists of introducing radiating effects in the polariz-
ability of the effective sphere, and considering the exact polarizability of
the core-shell constructed from the Mie scattering coefficient. This new
approach can be considered as an useful tool for designing coated particles
with desired plasmonic properties and engineering the effective permittivity of
composites with core-shell type inclusions which are used in photocatalysis and
solar energy harvesting applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02267</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Collet</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evelt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demidov</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prieto</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Youssef</keyname><forenames>J. Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Loubens</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bortolotti</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cros</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anane</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demokritov</keyname><forenames>S. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nano-patterned magnonic crystals based on ultrathin YIG films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures. Keywords: spin waves, magnonics, magnetic
  nanostructures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a microscopic magnonic-crystal waveguide produced by
nano-patterning of a 20 nm thick film of Yttrium Iron Garnet. By using the
phase-resolved micro-focus Brillouin light scattering spectroscopy, we map the
intensity and the phase of spin waves propagating in such a periodic magnetic
structure. Based on these maps, we obtain the dispersion and the attenuation
characteristics of spin waves providing detailed information about the physics
of spin-wave propagation in the magnonic crystal. We show that, in contrast to
the simplified physical picture, the maximum attenuation of spin waves is
achieved close to the edge of the magnonic band gap, which is associated with
non-trivial reflection characteristics of spin waves in non-uniform field
potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02281</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferrero</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizzi</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonsson</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>A Two-element Parasitic Antenna Approaching the Minimum Q-factor at a
  Given Directivity</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate a super-directive antenna based on a parasitic
structure with a circumscribing sphere of diameter 69 mm corresponding to
0.2$\lambda$@880 MHz. The antenna is modeled, simulated, measured, and it is
also evaluated against the new Q-factor bound for small antennas at a given
total directivity. A maximum directivity of 7.2 dBi is measured with a
radiation efficiency of -6.5 dB at 876 MHz. An intermediate directivity of 6.2
dBi is observed at 880 MHz with 20 dB front-to-back ratio and -7 dB radiation
efficiency. The antenna performs well with respect to the developed fundamental
bound. The results is promising for applications that require miniaturization
and spatial filtering. The above antenna properties are robust and we show with
measurements that the antenna preform well also when it is integrated as an
autonomous unit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02289</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02289</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Rosenhaus</keyname><forenames>V</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shankar</keyname><forenames>Ravi</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-symmetries II. Sub-symmetries and Conservation Laws</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Our previous paper &quot;Sub-symmetries and Infinite Conservation Laws for
  the Euler Equations&quot; has been split into Parts I and II. This is Part II;
  Part I is titled &quot;Sub-symmetries I. Main properties and applications&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our previous paper, the concept of sub-symmetry of a differential system
was introduced, and its properties and some applications were studied. It was
shown that sub-symmetries are important in decoupling a differential system,
and in the deformation of a system's conservation laws, to a greater extent
than regular symmetries. In this paper, we study the nature of a correspondence
between sub-symmetries and conservation laws of a differential system. We show
that for a large class of non-Lagrangian systems, there is a natural
association between sub-symmetries and local conservation laws based on the
Noether operator identity, and we prove an analogue of the first Noether
Theorem for sub-symmetries. We also demonstrate that infinite conservation laws
containing arbitrary functions of dependent variables can be generated by
infinite sub-symmetries through the Noether operator identity. We discuss the
application of sub-symmetries to the incompressible Euler equations of fluid
dynamics. Despite the fact that infinite symmetries (with arbitrary functions
of dependent variables) are not known for the Euler equations, we show that
these equations possess infinite sub-symmetries. We calculate infinite
sub-symmetries with arbitrary functions of dependent variables for the two-and
three-dimensional Euler equations in the velocity and vorticity formulations
with certain constraints. We demonstrate that these sub-symmetries generate
known series of infinite conservation laws, and obtain new classes of infinite
conservation laws
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02292</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Fass&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>CERN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>CERN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mokhov</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames><affiliation>HZDR, Dresden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames><affiliation>SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Roesler</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>CERN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sanami</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>KEK, Tsukuba</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Striganov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Versaci</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ELI Beamlines, Prague</affiliation></author></authors><title>Update On The Code Intercomparison and Benchmark For Muon Fluence and
  Absorbed Dose Induced By An 18-GeV Electron Beam After Massive Iron Shielding</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>14 pp. Presented paper at the 13th Meeting of the task-force on
  Shielding aspects of Accelerators, Targets and Irradiation Facilities
  (SATIF-13), HZDR, October 10-12, 2016, Dresden, Germany. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1502.01681</comments><proxy>Fermilab Proxy</proxy><report-no>Fermilab-Conf-16-574-APC</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In 1974, Nelson, Kase and Svensson published an experimental investigation on
muon shielding around SLAC high-energy electron accelerators. They measured
muon fluence and absorbed dose induced by 14 and 18 GeV electron beams hitting
a copper/water beamdump and attenuated in a thick steel shielding. In their
paper, they compared the results with the theoretical models available at that
time.
  In order to compare their experimental results with present model
calculations, we use the modern transport Monte Carlo codes MARS15, FLUKA2011
and GEANT4 to model the experimental setup and run simulations. The results are
then compared between the codes, and with the SLAC data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02305</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Shai</keyname><forenames>Saray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanley</keyname><forenames>Natalie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Granell</keyname><forenames>Clara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Dane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mucha</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Case studies in network community detection</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Community structure describes the organization of a network into subgraphs
that contain a prevalence of edges within each subgraph and relatively few
edges across boundaries between subgraphs. The development of
community-detection methods has occurred across disciplines, with numerous and
varied algorithms proposed to find communities. As we present in this Chapter
via several case studies, community detection is not just an &quot;end game&quot; unto
itself, but rather a step in the analysis of network data which is then useful
for furthering research in the disciplinary domain of interest. These
case-study examples arise from diverse applications, ranging from social and
political science to neuroscience and genetics, and we have chosen them to
demonstrate key aspects of community detection and to highlight that community
detection, in practice, should be directed by the application at hand.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02311</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsova</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leonov</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokaev</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stankevich</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization of hidden Chua attractors by the describing function method</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>Submitted to IFAC</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the Chua circuit with five linear elements and saturation
non-linearity is studied. Numerical localization of self-excited attractor in
the Chua circuit model can be done by computation of trajectory with initial
data in a vicinity of an unstable equilibrium. For a hidden attractor its basin
of attraction does not overlap with a small vicinity of equilibria, so it is
difficult to find the corresponding initial data for localization. This survey
is devoted to the application of describing function method for localization of
hidden periodic and chaotic attractors in the Chua model. We use a rigorous
justification of the describing function method, based on the method of small
parameter, to get the initial data for the visualization of the hidden
attractors. A new configuration of hidden Chua attractors is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.02323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-05-08</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.02323</id><created>2017-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Pigozzo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carneiro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing cosmic isotropy with galaxies position angles distribution</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the distribution of position angles of 1 million galaxies from the
Hyperleda catalogue, a sample that presents the galaxies coordinates in the
celestial sphere, information that allows us to look for a possible privileged
direction. Our analysis involves different tests and statistical methods, from
which it is possible to infer with high probability ($p$-value extremely low)
that the galactic planes are not randomly oriented in the sky. Whether this is
an evidence of a cosmological anisotropy or an observational bias due to local
effects is something deserving further studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
