<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:57:11Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-02" from="2017-01-02" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0907.0858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0907.0858</id><created>2009-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Ganquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jianhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Lee</forenames></author></authors><title>A Double Layer Electromagnetic Cloak And GL EM Modeling</title><categories>physics.optics physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>A Novel GL double Layer cloaks are proposed. Moreover, we discovered
  a single negative refractive index metamaterial. We fill it inside the single
  cloaked concealment, the EM wave field excited inside the this material in
  the concealment propagates out to free space through the single layer cloak.
  13 figures are included</comments><report-no>GLGEO EMCLOAK 01909</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we propose a novel electromagnetic (EM) cloaking structure
that consists of two annular layers between three spherical shells and model
its performance numerically and theoretically by using a Global and Local EM
field (GL) method. The two annular layers contain distinct cloaking materials:
the outer layer provides invisibility; the inner layer is fully absorbing. The
cloaking materials are weakly degenerative. The wavefield from an EM source
located outside the cloak propagates as in free space outside the outer shell,
never be disturbed by the cloak and does not penetrate into the inner absorbing
layer and concealment.
  The field of a source located inside inner layer or the cloaked concealment
is completely absorbed by the inner layer and never reaches the outside of the
middle shell, Moreover, the EM wavefield excited in concealment is not
disrupted by the cloak. There exists no Maxwell EM wavefield can be excited in
a single layer cloaked concealment which is filled by normal material.
Moreover, we find a negative dielectric and positive susceptibility
metamaterial to fill into the concealment, such that the interior EM wave
propagates from the concealment to free space through the single layer cloak.
Therefore, the double layer cloak is important and necessary for complete
invisibility. Numerical simulations and theoretical analysis verifying these
properties are performed using the GL EM modeling method that we described in
this paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.1889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.1889</id><created>2012-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tong</keyname><forenames>N. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single Mode Approximation for sub-Ohmic Spin-Boson Model: Adiabatic
  Limit and Critical Properties</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 86, 141 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2013-31100-y</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the quantum phase transition in the sub-Ohmic spin-boson model
is studied using a single-mode approximation, by combining the rotating wave
transformation and the transformations used in the numerical renormalization
group (NRG). Analytical results for the critical coupling strength $\alpha_c$,
the magnetic susceptibility $\chi(T)$, and the spin-spin correlation function
$C(\omega)$ at finite temperatures are obtained and further confirmed by
numerical results. We obtain the same $\alpha_c$ as the mean-field
approximation. The critical exponents are classical: $\beta=1/2$, $\delta=3$,
$\gamma=1$, $x=1/2$, $y_t^{*}=1/2$, in agreement with the spin-boson model in
$0&lt;s&lt;1/2$ regime. $C(\omega)$ has nontrivial behavior reflecting coherent
oscillation with temperature dependent damping effects due to the environment.
We point out the original NRG has problem with the crossover temperature
$T^{*}$, and propose a chain Hamiltonian possibly suitable for implementing NRG
without boson state truncation error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.3176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.3176</id><created>2013-06-13</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bremer</keyname><forenames>Christopher L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sage</keyname><forenames>Daniel S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A theory of minimal K-types for flat G-bundles</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>37 pages. A new trivialization-free definition of containment of a
  stratum in a flat G-bundle has been added. The paper has been reorganized so
  that the main definitions and results are given in Section 2</comments><msc-class>14D24 (Primary), 22E67, 34Mxx (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The theory of minimal K-types for p-adic reductive groups was developed in
part to classify irreducible admissible representations with wild ramification.
An important observation was that minimal K-types associated to such
representations correspond to fundamental strata. These latter objects are
triples (x, r, beta), where x is a point in the Bruhat-Tits building of the
reductive group G, r is a nonnegative real number, and beta is a semistable
functional on the degree r associated graded piece of the Moy-Prasad filtration
corresponding to x.
  Recent work on the wild ramification case of the geometric Langlands
conjectures suggests that fundamental strata also play a role in the geometric
setting. In this paper, we develop a theory of minimal K-types for formal flat
G-bundles. We show that any formal flat G-bundle contains a fundamental
stratum; moreover, all such strata have the same rational depth. We thus obtain
a new invariant of a flat G-bundle called the slope, generalizing the classical
definition for flat connections. The slope can also be realized as the minimum
depth of a stratum contained in the flat G-bundle, and in the case of positive
slope, all such minimal depth strata are fundamental. Finally, we show that a
flat G-bundle is irregular singular if and only if it has positive slope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.0223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.0223</id><created>2014-05-01</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ambikasaran</keyname><forenames>Sivaram</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Neil</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Karan Raj</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast symmetric factorization of hierarchical matrices with applications</title><categories>math.NA cs.NA physics.flu-dyn stat.CO</categories><comments>18 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a fast direct algorithm for computing symmetric factorizations,
i.e. $A = WW^T$, of symmetric positive-definite hierarchical matrices with
weak-admissibility conditions. The computational cost for the symmetric
factorization scales as $\mathcal{O}(n \log^2 n)$ for hierarchically
off-diagonal low-rank matrices. Once this factorization is obtained, the cost
for inversion, application, and determinant computation scales as
$\mathcal{O}(n \log n)$. In particular, this allows for the near optimal
generation of correlated random variates in the case where $A$ is a covariance
matrix. This symmetric factorization algorithm depends on two key ingredients.
First, we present a novel symmetric factorization formula for low-rank updates
to the identity of the form $I+UKU^T$. This factorization can be computed in
$\mathcal{O}(n)$ time if the rank of the perturbation is sufficiently small.
Second, combining this formula with a recursive divide-and-conquer strategy,
near linear complexity symmetric factorizations for hierarchically structured
matrices can be obtained. We present numerical results for matrices relevant to
problems in probability \&amp; statistics (Gaussian processes), interpolation
(Radial basis functions), and Brownian dynamics calculations in fluid mechanics
(the Rotne-Prager-Yamakawa tensor).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.2161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.2161</id><created>2014-08-09</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mira</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author></authors><title>The last sunset on mainland Europe</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Cartography and Geographic Information Science (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/15230406.2016.1249409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper documents the places in mainland Europe at which the sun sets
latest, by Coordinated Universal Time (UTC), on any given day (distortion due
to differences in local standard times is ignored). In contradiction to the
na\&quot;ive assumption that the sun always sets latest at the westernmost point,
the point of last sunset changes cyclically over the course of a year due to
the changing orientation of the axis of the Earth with respect to the sun.
Specifically, between the winter and summer solstices the last sunset shifts
successively from Cabo de Sao Vicente (Portugal) to Cabo da Roca (Portugal) to
Cabo Tourinan (Spain) to a site near Aglapsvik (Norway) to a location in the
Norwegian municipality of Masoy south of Havoysund; and it shifts back again
between the summer and winter solstices. There are two days in the year (April
24th and August 18th) on which the last sunset of mainland Europe (shared in
those days effectively by Cabo Tourinan and the Aglapsvik area) coincides with
the last sunset of mainland Africa, at a site in Western Sahara near Cap Blanc.
A similar analysis of the first Spanish sunrise shows that from April 22nd to
August 20th it occurs on the Costa Brava at Cap de Creus (Catalonia), and the
rest of the year at Punta de s'Espero (Balearic Islands), the easternmost point
of Spain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.07689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.07689</id><created>2015-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hengyue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tong</keyname><forenames>Ning-Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>A Standard Basis Operator Equation of Motion Impurity Solver for
  Dynamical Mean Field Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 88, 319 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60082-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an efficient impurity solver for the dynamical mean-field theory
(DMFT). It is based on the separation of bath degrees of freedom into the low
energy and the high energy parts. The former is solved exactly using exact
diagonalization and the latter is treated approximately using Green's function
equation of motion decoupling approximation. The two parts are combined
coherently under the standard basis operator formalism. The impurity solver is
applied to the Anderson impurity model and, combined with DMFT, to the one-band
Hubbard model. Qualitative agreement is found with other well established
methods. Some promising features and possible improvements of the present
solver are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04781</id><created>2015-04-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Aerts</keyname><forenames>Diederik</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano Sassoli</forenames></author></authors><title>The Extended Bloch Representation of Quantum Mechanics. Explaining
  Superposition, Interference and Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>40 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 122110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973356</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extended Bloch representation of quantum mechanics was recently derived
to offer a (hidden-measurement) solution to the measurement problem. In this
article we use it to investigate the geometry of superposition and entangled
states, explaining the interference effects, and the entanglement correlations,
in terms of the different orientations that a state-vector can take within the
generalized Bloch sphere. We also introduce a tensorial determination of the
generators of SU(N), particularly suitable to describe multipartite systems,
from the viewpoint of the sub-entities. We then use it to show that non-product
states admit a general description in which the sub-entities can always remain
in well-defined states, even when they are entangled. Therefore, the completed
version of quantum mechanics provided by the extended Bloch representation, in
which the density operators are also representative of pure states, allows to
solve not only the well-known measurement problem, but also the lesser-known
entanglement problem. This because we no longer need to give up the general
physical principle saying that a composite entity exists, and therefore is in a
pure state, if and only if its components also exist, and therefore are in
well-defined pure states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04704</id><created>2015-06-15</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sekara</keyname><forenames>Vedran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stopczynski</keyname><forenames>Arkadiusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lehmann</keyname><forenames>Sune</forenames></author></authors><title>Fundamental structures of dynamic social networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>Main Manuscript: 16 pages, 4 figures. Supplementary Information: 39
  pages, 34 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, USA 113 (36),
  9977-9982, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1602803113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Social systems are in a constant state of flux with dynamics spanning from
minute-by-minute changes to patterns present on the timescale of years.
Accurate models of social dynamics are important for understanding spreading of
influence or diseases, formation of friendships, and the productivity of teams.
While there has been much progress on understanding complex networks over the
past decade, little is known about the regularities governing the
micro-dynamics of social networks. Here we explore the dynamic social network
of a densely-connected population of approximately 1000 individuals and their
interactions in the network of real-world person-to-person proximity measured
via Bluetooth, as well as their telecommunication networks, online social media
contacts, geo-location, and demographic data. These high-resolution data allow
us to observe social groups directly, rendering community detection
unnecessary. Starting from 5-minute time slices we uncover dynamic social
structures expressed on multiple timescales. On the hourly timescale, we find
that gatherings are fluid, with members coming and going, but organized via a
stable core of individuals. Each core represents a social context. Cores
exhibit a pattern of recurring meetings across weeks and months, each with
varying degrees of regularity. Taken together, these findings provide a
powerful simplification of the social network, where cores represent
fundamental structures expressed with strong temporal and spatial regularity.
Using this framework, we explore the complex interplay between social and
geospatial behavior, documenting how the formation of cores are preceded by
coordination behavior in the communication networks, and demonstrating that
social behavior can be predicted with high precision.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04308</id><created>2015-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Mingming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Tommy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanski</keyname><forenames>Boleslaw K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A New Metric for Quality of Network Community Structure</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modularity is widely used to effectively measure the strength of the
community structure found by community detection algorithms. However,
modularity maximization suffers from two opposite yet coexisting problems: in
some cases, it tends to favor small communities over large ones while in
others, large communities over small ones. The latter tendency is known in the
literature as the resolution limit problem. To address them, we propose to
modify modularity by subtracting from it the fraction of edges connecting nodes
of different communities and by including community density into modularity. We
refer to the modified metric as Modularity Density and we demonstrate that it
indeed resolves both problems mentioned above. We describe the motivation for
introducing this metric by using intuitively clear and simple examples. We also
prove that this new metric solves the resolution limit problem. Finally, we
discuss the results of applying this metric, modularity, and several other
popular community quality metrics to two real dynamic networks. The results
imply that Modularity Density is consistent with all the community quality
measurements but not modularity, which suggests that Modularity Density is an
improved measurement of the community quality compared to modularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08161</id><created>2015-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Chamseddine</keyname><forenames>Ali H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Connes</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Suijlekom</keyname><forenames>Walter D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Grand Unification in the Spectral Pati-Salam Model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1511 (2015) 011</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2015)011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the running at one-loop of the gauge couplings in the spectral
Pati-Salam model that was derived in the framework of noncommutative geometry.
There are a few different scenario's for the scalar particle content which are
determined by the precise form of the Dirac operator for the finite
noncommutative space. We consider these different scenarios and establish for
all of them unification of the Pati-Salam gauge couplings. The boundary
conditions are set by the usual RG flow for the Standard Model couplings at an
intermediate mass scale at which the Pati-Salam symmetry is broken.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05793</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Messias V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; B. da</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Leite</keyname><forenames>Marcelo M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modern finite-size criticality: Dirichlet and Neumann boundary
  conditions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mtrl-sci hep-th</categories><comments>69 pages, 27 figures, some typos fixed, cosmetic changes</comments><report-no>YITP-35</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Finite-size critical systems defined on a parallel plate geometry of finite
extent along one single ($z$) direction with Dirichlet and Neumann boundary
conditions at $z=0,L$ are analyzed in momentum space. We introduce a modified
representation for the discrete eigenfunctions in a renormalized one-particle
irreducible vertex part ($1PI$) scalar field-theoretic framework using either
massless or massive fields. The appearance of multiplicities in the Feynman
rules to construct diagrams due to this choice of representation of the basis
functions is discussed along with the modified normalization conditions. For
nonvanishing external quasi-momenta, Dirichlet and Neumann boundary conditions
are shown to be unified within a single formalism. We examine the dimensional
crossover regimes for these and show a correspondence with those from
antiperiodic and periodic boundary conditions. It is demonstrated that
finite-size effects for Dirichlet and Neumann boundary conditions do not
require surface fields necessarily but are implemented nontrivially from the
Feynman rules involving only bulk terms in the Lagrangian. As an application,
the critical exponents $\eta$ and $\nu$ are evaluated at least up to two-loop
level through diagrammatic means. We show that the critical indices are the
same as those from the bulk (infinite) system irrespective of the boundary
conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04799</id><created>2015-10-16</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maity</keyname><forenames>Alok Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaudhury</keyname><forenames>Pinaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banik</keyname><forenames>Suman K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Information theoretical study of cross-talk mediated signal transduction
  in MAPK pathways</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Revised version, 17 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biochemical networks related to similar functional pathways are often
correlated due to cross-talk among the homologous proteins in the different
networks. Using a stochastic framework, we address the functional significance
of the cross-talk between two pathways. Our theoretical analysis on generic
MAPK pathways reveals cross-talk is responsible for developing coordinated
fluctuations between the pathways. The extent of correlation evaluated in terms
of the information theoretic measure provides directionality to net information
propagation. Stochastic time series and scattered plot suggest that the
cross-talk generates synchronization within a cell as well as in a cellular
population. Depending on the number of input and output, we identify signal
integration and signal bifurcation motif that arise due to inter-pathway
connectivity in the composite network. Analysis using partial information
decomposition quantifies the net synergy in the information propagation through
these branched pathways.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07538</id><created>2015-12-23</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hongliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Sichun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author></authors><title>Echoes of Inflationary First-Order Phase Transitions in the CMB</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>5+6 pages, 4 figures. V2 changed title, added one figure about
  constraints of Planck2015+BICEP2/Keck data, added references and removed
  appendix. Accepted by PLB</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.12.029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmological phase transitions (CPTs), such as the Grand Unified Theory (GUT)
and the electroweak (EW) ones, play a significant role in both particle physics
and cosmology. In this letter, we propose to probe the first-order CPTs, by
detecting gravitational waves (GWs) which are generated during the phase
transitions through the cosmic microwave background (CMB). If happened around
the inflation era, the first-order CPTs may yield low-frequency GWs due to
bubble dynamics, leaving imprints on the CMB. In contrast to the nearly
scale-invariant primordial GWs caused by vacuum fluctuation, these
bubble-generated GWs are scale dependent and have non-trivial B-mode spectra.
If decoupled from inflaton, the EWPT during inflation may serve as a probe for
the one after reheating where the baryon asymmetry could be generated via EW
baryogenesis (EWBG). The CMB thus provides a potential way to test the
feasibility of the EWBG, complementary to the collider measurements of Higgs
potential and the direct detection of GWs generated during EWPT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04941</id><created>2016-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chamseddine</keyname><forenames>Ali H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhanov</keyname><forenames>Viatcheslav</forenames></author></authors><title>Inhomogeneous Dark Energy</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1602 (2016) no.02, 040</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/02/040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We modify Einstein General Relativity by adding non-dynamical scalar fields
to account simultaneously for both dark matter and dark energy. The dark energy
in this case can be distributed in-homogeneously even within horizon scales.
Its inhomogeneities can contribute to the late time integrated Sachs-Wolfe
effect, possibly removing some of the low multipole anomalies in the
temperature fluctuations of the CMB spectrum. The presence of the inhomogeneous
dark matter also influences structure formation in the universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07137</id><created>2016-01-23</created><updated>2016-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ulrich</keyname><forenames>James L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Posner computing: a quantum neural network model</title><categories>quant-ph cs.ET</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a construction, rendered in Quipper, of a quantum algorithm which
probabilistically computes a classical function from n bits to n bits. The
construction is intended to be of interest primarily for the features of
Quipper it highlights. However, intrigued by the utility of quantum information
processing in the context of neural networks, we present the algorithm as a
simplest example of a particular quantum neural network which we first define.
As the definition is inspired by recent work of Fisher concerning possible
quantum substrates to cognition, we precede it with a short description of that
work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02295</id><created>2016-02-06</created><updated>2016-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chamseddine</keyname><forenames>Ali H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhanov</keyname><forenames>Viatcheslav</forenames></author></authors><title>On Unification of Gravity and Gauge Interactions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages. Mirror fermions now acquire masses utilizing a mechanism
  employed for topological superconductors</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1603 (2016) 020</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Considering a higher dimensional Lorentz group as the tangent symmetry, we
unify gravity and gauge interactions in a natural way. The spin connection of
the gauged Lorentz group is then responsible for both gravity and gauge fields,
and the action for the gauged fields becomes part of the spin curvature
squared. The realistic group which unifies all known particles and interactions
is the $SO(1,13)$ Lorentz group whose gauge part leads to $SO(10)$ grand
unified theory and contains double the number of required fermions in the
fundamental spinor representation. Mirror fermions could acquire mass utilizing
a mechanism employed for topological superconductors. Family unification could
be achieved by considering the $SO(1,21)$ Lorentz group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07670</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-07-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lombriser</keyname><forenames>Lucas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>Nelson A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Challenges to Self-Acceleration in Modified Gravity from Gravitational
  Waves and Large-Scale Structure</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages; v2 updated with newer data; v3 extended title</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 765, 382 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.12.048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the advent of gravitational-wave astronomy marked by the aLIGO GW150914
and GW151226 observations, a measurement of the cosmological speed of gravity
will likely soon be realized. We show that a confirmation of equality to the
speed of light as indicated by indirect Galactic observations will have
important consequences for a very large class of alternative explanations of
the late-time accelerated expansion of our Universe. It will break the dark
degeneracy of self-accelerated Horndeski scalar-tensor theories in the
large-scale structure that currently limits a rigorous discrimination between
acceleration from modified gravity and from a cosmological constant or dark
energy. Signatures of a self-acceleration must then manifest in the linear,
unscreened cosmological structure. We describe the minimal modification
required for self-acceleration with standard gravitational-wave speed and show
that its maximum likelihood yields a 3-sigma poorer fit to cosmological
observations compared to a cosmological constant. Hence, equality between the
speeds challenges the concept of cosmic acceleration from a genuine
scalar-tensor modification of gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00686</id><created>2016-03-02</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Birchall</keyname><forenames>Patrick M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabines-Chesterking</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>Jeremy L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cable</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>Jonathan C. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beating the Shot-Noise Limit with Sources of Partially-Distinguishable
  Photons</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 + 3 pages, 3 + 0 figures, comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum metrology promises high-precision measurements beyond the capability
of any classical techniques, and has the potential to be integral to
investigative techniques. However, all sensors must tolerate imperfections if
they are to be practical. Here we show that photons with perfectly overlapped
modes, which are therefore fully indistinguishable, are not required for
quantum-enhanced measurement, and that partially-distinguishable photons do not
have to be engineered to mitigate the adverse effects of distinguishability. We
quantify the effect of distinguishability on quantum metrology experiments, and
report results of an experiment to verify that two- and four-photon states
containing partially-distinguishable photons can achieve quantum-enhanced
sensitivity with low-visibility quantum interference. This demonstrates that
sources producing photons with mixed spectral states can be readily utilized
for quantum metrology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01780</id><created>2016-03-05</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tissot</keyname><forenames>Francois L. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dauphas</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossman</keyname><forenames>Lawrence</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of uranium isotope variations in early solar nebula condensates</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>51 pages, 3 figures, 1 table, 22 supplementary figures, 8
  supplementary tables</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Adv. 2016;2:e1501400</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1501400</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High temperature condensates found in meteorites display uranium isotopic
variations (235U/238U) that complicate dating of the formation of the Solar
System and whose origin remains mysterious. It is possible that these
variations are due to decay of the short-lived radionuclide 247Cm (t1/2=15.6
Myr) into 235U but they could also be due to uranium kinetic isotopic
fractionation during condensation. We report uranium isotope measurements of
meteoritic refractory inclusions that reveal excesses of 235U reaching ~+6 %
relative to average solar system composition, which can only be due to decay of
247Cm. This allows us to constrain the 247Cm/235U ratio at Solar System
formation to (7.0 +- 1.6) x 10-5. This value provides new clues on the
universality of nucleosynthetic r-process of rapid neutron capture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01946</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Isaev</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schachenmayer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rey</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit coupled correlated metal phase in Kondo lattices: an
  implementation with alkaline-earth atoms</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 135302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.135302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that an interplay between quantum effects, strong on-site
ferromagnetic exchange interaction and antiferromagnetic correlations in Kondo
lattices can give rise to an exotic spin-orbit coupled metallic state in
regimes where classical treatments predict a trivial insulating behavior. This
phenomenon can be simulated with ultracold alkaline-earth fermionic atoms
subject to a laser-induced magnetic field by observing dynamics of spin-charge
excitations in quench experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03953</id><created>2016-03-12</created><updated>2016-03-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scozzaro</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruchotzke</keyname><forenames>Will</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belding</keyname><forenames>Amanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardellino</keyname><forenames>Jeremy D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blomberg</keyname><forenames>Erick C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCullian</keyname><forenames>Brendan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhallamudi</keyname><forenames>Vidya P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelekhov</keyname><forenames>Denis V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammel</keyname><forenames>P. Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Resonance Force Detection using a Membrane Resonator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Magnetic Resonance Volume 271, October 2016, Pages
  15-20</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmr.2016.07.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The availability of compact, low-cost magnetic resonance imaging instruments
would further broaden the substantial impact of this technology. We report
highly sensitive detection of magnetic resonance using low-stress silicon
nitride (SiN$_x$) membranes. We use these membranes as low-loss, high-frequency
mechanical oscillators and find they are able to mechanically detect
spin-dependent forces with high sensitivity enabling ultrasensitive magnetic
resonance detection. The high force detection sensitivity stems from their high
mechanical quality factor $Q\sim10^6$ combined with the low mass of the
resonator. We use this excellent mechanical force sensitivity to detect the
electron spin magnetic resonance using a SiN$_x$ membrane as a force detector.
The demonstrated force sensitivity at 300 K is 4 fN/$\sqrt{\mathrm{Hz}}$,
indicating a potential low temperature (4 K) sensitivity of 25
aN/$\sqrt{\mathrm{Hz}}$. Given their sensitivity, robust construction, large
surface area and low cost, SiN$_x$ membranes can potentially serve as the
central component of a compact room-temperature ESR and NMR instrument that has
superior spatial resolution to conventional approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06057</id><created>2016-03-19</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garg</keyname><forenames>Priyanka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choudhuri</keyname><forenames>Indrani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahata</keyname><forenames>Arup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author></authors><title>Band Gap Opening in Stanene Induced by Patterned B-N doping</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>29 Pages, 7 figures and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP07505C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stanene is a quantum spin hall insulator and a promising material for
electronic and optoelectronic devices. Density functional theory (DFT)
calculations are performed to study the band gap opening in stanene by
elemental mono- (B, N) and co-doping (B-N). Different patterned B-N co-doping
is studied to change the electronic properties in stanene. A patterned B-N
co-doping opens the band gap in stanene and the semiconducting nature persists
with strain. Molecular dynamics (MD) simulations are performed to confirm the
thermal stability of such doped system. The stress-strain study indicates that
such doped system is as stable as pure stanene. Our work function calculations
show that stanene and doped stanene has lower work function than graphene and
thus promising material for photocatalysis and electronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01949</id><created>2016-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tylec</keyname><forenames>Tomasz I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on the tensor product structure of no-signaling theories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><msc-class>81P45, 81P10, 03G12</msc-class><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/50/4/04LT02</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the quantum logic framework we show that the no-signaling box model is a
particular type of tensor product of the logics of single boxes. Such notion of
tensor product is too strong to apply in the category of logics of quantum
mechanical systems. Consequently, we show that the no-signaling box models
cannot be considered as generalizations of quantum mechanical models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02236</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborti</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Arun Singh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanaujia</keyname><forenames>Pawan K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nath</keyname><forenames>Palash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>G. Vijaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanyal</keyname><forenames>Dirtha</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonance Raman scattering and ab initio calculation of electron energy
  loss spectra of MoS2 nanosheets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, uses IOP style</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 380 (2016) 4057-4061</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.10.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The presence of electron energy loss (EELS) peak is proposed theoretically in
molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) nanosheets. Using density functional theory
simulations and calculations, one EELS peak is identified in the visible energy
range, for MoS2 nanosheets with molybdenum vacancy. Experimentally, four
different laser sources are used for the Raman scattering study of MoS2
nanosheets, which show two distinct Raman peaks, one at 385 cm-1 (E12g) and the
other at 408 cm-1 (A1g). In the cases of three laser sources with wavelengths
405 nm (3.06 eV), 632 nm (1.96 eV) and 785 nm (1.58 eV), respectively, the
intensity of E12g Raman peak is more than the A1g Raman peak, while in the case
of excitation source of 532 nm (2.33 eV), the intensity profile is reversed and
A1g peak is the most intense. Thus a resonance Raman scattering phenomenon is
observed for 532 nm laser source.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04648</id><created>2016-04-15</created><updated>2016-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davoody</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karimi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knezevic</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of Exciton Energy Transfer in Carbon Nanotube Composites</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry C 120 (30), 16354-16366 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.6b04050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the exciton transfer (ET) rate between semiconducting single-wall
carbon nanotubes (SWNTs). We show that the main reasons for the wide range of
measured ET rates reported in the literature are 1) exciton confinement in
local quantum wells stemming from disorder in the environment and 2) exciton
thermalization between dark and bright states due to intratube scattering. The
SWNT excitonic states are calculated by solving the Bethe-Salpeter equation
using tight-binding basis functions. The ET rates due to intertube Coulomb
interaction are computed via Fermi's golden rule. In pristine samples, the ET
rate between parallel (bundled) SWNTs of similar chirality is very high ($\sim
10^{14}\;\text{s}^{-1}$) while the ET rate for dissimilar or nonparallel tubes
is considerably lower ($\sim 10^{12}\;\text{s}^{-1}$). Exciton confinement
reduces the ET rate between same-chirality parallel SWNTs by two orders of
magnitude, but has little effect otherwise. Consequently, the ET rate in most
measurements will be on the order of $ 10^{12}\;\text{s}^{-1}$, regardless of
the tube relative orientation or chirality. Exciton thermalization between
bright and dark states further reduces the ET rate to about
$10^{11}\;\text{s}^{-1}$. The ET rate also increases with increasing
temperature and decreases with increasing dielectric constant of the
surrounding medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08682</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-09-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rastegin</keyname><forenames>Alexey E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic uncertainty relations for successive measurements of
  canonically conjugate observables</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, no figures. Final improvements. The bibliography is
  extended. To appear in Ann. Phys. (Berlin)</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. (Berlin), Vol. 528, 835-844 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201600130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Uncertainties in successive measurements of general canonically conjugate
variables are examined. Such operators are approached within a limiting
procedure of the Pegg-Barnett type. Dealing with unbounded observables, we
should take into account a finiteness of detector resolution. An appropriate
reformulation of two scenarios of successive measurements is proposed and
motivated. Uncertainties are characterized by means of generalized entropies of
both the R\'{e}nyi and Tsallis types. The R\'{e}nyi and Tsallis formulations of
uncertainty relations are obtained for both the scenarios of successive
measurements of canonically conjugate operators. Entropic uncertainty relations
for the case of position and momentum are separately discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01611</id><created>2016-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Denjoe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filev</keyname><forenames>Veselin G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Membrane Matrix models and non-perturbative checks of gauge/gravity
  duality</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat</categories><comments>11 pages and 4 figures. To appear in the Proceedings of the Corfu
  Summer Institute 2015 &quot;School and Workshops on Elementary Particle Physics
  and Gravity&quot; 1-27 September 2015 Corfu, Greece</comments><report-no>DIAS-STP-16-03</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the bosonic and maximally supersymmetric membrane models. We find
that in Hoppe regulated form the bosonic membrane is well approximated by
massive Gaussian quantum matrix models. In contrast the similarly regulated
supersymmetric membrane, which is equivalent to the BFSS model, has a gravity
dual description. We sketch recent progress in checking gauge/gravity duality
in this context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02722</id><created>2016-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferraro</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>J. Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battaglia</keyname><forenames>Nick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spergel</keyname><forenames>David N.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Kinematic Sunyaev-Zel'dovich Effect with Projected Fields II:
  prospects, challenges, and comparison with simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123526 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123526</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The kinematic Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (kSZ) signal is a powerful probe of the
cosmic baryon distribution. The kSZ signal is proportional to the integrated
free electron momentum rather than the electron pressure (which sources the
thermal SZ signal). Since velocities should be unbiased on large scales, the
kSZ signal is an unbiased tracer of the large-scale electron distribution, and
thus can be used to detect the &quot;missing baryon&quot; that evade most observational
techniques. While most current methods for kSZ extraction rely on the
availability of very accurate redshifts, we revisit a method that allows
measurements even in the absence of redshift information for individual
objects. It involves cross-correlating the square of an appropriately filtered
cosmic microwave background (CMB) temperature map with a projected density map
constructed from a sample of large-scale structure tracers. We show that this
method will achieve high signal-to-noise when applied to the next generation of
high-resolution CMB experiments, provided that component separation is
sufficiently effective at removing foreground contamination. Considering
statistical errors only, we forecast that this estimator can yield $S/N \approx
$ 3, 120 and over 150 for Planck, Advanced ACTPol, and hypothetical Stage-IV
CMB experiments, respectively, in combination with a galaxy catalog from WISE,
and about 20% larger $S/N$ for a galaxy catalog from the proposed SPHEREx
experiment. This work serves as a companion paper to the first kSZ measurement
with this method, where we used CMB temperature maps constructed from Planck
and WMAP data, together with galaxies from the WISE survey, to obtain a 3.8 -
4.5$\sigma$ detection of the kSZ$^2$ amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06802</id><created>2016-05-22</created><updated>2016-12-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jiaqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Weisheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Shouzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Lang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Youguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bournel</keyname><forenames>Arnaud</forenames></author></authors><title>Large influence of capping layers on tunnel magnetoresistance in
  magnetic tunnel junctions</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 242403 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been reported in experiments that capping layers which enhance the
perpendicular magnetic anisotropy (PMA) of magnetic tunnel junctions (MTJs)
induce great impact on the tunnel magnetoresistance (TMR). To explore the
essential influence caused by capping layers, we carry out ab initio
calculations on TMR in the X(001)|CoFe(001)|MgO(001)|CoFe(001)|X(001) MTJ,
where X represents the capping layer material which can be tungsten, tantalum
or hafnium. We report TMR in different MTJs and demonstrate that tungsten is an
ideal candidate for a giant TMR ratio. The transmission spectrum in Brillouin
zone is presented. It can be seen that in the parallel condition of MTJ, sharp
transmission peaks appear in the minority-spin channel. This phenomenon is
attributed to the resonant tunnel transmission effect and we explained it by
the layer-resolved density of states (DOS). In order to explore transport
properties in MTJs, the density of scattering states (DOSS) was studied from
the point of band symmetry. It has been found that CoFe|tungsten interface
blocks scattering states transmission in the anti-parallel condition. This work
reports TMR and transport properties in MTJs with different capping layers, and
proves that tungsten is a proper capping layer material, which would benefit
the design and optimization of MTJs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01189</id><created>2016-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Chamseddine</keyname><forenames>Ali H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quanta of Geometry and Unification</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>To appear in the Proceedings of Abdus Salam 90th Birthday Memorial
  meeting, Editors L. Brink, M. Duff and K. Phua, 10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Mod.Phys.Lett. A31 (2016) no.40, 1630046</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316300469</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a tribute to Abdus Salam's memory whose insight and creative thinking
set for me a role model to follow. In this contribution I show that the simple
requirement of volume quantization in space-time (with Euclidean signature)
uniquely determines the geometry to be that of a noncommutative space whose
finite part is based on an algebra that leads to Pati-Salam grand unified
models. The Standard Model corresponds to a special case where a mathematical
constraint (order one condition) is satisfied. This provides evidence that
Salam was a visionary who was generations ahead of his time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02841</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Koley</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure Driven Phase Transition in 1T-TiSe$_2$ , a MOIPT+DMFT Study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 Pages, 6 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Solid State Communications 251, 23, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2016.12.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of unconventional superconductivity associated with charge density
wave order in transition metal dichalcogenides is currently a debated issue.
Starting from a normal state elec- tronic structure followed by a charge
ordered state how superconductivity in 1T-TiSe 2 arises with applied pressure
is still under research. A preformed excitonic liquid driven ordered state
mediated superconductivity is found in broad class of TMD on the border of CDW.
Using dynamical mean field theory with input from noninteracting band structure
calculation, I show a superconducting phase appears near about 2 GPa pressure
at a temperature of 2 K and this region persists upto 4 GPa Pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03082</id><created>2016-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Bradley</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisher</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;nault</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haley</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawson</keyname><forenames>C. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickett</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schanen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skyba</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsepelin</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zmeev</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Breaking the superfluid speed limit</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>25 pages - article and figures plus supplementary methods</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 1017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3813</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coherent condensates appear as emergent phenomena in many systems, sharing
the characteristic feature of an energy gap separating the lowest excitations
from the condensate ground state. This implies that a scattering object, moving
through the system with high enough velocity for the excitation spectrum in the
scatter frame to become gapless, can create excitations at no energy cost,
initiating the breakdown of the condensate. This limit is the well-known Landau
velocity. While, for the neutral Fermionic superfluid 3He-B in the T=0 limit,
flow around an oscillating body displays a very clear critical velocity for the
onset of dissipation, here we show that for uniform linear motion there is no
discontinuity whatsoever in the dissipation as the Landau critical velocity is
passed and exceeded. Since the Landau velocity is such a pillar of our
understanding of superfluidity, this is a considerable surprise, with
implications for the understanding of the dissipative effects of moving objects
in all coherent condensate systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03812</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Siu</keyname><forenames>Zhuo Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jalil</keyname><forenames>Mansoor B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Seng Ghee</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge field in systems with spin orbit interactions and additional
  discrete degrees of freedom to real spin</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>The first half of this article dealing with the derivation of the
  effective magnetization has been superseded by arXiv:1612.09102</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin gauge field formalism has been used to explain the emergence of out
of plane spin accumulation in two-dimensional spin orbit interaction (SOI)
systems in the presence of an in-plane electric field. The adiabatic alignment
of the charge carrier spins to the momentum dependent SOI field, which changes
in time due to the electric field, can be mathematically captured by the
addition of a gauge term in the Hamiltonian. This gauge term acts like an
effective, electric field dependent magnetization. In this work we show that
this effective magnetization can be generalized to systems which include
additional discrete degrees of freedom to real spin, such as the pseudospin
and/or valley degrees of freedom in emerging materials like molybdenum sulphide
and silicene. We show that the generalized magnetization recovers key results
from the Sundaram-Niu formalism as well as from the Kubo formula. We then use
the generalized magnetization to study the exemplary system of a topological
insulator thin film system where the presence of both a top as well as a bottom
surface provides an additional discrete degree of freedom in addition to the
real spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05024</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tsuji</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear light-Higgs coupling in superconductors beyond BCS: Effects of
  the retarded phonon-mediated interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 224519 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.224519</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the contribution of the Higgs amplitude mode on the nonlinear
optical response of superconductors beyond the BCS approximation by taking into
account the retardation effect in the phonon-mediated attractive interaction.
To evaluate the vertex correction in nonlinear optical susceptibilities that
contains the effect of collective modes, we propose an efficient scheme which
we call the &quot;dotted DMFT&quot; based on the nonequilibrium dynamical mean-field
theory (nonequilibrium DMFT) to go around the difficulty of solving the
Bethe-Salpeter equation and analytical continuation. The vertex correction is
represented by the derivative of the self-energy with respect to the external
driving field, which is self-consistently determined by the differentiated
(&quot;dotted&quot;) DMFT equations. We apply the method to the Holstein model, a
prototypical electron-phonon-coupled system, to calculate the susceptibility
for the third-harmonic generation including the vertex correction. The results
show that, in sharp contrast to the BCS theory, the Higgs mode can contribute
to the third-harmonic generation for general polarization of the laser field
with an order of magnitude comparable to the contribution from the pair
breaking or charge density fluctuations. The physical origin is traced back to
the nonlinear resonant light-Higgs coupling, which has been absent in the BCS
approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07343</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07343</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanungo</keyname><forenames>Sudipta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Binghai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-reversal-breaking topological phases in antiferromagnetic
  Sr$_2$FeOsO$_6$ films</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245135 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we studied time-reversal-breaking topological phases as a
result of the interplay between antiferromagnetism and inverted band structures
in thin films of antiferromagnetic double perovskite transition-metal
Sr$_2$FeOsO$_6$. By combining the first-principles calculations and analytical
models, we demonstrate that the quantum anomalous Hall phase and chiral
topological superconducting phase can be realized in this system. We find that
to achieve time-reversal-breaking topological phases in antiferromagnetic
materials, it is essential to break the combined symmetry of time reversal and
inversion, which generally exists in antiferromagnetic structures. As a result,
we can utilize an external electric gate voltage to induce the phase transition
between topological phases and trivial phases, thus providing an electrically
controllable topological platform for the future transport experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00124</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kovacevic</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Babkevich</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeong</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piatek</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf8;nnow</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing strongly hybrid nuclear-electronic states in a model quantum
  ferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214433 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214433</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present direct local-probe evidence for strongly hybridized
nuclear-electronic spin states of an Ising ferromagnet LiHoF$_4$ in a
transverse magnetic field. The nuclear-electronic states are addressed via a
magnetic resonance in the GHz frequency range using coplanar resonators and a
vector network analyzer. The magnetic resonance spectrum is successfully traced
over the entire field-temperature phase diagram, which is remarkably well
reproduced by mean-field calculations. Our method can be directly applied to a
broad class of materials containing rare-earth ions for probing the
substantially mixed nature of the nuclear and electronic moments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01378</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coutant</keyname><forenames>Antonin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richartz</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinfurtner</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author></authors><title>Detecting Rotational Superradiance in Fluid Laboratories</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>v2: title change, matches published version in PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 271101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.271101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rotational superradiance was predicted theoretically decades ago, and is
chiefly responsible for a number of important effects and phenomenology in
black-hole physics. However, rotational superradiance has never been observed
experimentally. Here, with the aim of probing superradiance in the lab, we
investigate the behavior of sound and surface waves in fluids resting in a
circular basin at the center of which a rotating cylinder is placed. We show
that with a suitable choice for the material of the cylinder, surface and sound
waves are amplified. Two types of instabilities are studied: one sets in
whenever superradiant modes are confined near the rotating cylinder and the
other, which does not rely on confinement, corresponds to a local excitation of
the cylinder. Our findings are experimentally testable in existing fluid
laboratories and, hence, offer experimental exploration and comparison of
dynamical instabilities arising from rapidly rotating boundary layers in
astrophysical as well as in fluid dynamical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01667</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2016-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kolomeisky</keyname><forenames>Eugene B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straley</keyname><forenames>Joseph P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous screening in two-dimensional materials with an extremum ring
  in the dispersion law</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4+ pages, 1 figure, minor changes, version to be published in Phys.
  Rev. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 245150 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.245150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A variety of two-dimensional materials possess a band structure with an
energy extremal ridge along a ring in momentum space. Examples are biased
bilayer graphene, and surfaces and interfaces with a Rashba spin-orbit
interaction where at low doping the carriers fill an annulus. This topological
feature causes an anomalous screening behavior, which we study using the
Thomas-Fermi theory. Specifically, reducing the doping is predicted to enhance
the linear screening response, while at zero doping the size of the screening
cloud surrounding a Coulomb impurity is found to increase as the cube root of
the impurity charge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03042</id><created>2016-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Barredo</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>de L&#xe9;s&#xe9;leuc</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lienhard</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahaye</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Browaeys</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author></authors><title>An atom-by-atom assembler of defect-free arbitrary 2d atomic arrays</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Science, vol 354, Issue 6315, p. 1021 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aah3778</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large arrays of individually controlled atoms trapped in optical tweezers are
a very promising platform for quantum engineering applications. However, to
date, only disordered arrays have been demonstrated, due to the
non-deterministic loading of the traps. Here, we demonstrate the preparation of
fully loaded, two-dimensional arrays of up to 50 microtraps each containing a
single atom, and arranged in arbitrary geometries. Starting from initially
larger, half-filled matrices of randomly loaded traps, we obtain user-defined
target arrays at unit filling. This is achieved with a real-time control system
and a moving optical tweezers that performs a sequence of rapid atom moves
depending on the initial distribution of the atoms in the arrays. These results
open exciting prospects for quantum engineering with neutral atoms in tunable
geometries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03914</id><created>2016-07-13</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fatemi</keyname><forenames>Zahra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salehi</keyname><forenames>Mostafa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnani</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple multiforce layout for multiplex networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce multiforce, a force-directed layout for multiplex networks,
where the nodes of the network are organized into multiple layers and both
in-layer and inter-layer relationships among nodes are used to compute node
coordinates. The proposed approach generalizes existing work, providing a range
of intermediate layouts in-between the ones produced by known methods. Our
experiments on real data show that multiforce can keep nodes well aligned
across different layers without significantly affecting their internal layouts
when the layers have similar or compatible topologies. As a consequence,
multiforce enriches the benefits of force-directed layouts by also supporting
the identification of topological correspondences between layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02465</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2016-11-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baranski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobialka</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Domanski</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-resolved interference due to Majorana state on interface between
  normal and superconducting leads</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 075603 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa5214</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the subgap spectrum and transport properties of the quantum
dot placed on interface between metallic and superconducting leads and
additionally side-coupled to the edge of topological superconducting (TS)
chain, hosting the Majorana quasiparticle. Due to chiral nature of the Majorana
states only one spin component, say $\uparrow$, of the quantum dot electrons is
directly hybridized with the TS wire. We study the spin-selective
interferometric patterns driven by the Majorana quasiparticle. The proximity
induced on-dot pairing effectively transmits the interference onto both spin
components, but each of them is characterized by completely different (even
opposite) signatures. To explain their origin we confront our results with the
toy model, where TS chain is replaced by the usual quantum and the tunneling of
$\downarrow$ electrons is prohibited. We also address unique interplay of the
Majorana and Kondo features, both appearing at zero energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03560</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the mass of the top quark in decays with a J/psi meson in
  pp collisions at 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/TOP-15-014/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-TOP-15-014, CERN-EP-2016-202</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 12 (2016) 123</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2016)123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A first measurement of the top quark mass using the decay channel t to (W to
l nu) (b to J/psi + X to mu+ mu- + X) is presented. The analysis uses events
selected from the proton-proton collisions recorded with the CMS detector at
the LHC at a center-of-mass energy of 8 TeV. The data correspond to an
integrated luminosity of 19.7 inverse femtobarns, with 666 t t-bar and single
top quark candidate events containing a reconstructed J/psi candidate decaying
into an oppositely-charged muon pair. The mass of the (J/psi + l) system, where
l is an electron or a muon from W boson decay, is used to extract a top quark
mass of 173.5 +/- 3.0 (stat) +/- 0.9 (syst) GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04352</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04352</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Erel</keyname><forenames>Can</forenames></author><author><keyname>Po</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crosby</keyname><forenames>Tamer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghoniem</keyname><forenames>Nasr</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation and interaction mechanisms of dipolar dislocation loops in fcc
  metals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Paper has changed significantly since the original arXiv submission</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dipolar dislocation loops, prevalent in fcc metals, are widely recognized as
controlling many physical aspects of plastic deformation. We present results of
3D dislocation dynamics simulations that shed light on the mechanisms of their
formation, motion, interactions, and large-scale patterning. We identify two
main formation mechanisms, enabled by cross-slip, and show that arrays of
dipoles can be easily formed as a result of the interaction between glide screw
dislocations. We present a systematic analysis of the spectrum of possible
junctions that can form as a result of mutual interaction between dipoles, and
between dipoles and glide dislocations. We show that fully immobile dislocation
segments arise in particular cases of these interactions, leading to hardening
and Frank-Read type sources. We reveal that the collective motion of dipolar
loop arrays can be induced by glide dislocations in the channels of Persistent
Slip Bands (PSB), and result in their clustering within PSB channel walls. An
efficient tripolar drag mechanism is found to contribute to the clustering of
dipolar loops near channel walls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03332</id><created>2016-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Iwahori</keyname><forenames>Koudai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawakami</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Periodically-driven Kondo impurity in nonequilibrium steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 063647 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063647</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the nonequilibrium dynamics of a periodically-driven anisotropic
Kondo impurity model. The periodic time dependence is introduced for a local
magnetic field which couples to the impurity spin and also for an in-plane
exchange interaction. We obtain the exact results on the time evolution for
arbitrary periodic time dependence at the special point in the parameter space
known as the Toulouse limit. We first consider a specific case where the local
magnetic field is periodically switched on and off. When the driving period is
much shorter than the inverse of the Kondo temperature, an intriguing
oscillating behavior (resonance phenomenon) emerges in the time average of the
impurity spin polarization with increasing the local magnetic field intensity.
By taking the high frequency limit of the external driving, we elucidate that
the system recovers the translational invariance in time and can be described
by a mixture of the zero-temperature and infinite-temperature properties. In
certain cases, the system is governed by either the zero-temperature or
infinite-temperature properties, and therefore can be properly described by the
corresponding equilibrium state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05591</id><created>2016-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Lebovka</keyname><forenames>Nikolai I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vygornitskii</keyname><forenames>Nikolai V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gigiberiya</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarasevich</keyname><forenames>Yuri Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Monte Carlo Simulation of Evaporation Driven Self-Assembly in Suspension
  of Colloidal Rods</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures, submitted to Phys. Rev. E</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062803 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The vertical drying of a colloidal film containing rod-like particles was
studied by means of kinetic Monte Carlo (MC) simulation. The problem was
approached using a two-dimensional square lattice and the rods were represented
as linear $k$-mers (i.e., particles occupying $k$ adjacent sites). The initial
state before drying was produced using a model of random sequential adsorption
(RSA) with isotropic orientations of the $k$-mers (orientation of the $k$-mers
along horizontal $x$ and vertical $y$ directions are equiprobable). In the RSA
model, overlapping of the $k$-mers is forbidden. During the evaporation, an
upper interface falls with a linear velocity of $u$ in the vertical direction
and the $k$-mers undergo translation Brownian motion. The MC simulations were
run at different initial concentrations, $p_i$, ($p_i \in [0, p_j]$, where
$p_j$ is the jamming concentration), lengths of $k$-mers ($k \in [1, 12]$), and
solvent evaporation rates, $u$. For completely dried films, the spatial
distributions of $k$-mers and their electrical conductivities in both $x$ and
$y$ directions were examined. Significant evaporation-driven self-assembly and
orientation stratification of the $k$-mers oriented along the $x$ and $y$
directions were observed. The extent of stratification increased with
increasing value of $k$. The anisotropy of the electrical conductivity of the
film can be finely regulated by changes in the values of $p_i$, $k$ and $u$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07097</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07097</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Purkayastha</keyname><forenames>Archak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>Abhishek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulkarni</keyname><forenames>Manas</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear transport in an out-of-equilibrium single-site Bose Hubbard
  model: scaling, rectification and time dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 052134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.052134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experiments in hybrid-quantum systems facilitate the potential
realization of one of the most fundamental interacting Hamiltonian-Reservoir
system, namely, the single-site Bose-Hubbard model coupled to two reservoirs at
different temperatures. Using Redfield equations in Born-Markov approximation,
we compute non-equilibrium average particle number, energy and currents beyond
linear response regime, both time-dynamics and steady state and investigate its
dependence on various tunable parameters analytically. We find interesting
scaling laws in high temperature regimes that are independent of choice of bath
spectral functions. We also demonstrate that the system shows very interesting
particle and energy current rectification properties which can be controlled
via the relative strength of interaction and temperatures, as well as via the
degree of asymmetry in system-bath coupling. Specifically, we find inversion of
direction of thermal rectification as a function of the relative strength of
the interaction strength and the temperatures. We also show that, in the limit
of low-temperature and high interaction strength our results are consistent
with the non-equilibrium spin-Boson model. Our results are experimentally
relevant not only to hybrid quantum systems, but also in other areas such as
molecular junctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09204</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2016-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pi</keyname><forenames>Shu-Ting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jeongwoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ruqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yin-Kuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chi-Ken</forenames></author></authors><title>New class of 3D topological insulator in double perovskite</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>submitted; title changed and new references added; see DOI for
  published version</comments><journal-ref>the Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters vol. 8 p. 332-339 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b02860</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We predict a new class of three-dimensional topological insulators (TIs) in
which the spin-orbit coupling (SOC) can more effectively generate a large band
gap at $\Gamma$ point. The band gap of conventional TI such as Bi$_2$Se$_3$ is
mainly limited by two factors, the strength of SOC and, from electronic
structure perspective, the band gap when SOC is absent. While the former is an
atomic property, we find that the latter can be minimized in a generic
rock-salt lattice model in which a stable crossing of bands {\it at} the Fermi
level along with band character inversion occurs for a range of parameters in
the absence of SOC. Thus, large-gap TI's or TI's comprised of lighter elements
can be expected. In fact, we find by performing first-principle calculations
that the model applies to a class of double perovskites A$_2$BiXO$_6$ (A = Ca,
Sr, Ba; X = Br, I) and the band gap is predicted up to 0.55 eV. Besides, more
detailed calculations considering realistic surface structure indicate that the
Dirac cones are robust against the presence of dangling bond at the boundary
with a specific termination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00249</id><created>2016-10-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wenxu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qiuru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Huizhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soh</keyname><forenames>Wee Tee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ong</keyname><forenames>Chong Kim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wanli</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin galvanic effect at the conducting SrTiO3 surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 262402 (2016);</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973479</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The (001) surface of SrTiO3 were transformed from insulating to conducting
after Ar+ irradiation, producing a quasi two-dimensional electron gas (2DEG).
This conducting surface layer can introduce Rashba spin orbital coupling due to
the broken inversion symmetry normal to the plane. The spin splitting of such a
surface has recently been demonstrated by magneto-resistance and angular
resolved photoemission spectra measurements. Here we present experiments
evidencing a large spin-charge conversion at the surface. We use spin pumping
to inject a spin current from NiFe film into the surface, and measure the
resulting charge current. The results indicate that the Rashba effect at the
surface can be used for efficient charge-spin conversion, and the large
efficiency is due to the multi-d-orbitals and surface corrugation. It holds
great promise in oxide spintronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00979</id><created>2016-09-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Manfredi</keyname><forenames>Luciano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mureika</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author></authors><title>Horizon Quantum Mechanics of Generalized Uncertainty Principle Black
  Holes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 color figures</comments><journal-ref>Adv. High Energy Phys. 2016:1543741 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/1543741</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Horizon Wavefunction (HWF) description of a generalized
uncertainty principle inspired metric that admits sub-Planckian black holes,
where the black hole mass $m$ is replaced by $M = m\left( 1 + \frac{\beta}{2}
\frac{M_{\rm Pl}^2}{m^2} \right)$. Considering the case of a wave-packet shaped
by a Gaussian distribution, we compute the HWF and the probability ${\cal
{P}}_{BH}$ that the source is a (quantum) black hole, i.e., that it lies within
its horizon radius. The case $\beta&lt;0$ is qualitatively similar to the standard
Schwarzschild case, and the general shape of ${\cal {P}}_{BH}$ is maintained
when decreasing the free parameter, but shifted to reduce the probability for
the particle to be a black hole accordingly. The probability grows with
increasing mass slowly for more negative $\beta$, and drops to 0 for a minimum
mass value. The scenario differs in significantly for increasing $\beta&gt;0$,
where a minimum in ${\cal {P}}_{BH}$ is encountered, thus meaning that every
particle has some probability of decaying to a black hole. Furthermore, for
sufficiently large $\beta$ we find that every particle is a quantum black hole,
in agreement with the intuitive effect of increasing $\beta$, which creates
larger $M$ and $R_{H}$ terms. This is likely due to a &quot;dimensional reduction&quot;
feature of the model, where the black hole characteristics for sub-Planckian
black holes mimic those in $(1+1)$-dimensions and the horizon size grows as
$R_H \sim M^{-1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01540</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eisler</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maislinger</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evertz</keyname><forenames>Hans Gerd</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal front propagation in the quantum Ising chain with domain-wall
  initial states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures, v2: references added, v3: minor revision</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 1, 014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.1.2.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the melting of domain walls in the ferromagnetic phase of the
transverse Ising chain, created by flipping the order-parameter spins along
one-half of the chain. If the initial state is excited by a local operator in
terms of Jordan-Wigner fermions, the resulting longitudinal magnetization
profiles have a universal character. Namely, after proper rescalings, the
profiles in the noncritical Ising chain become identical to those obtained for
a critical free-fermion chain starting from a step-like initial state. The
relation holds exactly in the entire ferromagnetic phase of the Ising chain and
can even be extended to the zero-field XY model by a duality argument. In
contrast, for domain-wall excitations that are highly non-local in the
fermionic variables, the universality of the magnetization profiles is lost.
Nevertheless, for both cases we observe that the entanglement entropy
asymptotically saturates at the ground-state value, suggesting a simple form of
the steady state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01663</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;rmann</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chusov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nordborg</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling and Simulation of the Current Quenching Behavior of a Line
  Lightning Protection Device</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><doi>10.1088/1361-6463/aa560e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a consistent model for a Line Lightning Protection Device and
demonstrate that this model can explain the two modes of current quenching --
impulse quenching and current zero quenching -- observed in such devices. A
dimensional analysis shows that impulse quenching can always be obtained if the
power loss from the electric arcs is large enough as compared to $U_0 I_f$,
where $U_0$ is the grid voltage and $I_f$ is the maximum follow current after a
lightning strike. We further show that the two modes of quenching can be
reproduced in a full 3D arc simulations coupled to the appropriate circuit
model. This means the arc simulations can be used for optimization and
development of future LLPDs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02856</id><created>2016-10-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Shahmansouri</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modulation and nonlinear evolution of multi-dimensional Langmuir wave
  envelopes in a relativistic plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures; to appear in Physics of Plasmas (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Plasmas 23, 122112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4971444</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The modulational instability (MI) and the evolution of weakly nonlinear
two-dimensional (2D) Langmuir wave (LW) packets are studied in an unmagnetized
collisionless plasma with weakly relativistic electron flow. By using a 2D
self-consistent relativistic fluid model and employing the standard
multiple-scale technique, a coupled set of Davey-Stewartson (DS)-like equations
is derived which governs the slow modulation and the evolution of LW packets in
relativistic plasmas. It is found that the relativistic effects favor the
instability of LW envelopes in the k{\theta} plane, where k is the wave number
and {\theta} the angle of modulation. It is also found that as the electron
thermal velocity or {\theta} increases, the growth rate of MI increases with
cutoffs at higher wave numbers of modulation. Furthermore, in the nonlinear
evolution of the DS-like equations, it is seen that with an effect of the
relativistic flow, a Gaussian wave beam collapses in a finite time, and the
collapse can be arrested when the effect of the thermal pressure or the
relativistic flow is slightly relaxed. The present results may be useful to the
MI and the formation of localized LW envelopes in cosmic plasmas with a
relativistic flow of electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01380</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Noshchenko</keyname><forenames>Dimitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Quiver relations and associated symmetric polynomials</title><categories>math.RT math.AG nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The idea is to identify certain path algebra elements with symmetric
functions. We propose such a morphism by solving the quiver relations, which
describe the Plucker-type embedding for quiver grassmannians.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02932</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brizuela</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiefer</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraemer</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-gravitational effects on gauge-invariant scalar and tensor
  perturbations during inflation: The slow-roll approximation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures, clarifications and references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123527 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123527</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We continue our study on corrections from canonical quantum gravity to the
power spectra of gauge-invariant inflationary scalar and tensor perturbations.
A direct canonical quantization of a perturbed inflationary universe model is
implemented, which leads to a Wheeler-DeWitt equation. For this equation, a
semiclassical approximation is applied in order to obtain a Schroedinger
equation with quantum-gravitational correction terms, from which we calculate
the corrections to the power spectra. We go beyond the de Sitter case discussed
earlier and analyze our model in the first slow-roll approximation, considering
terms linear in the slow-roll parameters. We find that the dominant correction
term from the de Sitter case, which leads to an enhancement of power on the
largest scales, gets modified by terms proportional to the slow-roll
parameters. A correction to the tensor-to-scalar ratio is also found at second
order in the slow-roll parameters. Making use of the available experimental
data, the magnitude of these quantum-gravitational corrections is estimated.
Finally, the effects for the temperature anisotropies in the cosmic microwave
background are qualitatively obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08916</id><created>2016-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Gachet</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Celletti</keyname><forenames>Alessandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pucacco</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efthymiopoulos</keyname><forenames>Christos</forenames></author></authors><title>Geostationary secular dynamics revisited: application to high
  area-to-mass ratio objects</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in CMDA</comments><doi>10.1007/s10569-016-9746-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The long-term dynamics of the geostationary Earth orbits (GEO) is revisited
through the application of canonical perturbation theory. We consider a
Hamiltonian model accounting for all major perturbations: geopotential at order
and degree two, lunisolar perturbations with a realistic model for the Sun and
Moon orbits, and solar radiation pressure. The long-term dynamics of the GEO
region has been studied both numerically and analytically, in view of the
relevance of such studies to the issue of space debris or to the disposal of
GEO satellites. Past studies focused on the orbital evolution of objects around
a nominal solution, hereafter called the forced equilibrium solution, which
shows a particularly strong dependence on the area-to-mass ratio. Here, we i)
give theoretical estimates for the long-term behavior of such orbits, and ii)
we examine the nature of the forced equilibrium itself. In the lowest
approximation, the forced equilibrium implies motion with a constant non-zero
average `forced eccentricity', as well as a constant non-zero average
inclination, otherwise known in satellite dynamics as the inclination of the
invariant `Laplace plane'. Using a higher order normal form, we demonstrate
that this equilibrium actually represents not a point in phase space, but a
trajectory taking place on a lower-dimensional torus. We give analytical
expressions for this special trajectory, and we compare our results to those
found by numerical orbit propagation. We finally discuss the use of proper
elements, i.e., approximate integrals of motion for the GEO orbits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00600</id><created>2016-12-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Juhee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Dong-Hee</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on Influence of induced interactions on superfluid properties of
  quasi-two-dimensional dilute Fermi gases with spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 067601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.067601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In an article in 2013, Caldas et al. [Phys. Rev. A 88, 023615 (2013)] derived
analytical expressions of the induced interaction within the scheme of Gorkov
and Melik-Barkhudrov in quasi-two-dimensional Fermi gases with Rashba
spin-orbit coupling (SOC). They claimed that the induced interaction is exactly
the same as the one for the case without SOC when the SOC is weak, and in the
region of strong SOC, it starts from a reduced value and then recovers the
value for the zero SOC in the limit of large SOC. We point out that their
calculations contain the critical errors and inconsistencies that significantly
affect the basis of these claims.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01475</id><created>2016-12-05</created><updated>2016-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stillinger</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torquato</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport, Geometrical and Topological Properties of Stealthy Disordered
  Hyperuniform Two-Phase Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics, 145, 244109 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972862</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Disordered hyperuniform many-particle systems have attracted considerable
recent attention. One important class of such systems is the classical ground
states of &quot;stealthy potentials.&quot; The degree of order of such ground states
depends on a tuning parameter. Previous studies have shown that these
ground-state point configurations can be counterintuitively disordered,
infinitely degenerate, and endowed with novel physical properties (e.g.,
negative thermal expansion behavior). In this paper, we focus on the disordered
regime in which there is no long-range order, and control the degree of
short-range order. We map these stealthy disordered hyperuniform point
configurations to two-phase media by circumscribing each point with a possibly
overlapping sphere of a common radius $a$: the &quot;particle&quot; and &quot;void&quot; phases are
taken to be the space interior and exterior to the spheres, respectively. We
study certain transport properties of these systems, including the effective
diffusion coefficient of point particles diffusing in the void phase as well as
static and time-dependent characteristics associated with diffusion-controlled
reactions. Besides these effective transport properties, we also investigate
several related structural properties, including pore-size functions, quantizer
error, an order metric, and percolation threshold. We show that these
transport, geometrical and topological properties of our two-phase media
derived from decorated stealthy ground states are distinctly different from
those of equilibrium hard-sphere systems and spatially uncorrelated overlapping
spheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03423</id><created>2016-12-11</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tylec</keyname><forenames>Tomasz I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku&#x15b;</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author></authors><title>Ignorance is a bliss: mathematical structure of many-box models</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><msc-class>81P45, 81P10, 03G12</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the propositional system of a many-box model is always a
set-representable effect algebra. In particular cases of 2-box and 1-box models
it is an orthomodular poset and an orthomodular lattice respectively. We
discuss the relation of the obtained results with the so-called Local
Orthogonality principle. We argue that non-classical properties of box models
are the result of a dual enrichment of the set of states caused by the
impoverishment of the set of propositions. On the other hand, quantum
mechanical models always have more propositions as well as more states than the
classical ones. Consequently, we show that the box models cannot be considered
as generalizations of quantum mechanical models and seeking for additional
principles that could allow to &quot;recover quantum correlations&quot; in box models is,
at least from the fundamental point of view, pointless.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04950</id><created>2016-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xun-Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Minima of the Scalar Potential in the Type II Seesaw Model: From Local
  to Global</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D94 (2016) no.11, 115025</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.115025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Type II seesaw model requires that its scalar doublet $H$ and triplet
$\Delta$ get specific patterns of VEVs $\langle H\rangle\propto(0,1)^{T}$ and
$\langle\Delta\rangle\propto(0,0,1)^{T}$ to accommodate neutrino masses.
However, other types of minima could also exist in the scalar potential, which
may strongly contradict to experimental observations. This paper studies when
the minimum at $\langle H\rangle\propto(0,1)^{T}$ and
$\langle\Delta\rangle\propto(0,0,1)^{T}$ will be global and finds the necessary
and sufficient condition for that, assuming that the lepton number violating
term $H^{2}\Delta$ in the potential is perturbatively small.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08042</id><created>2016-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Niri</keyname><forenames>Babak Nadiri</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear size corrections to the energy levels of single-electron atoms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>This manuscript includes 12 pages, 2 figures and 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>NPB-D-2016-00707</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A study is made of nuclear size corrections to the energy levels of
single-electron atoms for the ground state of hydrogen like atoms. We consider
Fermi charge distribution to the nucleus and calculate atomic energy level
shift due to the finite size of the nucleus in the perturbation theory context.
The exact relativistic correction based upon the available analytical
calculations is compared to the result of first-order relativistic perturbation
theory and the non-relativistic approximation. We find small discrepancies
between our perturbative results and those obtained from exact relativistic
calculation even for large nuclear charge number .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08241</id><created>2016-12-25</created><updated>2016-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iwai</keyname><forenames>Kazumasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimojo</keyname><forenames>Masumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asayama</keyname><forenames>Shinichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamidani</keyname><forenames>Tetsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastian</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saito</keyname><forenames>Masao</forenames></author></authors><title>The Brightness Temperature of the Quiet Solar Chromosphere at 2.6 mm</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>27 pages, 6 figures, accepted in publication of Solar Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-1044-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The absolute brightness temperature of the Sun at millimeter wavelengths is
an important diagnostic of the solar chromosphere. Because the Sun is so
bright, measurement of this property usually involves the operation of
telescopes under extreme conditions and requires a rigorous performance
assessment of the telescope. In this study, we establish solar observation and
calibration techniques at 2.6-mm wavelength for the Nobeyama 45-m telescope and
derive the absolute solar brightness temperature accurately. We tune the
superconductor-insulator-superconductor (SIS) receiver by inducing different
bias voltages onto the SIS mixer to prevent saturation. Then, we examine the
linearity of the receiver system by comparing outputs derived from different
tuning conditions. Further, we measure the lunar filled beam efficiency of the
telescope using the New Moon, and then derive the absolute brightness
temperature of the Sun. The derived solar brightness temperature is 7700+-310 K
at 115 GHz. The telescope beam pattern is modeled as a summation of three
Gaussian functions and derived using the solar limb. The real shape of the Sun
is determined via deconvolution of the beam pattern from the observed map. Such
well-calibrated single-dish observations are important for high-resolution
chromospheric studies because they provide the absolute temperature scale
missing from interferometer observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08768</id><created>2016-12-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Altmeyer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>Younghae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Ying-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of ferrofluidic flow in the Taylor-Couette system with a small
  aspect ratio</title><categories>physics.comp-ph nlin.PS</categories><comments>29 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate fundamental nonlinear dynamics of ferrofluidic Taylor-Couette
flow - flow confined between two concentric independently rotating cylinders -
consider small aspect ratio by solving the ferrohydrodynamical equations,
carrying out systematic bifurcation analysis. Without magnetic field, we find
steady flow patterns, previously observed with a simple fluid, such as those
containing normal one- or two vortex cells, as well as anomalous one-cell and
twin-cell flow states. However, when a symmetry-breaking transverse magnetic
field is present, all flow states exhibit stimulated, finite two-fold mode.
Various bifurcations between steady and unsteady states can occur,
corresponding to the transitions between the two-cell and one-cell states.
While unsteady, axially oscillating flow states can arise, we also detect the
emergence of new unsteady flow states. In particular, we uncover two new
states: one contains only the azimuthally oscillating solution in the
configuration of the twin-cell flow state, and another a rotating flow state.
Topologically, these flow states are a limit cycle and a quasiperiodic solution
on a two-torus, respectively. Emergence of new flow states in addition to
observed ones with classical fluid, indicates that richer but potentially more
controllable dynamics in ferrofluidic flows, as such flow states depend on the
external magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09310</id><created>2016-12-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Aloisi</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nali</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>La scala dell'energia</title><categories>physics.hist-ph physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>28 pages plus refs. page, 13 figures, 6 effigies, in Italian,
  re-edited from the version published on Sep. 9, 2005 on the SISSA online
  magazine &quot;Biblioteca dei 500&quot;, ISSN 1722-4306, website &quot;ULISSE - nella rete
  della scienza&quot;, available at
  http://ulisse.sissa.it/biblioteca/saggio/2005/Ubib050901s002/at_download/file/Ubib050901s002.pdf</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, halfway between popularized exposition and historical
account, some key moments in the development of atomic theory in its beginnings
are discussed. In particular, the events and the major discoveries that have
highlighted the discrete structure of the atom's energy levels are presented in
their logical and chronological sequence, starting from early studies on the
decomposition of light by prisms until the quantum theory.
  ---
  In questo articolo, a met\`a strada tra l'esposizione divulgativa e il
resoconto storico, vengono affrontati alcuni momenti significativi dello
sviluppo della teoria atomica ai suoi primordi. In particolare, sono
presentati, nella loro sequenza logica e cronologica, gli avvenimenti e le
scoperte principali che hanno messo in luce la struttura discreta dei livelli
di energia dell'atomo, dai primi studi sulla scomposizione della luce coi
prismi alla teoria quantistica.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09311</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Vodolazhskaya</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larenok</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevsky</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Image of Inverted World Tree on the Stone Slab and Vessels of the Bronze
  Age</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>archaeoastronomy</comments><journal-ref>Archaeoastronomy and Ancient Technologies 2016, 4(1), 150-168</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The article presents the results of the study of petroglyphs on a unique
stone slab discovered near the kurgan 1 of the kurgan field Varvarinsky I
(Rostov Oblast, Russia). Analysis of features of the location and style of
petroglyph &quot;tree&quot; showed that the branches could determine semi-minor semiaxes
m of the &quot;dial&quot; ellipses of analemmatic sundials with semi-major axis M = 24.2
cm for medium and high (northern) latitudes up to the North Pole and &quot;tree&quot;
marks the direction to the North. The desire to construct a tool with which it
was possible to build a &quot;dial&quot; for analemmatic sundial for different latitude
up to the latitude of the North Pole could appear under the influence of the
dominant mythological ideas about sacred geography of the surrounding world in
which the North is the World Mountain, World Tree or the abode of the gods. In
the article the authors conclude that the petroglyph &quot;tree&quot; on Varvarinsky slab
marks the direction to the North as a projection of the North Pole of the world
on the earth's surface, which simulates the slab. Petroglyph is an image of an
inverted World Tree, when viewed from the gnomon / man. The trunk of the Tree
corresponds to the astronomical world axis, and its branches symbolize the
visible daily path of the Sun and, perhaps, the night paths of stars across the
sky at different latitudes. During the research was carried out a comparative
analysis of the petroglyph &quot;tree&quot; with images of the inverted tree on the
Srubna vessels. According to the analysis it was concluded that a mythical
World Tree of Srubna population is likely to be a tree of pine family. Sign of
the inverted tree on the Srubna vessels has been interpreted by as a symbol of
the direction of the North and / or the north pole of the world; and
accompanying signs were interpreted as symbols of circumpolar stars and
constellations (asterisms).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09312</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Vodolazhskaya</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larenok</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevsky</keyname><forenames>M. Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>The Prototype of Ancient Analemmatic Sundials (Rostov Oblast, Russia)</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><journal-ref>Archaeoastronomy and Ancient Technologies 2016, 4(1), 96-116</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The article presents the results of a study of petroglyphs on a unique stone
slab discovered near the kurgan 1 of the kurgan field Varvarinsky I (Rostov
Oblast, Russia). During the study was done comparing it with plates of Srubna
burials on which were depicted the petroglyphs. Similar features for all the
considered slabs are elliptically arranged wells. Groove made to Varvarinsky
stone slab, has the same parameters as the ellipse from the wells on the slab
of the kurgan field Tavriya -1, discovered in the Rostov region, too. With the
help of astronomical methods previously been proved that elliptically located
wells on the Srubna slabs are hour markers of analemmatic sundial. By results
of the use of similar methods to study complex of petroglyphs on Varvarinsky
slab, it was concluded that the slab could be used for development of the
technology of markup of sundial on different geographical latitudes. Also,
Varvarinsky slab could serve as a model example for a markup of the ellipse on
which subsequently extorted wells for latitudes, close to the latitude of the
place of slab detection. Thus, Varvarinsky stone slab is the prototype of
analemmatic sundials, discovered in the Rostov and Donetsk oblasts. analemmatic
sundial, srubna burial, slab, wells, gnomon, model sample, archaeoastronomy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09313</id><created>2016-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Hedayatifar</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanibesheli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirazi</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farahani</keyname><forenames>S. Vasheghani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jafari</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The emergence of pseudo-stable states in network dynamics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of network dynamics, the complexity of systems increases
possible evolutionary paths that often are not deterministic. Occasionally,
some map routs form over the course of time which guide systems towards some
particular states. The main intention of this study is to discover an indicator
that can help predict these pseudo-deterministic paths in advance. Here we
investigate the dynamics of networks based on Heider balance theory that states
the tendency of systems towards decreasing tension. This inclination leads
systems to some local and global minimum tension states called &quot;jammed states&quot;
and &quot;balanced states&quot;, respectively. We show that not only paths towards jammed
states are not completely random but also there exist secret pseudo
deterministic paths that bound the system to end up in these special states.
Our results display that the Inverse Participation Ratio method (IPR) can be a
suitable indicator that exhibits collective behaviors of systems. According to
this method, these specific paths are those that host the most participation of
the constituents in the system. A direct proportionality exists between the
distance and the selectable paths towards local minimums; where by getting
close to the final steps there is no other way but the one to the jammed
states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09314</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zge Ekin</forenames></author></authors><title>Kant and Quantum Gravity</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In quantum gravity space and time lose their status as fundamental parts of
the physical reality. However, according to Kant, space and time are the a
priori conditions of our experience. Does Kantian characterization of these
notions give constraints to quantum gravity, or does quantum gravity make
Kantian characterization of space and time an invalid approach? This paper
provides answers to these questions with a philosophical approach to quantum
gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09315</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Smykalla</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukrynau</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zahn</keyname><forenames>Dietrich R. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hietschold</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Metalation of Phthalocyanine Molecules with Silver Surface Atoms by
  Adsorption on Ag(110)</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. C, 2015, 119 (30), 17228-17234</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.5b04977</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report that metal-free phthalocyanine (H2Pc) molecules with a central
cavity are able to incorporate Ag atoms from an Ag(110) surface thus creating
silver-phthalocyanine (AgPc). The reaction was investigated by means of
scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) under ultrahigh vacuum, and the metalation
of \ce{H2Pc} at the interface was confirmed with X-ray photoelectron
spectroscopy. Three different kinds of molecules were found on the surface that
are assigned to H2Pc, the corresponding dehydrogenated molecules (Pc) and AgPc.
The relative amounts of Pc and AgPc increase with increasing annealing
temperature. We suggest that the reaction with Ag atoms from the steps of the
surface occurs favorably only for already dehydrogenated molecules; thus, the
metalation of H2Pc is likely limited by the heat-induced dehydrogenation.
Density functional theory simulations of the reaction path are presented to
corroborate this hypothesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09319</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>Rog&#xe9;rio</forenames></author></authors><title>The (not so simple!) chain fountain</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given a sufficiently long bead chain in a cup, if we pull the end of the
chain over the rim of the cup, the chain tends to continuously flow out of the
cup, under gravity, in a common siphon process. Surprisingly enough, under
certain conditions, the chain forms a fountain in the air! This became known as
the Mould effect, after Steve Mould who discovered this phenomenon and made
this experiment famous on YouTube, in a video that went viral. The reason for
the emergence of this fountain remains unclear. This effect was shown to be due
to an anomalous reaction force from the top of the pile of beads, a possible
origin for this force was proposed in the same paper. Here, we describe some
experiments that give a contribution towards the clarification of the origin of
this force, and show that the explanation goes far beyond the one proposed
before.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09326</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ran</keyname><forenames>Shunjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eshun</keyname><forenames>Kwesi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qiliang</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain effect engineered in {\alpha}-Al2O3/monolayer MoS2 interface by
  first principle calculations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, 36 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the advances in low dimensional transition metal dichalcolgenides
(TMDCs) based metal oxide semiconductor field effect transistor (MOSFET), the
interface between semiconductors and dielectrics has received considerable
attention due to its dramatic effects on the morphology and charge transport of
semiconductors. In this study, first principle calculations were utilized to
investigate the strain effect induced by the interface between Al2O3 (0001) and
monolayer MoS2. The results indicate that Al2O3 in 1.3nm thickness can apply
the strain of 0.3% on MoS2 monolayer. The strain effect monotonically increases
with the larger thickness of the dielectric layer. Also, the study on
temperature effect indicates the monotonic lattice expansion induced by the
higher temperature. Our study proposes that the dielectric engineering can be
an effective tool for strain effect in the nanotechnology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09345</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Aliev</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bilmis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of radial excitations of octet baryons in QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the QCD sum rules method, we estimate the mass and residues of the
first radial excitations of octet baryons. The contributions coming from the
ground state baryons are eliminated by constructing the linear combinations of
the sum rules corresponding to different Lorentz structures. Our predictions of
the masses of the first radial excitations of octet baryons are in good
agreement with the data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09356</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Belhaj</keyname><forenames>Adil</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-qubits and Polyvalent Singularity in Type II Supestring Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, latex</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by geometric engineering method, we approach qubit systems in the
context of D-branes in type II superstrings. Concretely, we establish a
correspondence between such quantum systems and polyvalent singularities
appearing in local Calabi-Yau manifolds. First, we examine 1-qubit by
considering a D2-brane probing the su(2) toric singularity associated with type
IIA monovalent geometry. Then, we discuss the multi-qubits in terms of $n$
factors of su(2) singularities using the Cartan decomposition of non zero
roots. Applying mirror symmetry, the 4-qubits are linked to the tetravalent
singularity associated with the affine \widehat{so(8)} Lie algebra matching
with the ADE-correspondences in the context of quantum information theory.
Precisely, these states can be identified with wrapped D4-branes in a
Calabi-Yau 4-fold near such a singularity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09366</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Huey-Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>From C to Parton Sea: Bjorken-x Dependence of the PDFs</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>Plenary talk at the 34th annual International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory, 24-30 July 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studying the structure of nucleons is not only important to understanding the
strong interactions of quarks and gluons, but also to improving the precision
of new-physics searches. Since a broad class of experiments, including the LHC
and dark-matter detection, require Standard-Model backgrounds with parton
distribution functions (PDFs) as inputs for disentangling SM contributions from
potential new physics. For a long time, lattice calculations of the PDFs (as
well as many hadron structures) has been limited to the first few moments. In
this talk, we present a first direct calculation of the Bjorken-x dependence of
the PDFs using Large-Momentum Effective Theory (LaMET). An exploratory study of
the antiquark/sea flavor asymmetry of these distributions will be discussed.
This breakthrough opens an exciting new frontier calculating more complicated
quantities, such as gluon structure and transverse-momentum dependence, which
will complement existing theoretical programs for the upcoming Electron-Ion
Collider (EIC) or Large Hadron-Electron Collider (LHeC).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09367</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Huey-Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>Some Statistics on Women in Lattice QCD</title><categories>physics.soc-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>Contribution at the 34th annual International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory, 24-30 July 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a sampling of analyses concerning the gender ratio of plenary
speakers during the years 2000--2016 and make comparisons with other
conferences, such as the APS April meeting. We hope this will invite discussion
of ideas for how to make our field more accessible to women and minorities. We
are preparing for an in-depth survey of the lattice field and welcome any ideas
or suggestions. To leave post-conference comments and read about news affecting
women in our field, see our Facebook page: https://www.facebook.com/WLQCD
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09369</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Qifeng</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanluan</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>An improvement of the SBU-YLIN microphysics scheme in squall line
  simulation</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The default SBU-YLIN scheme in Weather Research and Forecasting Model (WRF)
is proved having a limited capability of producing a reasonable cold pool in
squall line simulations. With the help of wealthy observation data of a squall
line, we finally improve it by: adding a density factor to the precipitating
ice; modify the rain evaporation scheme and correct the saturation adjustment
process. The improved SBU-YLIN scheme could produce a reasonable cold pool.
Simulation of another two squall line cases in northern and eastern China
confirm our modifications are effective. In addition, further analysis reveals
that the modification of rain evaporation scheme is the most important among
them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09374</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Rui-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Peigang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Qing-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectrally pure states at telecommunications wavelengths from
  periodically poled $M$TiO$X$O$_4$ ($M$ = K, Rb, Cs; $X$ = P, As) crystals</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Review Applied 6, 064017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.6.064017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Significant successes have recently been reported in the study of the
generation of spectrally pure state in group-velocity-matched (GVM) nonlinear
crystals. However, the GVM condition can only be realized in limited kinds of
crystals and at limited wavelengths. Here, we investigate pure state generation
in the isomorphs of PPKTP crystal: i.e., periodically poled RTP, KTA, RTA and
CTA crystals. By numerical simulation, we find that these crystals from the KTP
family can generate pure photons with high spectral purity (over 0.8), wide
tunability (more than 400 nm), reasonable nonlinearity at a variety of
wavelengths (from 1300 nm to 2100 nm). It is also discovered that the PPCTA
crystal may achieve purity of 0.97 at 1506 nm. This study may provide more and
better choices for quantum state engineering at telecom wavelengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09381</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rad</keyname><forenames>Ali Izadi</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Measuring Vacuum Polarization of Quantum Electrodynamics with
  Superconducting Junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this proposal, we present an experimental setup based on superconducting
circuits and Josephson junctions to explore the modification of Josephson
coefficient in the presence of external magnetic field due to vacuum
polarization of quantum electrodynamics. This robust experiment can be
considered as one of the few possible chances to observe the fine quantum field
theory corrections in the low energy regimes in condensed matter systems. It
can also be a new check for the universality of Josephson constant which is
important in metrology. We will expect the signal to noise ratio of the
read-out signal to increases quadratically by running time of the experiment.
This characteristic of the output signal the will guarantee the feasibility of
measurements with desired precision
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09383</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09383</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Lehmann</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wardle</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-fluid dusty shocks: simple benchmarking problems and applications to
  protoplanetary discs</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 Pages, 8 Figures, submitted to MNRAS, comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The key role that dust plays in the interstellar medium has motivated the
development of numerical codes designed to study the coupled evolution of dust
and gas in systems such as turbulent molecular clouds and protoplanetary discs.
Drift between dust and gas has proven to be important as well as numerically
challenging. We provide simple benchmarking problems for dusty gas codes by
numerically solving the two-fluid dust-gas equations for steady, plane-parallel
shock waves. The two distinct shock solutions to these equations allow a
numerical code to test different forms of drag between the two fluids, the
strength of that drag and the dust to gas ratio. We also provide an
astrophysical application of J-type dust-gas shocks to studying the structure
of accretion shocks onto protoplanetary discs. We find that two-fluid effects
are most important for grains larger than 1 um, and that the peak dust
temperature within an accretion shock provides a signature of the dust-to-gas
ratio of the infalling material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09386</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Morelh&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;rgio L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fornari</keyname><forenames>Celso I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappl</keyname><forenames>Paulo H. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abramof</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanoscale characterization of bismuth telluride epitaxic layers by
  advanced X-ray analysis</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological insulator surface properties are strongly correlated to
structural properties, requiring high-resolution techniques capable of probing
both surface and bulk structures at once. In this work, high flux of
synchrotron source, recursive equations for fast X-ray dynamical diffraction
simulation, and genetic algorithm for data fitting are combined to reveal the
detailed structure of bismuth telluride epitaxic films with thickness ranging
from 8 to 168 nm. It includes stacking sequences, thickness and composition of
layers in model structures, interface coherence, surface termination and
morphology. These results are in agreement with the surface morphology
determined by atomic force microscopy. Moreover, by using X-ray data from zero
noise area detector to construct three-dimensional reciprocal space maps,
insights into the nanostructure of domains and stacking faults in Bi2Te3 films
are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09396</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaluna</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradley</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gillis-Davis</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucey</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulated Space Weathering of Fe- and Mg-rich Aqueously Altered Minerals
  Using Pulsed Laser Irradiation</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>27 Pages, 4 tables, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.12.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this work is to investigate contrasting spectral trends observed
in carbonaceous chondrites by simulating space weathering effects on a subset
of minerals found in these meteorites. We use pulsed laser irradiation to
simulate micrometeorite impacts on aqueously altered minerals and observe their
spectral and physical evolution as a function of irradiation time. Irradiation
of the mineral lizardite, a Mg-phyllosilicate, produces little reddening and
darkening, but a pronounced reduction in band depths. Irradiation of an Fe-rich
aqueously altered mineral assemblage composed of cronstedtite, pyrite and
siderite, produces significant darkening and band depth suppression. The
spectral slopes of the Fe-rich assemblage initially redden then become bluer
with increasing irradiation time. Analyses of the Fe-rich assemblage using
scanning and transmission electron microscopy reveal the presence of micron
sized carbon-rich particles that contain notable fractions of nitrogen and
oxygen. Radiative transfer modeling of the Fe-rich assemblage suggests that
npFe0 particles result in the initial spectral reddening of the samples, but
the increasing production of micron sized carbon particles results in the
subsequent spectral bluing. The presence of npFe0 and possibly cronstedtite
likely promotes the synthesis of these organic-like compounds. These
experiments indicate that space weathering processes may enable organic
synthesis reactions on the surfaces of volatile-rich asteroids. Furthermore,
Mg- and Fe-rich aqueously altered minerals are dominant at different phases of
the alteration process. Thus, the contrasting spectral slope evolution between
the Fe- and Mg-rich samples in these experiments may indicate that space
weathering trends of volatile-rich asteroids have a compositional dependency
that could be used to determine the aqueous histories of asteroid parent
bodies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09409</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Rajesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagchi</keyname><forenames>Kaushik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagchi</keyname><forenames>Biman</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures of quantum coherence in the optical line shape of an exciton
  in the presence of dynamic disorder</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>43 pages and 9 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the effects of quantum coherences on the optical line shape of an
exciton in the presence of dynamic disorder. We consider a one-dimensional
excitonic system that consists of two levels placed at regular intervals.
Detailed analytical calculations of line shape have been carried out by using
Kubo's stochastic Liouville equation (K-QSLE). We make use of the observation
that in the site representation, the Hamiltonian of our system with constant
off-diagonal coupling J is a tridiagonal Toeplitz matrix (TDTM) whose
eigenvalues and eigen functions are known analytically. This identification is
particularly useful for long chains where the eigen values of TDTM help to
understand crossover between static and fast modulation limits. We summarize
the new results as follows. (i) In the slow modulation limit when the bath
correlation time is large, the effects of spatial correlation are not
negligible. Here the line shape is broadened and the number of peak increases
beyond the ones obtained from TDTM (constant off-diagonal coupling element J
and no fluctuation). (ii) However, in the fast modulation limit when the bath
correlation time is small, the spatial correlation is less important (iii)
Importantly, we find that the line shape can capture that quantum coherence
affects in the two limits differently.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09421</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>LeFloch</keyname><forenames>Philippe G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The global nonlinear stability of Minkowski spacetime for
  self-gravitating massive fields. A brief overview</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a short review of a series of papers which, in collaboration with Yue
Ma, establish several novel existence results for systems of coupled
wave-Klein-Gordon equation. Our method, the Hyperbolic Hyperboloidal Method,
has allowed us to address the global evolution problem for the Einstein
equations of general relativity and investigate the global geometry of matter
spacetimes that are initially close to Minkowski spacetime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09432</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suhara</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanada-En'yo</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antisymmetrized molecular dynamics studies for exotic clustering
  phenomena in neutron-rich nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>96 pages, 44 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A52, 373 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16373-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a review of recent works on clustering phenomena in unstable
nuclei studied by antisymmetrized molecular dynamics (AMD). The AMD studies in
these decades have uncovered novel types of clustering phenomena brought about
by the excess neutrons. Among them, this review focuses on the molecule-like
structure of unstable nuclei. One of the earliest discussions on the clustering
in unstable nuclei was made for neutron-rich Be and B isotopes. AMD
calculations predicted that the ground state clustering is enhanced or reduced
depending on the number of excess neutrons. Today, the experiments are
confirming this prediction as the change of the proton radii. Behind this
enhancement and reduction of the clustering, there are underlying shell effects
called molecular- and atomic-orbits. These orbits form covalent and ionic
bonding of the clusters analogous to the atomic molecules. It was found that
this &quot;molecular-orbit picture&quot; reasonably explains the low-lying spectra of Be
isotopes. The molecular-orbit picture is extended to other systems having
parity asymmetric cluster cores and to the three cluster systems. O and Ne
isotopes are the candidates of the former, while the $3\alpha$ linear chains in
C isotopes are the latter. For both subjects, many intensive studies are now in
progress. We also pay a special attention to the observables which are the
fingerprint of the clustering. In particular, we focus on the monopole and
dipole transitions which are recently regarded as good probe for the
clustering. We discuss how they have and will reveal the exotic clustering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09441</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Shulzhenko</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amelchakov</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbashina</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiavassa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>N. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khokhlov</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamlev</keyname><forenames>N. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokoulin</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kompaniets</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Likiy</keyname><forenames>O. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovchinnikov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrukhin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saavedra</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shutenko</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of extensive air showers with the NEVOD-EAS cluster type
  detector</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new cluster type shower array NEVOD-EAS is designed for estimating the
size, axis position and arrival direction of extensive air showers registered
by the Cherenkov water detector NEVOD and coordinate detector DECOR (Moscow,
Russia). In 2015-2016, the central part of the array was deployed and started
its operation. It includes 4 independent clusters of scintillation detector
stations located around the NEVOD-DECOR experimental complex on the area of
about $10^{4} m^{2}$. This article presents the results of studying amplitude
and timing characteristics of the array clusters which are critical for EAS
parameters reconstruction, as well as the examples of registered events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09442</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Zaninetti</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Pad\'e approximant for the equation of motion of a supernova remnant</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, Gravitation and
  Cosmology,(2017),3, 78-86</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jhepgc.2017.31011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we derive three equations of motion for a supernova remnant
(SNR) in the framework of the thin layer approximation using the Pad\'e
approximant. The circumstellar medium is assumed to follow a density profile of
either an exponential type, a Gaussian type, or a Lane--Emden ($n=5$) type. The
three equations of motion are applied to four SNRs: Tycho, Cas A, Cygnus loop,
and SN~1006. The percentage error of the Pad\'e approximated solution is always
less than $10\%$. The theoretical decrease of the velocity over ten years for
SNRs is evaluated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09450</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Yashin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbashina</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiavassa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fakhrutdinov</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gromushkin</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khokhlov</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokoulin</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozhin</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrukhin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shulzhenko</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenkin</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zadeba</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>New detectors of the Experimental complex NEVOD for multicomponent EAS
  detection</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental complex (EC) NEVOD includes a number of unique experimental
facilities for studies of main components of cosmic rays on the Earth's
surface. The complex is used for the basic research of CR flux characteristics
and their interactions in the energy range 10^15 - 10^19 eV, and for applied
investigations directed to the development of methods of the muon diagnostics
of the atmosphere and the Earth's magnetosphere and near-terrestrial space. To
extend the experimental capabilities and raising the status of the installation
to the Mega Science level, nowadays new large-scale detectors: array for the
EAS registration - NEVOD-EAS, detector of atmospheric neutrons - URAN, and
large-area coordinate-tracking detector - TREK, are being deployed around EC
NEVOD. The description of new detectors and a common trigger system to ensure
the joint operation together with other detectors of EC NEVOD are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09455</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Phan</keyname><forenames>Manh-Huong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khurshid</keyname><forenames>Hafsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lampen-Kelley</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandra</keyname><forenames>Sayan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Repa</keyname><forenames>Kristen Stojak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemati</keyname><forenames>Zohreh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Raja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iglesias</keyname><forenames>&#xd2;scar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srikanth</keyname><forenames>Hariharan</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchange Bias Effects in Iron Oxide-Based Nanoparticle Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Review article, 30 pages, 14 figure</comments><journal-ref>Nanomaterials 6, 221 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/nano6110221</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exploration of exchange bias (EB) on the nanoscale provides a novel
approach to improving the anisotropic properties of magnetic nanoparticles for
prospective applications in nanospintronics and nanomedicine. However, the
physical origin of EB is not fully understood. Recent advances in chemical
synthesis provide a unique opportunity to explore EB in a variety of iron
oxide-based nanostructures ranging from core/shell to hollow and hybrid
composite nanoparticles. Experimental and atomistic Monte Carlo studies have
shed light on the roles of interface and surface spins in these nanosystems.
This review paper aims to provide a thorough understanding of the EB and
related phenomena in iron oxide-based nanoparticle systems, knowledge of which
is essential to tune the anisotropic magnetic properties of exchange-coupled
nanoparticle systems for potential applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09460</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Gromushkin</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrukhin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shchegolev</keyname><forenames>O. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stenkin</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yashin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurin</keyname><forenames>K. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characteristics of EAS neutron component obtained with PRISMA-32 array</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper is devoted to the results of the EAS neutron component
investigations by means of the PRISMA-32 array. The array consists of 32
en-detectors and enables to record delayed thermal neutrons accompanying
showers. For registration of thermal neutrons, the scintillator based on
$^{6}Li$ isotope as a target is used in the detectors. Some results of the
processing of data accumulated over a long period of time are presented: the
lateral distribution function of neutrons in EAS and preliminary results on EAS
neutron multiplicity spectrum and distribution of showers in e/n ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09461</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ostapchenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>LHC results and hadronic interaction models</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present status of high energy cosmic ray interaction models is discussed,
concentrating on recent model updates inspired by the data from Run 1 of the
LHC. A special attention is devoted to the remaining differences in the model
predictions and their relation to the underlying theoretical approaches.
Opportunities for the model discrimination by future LHC and cosmic ray
experimental studies are analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09462</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Teixeira</keyname><forenames>Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mian</keyname><forenames>Salman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hytti</keyname><forenames>Ulla</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooperation among competitors in the open-source arena: The case of
  OpenStack</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the 2016 International Conference on Information Systems
  (ICIS 2016), held in Dublin, Ireland, December 11-14, 2016. &quot;IS in
  Organizations and Society&quot; track. The official conference proceedings are
  available at the AIS eLibrary (http://aisel.aisnet.org/icis2016/)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interorganizational interactions are often complex and paradoxical. In this
research, we transcend two management paradoxes: competition versus cooperation
and open-source versus proprietary technology development. We follow the
OpenStack open-source ecosystem where competing firms cooperate in the
joint-development of a cloud infrastructure for big data. We provide a
narrative, complemented with social network visualizations, which depicts the
evolution of cooperation and competition. Our findings suggest that development
transparency and weak intellectual property rights (i.e., characteristics of
open-source ecosystems) allow a focal firm to transfer information and
resources more easily between multiple alliances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09464</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ichinose</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>On Three Imaginary-time Path Integral Formulas with Magnetic Fields in
  Relativistic Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages; based on talk at RIMS Joint Research {\sl &quot;Introductory
  Workshop on Path Integrals and Pseudo-Differential Operators&quot;}, October
  7--10, 2014</comments><msc-class>81S40, 58D30, 47D08, 81Q10, 35S05, 60J65, 60J75</msc-class><journal-ref>RIMS K\^oky\^uroku 1958, Research Institute for Mathematical
  Sciences, Kyoto University, Kyoto, Japan, July 2015, pp.117--142</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three magnetic relativistic Schr\&quot;odinger operators are considered,
corresponding to the classical relativistic Hamiltonian symbol with both
magnetic vector and electric scalar potentials. Path integral representations
for the solutions of their respective imaginary-time relativistic Schr\&quot;odinger
equations, i.e. heat equations are given in two ways. The one is by means of
the probability path space measure coming from the L\'evy process concerned,
and the other is through time-sliced approximation with Chernoff's theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09468</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wawrzyniak-Adamczewska</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wierzbowska</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melendez</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of graphene substrate on the spectroscopic properties of
  photovoltaic molecules: role of the in-plane and out-of-plane pi-bonds</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>AIMS Materials Science (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic structure of pentacene decorated with dipole groups
(d-pentacene) and adsorbed onto a graphene substrate has been studied within
the density functional theory. Three reference configurations have been
considered, namely the ideal molecule without distortions, the actual molecule
including intramolecular distortions and the molecule adsorbed onto graphene.
Calculations show a noticeable charge redistribution within the d-pentacene +
graphene system due to molecular distortion, as well as the formation of weak
$\pi$-bonds between the molecule and the substrate. Additionally, the effect of
the chemical modification of the terminal saturation with --H by --OH and =O is
checked to explore the possibility of &quot;levels engineering&quot;. The imaginary part
of the dielectric function of d-pentacene in the ideal and distorted
conformations and the molecule adsorbed at graphene were calculated within the
random phase approximation. Results show that, even though molecular
distortions change apreciably the absorption spectrum of isolated d-pentacene,
the adsorbed molecule exhibits an optical spectrum which mimics quite much that
of single graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09470</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bedingham</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collapse models and spacetime symmetries</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 2 figures, prepared for &quot;Collapse of the wave function&quot;
  edited by Gao Shan, to be published by Cambridge University Press</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A picture of dynamical collapse of the wave function which is relativistic
and time symmetric is presented. The part of the model which exhibits these
features is the set of collapse outcomes. These play the role of matter
distributed in space and time. It is argued that the dynamically collapsing
quantum state, which is both foliation dependent and follows a time-asymmetric
dynamics, is not fundamental: it represents a state of information about the
past matter distribution for the purpose of estimating the future matter
distribution. It is also argued from the point of view of collapse models that
both special and general relativistic considerations point towards a discrete
spacetime structure and that gravity may not need to be quantised to give a
theory that is consistent with quantum matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09484</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Yigitoglu</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gokbulut</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bohr Hamiltonian for gamma=0 with Davidson Potential</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A gamma-rigid solution of the Bohr Hamiltonian is derived for gamma=0
utilizing the Davidson potential in the beta variable. This solution is going
to be called X(3)-D. The energy eigenvalues and wave functions are obtained by
using an analytic method which has been developed by Nikiforov and Uvarov.
BE(2) transition rates are calculated. A variational procedure is applied to
energy ratios to determine whether or not the X(3) model is located at the
critical point between spherical and deformed nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09486</id><created>2016-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahdi</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rutter</keyname><forenames>Erica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>Stephen J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of non-physiological blood pressure artefacts on measures of
  cerebral autoregulation</title><categories>q-bio.TO physics.med-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><msc-class>92C35, 92C50</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cerebral autoregulation refers to regulation mechanisms that aim to maintain
cerebral blood flow approximately constant. It is often assessed by
autoregulation index (ARI), which uses arterial blood pressure and cerebral
blood flow velocity time series to produce a ten-scale index of autoregulation
performance (0 denoting the absence of and 9 the strongest autoregulation).
Unfortunately, data are rarely free from various artefacts. Here, we consider
four of the most common non-physiological blood pressure artefacts (saturation,
square wave, reduced pulse pressure and impulse) and study their effects on ARI
for a range of different artefact sizes. We show that a sufficiently large
saturation and square wave always result in ARI reaching the maximum value of
9. The pulse pressure reduction and impulse artefact lead to a more diverse
behaviour. Finally, we characterised the critical size of artefacts, defined as
the minimum artefact size that, on average, leads to a 10\% deviation of ARI
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09494</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Asis. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Atrayee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choudhary</keyname><forenames>Kamal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Santanu</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Mass in Bose-Einstein Condensation in the Bound State and
  Phonon Propagation in the Unbound States</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dark and bright solitons in different systems are already known in
Klein-Gordon lattice. Instead of an external driving force, if the intrinsic
field is only considered, then the modal dynamics for small oscillations could
be characterized by the bound state in a limited range of frequency, revealed
via associated Legendre polynomial. Bose Einstein condensation takes place
around bosonic particles having different wave functions within the bound
states in the temperature region T = 0 to Tc having implication for the
effective mass of the system. The pairing and interplay between the dark and
bright solitons also occur with their effect on the condensation. This
effective mass is calculated via statistical mechanics route by two-part
partition function that also gives an indication for the transition
temperature. The disappearance of the bound state after a critical frequency,
or equivalently, after a critical temperature, gives rise to quasi-particles or
phonons in the unbound states that propagate through the domains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09497</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Aleksandrin</keyname><forenames>S. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galper</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koldashov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayorova</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zharaspayev</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial distribution of high-energy protons in the inner radiation belt
  on the data of low Earth orbit space experiments</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of the ARINA instrument on board the Resurs-DK1 satellite
(altitude $\sim$ 600 km and inclination $\sim$ 70$^{o}$, since 2006 till 2016)
and the VSPLESK instrument on board the International Space Station (altitude
$\sim$ 400 km and inclination $\sim$ 52$^{o}$, since 2008 till 2013) in low
Earth orbits were presented in this report. Both instruments are identical in
terms of physical layout. They can measure high-energy protons in the range
30-100 MeV with 10\% energy resolution and 7$^{o}$ angular accuracy. Data
analysis was carried out for the total period of proton flux measurement by the
instruments. L-B proton distributions in the inner radiation belt (L$&lt;$2) were
studied in dependence on proton energy. Geographical and pitch-angle
distribution of proton intensity were studied for chosen L-shells. These
distributions were analyzed during the decreasing part of the 23$^{rd}$ solar
cycle and the main part of the 24$^{th}$ one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09498</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Wei-Tou</forenames></author></authors><title>Genesis of general relativity - a concise exposition</title><categories>physics.hist-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 tables, Chapter 2 of the book One Hundred Years of
  General Relativity: From Genesis and Empirical Foundations to Gravitational
  Waves, Cosmology and Quantum Gravity, edited by Wei-Tou Ni (World Scientific,
  Singapore, 2016); IJMPD, 1630004 (2016)</comments><doi>10.1142/S0218271816300044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This short exposition starts with a brief discussion of situation before the
completion of special relativity (Le Verrier's discovery of the Mercury
perihelion advance anomaly, Michelson-Morley experiment, E\&quot;otv\&quot;os experiment,
Newcomb's improved observation of Mercury perihelion advance, the proposals of
various new gravity theories and the development of tensor analysis and
differential geometry) and accounts for the main conceptual developments
leading to the completion of the general relativity: gravity has finite
velocity of propagation; energy also gravitates; Einstein proposed his
equivalence principle and deduced the gravitational redshift; Minkowski
formulated the special relativity in 4-dimantional spacetime and derived the
4-dimensional electromagnetic stress-energy tensor; Einstein derived the
gravitational deflection from his equivalence principle; Laue extended the
Minkowski's method of constructing electromagnetic stress-energy tensor to
stressed bodies, dust and relativistic fluids; Abraham, Einstein, and
Nordstr\&quot;om proposed their versions of scalar theories of gravity in 1911-13;
Einstein and Grossmann first used metric as the basic gravitational entity and
proposed a &quot;tensor&quot; theory of gravity (the &quot;Entwurf&quot; theory, 1913); Einstein
proposed a theory of gravity with Ricci tensor proportional to stress-energy
tensor (1915); Einstein, based on 1913 Besso-Einstein collaboration, correctly
derived the relativistic perihelion advance formula of his new theory which
agreed with observation (1915); Hilbert discovered the Lagrangian for
electromagnetic stress-energy tensor and the Lagrangian for the gravitational
field (1915), and stated the Hilbert variational principle; Einstein equation
of general relativity was proposed (1915); Einstein published his foundation
paper (1916).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09505</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>Patricia</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Higher Gauge Theory and M5-brane dynamics. Proceedings:
  Higher structures in String and M-theory, Tohoku Forum for Creativity, March
  7-11 2016</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages, Proceedings for &quot;Higher Structures in String and M-theory&quot;
  workshop, Tohoku Forum for Creativity, March 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a review of truncated L$_\infty$ algebras, as used in the study of
higher gauge theory. These structures are believed to hold the correct
properties to adequately describe gauge theory of extended objects. We discuss
how to construct topological higher-gauge-invariant theories and how their
solutions relate to multisymplectic geometries. We also show how Courant
algebroids fit into this formalism, so as to be able to study higher gauge
theory on generalized geometric bundles, i.e. on $ T\Sigma \oplus T^*\Sigma $,
for some space-time $\Sigma $. We will see that via this formalism we can match
and explain a recently proposed M5-brane model, arrived at in a more heuristic
way, whose field content seemed difficult to interpret but finds a natural
motivation in this framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09517</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Alan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fay</keyname><forenames>Thomas P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manolopoulos</keyname><forenames>David E.</forenames></author></authors><title>An efficient quantum mechanical method for radical pair recombination
  reactions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 244101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972277</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The standard quantum mechanical expressions for the singlet and triplet
survival probabilities and product yields of a radical pair recombination
reaction involve a trace over the states in a combined electronic and nuclear
spin Hilbert space. If this trace is evaluated deterministically, by performing
a separate time-dependent wavepacket calculation for each initial state in the
Hilbert space, the computational effort scales as $O(Z^2\log Z)$, where $Z$ is
the total number of nuclear spin states. Here we show that the trace can also
be evaluated stochastically, by exploiting the properties of spin coherent
states. This results in a computational effort of $O(MZ\log Z)$, where $M$ is
the number of Monte Carlo samples needed for convergence. Example calculations
on a strongly-coupled radical pair with $Z&gt;10^6$ show that the singlet yield
can be converged to graphical accuracy using just $M=200$ samples, resulting in
a speed up by a factor of $&gt;5000$ over a standard deterministic calculation. We
expect that this factor will greatly facilitate future quantum mechanical
simulations of a wide variety of radical pairs of interest in chemistry and
biology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09528</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bernhard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Capasso</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Diebold</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eisenkolb</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Eschbach</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Florin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>F&#xf6;hr</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Funk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gadola</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Garrecht</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hermann</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kalekin</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kalkuhl</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kasperek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kihm</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lahmann</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Marszalek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pfeifer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Principe</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>P&#xfc;hlhofer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>P&#xfc;rckhauer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rajda</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reimer</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Santangelo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schanz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Straumann</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tenzer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vollhardt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zietara</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>and the CTA consortium</affiliation></author></authors><title>Performance Verification of the FlashCam Prototype Camera for the
  Cherenkov Telescope Array</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>5 pages, 13 figures, Proceedings of the 9th International Workshop on
  Ring Imaging Cherenkov Detectors (RICH 2016), Lake Bled, Slovenia</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.12.056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Cherenkov Telescope Array (CTA) is a future gamma-ray observatory that is
planned to significantly improve upon the sensitivity and precision of the
current generation of Cherenkov telescopes. The observatory will consist of
several dozens of telescopes with different sizes and equipped with different
types of cameras. Of these, the FlashCam camera system is the first to
implement a fully digital signal processing chain which allows for a traceable,
configurable trigger scheme and flexible signal reconstruction. As of autumn
2016, a prototype FlashCam camera for the medium-sized telescopes of CTA nears
completion. First results of the ongoing system tests demonstrate that the
signal chain and the readout system surpass CTA requirements. The stability of
the system is shown using long-term temperature cycling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09531</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolduc</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knee</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauger</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leach</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Projected gradient descent algorithms for quantum state tomography</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Accurate quantum tomography is a vital tool in both fundamental and applied
quantum science. It is a task that involves processing a noisy measurement
record in order to construct a reliable estimate of an unknown quantum state,
and is central to quantum computing, metrology, and communication. To date,
many different approaches to quantum state estimation have been developed, yet
no one method fits all applications, and all fail relatively quickly as the
dimensionality of the unknown state grows. In this work, we suggest that
projected gradient descent is a method that can evade some of these
shortcomings. We present three novel tomography algorithms that use projected
gradient descent and compare their performance with state-of-the-art
alternatives, i.e. the diluted iterative algorithm and convex programming. Our
results find in favour of the general class of projected gradient descent
methods due to their speed, applicability to large states, and the range of
conditions in which they perform.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09539</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Shemyakin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimation of dilution of a Fast Faraday Cup response due to the finite
  particles speed</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deviation of the Fast Faraday Cup signal from the longitudinal shape of the
measured bunch is estimated, and a simple formula for the increase of the
signal rms width is suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09543</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09543</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Dovgan</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The emitted energy in RS</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The emitted energy of electrons is calculated in relativistic strophotron. It
is shown, that it is superposition of amplification at harmonics of main
resonance frequency of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09550</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Bonilla</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretero</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terragni</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Soliton-like attractor for blood vessel tip density in angiogenesis</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.PS</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94, 062415 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, numerical simulations of a stochastic model have shown that the
density of vessel tips in tumor induced angiogenesis adopts a soliton-like
profile [Sci. Rep. 6, 31296 (2016)]. In this work, we derive and solve the
equations for the soliton collective coordinates that indicate how the soliton
adapts its shape and velocity to varying chemotaxis and diffusion. The vessel
tip density can be reconstructed from the soliton formulas. While the
stochastic model exhibits large fluctuations, we show that the location of the
maximum vessel tip density for different replicas follows closely the soliton
peak position calculated either by ensemble averages or by solving an
alternative deterministic description of the density. The simple soliton
collective coordinate equations may also be used to ascertain the response of
the vessel network to changes in the parameters and thus to control it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09557</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Monaco</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panati</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisante</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teufel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Localization Dichotomy for gapped periodic quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><report-no>Roma01.Math.MP</report-no><msc-class>81Q70, 81V70</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the localization properties of gapped periodic quantum
systems, modeled by a periodic or covariant family of projectors, as e.g. the
orthogonal projectors on the occupied orbitals at fixed crystal momentum for a
gas of non-interacting electrons. We prove a general localization dichotomy for
dimension $d\leq 3$: either the system is topologically trivial i.e. all the
Chern numbers vanish, or any arbitrary choice of composite Wannier functions
yields an infinite expectation value for the squared position operator.
Equivalently, in the topologically non-trivial phase, the localization
functional introduced by Marzari and Vanderbilt diverges, as already noticed in
the case of the Haldane model. Our result is formulated by using only the
relevant symmetries of the system, and it is thus largely model-independent.
Possible applications include both tight-binding and continuous models of
crystalline solids, cold gases in optical lattices as well as flat band
superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09563</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Selmke</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selmke</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting the round bottom flask rainbow experiment</title><categories>physics.ed-ph physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A popular demonstration experiment in optics uses a round-bottom flask filled
with water to project a circular rainbow on a screen with a hole through which
the flask is illuminated. We show how the vessel's wall shifts the second-order
and first-order bows towards each other and consequentially narrows down
Alexander's dark band. We address the challenge this introduces in producing
Alexander's dark band, and explain the importance of a sufficient distance of
the flask to the screen. The wall-effect also introduces a splitting of the
bows which can easily be misinterpreted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09571</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lachish</keyname><forenames>Uri</forenames></author></authors><title>CdTe and CdZnTe Crystal Growth and Production of Gamma Radiation
  Detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.13140/RG.2.2.23843.25126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bridgman CdTe and CdZnTe crystal growth, with cadmium vapor pressure control,
is applied to production of semiconductor gamma radiation detectors. Crystals
are highly donor doped and highly electrically conducting. Annealing in
tellurium vapors transforms them into a highly compensated state of high
electrical resistance and high sensitivity to gamma radiation. N-type
detectors, equipped with ohmic contacts, and a grounded guard ring around the
positive contact, are not sensitive to hole trapping. Conductivity control, by
the doping level, optimizes the detector operation by trade-off between
electrons' lifetime and electrical resistance. Gamma spectra of single
detectors and detector arrays are presented. Detector optimization and gamma
detection mechanisms are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09577</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kravchenko</keyname><forenames>Vladislav V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of a transmutation for the one-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger
  operator and a representation for solutions</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new representation for solutions of the one-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger
equation -u&quot;+q(x)u=w^2u is obtained in the form of a series possessing the
following attractive feature. The truncation error is w-independent for all
real w. For the coefficients of the series simple recurrent integration
formulas are obtained which make the new representation applicable for
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09579</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Caroff</keyname><forenames>Sami</forenames><affiliation>for the AMS-02 collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>High Statistics Measurement of the Positron Fraction in Primary Cosmic
  Rays with the Alpha Magnetic Spectrometer on the International Space Station</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>XXV ECRS 2016 Proceedings - eConf C16-09-04.3</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A precision measurement by AMS-02 of the positron fraction in primary cosmic
rays is presented on this proceeding. Over the last two decades, there has been
a strong interest in the cosmic ray positron fraction which exhibit an excess
of high energy positrons whose origin is still highly uncertain. The Alpha
Magnetic Spectrometer (AMS-02) is a general purpose high-energy particle
physics detector operational on the International Space Station since May 2011.
During its unique long duration mission AMS-02 is collecting large amount of
data to study the behavior of cosmic ray electrons and positrons with
unprecedented precision. This measurement shows that the positron fraction
exhibit a rapid decrease from 1 to 8 GeV followed by a steady increase. We show
that above 275 GeV the positron fraction no longer exhibits an increase with
energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.09586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-02</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.09586</id><created>2016-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Cacciafesta</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fanelli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispersive estimates for the Dirac equation in an Aharonov-Bohm field</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><report-no>Roma01.Math</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove local smoothing and weighted Strichartz estimates for the Dirac
equation with a Aharonov-Bohm potential. The proof relies on an explicit
representation of the solution built in terms of spectral projections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
