<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T00:00:55Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-01-09" from="2017-01-09" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1009.1993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1009.1993</id><created>2010-09-10</created><updated>2013-04-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Katsanikas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patsis</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The structure of invariant tori in a 3D galactic potential</title><categories>nlin.CD astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, 34 figures, accepted for publication in the International
  Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos</comments><msc-class>70H08, 70H12, 70H14, 37J20, 37J35, 37J40, 85A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int.J.Bifurc.Chaos 21:467-496,2011</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218127411028520</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study in detail the structure of phase space in the neighborhood of stable
periodic orbits in a rotating 3D potential of galactic type. We have used the
color and rotation method to investigate the properties of the invariant tori
in the 4D spaces of section. We compare our results with those of previous
works and we describe the morphology of the rotational, as well as of the tube
tori in the 4D space. We find sticky chaotic orbits in the immediate
neighborhood of sets of invariant tori surrounding 3D stable periodic orbits.
Particularly useful for galactic dynamics is the behavior of chaotic orbits
trapped for long time between 4D invariant tori. We find that they support
during this time the same structure as the quasi-periodic orbits around the
stable periodic orbits, contributing however to a local increase of the
dispersion of velocities. Finally we find that the tube tori do not appear in
the 3D projections of the spaces of section in the axisymmetric Hamiltonian we
examined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.2463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.2463</id><created>2010-12-11</created><updated>2011-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Katsanikas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patsis</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contopoulos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The structure and evolution of confined tori near a Hamiltonian Hopf
  Bifurcation</title><categories>nlin.CD astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, 14 figures, accepted for publication in the International
  Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos</comments><msc-class>37J20, 37J25, 37J45, 70H07, 70H12, 70H14, 85A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Bifurcation Chaos 21, 2321-2330 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218127411029811</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the orbital behavior at the neighborhood of complex unstable
periodic orbits in a 3D autonomous Hamiltonian system of galactic type. At a
transition of a family of periodic orbits from stability to complex instability
(also known as Hamiltonian Hopf Bifurcation) the four eigenvalues of the stable
periodic orbits move out of the unit circle. Then the periodic orbits become
complex unstable. In this paper we first integrate initial conditions close to
the ones of a complex unstable periodic orbit, which is close to the transition
point. Then, we plot the consequents of the corresponding orbit in a 4D surface
of section. To visualize this surface of section we use the method of color and
rotation [Patsis and Zachilas 1994]. We find that the consequents are contained
in 2D &quot;confined tori&quot;. Then, we investigate the structure of the phase space in
the neighborhood of complex unstable periodic orbits, which are further away
from the transition point. In these cases we observe clouds of points in the 4D
surfaces of section. The transition between the two types of orbital behavior
is abrupt.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1103.3981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1103.3981</id><created>2011-03-21</created><updated>2011-09-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Katsanikas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patsis</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinotsis</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chains of rotational tori and filamentary structures close to high
  multiplicity periodic orbits in a 3D galactic potential</title><categories>nlin.CD astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages,22 figures, Accepted for publication in the International
  Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos</comments><msc-class>37J25, 37J35, 70K20, 70K50, 70K55, 70H07, 70H12, 85A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Bifurcation Chaos 21, 2331-2342 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218127411029823</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses phase space structures encountered in the neighborhood
of periodic orbits with high order multiplicity in a 3D autonomous Hamiltonian
system with a potential of galactic type. We consider 4D spaces of section and
we use the method of color and rotation [Patsis and Zachilas 1994] in order to
visualize them. As examples we use the case of two orbits, one 2-periodic and
one 7-periodic. We investigate the structure of multiple tori around them in
the 4D surface of section and in addition we study the orbital behavior in the
neighborhood of the corresponding simple unstable periodic orbits. By
considering initially a few consequents in the neighborhood of the orbits in
both cases we find a structure in the space of section, which is in direct
correspondence with what is observed in a resonance zone of a 2D autonomous
Hamiltonian system. However, in our 3D case we have instead of stability
islands rotational tori, while the chaotic zone connecting the points of the
unstable periodic orbit is replaced by filaments extending in 4D following a
smooth color variation. For more intersections, the consequents of the orbit
which started in the neighborhood of the unstable periodic orbit, diffuse in
phase space and form a cloud that occupies a large volume surrounding the
region containing the rotational tori. In this cloud the colors of the points
are mixed. The same structures have been observed in the neighborhood of all
m-periodic orbits we have examined in the system. This indicates a generic
behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1201.2108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1201.2108</id><created>2012-01-10</created><updated>2013-04-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Katsanikas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patsis</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contopoulos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Instabilities and stickiness in a 3D rotating galactic potential</title><categories>nlin.CD astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>29pages, 25 figures, accepted for publication in the International
  Journal of Bifurcation and Chaos</comments><msc-class>37J10, 37J20, 37J25, 70K05, 70K20, 70K44, 70K50, 70H14, 70H05,
  70H07, 85A05</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Bifurcation Chaos 23, 1330005 (2013) [30 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021812741330005X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics in the neighborhood of simple and double unstable
periodic orbits in a rotating 3D autonomous Hamiltonian system of galactic
type. In order to visualize the four dimensional spaces of section we use the
method of color and rotation. We investigate the structure of the invariant
manifolds that we found in the neighborhood of simple and double unstable
periodic orbits in the 4D spaces of section. We consider orbits in the
neighborhood of the families x1v2, belonging to the x1 tree, and the z-axis
(the rotational axis of our system). Close to the transition points from
stability to simple instability, in the neighborhood of the bifurcated simple
unstable x1v2 periodic orbits we encounter the phenomenon of stickiness as the
asymptotic curves of the unstable manifold surround regions of the phase space
occupied by rotational tori existing in the region. For larger energies, away
from the bifurcating point, the consequents of the chaotic orbits form clouds
of points with mixing of color in their 4D representations. In the case of
double instability, close to x1v2 orbits, we find clouds of points in the four
dimensional spaces of section. However, in some cases of double unstable
periodic orbits belonging to the z-axis family we can visualize the associated
unstable eigensurface. Chaotic orbits close to the periodic orbit remain sticky
to this surface for long times (of the order of a Hubble time or more). Among
the orbits we studied we found those close to the double unstable orbits of the
x1v2 family having the largest diffusion speed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.4406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.4406</id><created>2013-04-16</created><updated>2015-09-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rybski</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reusser</keyname><forenames>Dominik E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winz</keyname><forenames>Anna-Lena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fichtner</keyname><forenames>Christina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sterzel</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kropp</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cities as nuclei of sustainability?</title><categories>physics.soc-ph physics.ao-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1177/0265813516638340</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have assembled CO2 emission figures from collections of urban GHG emission
estimates published in peer reviewed journals or reports from research
institutes and non-governmental organizations. Analyzing the scaling with
population size we find that the exponent is development dependent with a
transition from super- to sub-linear scaling. From the climate change
mitigation point of view, the results suggest that urbanization is desirable in
developed countries and should be avoided in developing ones. Further, we
compare this analysis with a second scaling relation, namely the fundamental
allometry between city population and area, and propose that density might be
the decisive quantity. Last, we derive the theoretical country-wide urban
emissions by integration and obtain a dependence on the size of the largest
city.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.3696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.3696</id><created>2013-08-16</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Makotyn</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klauss</keyname><forenames>Catherine E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldberger</keyname><forenames>David L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornell</keyname><forenames>Eric. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Deborah S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal dynamics of a degenerate unitary Bose gas</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures. belated upload of corrected submission</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 10, 116-119 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys2850</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the rich behavior that emerges from systems of interacting
quantum particles, such as electrons in materials, nucleons in nuclei or
neutron stars, the quark-gluon plasma, and superfluid liquid helium, requires
investigation of systems that are clean, accessible, and have tunable
parameters. Ultracold quantum gases offer tremendous promise for this
application largely due to an unprecedented control over interactions.
Specifically, $a$, the two-body scattering length that characterizes the
interaction strength, can be tuned to any value. This offers prospects for
experimental access to regimes where the behavior is not well understood
because interactions are strong, atom-atom correlations are important,
mean-field theory is inadequate, and equilibrium may not be reached or perhaps
does not even exist. Of particular interest is the unitary gas, where $a$ is
infinite, and where many aspects of the system are universal in that they
depend only on the particle density and quantum statistics. While the unitary
Fermi gas has been the subject of intense experimental and theoretical
investigation, the degenerate unitary Bose gas has generally been deemed
experimentally inaccessible because of three-body loss rates that increase
dramatically with increasing $a$. Here, we investigate dynamics of a unitary
Bose gas for timescales that are short compared to the loss. We find that the
momentum distribution of the unitary Bose gas evolves on timescales fast
compared to losses, and that both the timescale for this evolution and the
limiting shape of the momentum distribution are consistent with universal
scaling with density. This work demonstrates that a unitary Bose gas can be
created and probed dynamically, and thus opens the door for further exploration
of this novel strongly interacting quantum liquid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1308.5258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1308.5258</id><created>2013-08-23</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nassif</keyname><forenames>Cl&#xe1;udio</forenames></author></authors><title>On the electrodynamics of moving particles in a quasi flat spacetime
  with Lorentz violation and its cosmological implications</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>49 pages and 7 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap
  with arXiv:physics/0702095, arXiv:0711.4897.
  http://www.worldscientific.com/worldscinet/ijmpd?journalTabs=read. text
  overlap with arXiv:0705.1836 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics D25:10, p.1-67 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271816500966</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This research aims to develop a new approach toward a consistent coupling of
electromagnetic and gravitational fields by using an electron that couples with
a weak gravitational potential by means of its electromagnetic field. We find
the value of the tiny coupling constant of gravity with electromagnetic fields,
which depends on the speed of light and a universal minimum speed that
represents the lowest limit of speed for any particle. Such a minimum speed,
unattainable by particles, represents a preferred reference frame associated
with a background field that breaks the Lorentz symmetry. The metric of the
flat spacetime shall include the presence of a uniform vacuum energy density,
which leads to a negative pressure at cosmological scales, i.e., the
cosmological anti-gravity. The tiny values of the cosmological constant and the
vacuum energy density will be successfully obtained in agreement with the
observational data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.5069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.5069</id><created>2014-02-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Barna</keyname><forenames>Imre Ferenc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imre</keyname><forenames>Attila Rikard</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical Study of Steam Condensation Induced Water Hammer Phenomena
  in Horizontal Pipeline</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, 1 table submitted to Experimental Thermal and
  Fluid Science</comments><journal-ref>Kerntechnik 80, (2015) 5</journal-ref><doi>10.3139/124.110537</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate steam condensation induced water hammer (CIWH) phenomena and
present new theoretical results. We use the WAHA3 model based on two-phase flow
six first-order partial differential equations that present one dimensional,
surface averaged mass, momentum and energy balances. A second order accurate
high-resolution shock-capturing numerical scheme was applied with different
kind of limiters in the numerical calculations. The applied two-fluid model
shows some similarities to Relap5 which is widely used in the nuclear industry
to simulate nuclear power plant accidents. This model was validated with
different CIWH experiments which were performed in the PMK-2 facility, which is
a full-pressure thermo-hydraulic model of the nuclear power plant of
VVER-440/312 type in the Energy Research Center of the Hungarian Academy of
Sciences in Budapest and in the Rosa facility in Japan. In our recent study we
show the first part of a planned large database which will give us the upper
and lower flooding mass flow rates for various pipe geometries where CIWH can
happen. Such a reliable database would be a great help for future reactor
constructions and scheming.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.5332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.5332</id><created>2014-03-20</created><updated>2015-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion Dark Matter Searches</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, contribution to the VII International Conference
  on Interconnections between Particle Physics and Cosmology, Deadwood, SD,
  USA, 2013</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1604 (2014) 456-461</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4883465</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nearly all astrophysical and cosmological data point convincingly to a large
component of cold dark matter in the Universe. The axion particle, first
theorized as a solution to the strong charge-parity problem of quantum
chromodynamics, has been established as a prominent CDM candidate. Cosmic
observation and particle physics experiments have bracketed the unknown mass of
the axion between approximately a $\mu$eV and a meV. The Axion Dark Matter
eXperiement (ADMX) has successfully completed searches between 1.9 and 3.7
$\mu$eV down to the KSVZ photon-coupling limit. ADMX and the Axion Dark Matter
eXperiement High-Frequency (ADMX-HF) will search for axions at weaker coupling
and/or higher frequencies within the next few years. Status of the experiments,
current research and development, and projected mass-coupling exclusion limits
are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.0353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.0353</id><created>2014-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Fluschnik</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kriewald</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ros</keyname><forenames>Anselmo Garc&#xed;a Cant&#xfa;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reusser</keyname><forenames>Dominik E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kropp</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybski</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>The size distribution, scaling properties and spatial organization of
  urban clusters: a global and regional perspective</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.data-an</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Geo-Inf. 5(7): 110, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/ijgi5070110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Human development has far-reaching impacts on the surface of the globe. The
transformation of natural land cover occurs in different forms and urban growth
is one of the most eminent transformative processes. We analyze global land
cover data and extract cities as defined by maximally connected urban clusters.
The analysis of the city size distribution for all cities on the globe confirms
Zipf's law. Moreover, by investigating the percolation properties of the
clustering of urban areas we assess the closeness to criticality for various
countries. At the critical thresholds, the urban land cover of the countries
undergoes a transition from separated clusters to a gigantic component on the
country scale. We study the Zipf-exponents as a function of the closeness to
percolation and find a systematic decrease with increasing scale, which could
be the reason for deviating exponents reported in literature. Moreover, we
investigate the average size of the clusters as a function of the proximity to
percolation and find country specific behavior. By relating the standard
deviation and the average of cluster sizes -- analogous to Taylor's law -- we
suggest an alternative way to identify the percolation transition. We calculate
spatial correlations of the urban land cover and find long-range correlations.
Finally, by relating the areas of cities with population figures we address the
global aspect of the allometry of cities, finding an exponent $\delta\approx
0.85$, i.e. large cities have lower densities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.6310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.6310</id><created>2014-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Barna</keyname><forenames>I. F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser assisted proton collision on light nuclei at moderate energies</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, will be submitted to Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Laser and Particle Beams 33, (2015) 299</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0263034615000191</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present analytic angular differential cross section model for laser
assisted proton nucleon scattering on a Woods-Saxon optical potential where the
nth-order photon absorption is taken into account simultaneously. As a physical
example we calculate cross sections for proton - $^{12}$C collision at 49 MeV
in the laboratory frame where the laser intensity is in the range of $ 10^{7} -
10^{21}$ W/cm$^2$ at optical frequencies. The upper intensity limit is slightly
below the relativistic regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2583</id><created>2014-09-08</created><updated>2015-03-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faria</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrillo-Bastos</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandler</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latg&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fano resonances in hexagonal zigzag graphene rings under external
  magnetic flux</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>To appear in JPCM</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 27 175301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/27/17/175301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study transport properties of hexagonal zigzag graphene quantum rings
connected to semi-infinite nanoribbons. Open two-fold symmetric structures
support localized states that can be traced back to those existing in the
isolated six-fold symmetric rings. Using a tight-binding Hamiltonian within the
Green's function formalism, we show that an external magnetic field promotes
these localized states to Fano resonances with robust signatures in transport.
Local density of states and current distributions of the resonant states are
calculated as a function of the magnetic flux intensity. For structures on
corrugated substrates we analyze the effect of strain by including an
out-of-plane centro-symmetric deformation in the model. We show that small
strains shift the resonance positions without further modifications, while high
strains introduce new ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1303</id><created>2014-10-06</created><updated>2014-11-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barna</keyname><forenames>Imre Ferenc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bognar</keyname><forenames>Gabriella</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-similar analytic solution of the two dimensional Navier-Stokes
  equation with a non-Newtonian type of viscosity</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures, submitted to Journal of Non-Newtonian Fluid
  Dynamics</comments><journal-ref>Mathematical Modelling and Analysis 21, (2016) 83</journal-ref><doi>10.3846/13926292.2016.1136901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the two dimensional incompressible Navier-Stokes(NS) and the
continuity equations in Cartesian coordinates and Eulerian description for
non-Newtonian fluids. As a non-Newtonian viscosity we consider the Ladyzenskaya
model with a non-linear velocity dependent stress tensor. The key idea is the
multi-dimensional generalization of the well-known self-similar Ansatz, which
was already used for non-compressible and compressible viscous flow studies.
The geometrical interpretations of the trial function is also discussed. We
compare our recent results to the former Newtonian ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06594</id><created>2015-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Refaei</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheirandish</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative noninteracting scalar field theory: A covariant formulation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Caldeira-Leggett model of reservoir is generalized to a reservoir modeled by
a continuum of real Klein-Gordon fields, instead of harmonic oscillators. A
quantum Langevin type dissipative equation is obtained for the scalar field.
The susceptibility of the medium is defined in terms of the reservoir Green's
function and the coupling function satisfying causality condition. The
connection between the coupling function and the susceptibility of the medium
is found to be a Hankel transform from which the coupling function can be
determined in terms of the susceptibility of the medium. Noise currents and
their fluctuation-dissipation relation are obtained. In a homogeneous medium or
reservoir, explicit form of the quantum scalar field, and its large-time limit,
are found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05039</id><created>2015-02-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Barna</keyname><forenames>I. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matyas</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic self-similar solutions of the Oberbeck-Boussinesq equations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaos Solitons and Fractals 78, (2015) 249</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chaos.2015.08.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we will present pure two-dimensional analytic solutions for
the coupled non-compressible Newtoniain Navier-Stokes
  --- with Boussinesq approximation --- and the heat conduction equation. The
system was investigated from E.N. Lorenz half a century ago with Fourier series
and pioneered the way to the paradigm of chaos. We present a novel analysis of
the same system where the key idea is the two-dimensional generalization of the
well-known self-similar Ansatz of Barenblatt which will be interpreted in a
geometrical way. The results, the pressure, temperature and velocity fields are
all analytic and can be expressed with the help of the error functions. The
temperature field has a strongly damped oscillating behavior which is an
interesting feature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.04860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.04860</id><created>2015-03-16</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dzhatdoev</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>On conservative models of &quot;the pair-production anomaly&quot; in blazar
  spectra at Very High Energies</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures. This paper tries to summarize the status of the
  field by the end of January, 2015. In v. 2 several typos were corrected</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series, Volume 632, Issue 1,
  article id. 012035 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/632/1/012035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For some blazars, the gamma-ray absorption features due to pair-production on
the Extragalactic Background Light (EBL) are fainter than expected. The present
work reviews the main models that could explain this paradox, with emphasis on
conservative ones, that do not include any new physics. The models that are
intrinsic to the source, do allow a very hard primary spectrum, but fail to
explain a regular redshift dependence of the anomaly starting energy. The model
that includes a contribution from secondary photons produced by cosmic rays
(CR) near the Earth seems to require a well collimated CR beam, what is hard to
achieve. Finally, the model with secondary photons produced in electromagnetic
(EM) cascades initiated by primary gamma-rays is considered. In principle, it
allows to decrease the statistical significance of the anomaly and, while
requiring quite low EGMF strength B, does not contradict to most contemporary
constraints on the B value. Additionally, it is shown that the recently
observed correlation between directions to hard gamma-ray sources and voids in
the Large Scale Structure is a natural feature of the EM cascade model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06988</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adami</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>LaBar</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>From Entropy to Information: Biased Typewriters and the Origin of Life</title><categories>q-bio.PE cs.IT math.IT nlin.AO q-bio.BM</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures in &quot;From Matter to Life: Information and
  Causality&quot;, S.I. Walker, P.C.W. Davies, and G. F. R. Ellis, eds., (Cambridge
  University Press, 2017) pp. 130-154</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of life can be understood mathematically to be the origin of
information that can replicate. The likelihood that entropy spontaneously
becomes information can be calculated from first principles, and depends
exponentially on the amount of information that is necessary for replication.
We do not know what the minimum amount of information for self-replication is
because it must depend on the local chemistry, but we can study how this
likelihood behaves in different known chemistries, and we can study ways in
which this likelihood can be enhanced. Here we present evidence from numerical
simulations (using the digital life chemistry &quot;Avida&quot;) that using a biased
probability distribution for the creation of monomers (the &quot;biased typewriter&quot;)
can exponentially increase the likelihood of spontaneous emergence of
information from entropy. We show that this likelihood may depend on the length
of the sequence that the information is embedded in, but in a non-trivial
manner: there may be an optimum sequence length that maximizes the likelihood.
We conclude that the likelihood of spontaneous emergence of self-replication is
much more malleable than previously thought, and that the biased probability
distributions of monomers that are the norm in biochemistry may significantly
enhance these likelihoods
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03480</id><created>2015-09-11</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Svozil</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized event structures and probabilities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures in Information and Complexity, World Scientific
  Series in Information Studies: Volume 6, ed. by Mark Burgin and Cristian S
  Calude, Chapter 11, pp. 276-300, (World Scientific, Singapore, 2016)</comments><doi>10.1142/9789813109032_0011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the classical mind, quantum mechanics is boggling enough; nevertheless
more bizarre behavior could be imagined, thereby concentrating on propositional
structures (empirical logics) that transcend the quantum domain. One can also
consistently suppose predictions and probabilities which are neither classical
nor quantum, but which are subject to subclassicality; that is, the additivity
of probabilities for mutually exclusive, co-measurable observables, as
formalized by admissibility rules and frame functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01109</id><created>2015-11-03</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yasir</keyname><forenames>Kashif Ammar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wu-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-Orbit Coupling Induced Back-action Cooling in Cavity-Optomechanics
  with a Bose-Einstein Condensate</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013810 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013810</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a spin-orbit coupling induced back-action cooling in an
optomechanical system, composed of a spin-orbit coupled Bose-Einstein
condensate trapped in an optical cavity with one movable end mirror, by
suppressing heating effects of quantum noises. The collective density
excitations of the spin-orbit coupling mediated hyperfine states - serving as
atomic oscillators equally coupled to the cavity field - trigger strongly
driven atomic back-action. We find that the back-action not only revamps
low-temperature dynamics of its own but also provides an opportunity to cool
the mechanical mirror to its quantum mechanical ground state. Further, we
demonstrate that the strength of spin-orbit coupling also superintends dynamic
structure factor and squeezes nonlinear quantum noises, like thermo-mechanical
and photon shot noise, which enhances optomechanical features of hybrid cavity
beyond the previous investigations. Our findings are testable in a realistic
setup and enhance the functionality of cavity-optomechanics with spin-orbit
coupled hyperfine states in the field of quantum optics and quantum
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04420</id><created>2016-01-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ching</keyname><forenames>Chee Leong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeo</keyname><forenames>Cheng Xun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>Wei Khim</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Relativistic Anti-Snyder Model and Some Applications</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A, Vol. 32 (2017) 1750009
  (28 pages)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17500099</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the (2+1)-dimensional Dirac equation in a homogeneous magnetic
field under the non-relativistic anti-Snyder model which is relevant to
deformed special relativity (DSR) since it exhibits an intrinsic upper bound of
the momentum of free particles. After setting up the formalism, exact eigen
solutions are derived in momentum space representation and they are expressed
in terms of finite orthogonal Romanovski polynomials. There is a finite maximum
number of allowable bound states due to the orthogonality of the polynomials
and the maximum energy is truncated at the maximum n. Similar to the minimal
length case, the degeneracy of the Dirac-Landau levels in anti- Snyder model
are modified and there are states that do not exist in the ordinary quantum
mechanics limit. By taking zero mass limit, we explore the motion of effective
zero mass charged Fermions in Graphene like material and obtained a maximum
bound of deformed parameter. Furthermore, we consider the modified energy
dispersion relations and its application in describing the behavior of
neutrinos oscillation under modified commutation relations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01276</id><created>2016-03-03</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shankar</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames><affiliation>University of Southampton</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>Mariangela</forenames><affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sheth</keyname><forenames>Ravi K.</forenames><affiliation>University of Pennsylvania</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ferrarese</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames><affiliation>Herzberg Institute of Astrophysics, Victoria</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Graham</keyname><forenames>Alister W.</forenames><affiliation>Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, Swinburne University of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Savorgnan</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames><affiliation>Centre for Astrophysics and Supercomputing, Swinburne University of Technology</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Allevato</keyname><forenames>Viola</forenames><affiliation>University of Helsinki</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Marconi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames><affiliation>Universita' degli Studi di Firenze</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Laesker</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institute for Astronomy</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lapi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames><affiliation>SISSA, Trieste</affiliation></author></authors><title>Selection bias in dynamically-measured super-massive black hole samples:
  its consequences and the quest for the most fundamental relation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>24 pages, 11 Figures, two Appendices. Replaced with accepted version
  in MNRAS. Minor revisions. A press release of the Royal Astronomical Society
  can be found at
  http://www.ras.org.uk/news-and-press/2861-black-holes-and-the-prospects-for-measuring-gravitational-waves</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 460, 3119, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw678</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the set of local galaxies having dynamically measured black holes
with a large, unbiased sample of galaxies extracted from the Sloan Digital Sky
Survey. We confirm earlier work showing that the majority of black hole hosts
have significantly higher velocity dispersions sigma than local galaxies of
similar stellar mass. We use Monte-Carlo simulations to illustrate the effect
on black hole scaling relations if this bias arises from the requirement that
the black hole sphere of influence must be resolved to measure black hole
masses with spatially resolved kinematics. We find that this selection effect
artificially increases the normalization of the Mbh-sigma relation by a factor
of at least ~3; the bias for the Mbh-Mstar relation is even larger. Our Monte
Carlo simulations and analysis of the residuals from scaling relations both
indicate that sigma is more fundamental than Mstar or effective radius. In
particular, the Mbh-Mstar relation is mostly a consequence of the Mbh-sigma and
sigma-Mstar relations, and is heavily biased by up to a factor of 50 at small
masses. This helps resolve the discrepancy between dynamically-based black
hole-galaxy scaling relations versus those of active galaxies. Our simulations
also disfavour broad distributions of black hole masses at fixed sigma.
Correcting for this bias suggests that the calibration factor used to estimate
black hole masses in active galaxies should be reduced to values of fvir~1.
Black hole mass densities should also be proportionally smaller, perhaps
implying significantly higher radiative efficiencies/black hole spins. Reducing
black hole masses also reduces the gravitational wave signal expected from
black hole mergers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07346</id><created>2016-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Qiushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pospischil</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhuiyan</keyname><forenames>Maruf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farmer</keyname><forenames>Damon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Bingchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Shu-Jen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Qiangfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Tso-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Fengnian</forenames></author></authors><title>Black Phosphorus Mid-Infrared Photodetectors with High Gain</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2016, 16 (7), pp 4648-4655</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b01977</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, black phosphorus (BP) has joined the two dimensional material
family as a promising candidate for photonic applications, due to its moderate
bandgap, high carrier mobility, and compatibility with a diverse range of
substrates. Photodetectors are probably the most explored BP photonic devices,
however, their unique potential compared with other layered materials in the
mid-infrared wavelength range has not been revealed. Here, we demonstrate BP
mid infrared detectors at 3.39 um with high internal gain, resulting in an
external responsivity of 82 A/W. Noise measurements show that such BP
photodetectors are capable of sensing low intensity mid-infrared light in the
picowatt range. Moreover, the high photoresponse remains effective at kilohertz
modulation frequencies, because of the fast carrier dynamics arising from BPs
moderate bandgap. The high photoresponse at mid infrared wavelengths and the
large dynamic bandwidth, together with its unique polarization dependent
response induced by low crystalline symmetry, can be coalesced to promise
photonic applications such as chip-scale mid-infrared sensing and imaging at
low light levels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00689</id><created>2016-04-03</created><updated>2016-09-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Sebabrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valiente</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldman</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spracklen</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;hberg</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>Robert R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of pair tunneling and coherent destruction of tunneling in
  arrays of optical waveguides</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, Appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 053853 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.053853</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the experimental realization of a photonic system that simulates
the one-dimensional two-particle Hubbard model. This analogy is realized by
means of two-dimensional arrays of coupled optical waveguides, fabricated using
femtosecond laser inscription. By tuning the analogous &quot;interaction strength&quot;,
we reach the strongly-interacting regime of the Hubbard Hamiltonian, and
demonstrate the suppression of standard tunneling for individual &quot;particles&quot;.
In this regime, the formation of bound states is identified through the direct
observation of pair tunneling. We then demonstrate the coherent destruction of
tunneling (CDT) for the paired particles in the presence of an engineered
oscillating force of high frequency. The precise control over the analogous
&quot;interaction strength&quot; and driving force offered by our experimental system
opens an exciting route towards quantum simulation of few-body physics in
photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02144</id><created>2016-04-07</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Glidden</keyname><forenames>Ana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooksey</keyname><forenames>Kathy L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simcoe</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Meara</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predominantly Low Metallicities Measured in a Stratified Sample of Lyman
  Limit Systems at z=3.7</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ, 21 Pages, 11 Figures</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/833/2/270</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measured metallicities for 33 z=3.4-4.2 absorption line systems drawn from
a sample of H I-selected-Lyman limit systems (LLSs) identified in Sloan Digital
Sky Survey (SDSS) quasar spectra and stratified based on metal line features.
We obtained higher-resolution spectra with the Keck Echellette Spectrograph and
Imager, selecting targets according to our stratification scheme in an effort
to fully sample the LLS population metallicity distribution. We established a
plausible range of H I column densities and measured column densities (or
limits) for ions of carbon, silicon, and aluminum, finding ionization-corrected
metallicities or upper limits. Interestingly, our ionization models were better
constrained with enhanced $\alpha$-to-aluminum abundances, with a median
abundance ratio of [$\alpha$/Al]=0.3. Measured metallicities were generally
low, ranging from [M/H]=-3 to -1.68, with even lower metallicities likely for
some systems with upper limits. Using survival statistics to incorporate
limits, we constructed the cumulative distribution function (CDF) for LLS
metallicities. Recent models of galaxy evolution propose that galaxies
replenish their gas from the low-metallicity intergalactic medium (IGM) via
high-density H I &quot;flows&quot; and eject enriched interstellar gas via outflows.
Thus, there has been some expectation that LLSs at the peak of cosmic star
formation ($z\approx3$) might have a bimodal metallicity distribution. We
modeled our CDF as a mix of two Gaussian distributions, one reflecting the
metallicity of the IGM and the other representative of the interstellar medium
of star-forming galaxies. This bimodal distribution yielded a poor fit. A
single Gaussian distribution better represented the sample with a low mean
metallicity of [M/H] $\approx -2.5$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02440</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tracy</keyname><forenames>Craig A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widom</keyname><forenames>Harold</forenames></author></authors><title>On the ground state energy of the delta-function Fermi gas</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages. Version 2 corrects misprints, adds references, and improves
  the exposition</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 57, 103301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The weak coupling asymptotics to order $\gamma$ of the ground state energy of
the delta-function Fermi gas, derived heuristically in the literature, is here
made rigorous. Further asymptotics are in principle computable. The analysis
applies to the Gaudin integral equation a method previously used by one of the
authors for the asymptotics of large Toeplitz matrices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05612</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2016-04-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Sebabrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spracklen</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valiente</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;hberg</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldman</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomson</keyname><forenames>Robert R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental observation of anomalous topological edge modes in a
  slowly-driven photonic lattice</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 13918 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13918</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The discovery of the quantised Hall effect, and its subsequent topological
explanation, demonstrated the important role topology can play in determining
the properties of quantum systems. This realisation led to the development of
topological band theory, where, in addition to band index and quasimomentum,
Bloch bands are also characterised by a set of topological invariants. This
topological theory can be readily extended to periodically-driven systems. In
the limit of fast driving, the topology of the system can still be captured by
the topological invariants used to describe static systems. In the limit of
slow driving, however, situations can arise where standard topological
invariants are zero, but yet, topologically protected edge modes are still
observed. These &quot;anomalous&quot; topological edge modes have no static analogue, and
are associated with a distinct topological invariant, which takes into account
the full time-evolution over a driving period. Here we demonstrate the first
experimental observation of such anomalous topological edge modes in an
ultrafast-laser-inscribed photonic lattice. This inscription technique allows
one to address each bond of a lattice independently and dynamically, generating
a rich band structure with robust anomalous chiral edge modes and the potential
for perfectly localised bulk states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06519</id><created>2016-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced superconductivity by strain and carrier-doping in borophene: A
  first principles prediction</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 122604 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4963179</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We predict by first principles calculations that the recently prepared
borophene is a pristine two-dimensional (2D) monolayer superconductor, in which
the superconductivity can be significantly enhanced by strain and charge
carrier doping. The intrinsic metallic ground state with high density of states
at Fermi energy and strong Fermi surface nesting lead to sizeable
electron-phonon coupling, making the freestanding borophene superconduct with
$T_c$ close to 19.0 K. The tensile strain can increase $T_c$ to 27.4 K, while
the hole doping can notably increase $T_c$ to 34.8 K. The results indicate that
the borophene grown on substrates with large lattice parameters or under
photoexcitation can show enhanced superconductivity with $T_c$ far more above
liquid hydrogen temperature of 20.3 K, which will largely broaden the
applications of such novel material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01237</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xue-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Shijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelster</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggert</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum domain walls induce incommensurate supersolid phase on the
  anisotropic triangular lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures. Latest version and more information at
  http://www.physik.uni-kl.de/eggert/papers/index.html</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 193201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.193201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the extended hard-core Bose-Hubbard model on the triangular
lattice as a function of spatial anisotropy with respect to both tunneling and
nearest-neighbor interaction strength. At half-filling the system can be tuned
from decoupled one-dimensional chains to a two-dimensional solid phase with
alternating density order by adjusting the anisotropic coupling. At
intermediate anisotropy, however, frustration effects dominate and an
incommensurate supersolid phase emerges, which is characterized by
incommensurate density order as well as an anisotropic superfluid density. We
demonstrate that this intermediate phase results from the proliferation of
topological defects in the form of quantum bosonic domain walls. Accordingly,
the structure factor has peaks at wave vectors, which are linearly related to
the number of domain walls in a finite system in agreement with extensive
quantum Monte Carlo simulations. We discuss possible connections with the
supersolid behavior in the high-temperature superconducting striped phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07961</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cartas-Fuentevilla</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>Puebla U., Inst. Fis.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Escalante</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames><affiliation>Puebla U., Inst. Fis.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Herrera-Aguilar</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames><affiliation>Puebla U., Inst. Fis.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Symplectic analysis of three dimensional Abelian topological gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed Faddeev-Jackiw quantization of an Abelian topological gravity is
performed; we show that this formalism is equivalent and more economical than
Dirac's method. In particular, we identify the complete set of constraints of
the theory, from which the number of physical degrees of freedom is explicitly
computed. We prove that the generalized Faddeev-Jackiw brackets and the Dirac
ones coincide to each other. Moreover, we perform the Faddeev-Jackiw analysis
of the theory at the chiral point, and the full set of constraints and the
generalized Faddeev-Jackiw brackets are constructed. Finally we compare our
results with those found in the literature and we discuss some remarks and
prospects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09729</id><created>2016-05-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dang</keyname><forenames>Yijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Image Matching</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1364-2</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum image processing (QIP) means the quantum based methods to speed up
image processing algorithms. Many quantum image processing schemes claim that
their efficiency are theoretically higher than their corresponding classical
schemes. However, most of them do not consider the problem of measurement. As
we all know, measurement will lead to collapse. That is to say, executing the
algorithm once, users can only measure the final state one time. Therefore, if
users want to regain the results (the processed images), they must execute the
algorithms many times and then measure the final state many times to get all
the pixels' values. If the measurement process is taken into account, whether
or not the algorithms are really efficient needs to be reconsidered. In this
paper, we try to solve the problem of measurement and give a quantum image
matching algorithm. Unlike most of the QIP algorithms, our scheme interests
only one pixel (the target pixel) instead of the whole image. It modifies the
probability of pixels based on Grover's algorithm to make the target pixel to
be measured with higher probability, and the measurement step is executed only
once. An example is given to explain the algorithm more vividly. Complexity
analysis indicates that the quantum scheme's complexity is $O(2^{n})$ in
contradistinction to the classical scheme's complexity $O(2^{2n+2m})$, where
$m$ and $n$ are integers related to the size of images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01476</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01476</id><created>2016-06-05</created><updated>2016-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Slavyanov</keyname><forenames>S. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satco</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishkhanyan</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotinyan</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation and removal of apparent singularities in linear ordinary
  differential equations with polynomial coefficients</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Theor. Math. Phys. 189, 1726-1733 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0040577916120059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss several examples of generating apparent singular points as a
result of differentiating particular homogeneous linear ordinary differential
equations with polynomial coefficients and formulate two general conjectures on
the generation and removal of apparent singularities in arbitrary Fuchsian
differential equations with polynomial coefficients. We consider a model
problem in polymer physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06189</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Altmeyer</keyname><forenames>Michaela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guterding</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschfeld</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>Roser</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scalapino</keyname><forenames>Douglas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of vertex corrections in the matrix formulation of the random phase
  approximation for the multiorbital Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214515 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of a multiorbital Hubbard model description of
superconductivity, a matrix formulation of the superconducting pairing
interaction that has been widely used is designed to treat spin, charge and
orbital fluctuations within a random phase approximation (RPA). In terms of
Feynman diagrams, this takes into account particle-hole ladder and bubble
contributions as expected. It turns out, however, that this matrix formulation
also generates additional terms which have the diagrammatic structure of vertex
corrections. Here we examine these terms and discuss the relationship between
the matrix-RPA superconducting pairing interaction and the Feynman diagrams
that it sums.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09153</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>Abdel Nasser</forenames><affiliation>Egyptian Ctr. Theor. Phys., Cairo, WLCAPP, Cairo</affiliation></author></authors><title>QCD Phase-transition and chemical freezeout in nonzero magnetic field at
  NICA</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figure, accepted for publication in Indian J. Phys. (June
  23rd, 2016)</comments><report-no>ECTP-2015-1, WLCAPP-2015-17</report-no><journal-ref>Indian J. Phys. 91 (2017) no 1, 93-99</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12648-016-0901-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Because of relativistic off-center motion of the charged spectators and the
local momentum-imbalance experienced by the participants, a huge magnetic field
is likely generated in high-energy collisions. The influence of such
short-lived magnetic field on the QCD phase-transition(s) shall be analysed.
From Polyakov linear-sigma model, we study the chiral phase-transition and the
magnetic response and susceptibility in dependence on temperature, density and
magnetic field strength. The systematic measurements of the phase-transition
characterizing signals, such as the fluctuations, the dynamical correlations
and the in-medium modifications of rho-meson, for instance, in different
interacting systems and collision centralities are conjectured to reveal an
almost complete description for the QCD phase-structure and the chemical
freezeout. We limit the discussion to NICA energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01260</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kamata</keyname><forenames>Syo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuura</keyname><forenames>So</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misumi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>Kazutoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomaly and Sign problem in $\mathcal{N}=(2,2)$ SYM on Polyhedra :
  Numerical Analysis</title><categories>hep-th hep-lat</categories><comments>28 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables. Typos corrected. An equation of WT id
  and the corresponding numerical result updated. The conclusion is unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2016) 123B01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the two-dimensional $\mathcal{N}=(2,2)$ supersymmetric
Yang-Mills (SYM) theory on the discretized curved space (polyhedra). We first
revisit that the number of supersymmetries of the continuum $\mathcal{N}=(2,2)$
SYM theory on any curved manifold can be enhanced at least to two by
introducing an appropriate $U(1)$ gauge background associated with the
$U(1)_{V}$ symmetry. We then show that the generalized Sugino model on the
discretized curved space, which was proposed in our previous work, can be
identified to the discretization of this SUSY enhanced theory, where one of the
supersymmetries remains and the other is broken but restored in the continuum
limit. We find that the $U(1)_{A}$ anomaly exists also in the discretized
theory as a result of an unbalance of the number of the fermions proportional
to the Euler characteristics of the polyhedra. We then study this model by
using the numerical Monte-Carlo simulation. We propose a novel phase-quench
method called &quot;anomaly-phase-quenched approximation&quot; with respect to the
$U(1)_A$ anomaly. We numerically show that the Ward-Takahashi (WT) identity
associated with the remaining supersymmetry is realized by adopting this
approximation. We figure out the relation between the sign (phase) problem and
pseudo-zero-modes of the Dirac operator. We also show that the divergent
behavior of the scalar one-point function gets milder as the genus of the
background increases. These are the first numerical observations for the
supersymmetric lattice model on the curved space with generic topologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02585</id><created>2016-07-09</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>Naohisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Algebraic construction of spherical harmonics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9pages, 13figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The angular wave functions for a hydrogen atom are well known to be spherical
harmonics, and are obtained as the solutions of a partial differential
equation. However, the differential operator is given by the Casimir operator
of the $SU(2)$ algebra and its eigenvalue $l(l+1) \hbar^2$, where $l$ is
non-negative integer, is easily obtained by an algebraic method. Therefore the
shape of the wave function may also be obtained by extending the algebraic
method. In this paper, we describe the method and show that wave functions with
different quantum numbers are connected by a rotational group in the cases of
$l=0$, 1 and 2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03248</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Parny</keyname><forenames>Laurent de Forges</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rousseau</keyname><forenames>Val&#xe9;ry G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum and Thermal Phase Transitions in a Bosonic Atom-Molecule Mixture
  in a Two-dimensional Optical Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 013606 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.013606</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ground state and the thermal phase diagram of a two-species
Bose-Hubbard model, with $U(1)\times \mathbb{Z}_2$ symmetry, describing atoms
and molecules on a 2D optical lattice interacting via a Feshbach resonance.
Using quantum Monte Carlo simulations and mean field theory, we show that the
conversion between the two-species, coherently coupling the atomic and
molecular states, has a crucial impact on the Mott-Superfluid transition and
stabilizes an insulating phase with a gap controlled by the conversion term --
\textit{the Feshbach insulator} -- instead of a standard Mott insulating phase.
Depending on the detuning between atoms and molecules, this model exhibits
three phases: the Feshbach insulator, a molecular condensate coexisting with
non condensed atoms and a mixed atomic-molecular condensate. Employing a
finite-size scaling method, we observe 3D XY (3D Ising) transition when $U(1)$
($ \mathbb{Z}_2$) is broken whereas the transition is first-order when both
$U(1)$ and $ \mathbb{Z}_2$ symmetries are spontaneously broken. The finite
temperature phase diagram is also discussed. The thermal disappearance of the
molecular superfluid leads to a Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless transition with
unusual universal jump in the superfluid density. The loss of the
quasi-long-range coherence of the mixed atomic and molecular superfluid is more
subtle since only atoms exhibit conventional Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless
criticality. We also observe a classical first-order transition between the
mixed superfluid and the normal Bose liquid at low temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05880</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tkachov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetoelectric Andreev effect due to proximity-induced non-unitary
  triplet superconductivity in helical metals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4.5 + 9 pages, 3 figures, version accepted by Physical Review
  Letters. Supplemental material includes discussion of a generic
  non-centrosymmetric superconductor</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 016802 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.016802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-centrosymmetric superconductors exhibit the magnetoelectric effect which
manifests itself in the appearance of the magnetic spin polarization in
response to a dissipationless electric current (supercurrent). While much
attention has been dedicated to the thermodynamic version of this phenomenon
(Edelstein effect), non-equilibrium transport magnetoelectric effects have not
been explored yet. We propose the magnetoelectric Andreev effect (MAE) which
consists in the generation of spin-polarized triplet Andreev conductance by an
electric supercurrent. The MAE stems from the spin polarization of the
Cooper-pair condensate due to a supercurrent-induced non-unitary triplet
pairing. We propose the realization of such non-unitary pairing and MAE in
superconducting proximity structures based on two-dimensional helical metals --
strongly spin-orbit-coupled electronic systems with the Dirac spectrum such as
the topological surface states. Our results uncover an unexplored route towards
electrically controlled superconducting spintronics and are a smoking gun for
induced unconventional superconductivity in spin-orbit-coupled materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00868</id><created>2016-08-02</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bernardo</keyname><forenames>Bert&#xfa;lio de Lima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canabarro</keyname><forenames>Askery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Azevedo</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;rgio</forenames></author></authors><title>How a single particle modifies the physical reality of two distant
  others simultaneously: a quantum nonlocality and weak value study</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 39767 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep39767</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of wave-particle duality, which is a key element of quantum
theory, has been remarkably found to manifest itself in several experimental
realizations as in the famous double-slit experiment. In this specific case, a
single particle seems to travel through two separated slits simultaneously.
Nevertheless, it is never possible to measure it in both slits, which naturally
appears as a manifestation of the collapse postulate. In this respect, one
could as well ask if it is possible to &quot;perceive&quot; the presence of the particle
at the two slits simultaneously, once its collapse could be avoided. In this
article, we use the recently proposed entanglement mediation protocol to
provide a positive answer to this question. It is shown that a photon which
behaves like a wave, i.e., which seems to be present in two distant locations
at the same time, can modify two existing physical realities in these
locations. Calculations of the &quot;weak trace&quot; left by such photon also enforce
the validity of the present argumentation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01005</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01005</id><created>2016-08-02</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garrison</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Using Gravitational Waves to put limits on Primordial Magnetic Fields</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1503.04764</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a technique for using simulated tensor perturbations in order to
place upper limits on the intensity of magnetic fields in the early universe.
As an example, we apply this technique to the beginning of primordial
nucleosynthesis. We determined that any magnetic seed fields that existed
before that time were still in the process of being amplified. In the future,
we plan to apply this technique to a wider range of initial magnetic fields and
cosmological epochs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05623</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Churchill</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Philbin</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic reflection, transmission and energy density at
  boundaries of nonlocal media</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures; Introduction extended, references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 235422 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235422</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a semi-infinite spatially dispersive dielectric with unequal
transverse and longitudinal susceptibilities. The effect of the boundary is
characterized by arbitrary reflection coefficients for polarization waves in
the material that propagate to the surface. Specific values of these
coefficients correspond to various additional boundary conditions (ABC) for
Maxwell's equations. We derive the electromagnetic reflection and transmission
coefficients at the boundary and investigate their dependence on material
parameters and ABC. We also investigate the electromagnetic zero-point and
thermal spectral energy density outside the dielectric. The nonlocal response
removes the boundary divergence of the spectral energy density that is present
in a local model. The spectral energy density shows a large dependence on the
difference between the transverse and longitudinal susceptibilities, even at
distances up to 10nm from the boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05728</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Simidzija</keyname><forenames>Petar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Martinez</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Information carrying capacity of a cosmological constant</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures. RevTeX 4.1. v2: Minor typos corrected and updated
  to match published version (including minor title change)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 025002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.025002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the exchange of information in different cosmological backgrounds
when sender and receiver are timelike separated and communicate through
massless fields (without the exchange of light-signals). Remarkably, we show
that the dominance of a cosmological constant makes the amount of recoverable
information imprinted in the field by the sender extremely resilient: it does
not decay in time or with the spatial separation of sender and receiver, and it
actually increases with the rate of expansion of the Universe. This is in stark
contrast with the information carried by conventional light-signals and with
previous results on timelike communication through massless fields in matter
dominated cosmologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07576</id><created>2016-08-26</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bachlechner</keyname><forenames>Thomas C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation Expels Runaways</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>56 pages, 17 figures; v2: fixed typos</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1612 (2016) 155</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2016)155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that moduli stabilization generically restricts the evolution
following transitions between weakly coupled de Sitter vacua and can induce a
strong selection bias towards inflationary cosmologies. The energy density of
domain walls between vacua typically destabilizes Kahler moduli and triggers a
runaway towards large volume. This decompactification phase can collapse the
new de Sitter region unless a minimum amount of inflation occurs after the
transition. A stable vacuum transition is guaranteed only if the inflationary
expansion generates overlapping past light cones for all observable modes
originating from the reheating surface, which leads to an approximately flat
and isotropic universe. High scale inflation is vastly favored. Our results
point towards a framework for studying parameter fine-tuning and inflationary
initial conditions in flux compactifications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00068</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jiefei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chattaraj</keyname><forenames>Swarnabha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Siyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madhukar</keyname><forenames>Anupam</forenames></author></authors><title>Mesa-top quantum dot single photon emitter arrays: growth, optical
  characteristics, and the simulated optical response of integrated dielectric
  nanoantenna-waveguide systems</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>24 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 120, 243103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972272</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanophotonic quantum information processing systems require spatially
ordered, spectrally uniform single photon sources (SPSs) integrated on-chip
with co-designed light manipulating elements providing emission rate
enhancement, emitted photon guidance, and lossless propagation. Towards this
goal, we consider systems comprising an SPS array with each SPS coupled to a
dielectric building block (DBB) based multifunctional light manipulation unit
(LMU). For the SPS array, we report triggered single photon emission from
GaAs(001)/InGaAs single quantum dots (SQDs) grown selectively on top of
nanomesas using the approach of substrate-encoded size-reducing epitaxy
(SESRE). Systematic temperature and power dependent photoluminescence (PL), PL
excitation, time-resolved PL, and emission statistics studies reveal high
spectral uniformity and single photon emission at 8 K with g(2)(0) of 0.19
plusminus 0.03. The SESRE based SPS arrays, following growth of a planarizing
overlayer, are readily integrable with LMUs fabricated subsequently using
either the 2D photonic crystal approach or, as theoretically examined here, DBB
based LMUs. We report the simulated optical response of SPS embedded in DBB
based nanoantenna-waveguide structures as the multifunctional LMU. The multiple
functions of emission rate enhancement, guiding, and lossless propagation
derive from the behavior of the same collective Mie resonance (dominantly
magnetic) of the interacting DBB based LMU tuned to the SPS targeted emission
wavelength of 980 nm. The simulation utilizes an analytical approach that
provides physical insight to the obtained numerical results. Together, the
combined experimental and modelling demonstrations open a rich approach to
implementing co-designed on-chip integrated SPS-LMU that, in turn, serve as
basic elements of integrated nanophotonic information processing systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01889</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gubler</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Toru T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author></authors><title>Flavor structure of $\Lambda$ baryons from lattice QCD: From strange to
  charm quarks</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ex hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures, 5 tables; v2 (published version in PRD): title
  slightly changed, discussion about systematic uncertainties extended, typos
  fixed, references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114518 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114518</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study $\Lambda$ baryons of spin-parity $\frac{1}{2}^{\pm}$ with either a
strange or charm valence quark in full 2+1 flavor lattice QCD. Multiple $SU(3)$
singlet and octet operators are employed to generate the desired single baryon
states on the lattice. Via the variational method, the couplings of these
states to the different operators provide information about the flavor
structure of the $\Lambda$ baryons. We make use of the gauge configurations of
the PACS-CS Collaboration and chirally extrapolate the results for the masses
and $SU(3)$ flavor components to the physical point. We furthermore gradually
change the hopping parameter of the heaviest quark from strange to charm to
study how the properties of the $\Lambda$ baryons evolve as a function of the
heavy quark mass. It is found that the baryon energy levels increase almost
linearly with the quark mass. Meanwhile, the flavor structure of most of the
states remains stable, with the exception of the lowest $\frac{1}{2}^{-}$
state, which changes from a flavor singlet $\Lambda$ to a $\Lambda_c$ state
with singlet and octet components of comparable size. Finally, we discuss
whether our findings can be interpreted with the help of a simple quark model
and find that the negative-parity $\Lambda_c$ states can be naturally explained
as diquark excitations of the light $u$ and $d$ quarks. On the other hand, the
quark-model picture does not appear to be adequate for the negative-parity
$\Lambda$ states, suggesting the importance of other degrees of freedom to
describe them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03908</id><created>2016-09-13</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dorn</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venturini</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alibert</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helled</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rivoldini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A generalized bayesian inference method for constraining the interiors
  of super Earths and sub-Neptunes</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Astronomy &amp; Astrophysics, 597, A37, 17 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 597, A37 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628708</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim to present a generalized Bayesian inference method for constraining
interiors of super Earths and sub-Neptunes. Our methodology succeeds in
quantifying the degeneracy and correlation of structural parameters for high
dimensional parameter spaces. Specifically, we identify what constraints can be
placed on composition and thickness of core, mantle, ice, ocean, and
atmospheric layers given observations of mass, radius, and bulk refractory
abundance constraints (Fe, Mg, Si) from observations of the host star's
photospheric composition. We employed a full probabilistic Bayesian inference
analysis that formally accounts for observational and model uncertainties.
Using a Markov chain Monte Carlo technique, we computed joint and marginal
posterior probability distributions for all structural parameters of interest.
We included state-of-the-art structural models based on self-consistent
thermodynamics of core, mantle, high-pressure ice, and liquid water.
Furthermore, we tested and compared two different atmospheric models that are
tailored for modeling thick and thin atmospheres, respectively. First, we
validate our method against Neptune. Second, we apply it to synthetic
exoplanets of fixed mass and determine the effect on interior structure and
composition when (1) radius, (2) atmospheric model, (3) data uncertainties, (4)
semi-major axes, (5) atmospheric composition (i.e., a priori assumption of
enriched envelopes versus pure H/He envelopes), and (6) prior distributions are
varied. Our main conclusions are: [...]
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06887</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lalak</keyname><forenames>Zygmunt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakonieczny</keyname><forenames>&#x141;ukasz</forenames></author></authors><title>Darkflation -- one scalar to rule them all?</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 6 figures, references expanded, version accepted for
  publication in the Physics of the Dark Universe</comments><doi>10.1016/j.dark.2017.01.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of explaining both inflationary and dark matter physics in the
framework of a minimal extension of the Standard Model was investigated. To
this end, the Standard Model completed by a real scalar singlet playing a role
of the dark matter candidate has been considered. We assumed both the dark
matter field and the Higgs doublet to be nonminimally coupled to gravity. Using
quantum field theory in curved spacetime we derived an effective action for the
inflationary period and analyzed its consequences. In this approach, after
integrating out both dark matter and Standard Model sectors we obtained the
effective action expressed purely in terms of the gravitational field. We paid
special attention to determination, by explicit calculations, of the form of
coefficients controlling the higher-order in curvature gravitational terms.
Their connection to the Standard Model coupling constants has been discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06903</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karukes</keyname><forenames>Ekaterina V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salucci</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>The universal rotation curve of dwarf disk galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>25 pages, 17 figures. Updated to match published version</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 2017, 465, p4703-4722</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the concept of the spiral rotation curves universality to investigate
the luminous and dark matter properties of the dwarf disc galaxies in the local
volume (size $\sim11$ Mpc). Our sample includes 36 objects with rotation curves
carefully selected from the literature. We find that, despite the large
variations of our sample in luminosities ($\sim$ 2 of dex), the rotation curves
in specifically normalized units, look all alike and lead to the lower-mass
version of the universal rotation curve of spiral galaxies found in Persic et
al. We mass model the double normalized universal rotation curve
$V(R/R_{opt})/V_{opt}$ of dwarf disc galaxies: the results show that these
systems are totally dominated by dark matter whose density shows a core size
between 2 and 3 stellar disc scale lengths. Similar to galaxies of different
Hubble types and luminosities, the core radius $r_0$ and the central density
$\rho_0$ of the dark matter halo of these objects are related by $ \rho_0 r_0
\sim 100\hspace{0.1cm} \mathrm{M_\odot pc^{-2}}$. The structural properties of
the dark and luminous matter emerge very well correlated. In addition, to
describe these relations, we need to introduce a new parameter, measuring the
compactness of light distribution of a (dwarf) disc galaxy. These structural
properties also indicate that there is no evidence of abrupt decline at the
faint end of the baryonic to halo mass relation. Finally, we find that the
distributions of the stellar disc and its dark matter halo are closely related.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07230</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kurumaji</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujioka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shishikura</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishiwata</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnon resonance in a collinear spin state of a polar
  antiferromagnet Fe2Mo3O8</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 020405(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.020405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic excitations are investigated for a hexagonal polar magnet Fe2Mo3O8
by terahertz spectroscopy. We observed magnon modes including an electric-field
active magnon, electromagnon, in the collinear antiferromagnetic phase with
spins parallel to the c axis. We unravel the nature of these excitations by
investigating the correlation between the evolution of the mode profile and the
magnetic transition from antiferromagnetic to ferrimagnetic order induced by
magnetic field or Zn-doping. We propose that the observed electromagnon mode
involves the collective precession of the spins with oscillating in-plane
electric polarization through the mechanism of the linear magnetoelectric
effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09418</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09418</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burridge</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnacik</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Infrequent social interaction can accelerate the spread of a persuasive
  idea</title><categories>nlin.AO physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062319 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062319</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spread of a persuasive new idea through a population of
continuous-time random walkers in one dimension. The idea spreads via social
gatherings involving groups of nearby walkers who act according to a biased
&quot;majority rule&quot;: After each gathering, the group takes on the new idea if more
than a critical fraction $\frac{1-\varepsilon}{2} &lt; \frac{1}{2}$ of them
already hold it; otherwise they all reject it. The boundary of a domain where
the new idea has taken hold expands as a traveling wave in the density of new
idea holders. Our walkers move by L\'{e}vy motion, and we compute the wave
velocity analytically as a function of the frequency of social gatherings and
the exponent of the jump distribution. When this distribution is sufficiently
heavy tailed, then, counter to intuition, the idea can propagate faster if
social gatherings are held less frequently. When jumps are truncated, a
critical gathering frequency can emerge which maximizes propagation velocity.
We explore our model by simulation, confirming our analytical results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03352</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03352</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Midtgaard</keyname><forenames>Jonatan Melk&#xe6;r</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Zhigang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruun</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological superfluidity of lattice fermions inside a Bose-Einstein
  condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063631</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the phase diagram of identical fermions in a 2-dimensional (2D)
lattice immersed in a 3D Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC). The fermions exchange
density fluctuations in the BEC, which gives rise to an attractive induced
interaction. The resulting zero temperature phase diagram exhibits topological
$p_x+ip_y$ superfluid phases as well as a phase separation region. We show how
to use the flexibility of the Bose-Fermi mixture to tune the induced
interaction, so that it maximises the pairing between nearest neighbour sites,
whereas phase separation originating from long range interactions is
suppressed. Finally, we calculate the Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless (BKT)
critical temperature of the topological superfluid in the lattice and discuss
experimental realisations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05052</id><created>2016-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Uzunov</keyname><forenames>Dimo I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical study of anisotropic layered antiferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Report at the National Congress in Physics (29 Sept - 3 Oct 2016,
  Sofia, Bulgaria)</comments><journal-ref>Bulg. J. Phys. 43 (2016) 311</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop the field theory of antiferromagnets to layered structures on BCT
crystal lattices with nearest-neibour and next-nearest-neighbour ferro- and/or
antiferromagnetic interactions. For this aim the field theoretical counterpart
of a lattice Heisenberg model is derived by standard theoretical methods:
Hubbard-Stratonovich transformation and a generalized mean-field approach. We
shown that the inter-layer interactions are a pure thermal fluctuation effect
whereas the ground state is characterized by a perfect in-layer
antiferromagnetic order and a lack of inter-layer coupling. This is a
demonstration of 2D-3D dimensional crossover which is supposed to occur in real
antiferromagnets, for example, in the spin-dimer antiferromagnet BaCuSi2O6.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05584</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Junya</forenames></author></authors><title>Branes and integrable lattice models</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages. Invited review article for Modern Physics Letters A. v2:
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A 32 (2017) 1730003</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317300038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a brief review of my work on the correspondence between
four-dimensional $\mathcal{N} = 1$ supersymmetric field theories realized by
brane tilings and two-dimensional integrable lattice models. I explain how to
construct integrable lattice models from extended operators in partially
topological quantum field theories, and elucidate the correspondence as an
application of this construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05816</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schomerus</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author></authors><title>Random matrix approaches to open quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Lecture notes for the Les Houches Summer School &quot;Stochastic Processes
  and Random Matrices&quot; held in July 2015. v2: Reformatted and slightly revised,
  35 pages and 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Over the past decades, a great body of theoretical and mathematical work has
been devoted to random-matrix descriptions of open quantum systems. In these
notes, based on lectures delivered at the Les Houches Summer School &quot;Stochastic
Processes and Random Matrices&quot; in July 2015, we review the physical origins and
mathematical structures of the underlying models, and collect key predictions
which give insight into the typical system behaviour. In particular, we aim to
give an idea how the different features are interlinked. The notes mainly focus
on elastic scattering but also include a short detour to interacting systems,
which we motivate by the overarching question of ergodicity. The first chapters
introduce general notions from random matrix theory, such as the ten
universality classes and ensembles of hermitian, unitary, positive-definite and
non-hermitian matrices. We then review microscopic scattering models that form
the basis for statistical descriptions, and consider signatures of random
scattering in decay, dynamics and transport. The last chapter briefly touches
on Anderson localization and localization in interacting systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07518</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>Rafael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Supriya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saridakis</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abreu</keyname><forenames>Everton M. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>New observational constraints on $f(R)$ gravity from cosmic chronometers</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures, 6 Tables, version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1701 (2017) no.01, 005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/01/005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the recently released cosmic chronometer data and the latest measured
value of the local Hubble parameter, combined with the latest joint light
curves of Supernovae Type Ia, and Baryon Acoustic Oscillation distance
measurements, in order to impose constraints on the viable and most used $f(R)$
gravity models. We consider four $f(R)$ models, namely the Hu-Sawicki, the
Starobinsky, the Tsujikawa, and the exponential one, and we parametrize them
introducing a distortion parameter $b$ that quantifies the deviation from
$\Lambda$CDM cosmology. Our analysis reveals that a small but non-zero
deviation from $\Lambda$CDM cosmology is slightly favored, with the
corresponding fittings exhibiting very efficient $AIC$ and $BIC$ Information
Criteria values. Clearly, $f(R)$ gravity is consistent with observations, and
it can serve as a candidate for modified gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08504</id><created>2016-10-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Xuheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treu</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suyu</keyname><forenames>Sherry H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Geoff C. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auger</keyname><forenames>Matthew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>Philip J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agnello</keyname><forenames>Adriano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Courbin</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nierenberg</keyname><forenames>Anna M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusu</keyname><forenames>Cristian E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sluse</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonnenfeld</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Kenneth C.</forenames></author></authors><title>H0LiCOW VI. Testing the fidelity of lensed quasar host galaxy
  reconstruction</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 13 figures. Revised version after submitted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (March 11, 2017) 465 (4): 4634-4649</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The empirical correlation between the mass of a super-massive black hole
(MBH) and its host galaxy properties is widely considered to be evidence of
their co-evolution. A powerful way to test the co-evolution scenario and learn
about the feedback processes linking galaxies and nuclear activity is to
measure these correlations as a function of redshift. Unfortunately, currently
MBH can only be estimated in active galaxies at cosmological distances. At
these distances, bright active galactic nuclei (AGN) can outshine the host
galaxy, making it extremely difficult to measure the host's luminosity.
Strongly lensed AGNs provide in principle a great opportunity to improve the
sensitivity and accuracy of the host galaxy luminosity measurements as the host
galaxy is magnified and more easily separated from the point source, provided
the lens model is sufficiently accurate. In order to measure the MBH-L
correlation with strong lensing, it is necessary to ensure that the lens
modelling is accurate, and that the host galaxy luminosity can be recovered to
at least a precision and accuracy better than that of the typical MBH
measurement. We carry out extensive and realistic simulations of deep Hubble
Space Telescope observations of lensed AGNs obtained by our collaboration. We
show that the host galaxy luminosity can be recovered with better accuracy and
precision than the typical uncertainty on MBH(~ 0.5 dex) for hosts as faint as
2-4 magnitudes dimmer than the AGN itself. Our simulations will be used to
estimate bias and uncertainties on the actual measurements to be presented in a
future paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08626</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Guterding</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeschke</keyname><forenames>Harald O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glasbrenner</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bascones</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>Roser</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-trivial role of interlayer cation states in iron-based
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 017204 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.017204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unconventional superconductivity in iron pnictides and chalcogenides has been
suggested to be controlled by the interplay of low-energy antiferromagnetic
spin fluctuations and the particular topology of the Fermi surface in these
materials. Based on this premise, one would also expect the large class of
isostructural and isoelectronic iron germanide compounds to be good
superconductors. As a matter of fact, they, however, superconduct at very low
temperatures or not at all. In this work we establish that superconductivity in
iron germanides is suppressed by strong ferromagnetic tendencies, which
surprisingly do not originate from changes in bond-angles or -distances with
respect to iron pnictides and chalcogenides, but are due to changes in the
electronic structure in a wide range of energies happening upon substitution of
atom species (As by Ge and the corresponding spacer cations). Our results
indicate that superconductivity in iron-based materials may not always be fully
understood based on $d$ or $dp$ model Hamiltonians only.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08661</id><created>2016-10-27</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brambleby</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goddard</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singleton</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaime</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lancaster</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wosnitza</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Topping</keyname><forenames>C. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carreiro</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>H. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manson</keyname><forenames>Z. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manson</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Adiabatic physics of an exchange-coupled spin-dimer system:
  magnetocaloric effect, zero-point fluctuations, and possible two-dimensional
  universal behavior</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.024404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the magnetic and thermal properties of the bosonic-superfluid
phase in a spin-dimer network using both quasistatic and rapidly-changing
pulsed magnetic fields. The entropy derived from a heat-capacity study reveals
that the pulsed-field measurements are strongly adiabatic in nature and are
responsible for the onset of a significant magnetocaloric effect (MCE). In
contrast to previous predictions we show that the MCE is not just confined to
the critical regions, but occurs for all fields greater than zero at
sufficiently low temperatures. We explain the MCE using a model of the thermal
occupation of exchange-coupled dimer spin-states and highlight that failure to
take this effect into account inevitably leads to incorrect interpretations of
experimental results. In addition, the heat capacity in our material is
suggestive of an extraordinary contribution from zero-point fluctuations and
appears to indicate universal behavior with different critical exponents at the
two field-induced critical points. The data are consistent with a
two-dimensional nature of spin excitations in the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09913</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09913</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-01-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leon</keyname><forenames>Zen-chen</forenames></author></authors><title>From Special Relativity to embedded generators in Cartan subalgebras of
  rank-4 spin algebras</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 0 figures</comments><report-no>7-2-3 $e\phi\ 002$</report-no><msc-class>06F99, 52C35</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Starting by revisiting Special Relativity, here we provide a reliable
characterization of the entire 4-dimensional fundamental structures in our
reality where the frame of discrete tangent space of $F^{1,3}$ is quantized to
massless, zero-momentum particles distributing on a 4-dimensional regular base
$\{\mathbb{N}\cdot c_\alpha\}$ with metric
$B(c_\alpha,c_\beta)=\delta_{\alpha\beta}=\text{diag}(+,+,+,+)$, determining
the constant $c$ locally, as well as instant characterizations on all particles
moving along the proper time of $\tau\in\mathbb{N}$. Together with
$\phi_\text{IV}$ on 1-dimensional space $\{\mathbb{N}\cdot c_4\}$ of
$B(c_\alpha,c_4)=0$, the quantized particles of tangent frame are split
anti-symmetrically from roots $\gamma_{\alpha4}$ in a rank-4 Lie algebra with
exactly $c_\alpha$ the generators of its Cartan subalgebra. As with the
combined frame-Higgs valued in $\gamma_{\alpha4}$, every massive particle is
related to some split frame and Higgs to obtain its unique quantized relative
3-velocity, 4-velocity, and rest mass under the restriction of Pauli Exclusion
Principle at each $\tau$. We calculated the domains $S_i\subset F$ and
$S_0\subset F_\geq$ in $F_\geq\oplus F^3$ the spacetime in which a massive
particle $\mathtt{p}$ evolves with $\{x^\alpha\}$ of $x^\alpha\in S_\alpha$ the
coordinate its Center-of-Mass under an eligible observation that $\vert
F\vert=\vert F_\geq\vert=\aleph_0&lt;\vert\mathbb{R}\vert$, available for
post-Newtonian approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02079</id><created>2016-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Khrapai</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagaev</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Current noise generated by spin imbalance in presence of spin relaxation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Pis'ma v ZhETF, vol. 105, iss. 1, pp. 21 - 22 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364017010015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate current (shot) noise in a metallic diffusive conductor generated
by spin imbalance in the absence of a net electric current. This situation is
modeled in an idealized three-terminal setup with two biased ferromagnetic
leads (F-leads) and one normal lead (N-lead). Parallel magnetization of the
F-leads gives rise in spin-imbalance and finite shot noise at the N-lead.
Finite spin relaxation results in an increase of the shot noise, which depends
on the ratio of the length of the conductor ($L$) and the spin relaxation
length ($l_s$). For $L\gg l_s$ the shot noise increases by a factor of two and
coincides with the case of the anti-parallel magnetization of the F-leads.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06859</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2016-12-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thoma</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnauber</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gschrey</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulze</keyname><forenames>Jan-Hindrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strittmatter</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodt</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heindel</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reitzenstein</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-photon interference from remote deterministic quantum dot
  microlenses</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 110, 011104 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on two-photon interference (TPI) experiments using remote
deterministic single-photon sources. Employing 3D in-situ electron-beam
lithography, we fabricate quantum-light sources at specific target wavelengths
by integrating pre-selected semiconductor quantum dots within monolithic
microlenses. The individual single-photon sources show TPI visibilities of 49%
and 22%, respectively, under pulsed p-shell excitation at 80 MHz. For the
mutual TPI of the remote sources, we observe an uncorrected visibility of 29%,
in quantitative agreement with the pure dephasing of the individual sources.
Due to its efficient photon extraction within a broad spectral range (&gt; 20 nm),
our microlens-based approach is predestinated for future entanglement swapping
experiments utilizing entangled photon pairs emitted by distant
biexciton-exciton radiative cascades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07301</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07301</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duclut</keyname><forenames>Charlie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delamotte</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency regulators for the nonperturbative renormalization group: A
  general study and the model A as a benchmark</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 012107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.012107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the necessary conditions for implementing a regulator that depends
on both momentum and frequency in the nonperturbative renormalization group
flow equations of out-of-equilibrium statistical systems. We consider model A
as a benchmark and compute its dynamical critical exponent $z$. This allows us
to show that frequency regulators compatible with causality and the
fluctuation-dissipation theorem can be devised. We show that when the Principle
of Minimal Sensitivity (PMS) is employed to optimize the critical exponents
$\eta$, $\nu$ and $z$, the use of frequency regulators becomes necessary to
make the PMS a self-consistent criterion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03439</id><created>2016-12-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Falaye</keyname><forenames>Babatunde James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Guo-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adepoju</keyname><forenames>Adenike Grace</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liman</keyname><forenames>Muhammed S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyewumi</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>An electron of helium atom under a high-intensity laser field</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.plasm-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>To appear in Laser Phys. 2017. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1610.01120</comments><journal-ref>Laser Phys. 27 (2017) 026004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1555-6611/aa5338</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We scrutinize the behavior of eigenvalues of an electron of Helium atom as it
interacts with electric field directed along $z$-axis and exposed to linearly
polarized intense laser field radiation. In order to achieve this, we freeze
one electron of the helium atom at its ionic ground state and the motion of the
second electron in the ion core is treated via a more general case of screened
Coulomb potential model. Using the Kramers-Henneberger (KH) unitary
transformation, which is semiclassical counterpart of the Block-Nordsieck
transformation in the quantized field formalism, the squared vector potential
that appears in the equation of motion is eliminated and the resultant equation
is expressed in KH frame. Within this frame, the resulting potential and the
corresponding wave function have been expanded in Fourier series and using
Ehlotzkys approximation, we obtain a laser-dressed potential to simulate
intense laser field. By fitting the more general case of screened Coulomb
potential model into the laser-dressed potential, and then expanding it in
Taylor series up to $\mathcal{O}(r^4,\alpha_0^9)$, we obtain the solution
(eigenvalues and wave function) of an electron of Helium atom under the
influence of external electric field and high-intensity laser field, within the
framework of perturbation theory formalism. We found that the variation in
frequency of laser radiation has no effect on the eigenvalues of an electron of
helium for a particular electric field intensity directed along $z$-axis. Also,
for a very strong external electric field and an infinitesimal screening
parameter, the system is strongly bound. This work has potential application in
the areas of atomic and molecular processes in external fields including
interactions with strong fields and short pulses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05138</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pourtsidou</keyname><forenames>Alkistis</forenames></author></authors><title>Synergistic tests of inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 tables, 3 figures; minor edits, version submitted in
  Physical Review D</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possibility of utilising 21cm intensity mapping, optical
galaxy, and Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB) surveys to constrain the power
spectrum of primordial fluctuations predicted by single-field slow-roll
inflation models. Implementing a Fisher forecast analysis, we derive
constraints on the spectral tilt parameter $n_{\rm s}$ and its first and second
runnings $(\alpha_{\rm s},\beta_{\rm s})$. We show that 21cm intensity mapping
surveys with instruments like the Square Kilometre Array, CHIME, and HIRAX, can
be powerful probes of the primordial features. We combine our forecasts with
the ones derived for a COrE-like CMB survey, as well as for a Stage IV optical
galaxy survey similar to Euclid. The synergies between different surveys can be
exploited to rule out a large fraction of the available inflationary models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06031</id><created>2016-12-18</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deur</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nucleon spin structure studies at Jefferson Lab</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Contribution to the proceedings of Spin16 (22nd International Spin
  Symposium). 6 pages, 3 figures (V2: corrected an erroneous reference)</comments><report-no>JLAB-PHY-17-2392</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the low and moderate Q^2 nucleon spin structure measurements
done at Jefferson Lab, examining specifically the inclusive program. We discuss
what the data teach us about quark confinement and the emergence of the
effective hadronic degrees of freedom from the fundamental partonic ones. We
show how this experimental program has reached its goal by providing a precise
mapping at low, intermediate and moderately high Q^2 which has followed in many
advances, e.g., with Chiral Perturbation Theory. Another example of a recent
advance imputable to the JLab spin data is the improved understanding of
\alpha_s at low energy, which allowed Light-Front Holographic QCD, an
approximation to non-perturbative QCD, to derive the hadron spectrum from
\Lambda_s.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06583</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Holmvall</keyname><forenames>Patric</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;ster</keyname><forenames>Ulli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinz</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsson</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Collinear cluster tri-partition: Kinematics constraints and stability of
  collinearity</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>20 pages, 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 014602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.014602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new mode of nuclear fission has been proposed by the FOBOS collaboration,
called Collinear Cluster Tri-partition (CCT), suggesting that three heavy
fission fragments can be emitted perfectly collinearly in low-energy fission.
It is surprising that CCT escaped observation for so long given the relatively
high reported yield, of roughly 0.5% relative to binary fission. These claims
call for an independent verification with a different experimental technique.
Verification experiments based on direct observation of CCT fragments with
fission fragment spectrometers require guidance with respect to the allowed
kinetic energy range, which we present in this paper. We discuss corresponding
model calculations which, if CCT is found in such verification experiments,
could indicate how the breakups proceed. We also study the intrinsic stability
of collinearity. Three different decay models are used, which span together the
timescales of three-body fission. These models are used to calculate the
possible kinetic energy ranges of CCT fragments in 235U(n,f) and 252Cf(sf). We
use semi-classical trajectory calculations with a Monte-Carlo method to study
the intrinsic stability of collinearity. CCT has a high net Q-value, but in a
sequential decay, the intermediate steps are energetically and geometrically
unfavorable or even forbidden. Moreover, perfect collinearity is extremely
unstable, and broken by the slightest perturbation. According to our results,
the central fragment would be very difficult to detect due to its low kinetic
energy, raising the question of why previous experiments could not detect a
missing-mass signature corresponding to CCT. We find that a realization of CCT
would require an unphysical fine-tuning of the initial conditions. Our results
enable independent experimental verification and encourage further critical
theoretical studies of CCT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06653</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ishikawa</keyname><forenames>Souichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Monopole transition strength function of ${}^{12}$C in three-$\alpha$
  model</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.061603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy level structure of ${}^{12}$C nucleus at a few MeV above the
three-$\alpha$ threshold is still unsatisfactory known. For instance, most
microscopic calculations predicted that there exist one $0^+$-state in this
energy region besides the well known Hoyle state, while some experimental and
theoretical studies show the existing of two $0^+$-states.
  In this paper, I will take a three-$\alpha$-boson (3$\alpha$) model for bound
and continuum states in ${}^{12}$C, and study a transition process from the
${}^{12}$C($0_1^+$) ground state to 3$\alpha$ $0^+$ continuum states by the
electric monopole ($E0$) operator. The strength distribution of the process
will be calculated as a function of $3\alpha$ energy using the Faddeev
three-body theory. The Hamiltonian for the $3\alpha$ system consists of two-
and three-$\alpha$ potentials, and some three-$\alpha$ potentials with
different range parameters will be examined.
  Results of the strength function show a double-peaked bump at low energy
region, which can be considered as two $0^+$-states. The peak at higher energy
may originate from a 3$\alpha$ resonant state. However, it is unlikely that the
peak at the lower energy is related to a resonant state, which suggests that it
may be due to so called &quot;ghost anomaly&quot;. Distributions of decaying particles
are also calculated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07046</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jafari</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johannesson</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Loschmidt Echo Revivals: Critical and Noncritical</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures (including Supplemental Material); to appear in
  Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 015701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.015701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum phase transition is generally thought to imprint distinctive
characteristics on the nonequilibrium dynamics of a closed quantum system.
Specifically, the Loschmidt echo after a sudden quench to a quantum critical
point $-$ measuring the time dependence of the overlap between initial and
time-evolved states $-$ is expected to exhibit an accelerated relaxation
followed by periodic revivals. We here introduce a new exactly solvable model,
the extended Su-Schrieffer-Heeger model, the Loschmidt echo of which provides a
counterexample. A parallell analysis of the quench dynamics of the three-site
spin-interacting $XY$ model allows us to pinpoint the conditions under which a
periodic Loschmidt revival actually appears
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07232</id><created>2016-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Allmendinger</keyname><forenames>Pitt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deiglmayr</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;veler</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schullian</keyname><forenames>Otto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkt</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of enhanced rate coefficients in the H$_2^+$ + H$_2$
  $\rightarrow$ H$_3^+$ + H reaction at low collision energies</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145(24), 244316 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4972130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy dependence of the rate coefficient of the H$_2^+\ + {\rm H}_2
\rightarrow {\rm H}_3^+ + {\rm H}$ reaction has been measured in the range of
collision energies between $k_\mathrm{B}\cdot 10$ K and $k_\mathrm{B}\cdot 300$
mK. A clear deviation of the rate coefficient from the value expected on the
basis of the classical Langevin-capture behavior has been observed at collision
energies below $k_\mathrm{B}\cdot 1$ K, which is attributed to the joint
effects of the ion-quadrupole and Coriolis interactions in collisions involving
ortho-H$_2$ molecules in the $j = 1$ rotational level, which make up 75% of the
population of the neutral H$_2$ molecules in the experiments. The experimental
results are compared to very recent predictions by Dashevskaya, Litvin, Nikitin
and Troe (J. Chem. Phys., in press), with which they are in agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08325</id><created>2016-12-25</created><updated>2017-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kohno</keyname><forenames>Wataru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueki</keyname><forenames>Hikaru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kita</keyname><forenames>Takafumi</forenames></author></authors><title>Hall Effect in the Vortex Lattice of d-Wave Superconductors with
  Anisotropic Fermi surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Physical Society of Japan 86, 023702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.023702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the basis of the augmented quasiclassical theory of superconductivity with
the Lorentz force, we study the mag- netic field dependence of the charge
distribution due to the Lorentz force in a d-wave vortex lattice with
anisotropic Fermi surfaces. Owing to the competition between the energy-gap and
Fermi surface anisotropies, the charge profile in the vortex lattice changes
dramatically with increasing magnetic field because of the overlaps of each
nearest vortex-core charge. In addition, the accumulated charge in the core
region may reverse its sign as a function of magnetic field. This strong field
dependence of the vortex-core charge cannot be observed in the model with an
isotropic Fermi surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00418</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00418</id><created>2017-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Wei-jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Zhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yu-xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying the QCD Phase Transitions via the Gravitational Wave
  Frequency</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures and 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nonradial oscillations of newly born neutron stars (NSs)
and strange quark stars (SQSs). This is done with the relativistic nuclear
field theory with hyperon degrees of freedom employed to describe the equation
of state for the stellar matter in NSs, and with both the MIT bag model and the
Nambu--Jona-Lasinio model adopted to construct the configurations of the SQSs.
We find that the gravitational-mode ($g$-mode) eigenfrequencies of newly born
SQSs are about one order of magnitude lower than those of NSs, which is
independent of models implemented to describe the equation of state for the
strange quark matter. Meanwhile the eigenfrequencies of the other modes of
nonradial oscillations, e.g., fundamental ($f$)- and pressure ($p$)-modes, are
much larger than those of the $g$-mode. In the light of the first direct
observation of gravitational waves, it is promising to employ the gravitational
waves to identify the QCD phase transition in high density strong interaction
matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.00978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.00978</id><created>2017-01-04</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jaouadi</keyname><forenames>Amine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ndong</keyname><forenames>Mamadou</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient STIRAP-like scheme for coherent population transfer by
  revisited optimal control theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that Optimal Control Theory (OCT) with a state-dependent
constraint which depends on the state of the system at each instant can
reproduce the famous counterintuitive mechanism of Stimulated Raman adiabatic
passage (STIRAP). We examine this behavior in a {\Lambda}-type three-level
system and we show that could be applied for sequentially coupled many-level
systems. We study the robustness of the two methods with respect to pulse
fluctuations and the decays. We show that new OCT formulation appears to be
more robust than STIRAP when a perturbation is introduced in the pulses. Such
method is of great use for systems involving coherence loss such as molecular
systems with dissociation or ionization limits. It also may find potential
applications in the control of chemical reactions, quantum optics, and quantum
information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01143</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>D'Agostini</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author></authors><title>More lessons from the six box toy experiment</title><categories>math.HO math.PR physics.data-an</categories><comments>Addendum to arXiv:1612.05292, 18 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following a paper in which the fundamental aspects of probabilistic inference
were introduced by means of a toy experiment, details of the analysis of
simulated long sequences of extractions are shown here. In fact, the striking
performance of probability-based inference and forecasting, compared to those
obtained by simple `rules', might impress those practitioners who are usually
underwhelmed by the philosophical foundation of the different methods. The
analysis of the sequences also shows how the smallness of the probability of
what has been actually observed, given the hypotheses of interest, is
irrelevant for the purpose of inference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01274</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-01-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kudelka</keyname><forenames>Milos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochodkova</keyname><forenames>Eliska</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zehnalova</keyname><forenames>Sarka</forenames></author></authors><title>Around Average Behavior: 3-lambda Network Model</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Fix of typo in title</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The analysis of networks affects the research of many real phenomena. The
complex network structure can be viewed as a network's state at the time of the
analysis or as a result of the process through which the network arises.
Research activities focus on both and, thanks to them, we know not only many
measurable properties of networks but also the essence of some phenomena that
occur during the evolution of networks. One typical research area is the
analysis of co-authorship networks and their evolution. In our paper, the
analysis of one real-world co-authorship network and inspiration from existing
models form the basis of the hypothesis from which we derive new 3-lambda
network model. This hypothesis works with the assumption that regular behavior
of nodes revolves around an average. However, some anomalies may occur. The
3-lambda model is stochastic and uses the three parameters associated with the
average behavior of the nodes. The growth of the network based on this model
assumes that one step of the growth is an interaction in which both new and
existing nodes are participating. In the paper we present the results of the
analysis of a co-authorship network and formulate a hypothesis and a model
based on this hypothesis. Later in the paper, we examine the outputs from the
network generator based on the 3-lambda model and show that generated networks
have characteristics known from the environment of real-world networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01431</id><created>2017-01-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolokolova</keyname><forenames>Ludmilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Aigen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneda</keyname><forenames>Hidehiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augereau</keyname><forenames>Cornelia J&#xe4;ger Jean-Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic dust VIII</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Planetary and Space Science, 133, 1-6, November 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2016.09.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is an editorial to the special issue on Cosmic Dust VIII.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01434</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Dahmen</keyname><forenames>Silvio R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazzan</keyname><forenames>A. L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramsch</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Community Detection in the Network of German Princes in 1225: a Case
  Study</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many social networks exhibit some underlying community structure. In
particular, in the context of historical research, clustering of different
groups into warring or friendly factions can lead to a better understanding of
how conflicts may arise, and whether they could be avoided or not. In this work
we study the crisis that started in 1225 when the Emperor of the Holy Roman
Empire, Frederick II and his son Henry VII got into a conflict which almost led
to the rupture and dissolution of the Empire. We use a spin-glass-based
community detection algorithm to see how good this method is in detecting this
rift and compare the results with an analysis performed by one of the authors
(Gramsch) using standard social balance theory applied to History.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01441</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Oehm</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thies</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kroupa</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on the dynamical evolution of the galaxy group M81</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 14 figures, accepted for publication in the MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3381</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to the standard model of cosmology, galaxies are embedded in dark
matter halos which are made of particles beyond the standard model of particle
physics, thus extending the mass and the size of the visible baryonic matter by
typically two orders of magnitude. The observed gas distribution throughout the
nearby M81 group of galaxies shows evidence for past significant galaxy--galaxy
interactions but without a merger having occurred. This group is here studied
for possible dynamical solutions within the dark-matter standard model. In
order to cover a comprehensive set of initial conditions, the inner three core
members M81, M82 and NGC3077 are treated as a three-body model based on
Navarro-Frenk-White profiles. The possible orbits of these galaxies are
examined statistically taking into account dynamical friction. Long living,
non-merging initial constellations which allow multiple galaxy-galaxy
encounters comprise unbound galaxies only, which are arriving from a far
distance and happen to simultaneously encounter each other within the recent
500 Myr. Our results are derived by the employment of two separate and
independent statistical methods, namely a Markov chain Monte Carlo method and
the genetic algorithm using the SAP system environment. The conclusions reached
are confirmed by high-resolution simulations of live self-consistent systems
(N-body calculations). Given the observed positions of the three galaxies the
solutions found comprise predictions for their proper motions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01450</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Guerreschi</keyname><forenames>Gian Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smelyanskiy</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Practical optimization for hybrid quantum-classical algorithms</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel class of hybrid quantum-classical algorithms based on the variational
approach have recently emerged from separate proposals addressing, for example,
quantum chemistry and combinatorial problems. These algorithms provide an
approximate solution to the problem at hand by encoding it in the state of a
quantum computer. The operations used to prepare the state are not a priori
fixed but, quite the opposite, are subjected to a classical optimization
procedure that modifies the quantum gates and improves the quality of the
approximate solution. While the quantum hardware determines the size of the
problem and what states are achievable (limited, respectively, by the number of
qubits and by the kind and number of possible quantum gates), it is the
classical optimization procedure that determines the way in which the quantum
states are explored and whether the best available solution is actually
reached. In addition, the quantities required in the optimization, for example
the objective function itself, have to be estimated with finite precision in
any experimental implementation. While it is desirable to have very precise
estimates, this comes at the cost of repeating the state preparation and
measurement multiple times. Here we analyze the competing requirements of high
precision and low number of repetitions and study how the overall performance
of the variational algorithm is affected by the precision level and the choice
of the optimization method. Finally, this study introduces quasi-Newton
optimization methods in the general context of hybrid variational algorithms
and presents quantitative results for the Quantum Approximate Optimization
Algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01451</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01451</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bottrell</keyname><forenames>Connor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torrey</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simard</keyname><forenames>Luc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ellison</keyname><forenames>Sara L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Galaxies in the Illustris simulation as seen by the Sloan Digital Sky
  Survey - I: Bulge+disc decompositions, methods, and biases</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS. 37 pages, 25 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an image-based method for comparing the structural properties of
galaxies produced in hydrodynamical simulations to real galaxies in the Sloan
Digital Sky Survey. The key feature of our work is the introduction of
extensive observational realism, such as object crowding, noise and viewing
angle, to the synthetic images of simulated galaxies, so that they can be
fairly compared to real galaxy catalogs. We apply our methodology to the
dust-free synthetic image catalog of galaxies from the Illustris simulation at
$z=0$, which are then fit with bulge+disc models to obtain morphological
parameters. In this first paper in a series, we detail our methods, quantify
observational biases, and present publicly available bulge+disc decomposition
catalogs. We find that our bulge+disc decompositions are largely robust to the
observational biases that affect decompositions of real galaxies. However, we
identify a significant population of galaxies (roughly 30\% of the full sample)
in Illustris that are prone to internal segmentation, leading to systematically
reduced flux estimates by up to a factor of 6, smaller half-light radii by up
to a factor of $\sim$ 2, and generally erroneous bulge-to-total fractions of
(B/T)=0.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01457</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Amit K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopalakrishnan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganguli</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified nonlocal rational continuum models developed from discrete
  atomistic equations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>43 pages, 11 figures, journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a unified nonlocal rational continuum enrichment technique is
presented for improving the dispersive characteristics of some well known
classical continuum equations on the basis of atomistic dispersion relations.
This type of enrichment can be useful in a wide range of mechanical problems
such as localization of strain and damage in many quasibrittle structures, size
effects in microscale elastoplasticity, and multiscale modeling of materials. A
novel technique of transforming a discrete differential expression into an
exact equivalent rational continuum derivative form is developed considering
the Taylor's series transformation of the continuous field variables and
traveling wave type of solutions for both the discrete and continuum field
variables. An exact equivalent continuum rod representation of the 1D harmonic
lattice with the non-nearest neighbor interactions is developed considering the
lattice details. Using similar enrichment technique in the variational
framework, other useful higher-order equations, namely nonlocal rational
Mindlin-Herrmann rod and nonlocal rational Timoshenko beam equations, are
developed to explore their nonlocal properties in general. Some analytical and
numerical studies on the high frequency dynamic behavior of these novel
nonlocal rational continuum models are presented with their comparison with the
atomistic solutions for the respective physical systems. These enriched
rational continuum equations have crucial use in studying high-frequency
dynamics of many nano-electro-mechanical sensors and devices, dynamics of
phononic metamaterials, and wave propagation in composite structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01463</id><created>2017-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyburska-P&#xfc;schel</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voyles</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sridharan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of small defect clusters in ion-irradiated 3C-SiC: combined
  cluster dynamics modeling and experimental study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 10 figures, journal</comments><journal-ref>Acta Materialia 125 (2017) 377-389</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2016.12.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Distribution of black spot defects and small clusters in 1 MeV krypton
irradiated 3C-SiC has been investigated using advanced scanning transmission
electron microscopy (STEM) and TEM. We find that two thirds of clusters smaller
than 1 nm identified in STEM are invisible in TEM images. For clusters that are
larger than 1 nm, STEM and TEM results match very well. A cluster dynamics
model has been developed for SiC to reveal processes that contribute to
evolution of defect clusters and validated against the (S)TEM results.
Simulations showed that a model based on established properties of point
defects (PDs) generation, reaction, clustering, and cluster dissociation, is
unable to predict black spot defects distribution consistent with STEM
observations. This failure suggests that additional phenomena not included in a
simple point-defect picture may contribute to radiation-induced evolution of
defect clusters in SiC and using our model we have determined the effects of a
number of these additional phenomena on cluster evolution. Using these
additional phenomena it is possible to fit parameters within physically
justifiable ranges that yield agreement between cluster distributions predicted
by simulations and those measured experimentally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01467</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Trotta</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames><affiliation>Imperial</affiliation></author></authors><title>Bayesian Methods in Cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM stat.ME</categories><comments>86 pages, 16 figures. Lecture notes for the 44th Saas Fee Advanced
  Course on Astronomy and Astrophysics, &quot;Cosmology with wide-field surveys&quot;
  (March 2014), to be published by Springer. Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  These notes aim at presenting an overview of Bayesian statistics, the
underlying concepts and application methodology that will be useful to
astronomers seeking to analyse and interpret a wide variety of data about the
Universe. The level starts from elementary notions, without assuming any
previous knowledge of statistical methods, and then progresses to more
advanced, research-level topics. After an introduction to the importance of
statistical inference for the physical sciences, elementary notions of
probability theory and inference are introduced and explained. Bayesian methods
are then presented, starting from the meaning of Bayes Theorem and its use as
inferential engine, including a discussion on priors and posterior
distributions. Numerical methods for generating samples from arbitrary
posteriors (including Markov Chain Monte Carlo and Nested Sampling) are then
covered. The last section deals with the topic of Bayesian model selection and
how it is used to assess the performance of models, and contrasts it with the
classical p-value approach. A series of exercises of various levels of
difficulty are designed to further the understanding of the theoretical
material, including fully worked out solutions for most of them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01490</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Shapovalova</keyname><forenames>Alla I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chavushyan</keyname><forenames>V. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Afanasiev</keyname><forenames>V. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ili&#x107;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovacevi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burenkov</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kollatschny</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiridonova</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valdes</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bochkarev</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patino-Alvarez</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrasco</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhdanova</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-term optical spectral monitoring of NGC 7469</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted in Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of the long-term (20-year period, from 1996 to 2015)
optical spectral monitoring of the Seyfert 1 galaxy NGC 7469. The variation in
the light-curves of the broad He II {\lambda}4686A H{\beta} and H{\alpha}
lines, and the continuum at 5100A and 6300A have been explored. The maximum of
activity was in 1998, and the variability in the continuum and lines seems to
have two periods of around 1200 and 2600 days, however these periodicities
should be taken with caution because of the red-noise. Beside these periods,
there are several short-term (1-5 days) flare-like events in the light-curves.
There are good correlations between the continuum fluxes and H{\alpha} and
H{\beta} line fluxes, but significantly smaller correlation between the He II
and continuum. We found that the time-lags between the continuum and broad
lines are different for H{\beta} (~20 l.d.) and H{\alpha} (~3 l.d.), and that
He II also has a smaller lag (~2-3 l.d.). The H{\alpha} and H{\beta} line
profiles show a slight red asymmetry, and the broad line profiles did not
changed in the 20-year period. Using the lags and widths of H{\alpha} and
H{\beta} we estimated the central black hole mass and found that it is
~(1-6)x$10^7 M_{\odot}$, which is in agreement with previous reverberation
estimates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01513</id><created>2016-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Chiavazzo</keyname><forenames>Eliodoro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coifman</keyname><forenames>Ronald R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Covino</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gear</keyname><forenames>C. William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Georgiou</keyname><forenames>Anastasia S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hummer</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>Ioannis G.</forenames></author></authors><title>iMapD: intrinsic Map Dynamics exploration for uncharted effective free
  energy landscapes</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe and implement iMapD, a computer-assisted approach for
accelerating the exploration of uncharted effective Free Energy Surfaces (FES),
and more generally for the extraction of coarse-grained, macroscopic
information from atomistic or stochastic (here Molecular Dynamics, MD)
simulations. The approach functionally links the MD simulator with nonlinear
manifold learning techniques. The added value comes from biasing the simulator
towards new, unexplored phase space regions by exploiting the smoothness of the
(gradually, as the exploration progresses) revealed intrinsic low-dimensional
geometry of the FES.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01517</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Tempone-Wiltshire</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnstone</keyname><forenames>Shaun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helmerson</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical vortex knots - one photon at a time</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Reports, 6, 24463-68 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Feynman described the double slit experiment as &quot;a phenomenon which is
impossible, absolutely impossible, to explain in any classical way and which
has in it the heart of quantum mechanics&quot;. The double slit experiment,
performed one photon at a time, dramatically demonstrates the particle-wave
duality of quantum objects by generating a fringe pattern corresponding to the
interference of light (a wave phenomenon) from two slits, even when there is
only one photon (a particle) at a time passing through the apparatus. The
particle-wave duality of light should also apply to complex three dimensional
optical fields formed by multi-path interference, however, this has not been
demonstrated. Here we observe particle-wave duality of a three dimensional
field by generating a trefoil optical vortex knot - one photon at a time. This
result demonstrates a fundamental physical principle, that particle-wave
duality implies interference in both space (between spatially distinct modes)
and time (through the complex evolution of the superposition of modes), and has
implications for topologically entangled single photon states, orbital angular
momentum multiplexing and topological quantum computing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01518</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Fuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical properties of electrochemical capacitance in disordered
  mesoscopic capacitors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 89, 245430 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.245430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically investigate the statistical properties of electrochemical
capacitance in disordered two-dimensional mesoscopic capacitors. Based on the
tight-binding Hamiltonian, the Green's function formalism is adopted to study
the average electrochemical capacitance, its fluctuation as well as the
distribution of capacitance of the disordered mesoscopic capacitors for three
different ensembles: orthogonal (symmetry index \beta=1), unitary (\beta=2),
and symplectic (\beta=4). It is found that the electrochemical capacitance in
the disordered systems exhibits universal behavior. In the case of single
conducting channel, the electrochemical capacitance follows a symmetric
Gaussian distribution at weak disorders as expected from the random matrix
theory. In the strongly disordered regime, the distribution is found to be a
sharply one-sided form with a nearly-constant tail in the large capacitance
region. This behavior is due to the existence of the necklace states in
disordered systems, which is characterized by the multi-resonance that gives
rise to a large density of states. In addition, it is found that the necklace
state also enhances the fluctuation of electrochemical capacitance in the case
of single conducting channel. When the number of conducting channels increases,
the influence of necklace states becomes less important. For large number of
conducting channels, the electrochemical capacitance fluctuation develops a
plateau region in the strongly disordered regime. The plateau value is
identified as universal electrochemical capacitance fluctuation, which is
independent of system parameters such as disorder strength, Fermi energy,
geometric capacitance, and system size. Importantly, the universal
electrochemical capacitance fluctuation is the same for all three ensembles,
suggesting a super-universal behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01519</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Fuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>Yanxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical study of parametric pumping current in mesoscopic systems in
  the presence of magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 84, 245323 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.84.245323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically study the parametric pumped current when magnetic field is
applied both in the adiabatic and non-adiabatic regimes. In particular, we
investigate the nature of pumped current for systems with resonance as well as
anti-resonance. It is found that in the adiabatic regime, the pumped current
changes sign across the sharp resonance with long lifetime while the
non-adiabatic pumped current at finite frequency does not. When the lifetime of
resonant level is short, the behaviors of adiabatic and non-adiabatic pumped
current are similar with sign changes. Our results show that at the energy
where complete transmission occurs the adiabatic pumped current is zero while
non-adiabatic pumped current is non-zero. Different from the resonant case,
both adiabatic and non-adiabatic pumped current are zero at anti-resonance with
complete reflection. We also investigate the pumped current when the other
system parameters such as magnetic field, pumped frequency, and pumping
potentials. Interesting behaviors are revealed. Finally, we study the symmetry
relation of pumped current for several systems with different spatial symmetry
upon reversal of magnetic field. Different from the previous theoretical
prediction, we find that a system with general inversion symmetry can pump out
a finite current in the adiabatic regime. At small magnetic field, the pumped
current has an approximate relation I(B) \approx I(-B) both in adiabatic and
non-adiabatic regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01520</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01520</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yunjin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yanfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Langhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Fuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Yadong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoinduced valley-polarized current of layered MoS2 by electric tuning</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 185202 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/18/185202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A photoinduced current of a layered MoS2-based transistor is studied from
first-principles. Under the illumination of circular polarized light, a
valley-polarized current is generated, which can be tuned by the gate voltage.
For monolayer MoS2, the valley-polarized spin-up (down) electron current at K
(K') points is induced by the right (left) circular polarized light. The valley
polarization is found to reach +1.0 (-1.0) for the valley current that carried
such a K (K') index. For bilayer MoS2, the spin-up (down) current can be
induced at both K and K' valleys by the right (left) circular light. In
contrast to monolayer MoS2, the photoinduced valley polarization shows
asymmetric behavior upon reversal of the gate voltage. Our results show that
the valley polarization of the photoinduced current can be modulated by the
circular polarized light and the gate voltage. All the results can be well
understood using a simple kp model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01521</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zhizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Fuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Valley Seebeck effect in gate tunable zigzag graphene nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 99,451-455 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2015.12.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose, for the first time, a valley Seebeck effect in gate tunable
zigzag graphene nanoribbons as a result of the interplay between thermal
gradient and valleytronics. A pure valley current is further generated by the
thermal gradient as well as the external bias. In a broad temperature range,
the pure valley current is found to be linearly dependent on the temperature
gradient while it increases with the increasing temperature of one lead for a
fixed thermal gradient. A valley field effect transistor (FET) driven by the
temperature gradient is proposed that can turn on and off the pure valley
current by gate voltage. The threshold gate voltage and on valley current are
proportional to the temperature gradient. When the system switches on at
positive gate voltage, the pure valley current is nearly independent of gate
voltage. The valley transconductance is up to 30 {\mu}S if we take Ampere as
the unit of the valley current. This valley FET may find potential application
in future valleytronics and valley caloritronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01522</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jingdong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Breaking through the bandwidth barrier in distributed fiber vibration
  sensing by sub-Nyquist randomized sampling</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The round trip time of the light pulse limits the maximum detectable
frequency response range of vibration in phase-sensitive optical time domain
reflectometry ({\phi}-OTDR). We propose a method to break the frequency
response range restriction of {\phi}-OTDR system by modulating the light pulse
interval randomly which enables a random sampling for every vibration point in
a long sensing fiber. This sub-Nyquist randomized sampling method is suits for
detecting sparse-wideband-frequency vibration signals. Up to MHz resonance
vibration signal with over dozens of frequency components and 1.153MHz single
frequency vibration signal are clearly identified for a sensing range of 9.6km
with 10kHz maximum sampling rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01523</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01523</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Chandralekha</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving Student Understanding of Magnetism</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, Paper presented at 2008 Annual Conference &amp; Exposition,
  Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. https://peer.asee.org/3117</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Formally investigating the sources of students' difficulties around specific
subjects is crucial for developing appropriate strategies to help students. We
have been studying difficulties in understanding magnetism encountered by
students in the calculus-based introductory physics courses. A majority of
these students are engineering majors. Student difficulties were assessed by
administering written free-response questions and by developing and
administering a research-based multiple-choice test to students. We also
conducted individual interviews with a subset of students. Some of these
interviews were lecture-demonstration based interviews in which students were
asked to predict the outcomes of experiments, perform the experiments and
reconcile the differences between their predictions and observations. Some of
the common misconceptions found in magnetism are analogous to those found in
electrostatics. Some additional difficulties are due to the non-intuitive three
dimensional nature of the relation between magnetic field, magnetic force and
velocity of the charged particles or direction of current. Another finding is
that students often used their gut feeling and had more difficulty reconciling
with the idea that the magnetic force and field are perpendicular to each other
when they were shown actual lecture-demonstration setups and asked to predict
outcomes of experiments than when they were asked to explain relation between
magnetic force and field theoretically solely based upon an equation. We
discuss the implications of this research to teaching and learning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01537</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author></authors><title>A Novel Quantum Image Compression Method Based on JPEG</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum image processing has been a hot topic. The first step of it is to
store an image into qubits, which is called quantum image preparation.
Different quantum image representations may have different preparation methods.
In this paper, we use GQIR (the generalized quantum image representation) to
represent an image, and try to decrease the operations used in preparation,
which is also known as quantum image compression. Our compression scheme is
based on JPEG (named from its inventor: the Joint Photographic Experts Group)
--- the most widely used method for still image compression in classical
computers. We input the quantized JPEG coefficients into qubits and then
convert them into pixel values. Theoretical analysis and experimental results
show that the compression ratio of our scheme is obviously higher than that of
the previous compression method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01554</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>Mikko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vuorinen</keyname><forenames>Aleksi</forenames></author></authors><title>Basics of thermal field theory - a tutorial on perturbative computations</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>229 pages</comments><journal-ref>Lect. Notes Phys. 925 (2016) pp.1-281</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-31933-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  These lecture notes, suitable for a two-semester introductory course or
self-study, offer an elementary and self-contained exposition of the basic
tools and concepts that are encountered in practical computations in
perturbative thermal field theory. Selected applications to heavy ion collision
physics and cosmology are outlined in the last chapter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01568</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>McEniry</keyname><forenames>Eunan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drautz</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear-scaling electronic structure theory: Electronic temperature in
  the Kernel Polynomial Method</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Linear-scaling electronic structure methods based on the calculation of
moments of the underlying electronic Hamiltonian offer a computationally
efficient and numerically robust scheme to drive large-scale atomistic
simulations, in which the quantum-mechanical nature of the electrons is
explicitly taken into account. We compare the kernel polynomial method to the
Fermi operator expansion method and establish a formal connection between the
two approaches. We show that the convolution of the kernel polynomial method
may be understood as an effective electron temperature. The results of a number
of possible kernels are formally examined, and then applied to a representative
tight-binding model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01569</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Nikitin</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author></authors><title>Static spherically symmetric solutions of Einstein field equations with
  radial dark matter</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a static spherically symmetric problem with a black hole and
radially directed geodesic flows of dark matter. The obtained solutions have
the following properties. At large distances, the gravitational field produces
constant velocities of circular motion, i.e., flat rotation curves. At smaller
distances, the field switches to Newtonian regime, then to Schwarzschild
regime. Deviations from Schwarzschild regime start below the gravitational
radius. The dark matter prevents the creation of event horizon, instead, a
spherical region possessing extremely large redshift is created. The structure
of space-time for the obtained solutions is investigated and the implications
for the models of the galaxies are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01583</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Feldmeier-Krause</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neumayer</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van de Ven</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Zeeuw</keyname><forenames>P. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;del</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Triaxial orbit-based modelling of the Milky Way Nuclear Star Cluster</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3377</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct triaxial dynamical models for the Milky Way nuclear star cluster
using Schwarzschild's orbit superposition technique. We fit the stellar
kinematic maps presented in Feldmeier et al. (2014). The models are used to
constrain the supermassive black hole mass M_BH, dynamical mass-to-light ratio
M/L, and the intrinsic shape of the cluster. Our best-fitting model has M_BH =
(3.0 +1.1 -1.3)x10^6 M_sun, M/L = (0.90 +0.76 -0.08) M_sun/L_{sun,4.5micron},
and a compression of the cluster along the line-of-sight. Our results are in
agreement with the direct measurement of the supermassive black hole mass using
the motion of stars on Keplerian orbits. The mass-to-light ratio is consistent
with stellar population studies of other galaxies in the mid-infrared. It is
possible that we underestimate M_BH and overestimate the cluster's triaxiality
due to observational effects. The spatially semi-resolved kinematic data and
extinction within the nuclear star cluster bias the observations to the near
side of the cluster, and may appear as a compression of the nuclear star
cluster along the line-of-sight. We derive a total dynamical mass for the Milky
Way nuclear star cluster of M_MWNSC = (2.1 +-0.7)x10^7 M_sun within a sphere
with radius r = 2 x r_eff = 8.4 pc. The best-fitting model is tangentially
anisotropic in the central r = 0.5-2 pc of the nuclear star cluster, but close
to isotropic at larger radii. Our triaxial models are able to recover complex
kinematic substructures in the velocity map.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01593</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zahner</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lochb&#xfc;hler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariethoz</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Image synthesis with graph cuts: a fast model proposal mechanism in
  probabilistic inversion</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Geophysical Journal International, 204, 1179-1190 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/gji/ggv517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geophysical inversion should ideally produce geologically realistic
subsurface models that explain the available data. Multiple-point statistics is
a geostatistical approach to construct subsurface models that are consistent
with site-specific data, but also display the same type of patterns as those
found in a training image. The training image can be seen as a conceptual model
of the subsurface and is used as a non-parametric model of spatial variability.
Inversion based on multiple-point statistics is challenging due to high
nonlinearity and time-consuming geostatistical resimulation steps that are
needed to create new model proposals. We propose an entirely new model proposal
mechanism for geophysical inversion that is inspired by texture synthesis in
computer vision. Instead of resimulating pixels based on higher-order patterns
in the training image, we identify a suitable patch of the training image that
replace a corresponding patch in the current model without breaking the
patterns found in the training image, that is, remaining consistent with the
given prior. We consider three cross-hole ground-penetrating radar examples in
which the new model proposal mechanism is employed within an extended
Metropolis Markov chain Monte Carlo (MCMC) inversion. The model proposal step
is about 40 times faster than state-of-the-art multiple-point statistics
resimulation techniques, the number of necessary MCMC steps is lower and the
quality of the final model realizations is of similar quality. The model
proposal mechanism is presently limited to 2-D fields, but the method is
general and can be applied to a wide range of subsurface settings and
geophysical data types.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01594</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Gong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yongchong</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanping</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csaba</keyname><forenames>Cserh&#xe1;ti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Attila</keyname><forenames>Csik</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of periodic-layered structure in Zn/CuxTiy systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.11900/0412.1961.2015.00289</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diffusion couples Zn/CuxTiy were prepared by the melting contact method and
then annealed at 663K for various times. Using scanning electron microscopy
(SEM) with energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy (EDS), we discovered 7 new
systems, i.e. Zn/Cu9Ti, Zn/Cu4Ti, Zn/Cu2Ti, Zn/Cu7Ti3, Zn/Cu3Ti2, Zn/Cu11Ti9
and Zn/Cu9Ti11, which can form the interesting periodic-layered structure
within the reaction zones. By the traditional metallographic treatment and the
in-situ section observation method respectively, it was confirmed that the
periodic-layered structure is really composed of the CuZn2 singer-phase and the
(CuZn2+TiZn3) two-phase layers distributing alternately within the reaction
front area. Furthermore, the thickness of the periodic layers relates to the
composition of Cu-Ti substrates: the higher content of Cu atoms in C--Ti alloy
substrates, the thinner the layers will be. The experimental results are in
accordance to the prediction of the diffusion-induced stresses model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01596</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zaka</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shenouda</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fouad</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medhat</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katona</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beke</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation of Cu6Sn5 phase by cold homogenization in nanocrystalline
  Cu-Sn bilayers at room temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.microrel.2015.10.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solid state reaction between nanocrystalline Cu and Sn films was investigated
at room temperature by depth profiling with secondary neutral mass spectrometry
and by X-ray diffraction. A rapid diffusion intermixing was observed leading to
the formation of homogeneous Cu 6Sn5 layer. There is no indication of the
appearance of the Cu3Sn phase. This offers a way for solid phase soldering at
low temperatures, i.e. to produce homogeneous Cu6Sn5 intermediate layer of
several tens of nanometers during reasonable time (in the order of hours or
less). From the detailed analysis of the growth of the planar reaction layer,
formed at the initial interface in Sn(100 nm)/Cu(50 nm) system, the value of
the parabolic growth rate coefficient at room temperature is 2.3 x 10-15 cm2/s.
In addition, the overall increase of the composition near to the substrate
inside the Cu film was interpreted by grain boundary diffusion induced solid
state reaction: the new phase formed along the grain boundaries and grew
perpendicular to the boundary planes. From the initial slope of the composition
versus time function, the interface velocity during this reaction was estimated
to be about 0.5 nm/h.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01597</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zayachuk</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slynko</keyname><forenames>E. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slynko</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Oscillations and huge preferences of PbTe crystal surface sputtering
  under Secondary Neutral Mass Spectrometry conditions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.matlet.2016.03.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sputtering of PbTe crystals by Ar plasma with ion energies 50-550 eV is
investigated. A dependence of sputter yields of the Te and Pb on the sputtering
ion energy and sputtering time is measured. New phenomena: aperiodical
oscillations of Pb and Te sputtering; a huge preference of Te sputtering
reaching more than two orders of magnitude at the beginning of sputtering
process; and a significant excess of Te integrated sputter yield over that of
Pb for prolonged sputtering by low energy plasma at 50-160 eV, are observed. It
is substantiated that these phenomena can be caused by the peculiarities of the
charge states of the interstitial Pb and Te in PbTe crystal matrix and the
processes of re-deposition of sputtered atoms on the sputtered surface
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01600</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01600</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Floch</keyname><forenames>Jean-Michel Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartnett</keyname><forenames>John Gideon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madrangeas</keyname><forenames>Valerie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krupka</keyname><forenames>Jerzy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cros</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobar</keyname><forenames>Michael Edmund</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency-Temperature sensitivity reduction with optimized microwave
  Bragg resonators</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>24 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables, journal article</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 121, 014102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4973676</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dielectric resonators are employed to build state-of-the-art low-noise and
high- stability oscillators operating at room and cryogenic temperatures. A
resonator temperature coefficient of frequency is one criterion of performance.
This paper reports on predictions and measurements of this temperature
coefficient of frequency for three types of cylindrically-symmetric Bragg
resonators operated at microwave frequencies. At room temperature, microwave
Bragg resonators have the best potential to reach extremely high Q-factors.
Research has been conducted over the last decade on modeling, optimizing and
realizing such high Q-factor devices for applications such as filtering,
sensing, and frequency metrology. We present an optimized design, which has a
temperature sensitivity 2 to 4 times less than current whispering gallery mode
resonators without using temperature compensating techniques and about 30% less
than other existing Bragg resonators. Also, the performance of a new generation
single-layered Bragg resonators, based on a hybrid-Bragg-mode, is reported with
a sensitivity of about -12ppm/K at 295K. For a single reflector resonator, it
achieves a similar level of performance as a double-Bragg-reflector resonator
but with a more compact structure and performs six times better than
whispering-gallery-mode resonators. The hybrid resonator promises to deliver a
new generation of high-sensitivity sensors and high-stability room-temperature
oscillators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01601</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Zayachuk</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slynko</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Morphology of PbTe crystal surface sputtered by argon plasma under
  Secondary Neutral Mass Spectrometry conditions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.15330/pcss.17.3.336-341</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated morphology of the lateral surfaces of PbTe crystal
samples grown from melt by the Bridgman method sputtered by Ar+ plasma with ion
energy of 50-550 eV for 5-50 minutes under Secondary Neutral Mass Spectrometry
(SNMS) conditions. The sputtered PbTe crystal surface was found to be
simultaneously both the source of sputtered material and the efficient
substrate for re-deposition of the sputtered material during the depth
profiling. During sputtering PbTe crystal surface is forming the dimple relief.
To be redeposited the sputtered Pb and Te form arrays of the microscopic
surface structures in the shapes of hillocks, pyramids, cones and others on the
PbTe crystal sputtered surface. Correlation between the density of re-deposited
microscopic surface structures, their shape, and average size, on the one hand,
and the energy and duration of sputtering, on the other, is revealed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01602</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukerji</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geological realism in hydrogeological and geophysical inverse modeling:
  a review</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Advances in Water Resources, 86, 86-101 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.advwatres.2015.09.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scientific curiosity, exploration of georesources and environmental concerns
are pushing the geoscientific research community toward subsurface
investigations of ever-increasing complexity. This review explores various
approaches to formulate and solve inverse problems in ways that effectively
integrate geological concepts with geophysical and hydrogeological data. Modern
geostatistical simulation algorithms can produce multiple subsurface
realizations that are in agreement with conceptual geological models and
statistical rock physics can be used to map these realizations into physical
properties that are sensed by the geophysical or hydrogeological data. The
inverse problem consists of finding one or an ensemble of such subsurface
realizations that are in agreement with the data. The most general inversion
frameworks are presently often computationally intractable when applied to
large-scale problems and it is necessary to better understand the implications
of simplifying (1) the conceptual geological model (e.g., using model
compression); (2) the physical forward problem (e.g., using proxy models); and
(3) the algorithm used to solve the inverse problem (e.g., Markov chain Monte
Carlo or local optimization methods) to reach practical and robust solutions
given today's computer resources and knowledge. We also highlight the need to
not only use geophysical and hydrogeological data for parameter estimation
purposes, but also to use them to falsify or corroborate alternative geological
scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01605</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Burunkova</keyname><forenames>Julia A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denisiuk</keyname><forenames>Ihor Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuk</keyname><forenames>Dmitri I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daroczi</keyname><forenames>Lajos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csarnovics</keyname><forenames>Istv&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokenyesi</keyname><forenames>S&#xe1;ndor</forenames></author></authors><title>Fabrication and properties of luminescence polymer composites with
  erbium/ytterbium oxides and gold nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.3762/bjnano.7.55</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rare-earth-doped optical materials are important for light sources in
optoelectronics, as well as for efficient optical amplification elements and
other elements of photonics. On the basis of the previously developed method of
anhydrous, low-temperature synthesis of Er/Yb oxides from their chlorides we
fabricated proper nanoparticles with defined parameters and used them for the
development of optically transparent, luminescent polymer nanocomposite with
low optical scattering, suitable for direct, light-induced formation of
photonic elements. Introduction of preformed gold nanoparticles in such a
nanocomposite was also performed and an enhancement of luminescence due to the
influence of plasmon effects was detected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01608</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Narski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast Kinetic Scheme : efficient MPI parallelization strategy for 3D
  Boltzmann equation</title><categories>math.NA physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a parallelization strategy on distributed memory
systems for the Fast Kinetic Scheme --- a semi-Lagrangian scheme developed in
[J. Comput. Phys., Vol. 255, 2013, pp 680-698] for solving kinetic equations.
The original algorithm was proposed for the BGK approximation of the collision
kernel. In this work we deal with its extension to the full Boltzmann equation
in six dimensions, where the collision operator is resolved by means of fast
spectral method. We present close to ideal scalability of the proposed
algorithm on tera- and peta-scale systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01609</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Csarnovics</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hajd</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biri</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heged&#x171;s</keyname><forenames>Cs.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kok&#xe9;nyesi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xe1;cz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preliminary studies of creation of gold nanoparticles on titanium
  surface towards biomedical applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.vacuum.2016.01.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is devoted to present the results of creation of gold
nanoparticles on titanium surface. We focused on the problem how to create gold
nanoparticles on the titanium surface with defined particle size and
distribution, which could be interesting for several applications (e.g.
providing well-defined substrates for biomedical research, etc.). To do that
the sample is affected by the complex physical rout of gold nanoparticles
formation: by gold ion implantation, thin Au layer deposition and thermal
annealing. The effect of the technology, influence on the surface structure and
its parameters were investigated by the X-ray diffraction, Scanning Electron
and Atomic Force Microscopy, as well as by Secondary Neutral Mass Spectrometry
methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01612</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Drozdov</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drozdov</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vad</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunin</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurasov</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Belykh</keyname><forenames>S. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gololobov</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suvorov</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tolstogouzov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative depth profiling of Si1-xGex structures by time-of-flight
  secondary ion mass spectrometry and secondary neutral mass spectrometry</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.tsf.2016.03.049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantification of Ge in Si1-xGex structures (0.092&lt;x&lt;0.78) was carried by
time-of-flight secondary ion mass spectrometry (TOF-SIMS) and electron-gas
secondary neutral mass spectrometry (SNMS). A good linear correlation
(R2&gt;0.9997) of intensity ratios of GeCs2+/SiCs2+ and 74Ge-/30Si- secondary ions
and post-ionized 70Ge+/28Si+ sputtered neutrals with Ge concentration was
obtained. The calibration data were used for quantitative depth profiling of
[10x(12.3 nm Si0.63Ge0.37/34 nm Si)] structures on Si. Satisfactory compliance
of the quantified Ge concentration in SiGe layers with the data measured by
high-resolution X-ray diffraction was obtained for both techniques. Both SIMS
and SNMS experimental profiles were fitted using the Hofmann
mixing-roughness-information depth (MRI) model. In case of TOF-SIMS the quality
of the reconstruction was higher than for SNMS since not only the progressing
roughening, but also crater effect and other processes unaccounted in the MRI
simulation could have significant impact on plasma sputter depth profiling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01613</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Heged&#x171;s</keyname><forenames>Csaba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Chia-Che</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biri</keyname><forenames>S&#xe1;ndor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Shinn-Jyh</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced physicochemical and biological properties of ion-implanted
  Titanium using Electron Cyclotron Resonance ion sources</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.3390/ma9010025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The surface properties of metallic implants play an important role in their
clinical success. Improving upon the inherent shortcomings of Ti implants, such
as poor bioactivity, is imperative for achieving clinical use. In this study,
we have developed a Ti implant modified with Ca or dual Ca + Si ions on the
surface using an electron cyclotron resonance ion source (ECRIS). The
physicochemical and biological properties of ion-implanted Ti surfaces were
analyzed using various analytical techniques, such as surface analyses,
potentiodynamic polarization and cell culture. Experimental results indicated
that a rough morphology was observed on the Ti substrate surface modified by
ECRIS plasma ions. The in vitro electrochemical measurement results also
indicated that the Ca + Si ion-implanted surface had a more beneficial and
desired behavior than the pristine Ti substrate. Compared to the pristine Ti
substrate, all ion-implanted samples had a lower hemolysis ratio. MG63 cells
cultured on the high Ca and dual Ca + Si ion-implanted surfaces revealed
significantly greater cell viability in comparison to the pristine Ti
substrate. In conclusion, surface modification by electron cyclotron resonance
Ca and Si ion sources could be an effective method for Ti implants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01615</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lochb&#xfc;hler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dogan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dam</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tomogram-based comparison of geostatistical models: Application to the
  MAcro-Dispersion Experiment (MADE) site</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Hydrology, 531, 543-556 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jhydrol.2015.10.073</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new framework to compare alternative geostatistical descriptions
of a given site. Multiple realizations of each of the considered geostatistical
models and their corresponding tomograms (based on inversion of
noise-contaminated simulated data) are used as a multivariate training image.
The training image is scanned with a direct sampling algorithm to obtain
conditional realizations of hydraulic conductivity that are not only in
agreement with the geostatistical model, but also honor the spatially varying
resolution of the site-specific tomogram. Model comparison is based on the
quality of the simulated geophysical data from the ensemble of conditional
realizations. The tomogram in this study is obtained by inversion of cross-hole
ground-penetrating radar (GPR) first-arrival travel time data acquired at the
MAcro-Dispersion Experiment (MADE) site in Mississippi (USA). Various
heterogeneity descriptions ranging from multi-Gaussian fields to fields with
complex multiple-point statistics inferred from outcrops are considered. Under
the assumption that the relationship between porosity and hydraulic
conductivity inferred from local measurements is valid, we find that
conditioned multi-Gaussian realizations and derivatives thereof can explain the
crosshole geophysical data. A training image based on an aquifer analog from
Germany was found to be in better agreement with the geophysical data than the
one based on the local outcrop, which appears to under-represent high hydraulic
conductivity zones. These findings are only based on the information content in
a single resolution-limited tomogram and extending the analysis to tracer or
higher resolution surface GPR data might lead to different conclusions (e.g.,
that discrete facies boundaries are necessary).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01616</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>L&#xe9;vai</keyname><forenames>G&#xe1;bor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godzs&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>Melinda</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf6;r&#xf6;k</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakl</keyname><forenames>J&#xf3;zsef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tak&#xe1;ts</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csik</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vad</keyname><forenames>K&#xe1;lm&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaptay</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Designing the color of hot-dip galvanized steel sheet through
  destructive light interference using a Zn-Ti liquid metallic bath</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1007/s11661-016-3545-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The color of hot-dip galvanized steel sheet was adjusted in a reproducible
way using a liquid Zn-Ti metallic bath, air atmosphere, and controlling the
bath temperature as the only experimental parameter. Coloring was found only
for sample s cooled in air and dipped into Ti-containing liquid Zn. For samples
dipped into a 0.15 wt pct Ti-containing Zn bath, the color remained metallic
(gray) below a 792 K (519 C) bath temperature; it was yellow at 814 K, violet
at 847 K, and blue at 873 K. With the increasing bath temperature, the
thickness of the adhered Zn-Ti layer gradually decreased from 52 to 32
micrometers, while the thickness of the outer TiO2 layer gradually increased
from 24 to 69 nm. Due to small Al contamination of the Zn bath, a thin (around
2 nm) alumina-rich layer is found between the outer TiO2 layer and the inner
macroscopic Zn layer. It is proven that the color change was governed by the
formation of thin outer TiO2 layer; different colors appear depending on the
thickness of this layer, mostly due to the destructive interference of visible
light on this transparent nano-layer. A complex model was built to explain the
results using known relationships of chemical thermodynamics, adhesion, heat
flow, kinetics of chemical reactions, diffusion, and optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01626</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doetsch</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Joint inversion in hydrogeophysics and near-surface geophysics</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Integrated imaging of the Earth, M. Moorkamp, P. Lelievre, N.
  Linde, and A. Khan (Editors), ch.7, 119-135 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/9781118929063.ch7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The near-surface environment is often too complex to enable inference of
hydrological and environmental variables using one geophysical data type alone.
Joint inversion and coupled inverse modeling involving numerical flow- and
transport simulators have, in the last decade, played important roles in
pushing applications towards increasingly challenging targets. Joint inversion
of geophysical data that is based on structural constraints is often favored
over model coupling based on explicit petrophysical relationships. More
specifically, cross-gradient joint inversion has been applied to a wide range
of near-surface applications and geophysical data types. To infer hydrological
subsurface properties, the most appropriate approach is often to use temporal
changes in geophysical data that can be related to hydrological state
variables. This allows using geophysical data as indirect hydrological
observables, while the coupling with a flow- and transport simulator ensures
physical consistency. Future research avenues include investigating the
validity of different coupling strategies at various scales, the spatial
statistics of near-surface petrophysical relationships, the influence of the
model conceptualization, fully probabilistic joint inversions, and how to
include complex prior information in the joint inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01634</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Linde</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vrugt</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Distributed soil moisture from crosshole ground-penetrating radar travel
  times using stochastic inversion</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>in Vadose Zone Journal, 12 (2013)</comments><doi>10.2136/vzj2012.0101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geophysical methods offer several key advantages over conventional subsurface
measurement approaches, yet their use for hydrologic interpretation is often
problematic. Here, we introduce theory and concepts of a novel Bayesian
approach for high-resolution soil moisture estimation using traveltime
observations from crosshole Ground Penetrating Radar (GPR) experiments. The
recently developed Multi-try DiffeRential Evolution Adaptive Metropolis with
sampling from past states, MT-DREAM(ZS) is being used to infer, as closely and
consistently as possible, the posterior distribution of spatially distributed
vadose zone soil moisture and/or porosity under saturated conditions. Two
differing and opposing model parameterization schemes are being considered, one
involving a classical uniform grid discretization and the other based on a
discrete cosine transformation (DCT). We illustrate our approach using two
different case studies involving geophysical data from a synthetic water tracer
infiltration study and a real-world field study under saturated conditions. Our
results demonstrate that the DCT parameterization yields the most accurate
estimates of distributed soil moisture for a large range of spatial
resolutions, and superior MCMC convergence rates. In addition, DCT is admirably
suited to investigate and quantify the effects of model truncation errors on
the MT-DREAM(ZS) inversion results. For the field example, lateral anisotropy
needs to be enforced to derive reliable soil moisture variability. Our results
also demonstrate that the posterior soil moisture uncertainty derived with the
proposed Bayesian procedure is significantly larger than its counterpart
estimated from classical smoothness-constrained deterministic inversions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01638</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tk&#xe1;&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17d;e&#x161;ko</keyname><forenames>Matija</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agner</keyname><forenames>Josef Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmutz</keyname><forenames>Hansj&#xfc;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkt</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Rydberg states of helium in electric and magnetic fields of arbitrary
  relative orientation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49(10), 094006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/10/104002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A spectroscopic study of Rydberg states of helium ($n$ = 30 and 45) in
magnetic, electric and combined magnetic and electric fields with arbitrary
relative orientations of the field vectors is presented. The emphasis is on two
special cases where (i) the diamagnetic term is negligible and both
paramagnetic Zeeman and Stark effects are linear ($n$ = 30, $B \leq$ 120 mT and
$F$ = 0 - 78 V/cm ), and (ii) the diamagnetic term is dominant and the Stark
effect is linear ($n$ = 45, $B$ = 277 mT and $F$ = 0 - 8 V/cm). Both cases
correspond to regimes where the interactions induced by the electric and
magnetic fields are much weaker than the Coulomb interaction, but much stronger
than the spin-orbit interaction. The experimental spectra are compared to
spectra calculated by determining the eigenvalues of the Hamiltonian matrix
describing helium Rydberg states in the external fields. The spectra and the
calculated energy-level diagrams in external fields reveal avoided crossings
between levels of different $m_l$ values and pronounced $m_l$-mixing effects at
all angles between the electric and magnetic field vectors other than 0. These
observations are discussed in the context of the development of a method to
generate dense samples of cold atoms and molecules in a magnetic trap following
Rydberg-Stark deceleration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01646</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaldewey</keyname><forenames>Timo</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Basel, Switzerland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kuhlmann</keyname><forenames>Andreas V.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Basel, Switzerland</affiliation><affiliation>IBM Research-Zurich, Switzerland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Valentin</keyname><forenames>Sascha R.</forenames><affiliation>Lehrstuhl f&#xfc;r Angewandte Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Ruhr-Universit&#xe4;t Bochum, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ludwig</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames><affiliation>Lehrstuhl f&#xfc;r Angewandte Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Ruhr-Universit&#xe4;t Bochum, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wieck</keyname><forenames>Andreas D.</forenames><affiliation>Lehrstuhl f&#xfc;r Angewandte Festk&#xf6;rperphysik, Ruhr-Universit&#xe4;t Bochum, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Warburton</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Basel, Switzerland</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical nanoscopy via quantum control</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>Main manuscript 6 pages and 3 figures, Supplementary Materials 9
  pages and 10 figures, submitted to Sciences Advances</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a scheme for nanoscopic imaging of a quantum mechanical two-level
system using an optical probe in the far-field. Existing super-resolution
schemes require more than two-levels and depend on an incoherent response to
the lasers. Here, quantum control of the two states proceeds via rapid
adiabatic passage. We implement this scheme on an array of semiconductor
self-assembled quantum dots. Each quantum dot results in a bright spot in the
image with extents down to 30 nm ({\lambda}/31). Rapid adiabatic passage is
established as a versatile tool in the super-resolution toolbox.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01655</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhitong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shiqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levchenko</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beilis</keyname><forenames>Isak I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keidar</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>In vitro Demonstration of Cancer Inhibiting Properties from Stratified
  Self-Organized Micro-Discharge Plasma-Liquid Interface</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.bio-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experiments have revealed a nontrivial cancer-inhibiting capability of liquid
media treated by the plasma jet capable of forming thinly stratified
self-organized patterns at a plasma-liquid interface. A pronounced cancer
depressing activity towards at least two kinds of human cancer cells, namely
breast cancer MDA-MB-231 and human glioblastoma U87 cancer lines, was
demonstrated. After a short treatment at the thinly stratified self-organized
plasma-liquid interface pattern, the cancer inhibiting media demonstrate well
pronounced depression and apoptosis activities towards tumor cells, not
achievable without interfacial stratification of plasma jet to thin (of several
um) current filaments, which therefore play a pivotal (yet still not completely
clear) role in building up the cancer inhibition properties. Moreover, thinly
stratified, self-organized interfacial discharge is capable to efficiently
control the ROS and RNS concentrations in the cancer-inhibiting media, and in
particular, abnormal ROS/RNS ratios not achievable in discharges which do not
form stratified thin-filament patterns could be obtained. These results were
explained in terms of interaction of thin plasma filaments of the
self-organized pattern with gas and liquid, where the unusual interaction
conditions (i.e., high surface-to-volume ratios etc.) cause accumulation of
ROS, RNS and other species in unusual ratios and concentrations, thus forming
potentially efficient anti-cancer cocktail. Our funding could be extremely
important for handling the cancer proliferation problem, and hence, it should
be brought to light to attract due attention of the researchers and explore the
possible potential of this approach in tackling the challenging problem of high
cancer-induced mortality and rising morbidity trends.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01659</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Emile</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames><affiliation>URU 435 LPL</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Emile</keyname><forenames>Janine</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author></authors><title>Towards an optofluidic pump?</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Optofluidics, Microfluidics, and Nanofluidics , De Gruyter, 2016,
  3 (1), pp.49-52</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/optof-2016-0007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most of the vibrating mechanisms of optofluidicsystems are based on local
heating of membranes that in-duces liquid flow. We report here a new type of
diaphragmpump in a liquid film based on the optical radiation pres-sure force.
We modulate a low power laser that gener-ates, at resonance, a symmetric
vibration of a free standingsoap film. The film lifetime strongly varies from
56 s at lowpower (2 mW) to 2 s at higher power (70 mW). Since thelaser beam
only acts mechanically on the interfaces, sucha pump could be easily
implemented on delicate micro-equipment on chips or in biological systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01661</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Adibekyan</keyname><forenames>Vardan</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation and evolution of exoplanets in different environments</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Invited Review. To appear in Astronomical Society of the Pacific
  (ASP) Conference Series &quot;Non-Stable Universe: Energetic Resources, Activity
  Phenomena and Evolutionary Processes&quot; dedicated to the 70th anniversary of
  Byurakan Astrophysical Observatory</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ultimate goal of exoplanetologists is to discover life outside our Earth
and to fully understand our place in the Universe. Even though we have never
been closer to attaining this goal, we still need to understand how and where
the planets (efficiently) form. In this manuscript I briefly discuss the
important role of stellar metallicity and chemistry on the formation and
evolution of exoplanets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01686</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kezerashvili</keyname><forenames>Roman Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsiklauri</keyname><forenames>Shalva M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Trion and Biexciton in Monolayer Transition Metal Dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst. 58: 18 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-016-1186-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the trion and biexciton in transition metal dichalcogenides
monolayers within the framework of a nonrelativistic potential model using the
method of hyperspherical harmonics (HH). We solve the three- and four-body
Schr\&quot;odinger equations with the Keldysh potential by expanding the wave
functions of a trion and biexciton in terms of the antisymmetrized HH. Results
of the calculations for the ground state energies are in good agreement with
similar calculations for the Keldysh potential and in reasonable agreement with
experimental measurements of trion and biexciton binding energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01696</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Nuno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bicudo</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Flux tubes at Finite Temperature</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>6 pages, Presented at Excited QCD 2016 conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we show the flux tubes of the quark-antiquark and quark-quark
at finite temperature for SU(3) Lattice QCD. The chromomagnetic and
chromoelectric fields are calculated above and below the phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01700</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>De Causmaecker</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuks</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahmoudi</keyname><forenames>Farvah</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Leary</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porod</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekmen</keyname><forenames>Sezen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strobbe</keyname><forenames>Nadja</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the squark flavour structure of the MSSM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of the 38th
  International Conference of High Energy Physics (ICHEP), Chicago, Aug. 3-10,
  2016</comments><report-no>LAPTH-Conf-065/16, CERN-TH-2016-234, FERMILAB-CONF-16-500-PPD</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an extensive study of the MSSM parameter space allowing for
general generation mixing in the squark sector. Employing an MCMC algorithm, we
establish the parameter ranges which are allowed with respect to various
experimental and theoretical constraints. Based on this analysis, we propose
benchmark scenarios for future studies. Moreover, we discuss aspects of
signatures at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01714</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Manz</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Minimal Basis Iterative Stockholder: Atoms in Molecules for
  Force-Field Development&quot;</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure, 1 table, comment on arXiv:1608.05556, two
  paragraphs quoted from arXiv:1512.08270</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Verstraelen et al. (J. Chem. Theory Comput. 12 (2016) 3894-3912) recently
introduced a new method for partitioning the electron density of a material
into constituent atoms. Their approach falls within the class of atomic
population analysis methods called stockholder charge partitioning methods in
which a material electron distribution is divided into overlapping atoms. The
Minimal Basis Iterative Stockholder (MBIS) method proposed by Verstraelen et
al. composes the pro-atom density as a sum of exponential functions, where the
number of exponential functions equals that element's row in the Periodic
Table. Specifically, one exponential function is used for H and He, two for Li
through Ne, three for Na through Ar, etc. In the MBIS method, the exponential
functions parameters defining the pro-atom density are optimized in a
self-consistent iterative procedure. Close examination reveals some important
anomalies in the article by Verstaelen et al. The purpose of this comment
article is to bring these important issues to readers' attention and to start a
discussion of them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-01-09</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01715</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Swaim</keyname><forenames>Jon D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>David</keyname><forenames>Kaitlyn N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>Erin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rios</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danaci</keyname><forenames>Onur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glasser</keyname><forenames>Ryan T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic vapor as a source of tunable, non-Gaussian self-reconstructing
  optical modes</title><categories>physics.optics physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this manuscript, we demonstrate the ability of nonlinear light-atom
interactions to produce tunably non-Gaussian, partially self-healing optical
modes. Gaussian spatial-mode light tuned near to the atomic resonances in hot
rubidium vapor is shown to result in non-Gaussian output mode structures that
may be controlled by varying either the input beam power or the temperature of
the atomic vapor. We show that the output modes exhibit a degree of
self-reconstruction after encountering an obstruction in the beam path. The
resultant modes are similar to truncated Bessel-Gauss modes that exhibit the
ability to self-reconstruct earlier upon propagation than Gaussian modes. The
ability to generate tunable, self-reconstructing beams has potential
applications to a variety of imaging and communication scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
