<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:15:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-26" from="2016-09-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0910.5415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0910.5415</id><created>2009-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Jafarizadeh</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazhari</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aali</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The minimum-error discrimination via Helstrom family of ensembles and
  Convex Optimization</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf Process (2011) 10: 155</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-010-0185-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the convex optimization method and Helstrom family of ensembles
introduced in Ref. [1], we have discussed optimal ambiguous discrimination in
qubit systems. We have analyzed the problem of the optimal discrimination of N
known quantum states and have obtained maximum success probability and optimal
measurement for N known quantum states with equiprobable prior probabilities
and equidistant from center of the Bloch ball, not all of which are on the one
half of the Bloch ball and all of the conjugate states are pure. An exact
solution has also been given for arbitrary three known quantum states. The
given examples which use our method include: 1. Diagonal N mixed states; 2. N
equiprobable states and equidistant from center of the Bloch ball which their
corresponding Bloch vectors are inclined at the equal angle from z axis; 3.
Three mirror-symmetric states; 4. States that have been prepared with equal
prior probabilities on vertices of a Platonic solid.
  Keywords: minimum-error discrimination, success probability, measurement,
POVM elements, Helstrom family of ensembles, convex optimization, conjugate
states PACS Nos: 03.67.Hk, 03.65.Ta
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0911.3668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0911.3668</id><created>2009-11-18</created><updated>2009-11-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>McDonnell</keyname><forenames>Mark D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flitney</keyname><forenames>Adrian P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signal acquisition via polarization modulation in single photon sources</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, accepted by Physical Review E. This version adds
  a reference</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 80, 060102(R) (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.80.060102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple model system is introduced for demonstrating how a single photon
source might be used to transduce classical analog information. The theoretical
scheme results in measurements of analog source samples that are (i) quantized
in the sense of analog-to-digital conversion and (ii) corrupted by random noise
that is solely due to the quantum uncertainty in detecting the polarization
state of each photon. This noise is unavoidable if more than one bit per sample
is to be transmitted, and we show how it may be exploited in a manner inspired
by suprathreshold stochastic resonance. The system is analyzed information
theoretically, as it can be modeled as a noisy optical communication channel,
although unlike classical Poisson channels, the detector's photon statistics
are binomial. Previous results on binomial channels are adapted to demonstrate
numerically that the classical information capacity, and thus the accuracy of
the transduction, increases logarithmically with the square root of the number
of photons, N. Although the capacity is shown to be reduced when an additional
detector nonideality is present, the logarithmic increase with N remains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.1009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.1009</id><created>2012-04-04</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amsalu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houdr&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matzinger</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sparse long blocks and the variance of the longest common subsequences
  in random words</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages</comments><msc-class>60C05, 60F05, 05A16</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Consider two independent random strings having same length and taking values
uniformly in a common finite alphabet. We study the order of the variance of
the length of the longest common subsequences (LCS) of these strings when long
blocks, or other types of atypical substrings, are sparsely added into one of
them. Under weak conditions on the derivative of the mean LCS-curve, the order
of the variance of the LCS is shown to be linear in the length of the strings.
We also argue that our proofs carry over to many models used by computational
biologists to simulate DNA-sequences. This is the first result where the open
question of the order of the fluctuation of the LCS of random strings is solved
for a realistic model. Until now, this type of result had only been established
for low entropy cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.4431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.4431</id><created>2012-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum fluctuations the clue for a realistic interpretation of quantum
  mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>34 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1203.5688, arXiv:1205.0916</comments><journal-ref>Interpretations of Quantum Mechanics. Ulf Edvison, editor. 2016.
  Chapter 12</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Arguments are gived for the plausibility that quantum mechanics is a
stochastic theory and that many quantum phenomena derive from the existence of
a real noise consisting of vacuum fluctuations of all fundamental fields
existing in nature. Planck's constant appears as the parameter fixing the scale
of the fluctuations. Hints for an intuitive explanation are offered for some
typical quantum features, like the uncertainty principle or the particle
behaviour of fields. It is proposed that the recent discovery of dark energy in
the universe is an argument for the reality of the vacuum fluctuations. A study
is made of the compatibility of the model with the results of performed tests
of Bell\'{}s inequalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.4437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.4437</id><created>2014-07-16</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lesovik</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebedev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadovskyy</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suslov</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinokur</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>H-theorem in quantum physics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>82C10</msc-class><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 32815 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep32815</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Remarkable progress of quantum information theory (QIT) allowed to formulate
mathematical theorems for conditions that data-transmitting or data-processing
occurs with a non-negative entropy gain. However, relation of these results
formulated in terms of entropy gain in quantum channels to temporal evolution
of real physical systems is not thoroughly understood. Here we build on the
mathematical formalism provided by QIT to formulate the quantum H-theorem in
terms of physical observables. We discuss the manifestation of the second law
of thermodynamics in quantum physics and uncover special situations where the
second law can be violated. We further demonstrate that the typical evolution
of energy-isolated quantum systems occurs with non-diminishing entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.6847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.6847</id><created>2014-09-24</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shamsi</keyname><forenames>Zahid Hussain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>DaiGyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Younghun</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Fisher information of fermionic cavity modes in an accelerated
  motion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of the inertial and non-inertial segments of
relativistic motion on the quantum Fisher information of (1+1) Dirac field
modes confined to cavities. %For this purpose, a bipartite system comprising of
Alice's and Rob's cavities with appropriate boundary conditions is prepared.
For the purpose, we consider the situation that Rob's cavity, initially
inertial, accelerates uniformly with respect to its proper time and then again
becomes inertial while Alice's cavity remains inertial. The acceleration is
assumed to be very small and its effects were analyzed in a perturbative
regime. For analysis, we consider $\theta$ parameterized two-qubit pure
entangled state and a Werner state. In contrast to the degradation of
entanglement due to the relativistic motion between the cavities, the quantum
Fisher information of the pure composite system $\mathcal{F}_\theta$ with
respect to parameter $\theta$ is found to be invariant under the same
conditions. However, in the case of the Werner state, the quantum Fisher
information displays periodic degradation, due to the inertial and non-inertial
segments of motion. Further, we investigate how this evolution process affects
the quantum Fisher information distribution over the subsystems of Alice's and
Rob's cavities. We find that the quantum Fisher information over the Rob's
cavity shows the periodic degradation behavior depending upon the parameter
$\theta$ as well as the uniform acceleration for both the two qubit pure state
and Werner state. The quantum Fisher information over Alice's cavity remains
invariant throughout the motion of Rob's cavity for the two qubit pure state
whereas for Werner state it is affected by the mixing parameter of the Werner
state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02648</id><created>2015-02-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Salehi</keyname><forenames>Amin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farajollahi</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadeghi</keyname><forenames>Jafar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pourali</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase plane analysis and statefinder diagnostic of agegraphic dark
  energy in 5D Brans-Dicke cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 17 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1201.0007</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an autonomous phase-plane describing the evolution of field
equations containing an agegraphic dark energy in 5D Brans- Dicke cosmology. To
observationally verify the numerical results, we simultaneously solve the
equations by constraining the model parameters with SNe Ia data. We find
conditions for the existence and stability of the critical points (states of
the universe) and numerically examine the cosmological parameters. We also
investigate the model by means of statefinder diagnostic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06697</id><created>2015-04-25</created><updated>2016-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Munehisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akai</keyname><forenames>Hisazumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harashima</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>Shotaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyake</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Relevance of $4f$-$3d$ exchange to finite-temperature magnetism of
  rare-earth permanent magnets: an ab-initio-based spin model approach for
  NdFe$_{12}$N</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, ab initio parameters re-defined sustaining the
  same conclusion, accepted for publication on J. Appl. Phys</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 119, 213901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4952989</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A classical spin model derived ab initio for rare-earth-based permanent
magnet compounds is presented. Our target compound, NdFe$_{12}$N, is a material
that goes beyond today's champion magnet compound Nd$_{2}$Fe$_{14}$B in its
intrinsic magnetic properties with a simpler crystal structure. Calculated
temperature dependence of the magnetization and the anisotropy field agree with
the latest experimental results in the leading order. Having put the realistic
observables under our numerical control, we propose that engineering
$5d$-electron-mediated indirect exchange coupling between $4f$-electrons in Nd
and $3d$-electrons from Fe would most critically help to enhance the material's
utility over the operation-temperature range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.07951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.07951</id><created>2015-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Malyshev</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paston</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokhvatilov</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zubov</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franke</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pauli-Villars Regularization in nonperturbative Hamiltonian approach on
  the Light Front</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX, 10 pages, 2 figures. Article will be published in AIP
  Conference Proceedings, the final publication will be available at
  http://scitation.aip.org/content/aip/proceeding/aipcp</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conference Proceedings, 1701, 100012 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4938721</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The advantage of Pauli-Villars regularization in quantum field theory
quantized on the light front is explained. Simple examples of scalar
$\lambda\varphi^4$ field theory and Yukawa-type model are used. We give also an
example of nonperturbative calculation in the theory with Pauli-Villars fields,
using for that a model of anharmonic oscillator modified by inclusion of ghost
variables playing the role similar to Pauli-Villars fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00272</id><created>2015-05-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Malyshev</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paston</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokhvatilov</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zubov</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franke</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pauli-Villars Regularization and Light Front Hamiltonian in
  (2+1)-dimensional Yang-Mills Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX, 12 pages, 2 figures. Article will be published in Theoretical
  and Mathematical Physics, the final publication will be available at
  http://link.springer.com/journal/11232</comments><journal-ref>Theor. Math. Phys. (2015) 184, 1314-1323</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11232-015-0340-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The renormalization problem of (2+1)-dimensional Yang-Mills theory quantized
on the light front is considered. Extra fields analogous to those used in
Pauli-Villars regularization are introduced to restore perturbative equivalence
between such quantized theory and conventional formulation in Lorentz
coordinates. These fields also provide necessary ultraviolet regularization to
the theory. Obtained results allow to construct renormalized Hamiltonian of the
theory on the light front.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03010</id><created>2015-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Feng-lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Rui-qin</forenames></author></authors><title>Hadronization effects on the baryon-strangeness correlation in quark
  combination models</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C92 (2015) no.4, 044913</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.92.044913</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  The baryon-strangeness correlation in the hadronization of the quark matter
is studied within the quark combination mechanism. We calculate the correlation
coefficient $C_{BS} = -3\big(\langle B S \rangle -\langle B\rangle \langle
S\rangle\big)/\big( \langle S^2 \rangle-\langle S \rangle^2 \big)$ of initial
hadrons produced from the deconfined free quark system with $C^{(q)}_{BS}=1$.
The competition of the production of baryons against that of mesons is the key
dynamics that is most relevant to the change of baryon-strangeness correlation
during system hadronization. Results of quark combination under the Poisson
statistics agree with the statistical model predictions for a hadron resonance
gas at vanishing chemical potential but differ from those at relatively large
chemical potentials. Results beyond Poisson statistics are also obtained and
are compared with calculations of Lattice QCD in the phase boundary, giving the
best agreement at temperature $T =163$ MeV. We predict the dependence of the
$C_{BS}$ of hadron system on the baryon chemical potential and strangeness.
These predictions are expected to be tested by the future Lattice QCD
calculations at non-zero chemical potentials and/or by the Beam Energy Scan
experiment of STAR Collaboration at RHIC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01969</id><created>2015-06-05</created><updated>2015-06-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu-Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiong-Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry Reduction and Boundary Modes for Fe-Chains on an s-wave
  Superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures; some minor errors are corrected</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 475701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/47/475701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the superconducting phase diagram and boundary modes for a
quasi-1D system formed by three Fe-Chains on an s-wave superconductor,
motivated by the recent Princeton experiment. The $\vec l\cdot\vec s$ onsite
spin-orbit term, inter-chain diagonal hopping couplings, and magnetic disorders
in the Fe-chains are shown to be crucial for the superconducting phases, which
can be topologically trivial or nontrivial in different parameter regimes. For
the topological regime a single Majorana and multiple Andreew bound modes are
obtained in the ends of the chain, while for the trivial phase only low-energy
Andreev bound states survive. Nontrivial symmetry reduction mechanism induced
by the $\vec l\cdot\vec s$ term, diagonal hopping couplings, and magnetic
disorder is uncovered to interpret the present results. Our study also implies
that the zero-bias peak observed in the recent experiment may or may not
reflect the Majorana zero modes in the end of the Fe-chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06856</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2016-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Subhajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaudhury</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Samir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-phenomenological analysis of neutron scattering results for
  quasi-two dimensional quantum anti-ferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 table, 6 figures and 1 Appendix, Submitted for
  publication; minor typos are corrected</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Magnetism and Magnetic Materials, 421(2017), 207 - 215</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2016.08.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The available results from the inelastic neutron scattering experiment
performed on the quasi-two dimensional spin $\frac{1}{2}$ anti-ferromagnetic
material $La_2 Cu O_4$ have been analysed theoretically. The formalism of ours
is based on a semi-classical like treatment involving a model of an ideal gas
of mobile vortices and anti-vortices built on the background of the
N$\acute{e}$el state, using the bipartite classical spin configuration
corresponding to an XY- anisotropic Heisenberg anti-ferromagnet on a square
lattice. The results for the integrated intensities for our spin $\frac{1}{2}$
model corresponding to different temperatures, show occurrence of vigorous
unphysical oscillations, when convoluted with a realistic spectral window
function. These results indicate failure of the conventional semi-classical
theoretical model of ideal vortex/anti-vortex gas arising in the
Berezinskii-Kosterlitz-Thouless theory for the low spin magnetic systems. A
full fledged quantum mechanical formalism and calculations seem crucial for the
understanding of topological excitations in such low spin systems. Furthermore,
a severe disagreement is found to occur at finite values of energy transfer
between the integrated intensities obtained theoretically from the conventional
formalism and those obtained experimentally. This further suggests strongly
that the full quantum treatment should also incorporate the interaction between
the fragile-magnons and the topological excitations. This is quite plausible in
view of the recent work establishing such a process in XXZ quantum ferromagnet
on 2D lattice. The high spin XXZ quasi-two dimensional antiferromagnet like
$MnPS_3$ however follows the conventional theory quite well
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07531</id><created>2015-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Baldassare</keyname><forenames>Vivienne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reines</keyname><forenames>Amy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallo</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Jenny</forenames></author></authors><title>A ~50,000 solar mass black hole in the nucleus of RGG 118</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted to ApJL. 6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/2041-8205/809/1/L14</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scaling relations between black hole (BH) masses and their host galaxy
properties have been studied extensively over the last two decades, and point
towards co-evolution of central massive BHs and their hosts. However, these
relations remain poorly constrained for BH masses below $\sim10^{6}$ M_sun.
Here we present optical and X-ray observations of the dwarf galaxy RGG 118
taken with the Magellan Echellette Spectrograph on the 6.5m Clay Telescope and
Chandra X-ray Observatory. Based on Sloan Digital Sky Survey spectroscopy, RGG
118 was identified as possessing narrow emission line ratios indicative of
photoionization partly due to an active galactic nucleus. Our higher resolution
spectroscopy clearly reveals broad H$\alpha$ emission in the spectrum of RGG
118. Using virial BH mass estimate techniques, we calculate a BH mass of
$\sim50,000$ \msun. We detect a nuclear X-ray point source in RGG 118,
suggesting a total accretion powered luminosity of $L=4\times10^{40}~{\rm
erg~s^{-1}}$, and an Eddington fraction of $\sim1$ per cent. The BH in RGG 118
is the smallest ever reported in a galaxy nucleus and we find that it lies on
the extrapolation of the $M_{\rm BH}-\sigma_{\ast}$ relation to the lowest
masses yet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01176</id><created>2015-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Shin</keyname><forenames>Jaeoh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherstvy</keyname><forenames>Andrey G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-subdiffusion in solutions of star-shaped crowders: non-monotonic
  effects of inter-particle interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17, 113028 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/11/113028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine by extensive computer simulations the self-diffusion of
anisotropic star like particles in crowded two-dimensional solutions. We
investigate the implications of the area coverage fraction $\phi$ of the
crowders and the crowder-crowder adhesion properties on the regime of transient
anomalous diffusion. We systematically compute the mean squared displacement
(MSD) of the particles, their time averaged MSD, as well as the effective
diffusion coefficient. The diffusion appears ergodic in the limit of long
traces, such that the time averaged MSD converges towards the ensemble averaged
MSD and features a small residual amplitude spread of the time averaged MSD
from individual trajectories. At intermediate time scales we quantify the
anomalous diffusion in the system. Also, we show that the translational---but
not rotational---diffusivity of the particles $D$ is a non-monotonic function
of the attraction strength between them. Both diffusion coefficients decrease
as $D(\phi)\sim (1-\phi/\phi^*)^2$ with the area fraction $\phi$ occupied by
the crowders. Our results might be applicable to rationalising the experimental
observations of non-Brownian diffusion for a number of standard macromolecular
crowders used in vitro to mimic the cytoplasmic conditions of living cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03192</id><created>2015-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Shin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherstvy</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>W. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Facilitation of polymer looping and giant polymer diffusivity in crowded
  solutions of active particles</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures, IOPLaTeX</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17, 113008 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/11/113008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of polymer chains in a bath of self-propelled particles
(SPP) by extensive Langevin dynamics simulations in a two dimensional system.
Specifically, we analyse the polymer looping properties versus the SPP activity
and investigate how the presence of the active particles alters the chain
conformational statistics. We find that SPPs tend to extend flexible polymer
chains while they rather compactify stiffer semiflexible polymers, in agreement
with previous results. Here we show that larger activities of SPPs yield a
higher effective temperature of the bath and thus facilitate looping kinetics
of a passive polymer chain. We explicitly compute the looping probability and
looping time in a wide range of the model parameters. We also analyse the
motion of a monomeric tracer particle and the polymer's centre of mass in the
presence of the active particles in terms of the time averaged mean squared
displacement, revealing a giant diffusivity enhancement for the polymer chain
via SPP pooling. Our results are applicable to rationalising the dimensions and
looping kinetics of biopolymers at constantly fluctuating and often actively
driven conditions inside biological cells or suspensions of active colloidal
particles or bacteria cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03637</id><created>2015-07-13</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Kyo-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K. -W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickett</keyname><forenames>W. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-orbit interaction driven collective electron-hole excitations in a
  noncentrosymmetric nodal loop Weyl semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages (corrected Fig. 6)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 115149 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.115149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NbP is one member of a new class of nodal loop semimetals characterized by
the cooperative effects of spin-orbit coupling (SOC) and a lack of inversion
center. Here transport and spectroscopic properties of NbP are evaluated using
density functional theory methods. SOC together with the lack of inversion
symmetry splits degeneracies, giving rise to &quot;Russian doll nested&quot; Fermi
surfaces containing 4*10$^{-4}$ electron (hole) carriers/f.u. Due to the modest
SOC strength in Nb, the Fermi surfaces map out the Weyl nodal loops. Calculated
structure around T$^*$~100 K in transport properties reproduces well the
observed transport behavior only when SOC is included, attesting to the
precision of the (delicate) calculations and the stoichiometry of the samples.
Low energy collective electron-hole excitations (plasmons) in the 20-60 meV
range result from the nodal loop splitting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03916</id><created>2015-08-16</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asteroseismology of a $\delta$ Scuti star CoRoT 102749568</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>the paper has been rejected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For $\delta$ Scuti star CoRoT 102749568, 52 independent frequencies were
obtained by Papar$\acute{o}$ et al. 2013. We find that there are 4 multiplets
and 8 doublets with nearly equal split caused by rotation. Differential
rotation is suggested instead of rigid body rotation to explain the equal split
phenomenon. Grids of models are computed with MESA to fit observational
frequencies of CoRoT 102749568. After rejecting modes of $m\neq0$ in multiplets
and doublets, we identify 31 modes of $m = 0$ and 3 modes of $m\neq0$,
including 4 modes of $l = 0$, 9 modes of $l=1$, 11 modes of $l=2$, and 10 modes
of $l=3$. The mean error is 0.447$\mu$Hz for the best-fitting model, and the
physical parameters of the corresponding model are as followings: $M=1.95$ $\rm
M_{\odot}$, $Z=0.025$, $T_{\rm eff}=7096$ K, log$g=3.727$, $L=22.77$ $\rm
L_{\odot}$, $Age=1.113$ Gyr.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05743</id><created>2015-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Jian-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Wei-Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial classification of cuspidal simple modules for Virasoro-like
  algebra</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><msc-class>17B10, 17B63, 17B65, 17B66, 17B68, 17B70</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Algebra, 464 (2016) 266-278</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jalgebra.2016.06.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $\mathfrak P$ be the Lie algebra of Hamiltonian vector fields on the
torus, which is also known as the Virasoro-like algebra, a special kind of the
so-called Block type Lie algebra. And let $\mathfrak A$ be the Laurent
polynomial algebra in two variables. In this paper, by following S.E. Rao's
strategy of &quot;backward induction&quot;, we prove that any quasi-finite simple
$(\mathfrak A,\mathfrak P)$-module has to come from Larsson-Shen's
construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00518</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00518</id><created>2015-09-01</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>DeWolfe</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gubser</keyname><forenames>Steven S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henriksson</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosen</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermionic Response in Finite-Density ABJM Theory with Broken Symmetry</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>44 pages, 12 figures. v2: significant reinterpretation of Dirac
  mixing matrix as not being top-down</comments><report-no>COLO-HEP-588, PUPT-2485, CCTP-2015-18, CCQCN-2015-101</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 026001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.026001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate fermionic response in domain wall backgrounds of
four-dimensional gauged supergravity interpolating between distinct stable AdS
vacua. The backgrounds, found by Bobev et al., are holographically dual to
zero-temperature states of ABJM theory at finite density for monopole charge
and are similar to zero-temperature limits of holographic superconductors, but
with a symmetry-breaking source as well. The condensed scalar mixes charged and
neutral fields dual to composite fermionic operators in the Dirac equations.
Both gapped and gapless bands of stable quasiparticles are found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02629</id><created>2015-09-08</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Techakesari</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nurdin</keyname><forenames>H. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Error Bounds for Finite-Dimensional Approximations of Input-Output Open
  Quantum Systems by Subspace Truncation and Adiabatic Elimination</title><categories>quant-ph cs.SY math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>33 pages. A preliminary condensed version of this work appeared in
  Proceedings of the 54th IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (CDC) (Osaka,
  Japan, December 15-18, 2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An important class of physical systems that are of interest in practice are
input-output open quantum systems that can be described by quantum stochastic
differential equations and defined on an infinite-dimensional underlying
Hilbert space. Most commonly, these systems involve coupling to a quantum
harmonic oscillator as a system component. This paper is concerned with error
bounds in the finite-dimensional approximations of input-output open quantum
systems defined on an infinite-dimensional Hilbert space. We develop a
framework for developing error bounds between the time evolution of the state
of a class of infinite-dimensional quantum systems and its approximation on a
finite-dimensional subspace of the original, when both are initialized in the
latter subspace. This framework is then applied to two approaches for obtaining
finite-dimensional approximations: subspace truncation and adiabatic
elimination. Applications of the bounds to some physical examples drawn from
the literature are provided to illustrate our results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07672</id><created>2015-09-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mailler</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;cile</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;rters</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueltschi</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Condensation and symmetry-breaking in the zero-range process with weak
  site disorder</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Stoch. Proc. Appl. 126, 3283-3309 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.spa.2016.04.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Condensation phenomena in particle systems typically occur as one of two
distinct types: either as a spontaneous symmetry breaking in a homogeneous
system, in which particle interactions enforce condensation in a randomly
located site, or as an explicit symmetry breaking in a system with background
disorder, in which particles condensate in the site of extremal disorder. In
this paper we confirm a recent conjecture by Godr\`eche and Luck by showing,
for a zero range process with weak site disorder, that there exists a phase
where condensation occurs with an intermediate type of symmetry-breaking, in
which particles condensate in a site randomly chosen from a range of sites
favoured by disorder. We show that this type of condensation is characterised
by the occurrence of a Gamma distribution in the law of the disorder at the
condensation site. We further investigate fluctuations of the condensate size
and confirm a phase diagram, again conjectured by Godr\`eche and Luck, showing
the existence of phases with normal and anomalous fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08430</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2015-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cherqui</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakkar</keyname><forenames>Niket</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camden</keyname><forenames>Jon P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masiello</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizing localized surface plasmons using electron energy-loss
  spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>When citing this paper, please use the following: Cherqui C, Thakkar
  N, Li G, Camden JP, Masiello DJ. 2015. Characterizing localized surface
  plasmons using electron energy-loss spectroscopy. Annu. Rev. Phys. Chem. 67:
  Submitted. Doi: 10.1146/annurev-physchem-040214-121612</comments><doi>10.1146/annurev-physchem-040214-121612</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron energy-loss spectroscopy (EELS) offers a window to view nanoscale
properties and processes. When performed in a scanning transmission electron
microscope, EELS can simultaneously render images of nanoscale objects with
sub-nanometer spatial resolution and correlate them with spectroscopic
information of $\sim10 - 100$ meV spectral resolution. Consequently, EELS is a
near-perfect tool for understanding the optical and electronic properties of
individual and few-particle plasmonic metal nanoparticles assemblies, which are
significant in a wide range of fields. This review presents an overview of
basic plasmonics and EELS theory and highlights several recent noteworthy
experiments involving the electron-beam interrogation of plasmonic metal
nanoparticle systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00932</id><created>2015-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Godec</keyname><forenames>Aljaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>First passage time distribution in heterogeneity controlled kinetics:
  going beyond the mean first passage time</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, IOP LaTeX</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 20349 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep20349</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first passage is a generic concept for quantifying when a random quantity
such as the position of a diffusing molecule or the value of a stock crosses a
preset threshold (target) for the first time. The last decade saw an
enlightening series of new results focusing mostly on the so-called mean and
global first passage time (MFPT and GFPT, respectively) of such processes. Here
we push the understanding of first passage processes a step further. For a
simple heterogeneous system we derive rigorously the complete distribution of
first passage times (FPTs). Our results demonstrate that the typical FPT
significantly differs from the MFPT, which corresponds to the long time
behaviour of the FPT distribution. Conversely, the short time behaviour is
shown to correspond to trajectories connecting directly from the initial value
to the target. Remarkably, we reveal a previously overlooked third
characteristic time scale of the first passage dynamics mirroring brief
excursion away from the target.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02060</id><created>2015-10-07</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutra</keyname><forenames>Mariana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louren&#xe7;o</keyname><forenames>Odilon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>D&#xe9;bora P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stellar properties and nuclear matter constraints</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>Published version in Phys. Rev. C along with an erratum that corrects
  a technical mistake in the calculations concerning two specific
  parametrizations, namely, DDH\delta and DD-ME\delta. New corrected figures
  and tables regarding these two parametrizations are provided</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 025806 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.025806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analyzed stellar properties of the relativistic mean-field (RMF)
parametrizations shown to be consistent with the recently studied constraints
related to nuclear matter, pure neutron matter, symmetry energy and its
derivatives [Dutra et al., Phys. Rev. C 90, 055203 (2014)]. Our results show
that only two RMF parametrizations do not allow the emergence of the direct
Urca process, important aspect regarding the evolution of a neutron star.
Moreover, among all approved RMF models, fourteen of them produce neutron stars
with maximum masses inside the range $1.93\leqslant M/M_\odot\leqslant 2.05$,
with $M_\odot$ being the solar mass. Only three models yield maximum masses
above this range and a discussion on the inclusion of hyperons is presented.
Finally, we have verified that the models satisfying the neutron star maximum
mass constraint do not observe the squared sound velocity bound, namely, $v_s^2
&lt; 1/3$, corroborating recent findings. However, the recently proposed
$\sigma$-cut scheme can make the RMF models consistent with both constraints
depending on the isoscalar-vector interaction of each parametrization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02170</id><created>2015-10-07</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Phan</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauer</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>E. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loomba</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>J. A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>GEM-based TPC with CCD Imaging for Directional Dark Matter Detection</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><doi>10.1016/j.astropartphys.2016.08.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The world's leading directional dark matter experiments currently all utilize
low-pressure gas Time Projection Chamber (TPC) technologies. We discuss some of
the challenges for this technology, for which balancing the goal of achieving
the best sensitivity with that of cost effective scale-up requires optimization
over a large parameter space. Critical for this are the precision measurements
of the fundamental properties of both electron and nuclear recoil tracks down
to the lowest detectable energies. Such measurements are necessary to provide a
benchmark for background discrimination and directional sensitivity that could
be used for future optimization studies for directional dark matter
experiments. In this paper we describe a small, high resolution, high signal-
to-noise GEM-based TPC with a 2D CCD readout designed for this goal. The
performance of the detector was characterized using alpha particles, X-rays,
gamma-rays, and neutrons, enabling detailed measurements of electron and
nuclear recoil tracks. Stable effective gas gains of greater than $1 \times
10^5$ were obtained in 100 Torr of pure CF$_4$ by a cascade of three standard
CERN GEMs each with a 140 $\mu$m pitch. The high signal-to-noise and
sub-millimeter spatial resolution of the GEM amplification and CCD readout,
together with low diffusion, allow for excellent background discrimination
between electron and nuclear recoils down below $\sim$10 keVee ($\sim$23 keVr
fluorine recoil). Even lower thresholds, necessary for the detection of low
mass WIMPs for example, might be achieved by lowering the pressure and
utilizing full 3D track reconstruction. These and other paths for improvements
are discussed, as are possible fundamental limitations imposed by the physics
of energy loss.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06830</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06830</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ozawa</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayami</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barros</keyname><forenames>Kipton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chern</keyname><forenames>Gia-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motome</keyname><forenames>Yukitoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batista</keyname><forenames>Cristian D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vortex Crystals with Chiral Stripes in Itinerant Magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 103703 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.103703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study noncoplanar magnetic ordering in frustrated itinerant magnets. For a
family of Kondo square lattice models with classical local moments, we find
that a double-$Q$ noncoplanar vortex crystal has lower energy than the
single-$Q$ helical order expected from the Ruderman-Kittel-Kasuya-Yosida
interaction whenever the lattice symmetry dictates four global maxima in the
bare magnetic susceptibility. By expanding in the small Kondo exchange and the
degree of noncoplanarity, we demonstrate that this noncoplanar state arises
from a Fermi surface instability, and it is generic for a wide range of
electron filling fractions whenever the two ordering wave vectors connect
independent sections of the Fermi surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02636</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Rashid</forenames></author></authors><title>Debye mass of massless \phi^4-theory to order g^6 at weak coupling</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due a crucial error in
  calculation</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the Debye mass of massless \phi^4-theory to order g^6 at weak
coupling. The contributions to the Debye mass arise from the hard momentum
scale of order T and the soft momentum scale of order gT. Effective field
theory methods and dimensional reduction are used to separate the contributions
from the two momentum scales. The hard contribution can be calculated as a
power series in g^2 using naive perturbation theory with bare propagators. The
soft contribution is calculated using an effective theory in three dimensions,
whose coefficients are power series in g^2. This contribution is a power series
in g starting at order g^3. The calculation of the hard part to order g^6. The
calculation of the soft part requires calculating the mass parameter in the
effective theory to order g^6 and the evaluation of four-loop self-energy
diagrams in three dimensions. This gives the Debye mass correct up to order
g^6. We discuss the convergence of the perturbative series as well as the loop
expansion in three dimensions which implies a selective resummation of
higher-order terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03573</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yaida</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>Ludovic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charbonneau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarjus</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author></authors><title>Point-to-set lengths, local structure, and glassiness</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures; v2: Fig.4 added, presentation improved. Data
  relevant to this work can be accessed at http://doi.org/10.7924/G8BG2KWP</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032605 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The growing sluggishness of glass-forming liquids is thought to be
accompanied by growing structural order. The nature of such order, however,
remains hotly debated. A decade ago, point-to-set (PTS) correlation lengths
were proposed as measures of amorphous order in glass formers, but recent
results raise doubts as to their generality. Here, we extend the definition of
PTS correlations to agnostically capture any type of growing order in liquids,
be it local or amorphous. This advance enables the formulation of a clear
distinction between slowing down due to conventional critical ordering and that
due to glassiness, and provides a unified framework to assess the relative
importance of specific local order and generic amorphous order in glass
formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04118</id><created>2015-11-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Karpov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oelsner</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greenberg</keyname><forenames>Ya. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilichev</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signal amplification in a qubit-resonator system</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Low Temp. Phys. 42, 189 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4942759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of a qubit-resonator system, when the resonator is
driven by two signals. The interaction of the qubit with the high-amplitude
driving we consider in terms of the qubit dressed states. Interaction of the
dressed qubit with the second probing signal can essentially change the
amplitude of this signal. We calculate the transmission amplitude of the probe
signal through the resonator as a function of the qubit's energy and the
driving frequency detuning. The regions of increase and attenuation of the
transmitted signal are calculated and demonstrated graphically. We present the
influence of the signal parameters on the value of the amplification, and
discuss the values of the qubit-resonator system parameters for an optimal
amplification and attenuation of the weak probe signal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07266</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuffrida</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denaro</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pizzolato</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curcio</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spagnolo</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basilone</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonanno</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise Induced Phenomena in the Dynamics of Two Competing Species</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>23 pages, 8 figures; to be published in Math. Model. Nat. Phenom.
  (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Noise through its interaction with the nonlinearity of the living systems can
give rise to counter-intuitive phenomena. In this paper we shortly review noise
induced effects in different ecosystems, in which two populations compete for
the same resources. We also present new results on spatial patterns of two
populations, while modeling real distributions of anchovies and sardines. The
transient dynamics of these ecosystems are analyzed through generalized
Lotka-Volterra equations in the presence of multiplicative noise, which models
the interaction between the species and the environment. We find noise induced
phenomena such as quasi-deterministic oscillations, stochastic resonance, noise
delayed extinction, and noise induced pattern formation. In addition, our
theoretical results are validated with experimental findings. Specifically the
results, obtained by a coupled map lattice model, well reproduce the spatial
distributions of anchovies and sardines, observed in a marine ecosystem.
Moreover, the experimental dynamical behavior of two competing bacterial
populations in a meat product and the probability distribution at long times of
one of them are well reproduced by a stochastic microbial predictive model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03846</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hauru</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evenbly</keyname><forenames>Glen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Wen Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaiotto</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>Guifre</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological conformal defects with tensor networks</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages + 7 pages of appendices. 30 figures; v2: Added a note and
  Python 3 source code, plus minor fixes; v3: Typos &amp; aesthetics</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The critical 2d classical Ising model on the square lattice has two
topological conformal defects: the $\mathbb{Z}_2$ symmetry defect
$D_{\epsilon}$ and the Kramers-Wannier duality defect $D_{\sigma}$. These two
defects implement antiperiodic boundary conditions and a more exotic form of
twisted boundary conditions, respectively. On the torus, the partition function
$Z_{D}$ of the critical Ising model in the presence of a topological conformal
defect $D$ is expressed in terms of the scaling dimensions $\Delta_{\alpha}$
and conformal spins $s_{\alpha}$ of a distinct set of primary fields (and their
descendants, or conformal towers) of the Ising CFT. This characteristic
conformal data $\{\Delta_{\alpha}, s_{\alpha}\}_{D}$ can be extracted from the
eigenvalue spectrum of a transfer matrix $M_{D}$ for the partition function
$Z_D$. In this paper we investigate the use of tensor network techniques to
both represent and coarse-grain the partition functions $Z_{D_\epsilon}$ and
$Z_{D_\sigma}$ of the critical Ising model with either a symmetry defect
$D_{\epsilon}$ or a duality defect $D_{\sigma}$. We also explain how to
coarse-grain the corresponding transfer matrices $M_{D_\epsilon}$ and
$M_{D_\sigma}$, from which we can extract accurate numerical estimates of
$\{\Delta_{\alpha}, s_{\alpha}\}_{D_{\epsilon}}$ and $\{\Delta_{\alpha},
s_{\alpha}\}_{D_{\sigma}}$. Two key new ingredients of our approach are (i)
coarse-graining of the defect $D$, which applies to any (i.e. not just
topological) conformal defect and yields a set of associated scaling dimensions
$\Delta_{\alpha}$, and (ii) construction and coarse-graining of a generalized
translation operator using a local unitary transformation that moves the
defect, which only exist for topological conformal defects and yields the
corresponding conformal spins $s_{\alpha}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05443</id><created>2016-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Minsung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ihm</keyname><forenames>Jisoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Suk Bum</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly enhanced Rashba splittings in oxide heterostructure: a
  tantalite monolayer on BaHfO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115431 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the two-dimensional electron gas (2DEG) emerging at the transition metal
oxide surface and interface, it has been pointed out that the Rashba spin-orbit
interaction, the momentum-dependent spin splitting due to broken inversion
symmetry and atomic spin-orbit coupling, can have profound effects on
electronic ordering in the spin, orbit, and charge channels, and may help give
rise to exotic phenomena such as ferromagnetism-superconductivity coexistence
and topological superconductivity. Although a large Rashba splitting is
expected to improve experimental accessibility of such phenomena, it has not
been understood how we can maximally enhance this splitting. Here, we present a
promising route to realize significant Rashba-type band splitting using a thin
film heterostructure. Based on first-principles methods and analytic model
analyses, a tantalate monolayer on BaHfO$_3$ is shown to host two-dimensional
bands originating from Ta $t_{2g}$ states with strong Rashba spin splittings -
up to nearly 10% of the bandwidth - at both the band minima and saddle points
due to the maximal breaking of the inversion symmetry. Such 2DEG band structure
makes this oxide heterostructure a promising platform for realizing both a
topological superconductor which hosts Majorana fermions and the electron
correlation physics with strong spin-orbit coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06049</id><created>2016-01-22</created><updated>2016-05-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harder</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Lihui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Match</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirker</keyname><forenames>Jesko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Can-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the cavity-magnon-polariton transmission line shape</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. China Phys. Mech. Astron. 59, 117511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11433-016-0228-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally and theoretically investigate the microwave transmission
line shape of the cavity-magnon-polariton (CMP) created by inserting a low
damping magnetic insulator into a high quality 3D microwave cavity. While fixed
field measurements are found to have the expected Lorentzian characteristic, at
fixed frequencies the field swept line shape is in general asymmetric. Such
fixed frequency measurements demonstrate that microwave transmission can be
used to access magnetic characteristics of the CMP, such as the field line
width $\Delta H$. By developing an effective oscillator model of the microwave
transmission we show that these line shape features are general characteristics
of harmonic coupling. At the same time, at the classical level the underlying
physical mechanism of the CMP is electrodynamic phase correlation and a second
model based on this principle also accurately reproduces the experimental line
shape features. In order to understand the microscopic origin of the effective
coupled oscillator model and to allow for future studies of CMP phenomena to
extend into the quantum regime, we develop a third, microscopic description,
based on a Green's function formalism. Using this method we calculate the
transmission spectra and find good agreement with the experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07764</id><created>2016-01-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cobanera</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>What is a particle-conserving Topological Superfluid?</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 372, 357 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.05.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish a criterion for characterizing superfluidity in interacting,
particle-number conserving systems of fermions as topologically trivial or
non-trivial. Because our criterion is based on the concept of many-body
fermionic parity switches, it is directly associated to the observation of the
fractional Josephson effect and indicates the emergence of zero-energy modes
that anticommute with fermionic parity. We tested these ideas on the
Richardson-Gaudin-Kitaev chain, a particle-number conserving system that is
solvable by way of the algebraic Bethe ansatz, and reduces to a long-range
Kitaev chain in the mean-field approximation. Guided by its closed-form
solution, we introduce a procedure for constructing many-body Majorana
zero-energy modes of gapped topological superfluids in terms of coherent
superpositions of states with different number of fermions. We discuss their
significance and the physical conditions required to enable quantum control in
the light of superselection rules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01621</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carpentier</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Mario S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>VItorino</keyname><forenames>Miguel V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevrier</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency dependent visco-elastic properties of a water nanomeniscus :
  an AFM study in Force Feedback Mode</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, using an Atomic Force Microscope and a single cantilever excited at
different frequencies it was shown that water nanomeniscus can exhibit a
transition in mechanical responses when submitted to stimuli above few tens of
kHz. The use of a single cantilever to explore phenomena at frequencies far
from the cantilever resonance frequency is not a common and well-established
strategy, and because water meniscus are ubiquitous in nature, we have also
studied the water meniscus mechanical response, the stiffness G' (N/m) and the
dissipation G&quot;(kg/s), as a function of frequency by using cantilevers with
different resonance frequencies. These results, based on classic dynamical AFM
technics, confirm the anomalous mechanical response of water nanomeniscus when
stimulated at frequencies high enough.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02511</id><created>2016-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kamano</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-quark baryon spectroscopy within ANL-Osaka dynamical
  coupled-channels approach</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of ECT* Workshop
  on Nucleon Resonances: From Photoproduction to High Photon Virtualities,
  Trento, Italy, October 12-16, 2015</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst. 57, 933 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-016-1130-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent results on the study of light-quark baryons with the ANL-Osaka
dynamical coupled-channels (DCC) approach are presented, which contain the N*
and Delta* spectroscopy via the analysis of pi N and gamma N reactions and the
Lambda* and Sigma* spectroscopy via the analysis of K- p reactions. A recent
application of our DCC approach to neutrino-nucleon reactions in the resonance
region is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08652</id><created>2016-02-27</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoover</keyname><forenames>William Graham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sprott</keyname><forenames>Julien Clinton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoover</keyname><forenames>Carol Griswold</forenames></author></authors><title>A Tutorial: Adaptive Runge-Kutta Integration for Stiff Systems :
  Comparing the Nos\'e and Nos\'e-Hoover Oscillator Dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.CD physics.class-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>24 pages with ten figures written for the American Journal of Physics
  --- Both here and in the published AJP version of October 2016 the time
  ranges shown in Figure 3 were permuted. 0 to 200 corresponds to the upper
  portion and 750 to 790 to the lower portion. We regret the error</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  &quot;Stiff&quot; differential equations are commonplace in engineering and dynamical
systems. To solve them we need flexible integrators that can deal with
rapidly-changing righthand sides. This tutorial describes the application of
&quot;adaptive&quot; [ variable timestep ] integrators to &quot;stiff&quot; mechanical problems
encountered in modern applications of Gibbs' 1902 statistical mechanics. Linear
harmonic oscillators subject to nonlinear thermal constraints can exhibit
either stiff or smooth dynamics. Two closely-related examples, Nos\'e's 1984
dynamics and Nos\'e-Hoover 1985 dynamics, are both based on Hamiltonian
mechanics, as was ultimately clarified by Dettmann and Morriss in 1996. Both
these dynamics are consistent with Gibbs' canonical ensemble. Nos\'e's dynamics
is &quot;stiff&quot; and can present severe numerical difficulties. Nos\'e-Hoover
dynamics, though it follows exactly the same trajectory, is &quot;smooth&quot; and
relatively trouble-free. Our tutorial emphasises the power of adaptive
integrators to resolve stiff problems like the Nos\'e oscillator. The solutions
obtained illustrate the power of computer graphics to enrich numerical
solutions. Adaptive integration with computer graphics are basic to an
understanding of dynamical systems and statistical mechanics. These tools lead
naturally into the visualization of intricate fractal structures formed by
chaos as well as elaborate knots tied by regular nonchaotic dynamics. This work
was invited by the American Journal of Physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.09068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.09068</id><created>2016-02-29</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dittmann</keyname><forenames>Niklas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Splettstoesser</keyname><forenames>Janine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giazotto</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Clocked single-spin source based on a spin-split superconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 083019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/8/083019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an accurate clocked single-spin source for ac-spintronic
applications. Our device consists of a superconducting island covered by a
ferromagnetic insulator layer through which it is coupled to superconducting
leads. Single-particle transfer relies on the energy gaps and the island's
charging energy, and is enabled by a bias and a time-periodic gate voltage.
Accurate spin transfer is achieved by the ferromagnetic insulator layer which
polarizes the island, provides spin-selective tunneling barriers and improves
the precision by suppressing Andreev reflection. We analyze realistic material
combinations and experimental requirements which allow for a clocked spin
current in the MHz regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00245</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Neilinger</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bog&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reh&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oelsner</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;bner</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Astafiev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grajcar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Il'ichev</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau-Zener-St\&quot;uckelberg-Majorana lasing in circuit QED</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 094519 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094519</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate amplification (and attenuation) of a probe signal by a driven
two-level quantum system in the Landau-Zener-St\&quot;{u}ckelberg-Majorana regime by
means of an experiment, in which a superconducting qubit was strongly coupled
to a microwave cavity, in a conventional arrangement of circuit quantum
electrodynamics. Two different types of flux qubit, specifically a conventional
Josephson junctions qubit and a phase-slip qubit, show similar results, namely,
lasing at the working points where amplification takes place. The experimental
data are explained by the interaction of the probe signal with Rabi-like
oscillations. The latter are created by constructive interference of
Landau-Zener-St\&quot;{u}ckelberg-Majorana (LZSM) transitions during the driving
period of the qubit. A detailed description of the occurrence of these
oscillations and a comparison of obtained data with both analytic and numerical
calculations are given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03749</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03749</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-09-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dotti</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author></authors><title>Black hole nonmodal linear stability: the Schwarzschild (A)dS cases</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Typos corrected, changes in the Introduction (including example of
  nonmodal instability)</comments><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav. 33 (2016) 205005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/20/205005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonmodal linear stability of the Schwarzschild black hole established in
Phys. Rev. Lett. 112 (2014) 191101 is generalized to the case of a nonnegative
cosmological constant $\Lambda$. Two gauge invariant combinations $G_{\pm}$ of
perturbed scalars made out of the Weyl tensor and its first covariant
derivative are found such that the map $[h_{\alpha \beta}] \to \left( G_-
\left([h_{\alpha \beta}] \right), G_+ \left([h_{\alpha \beta}] \right) \right)$
with domain the set of equivalent classes $[h_{\alpha \beta}]$ under gauge
transformations of solutions of the linearized Einstein's equation, is
invertible. The way to reconstruct a representative of $[h_{\alpha \beta}]$ in
terms of $(G_-,G_+)$ is given. It is proved that, for an arbitrary perturbation
consistent with the background asymptote, $G_+$ and $G_-$ are bounded in the
the outer static region. At large times, the perturbation decays leaving a
linearized Kerr black hole around the Schwarzschild or Schwarschild de Sitter
background solution. For negative cosmological constant it is shown that there
is a choice of boundary conditions at the time-like boundary under which the
Schwarzschild anti de Sitter black hole is unstable. The root of
Chandrasekhar's duality relating odd and even modes is exhibited, and some
technicalities related to this duality and omitted in the original proof of the
$\Lambda=0$ case are explained in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03759</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agarwalla</keyname><forenames>Sanjib Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>Sabya Sachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palazzo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Physics Reach of DUNE with a Light Sterile Neutrino</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>26 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables. Minor revisions. Accepted in JHEP</comments><report-no>IP/BBSR/2016-3</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the implications of one light eV scale sterile neutrino on the
physics potential of the proposed long-baseline experiment DUNE. If the future
short-baseline experiments confirm the existence of sterile neutrinos, then it
can affect the mass hierarchy (MH) and CP-violation (CPV) searches at DUNE. The
MH sensitivity still remains above 5$\sigma$ if the three new mixing angles
($\theta_{14}, \theta_{24}, \theta_{34}$) are all close to $\theta_{13}$. In
contrast, it can decrease to 4$\sigma$ if the least constrained mixing angle
$\theta_{34}$ is close to its upper limit $\sim 30^0$. We also assess the
sensitivity to the CPV induced both by the standard CP-phase $\delta_{13}
\equiv \delta$, and the new CP-phases $\delta_{14}$ and $\delta_{34}$. In the
3+1 scheme, the discovery potential of CPV induced by $\delta_{13}$ gets
deteriorated compared to the 3$\nu$ case. In particular, the maximal
sensitivity (reached around $\delta_{13}$ $\sim$ $\pm$ $90^0$) decreases from
$5\sigma$ to $4\sigma$ if all the three new mixing angles are close to
$\theta_{13}$. It can further diminish to almost $3\sigma$ if $\theta_{34}$ is
large ($\sim 30^0$). The sensitivity to the CPV due to $\delta_{14}$ can reach
3$\sigma$ for an appreciable fraction of its true values. Interestingly,
$\theta_{34}$ and its associated phase $\delta_{34}$ can influence both the
$\nu_e$ appearance and $\nu_\mu$ disappearance channels via matter effects,
which in DUNE are pronounced. Hence, DUNE can also probe CPV induced by
$\delta_{34}$ provided $\theta_{34}$ is large. We also reconstruct the two
phases $\delta_{13}$ and $\delta_{14}$. The typical 1$\sigma$ uncertainty on
$\delta_{13}$ ($\delta_{14}$) is $\sim20^0$ ($30^0$) if $\theta_{34} =0$. The
reconstruction of $\delta_{14}$ (but not that of $\delta_{13}$) degrades if
$\theta_{34}$ is large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05805</id><created>2016-03-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Jian-Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chowdhury</keyname><forenames>S. Hasibul Hassan</forenames></author></authors><title>Deformation of Noncommutative Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>11 pages, no figure</comments><msc-class>17B37, 20G42, 81R50</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 091703 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4963142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the Lie group $G_{NC}^{\alpha,\beta,\gamma}$, of which the
kinematical symmetry group $G_{NC}$ of noncommutative quantum mechanics (NCQM)
is a special case due to fixed nonzero $\alpha$, $\beta$ and $\gamma$, is
three-parameter deformation quantized using the method suggested by Ballesteros
and Musso in &quot;Quantum Algebras as Quantizations of Dual Poisson-Lie Groups&quot; [J.
Phys. A: Math. Theor., 46 (2013), 195203]. A certain family of QUE algebras,
corresponding to $G_{NC}^{\alpha,\beta,\gamma}$ with two of the deformation
parameters approaching zero, is found to be in agreement with the existing
results of the literature on quantum Heisenberg group. Finally, we dualize the
underlying QUE algebra to obtain an expression for the underlying star-product
between smooth functions on $G_{NC}^{\alpha,\beta,\gamma}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06959</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Youngshin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>James T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Lifshitz fermions and exponentially suppressed spectral
  weight</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figure, references added and comments on exponential
  suppression of spectral weight clarified</comments><report-no>MCTP-16-07, YITP-SB-16-7</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The absence of fixed momentum excitations in a theory with Lifshitz scale
invariance gives rise to exponential suppression of spectral weight in the
low-frequency limit. In the holographic dual, this suppression arises as a
consequence of a tunneling barrier that decouples the horizon from the
boundary. We compute the spin-1/2 holographic Green's function and show that
the form of the barrier is identical to that of the scalar case. We furthermore
demonstrate that the suppression factor is universal in the $\hat\omega\to0$
limit where $\hat\omega=\omega/|\vec k|^z$. In particular, it depends only on
$\hat\omega$ and the critical exponent $z$, and is independent of scaling
dimension and spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08387</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kiktenko</keyname><forenames>E. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trushechkin</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurochkin</keyname><forenames>Y. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Post-processing procedure for industrial quantum key distribution
  systems</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>5 pages; presented at the 3rd International School and Conference
  &quot;Saint-Petersburg OPEN 2016&quot; (Saint-Petersburg, March 28-30, 2016)</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 741, 012081 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/741/1/012081</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present algorithmic solutions aimed on post-processing for industrial
quantum key distribution systems with hardware sifting. The main steps of the
procedure are error correction, parameter estimation, and privacy
amplification. Authentication of a classical public communication channel is
also considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03129</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Corzo</keyname><forenames>N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gouraud</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goban</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheremet</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupriyanov</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurat</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Bragg Reflection from One-Dimensional Chains of Trapped Atoms Near
  a Nanoscale Waveguide</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Minor corrections. Close to published version. See also the
  associated Focus in Physics http://physics.aps.org/articles/v9/109</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 133603 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.133603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report experimental observations of large Bragg reflection from arrays of
cold atoms trapped near a one-dimensional nanoscale waveguide. By using an
optical lattice in the evanescent field surrounding a nanofiber with a period
nearly commensurate with the resonant wavelength, we observe a reflectance of
up to 75% for the guided mode. Each atom behaves as a partially-reflecting
mirror and an ordered chain of about 2000 atoms is sufficient to realize an
efficient Bragg mirror. Measurements of the reflection spectra as a function of
the lattice period and the probe polarization are reported. The latter shows
the effect of the chiral character of nanoscale waveguides on this reflection.
The ability to control photon transport in 1D waveguides coupled to spin
systems would enable novel quantum network capabilities and the study of
many-body effects emerging from long-range interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04276</id><created>2016-04-14</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertini</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fagotti</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the Nonequilibrium Steady State Emerging from a Defect</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures; v3: published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 130402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.130402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the non-equilibrium time evolution of a translationally invariant
state under a Hamiltonian with a localized defect. We discern the situations
where a light-cone spreads out from the defect and separates the system into
regions with macroscopically different properties. We identify the light-cone
and propose a procedure to obtain a (quasi-)stationary state describing the
late time dynamics of local observables. As an explicit example, we study the
time evolution generated by the Hamiltonian of the transverse-field Ising chain
with a local defect that cuts the interaction between two sites (a quench of
the boundary conditions alongside a global quench). We solve the dynamics
exactly and show that the late time properties can be obtained with the general
method proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06077</id><created>2016-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Block</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fast</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn Johansson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundgren</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhdanov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;&#xf6;k</keyname><forenames>Fredrik</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Dimensional Flow Nanometry of Biological Nanoparticles for Accurate
  Determination of Their Size and Emission Intensity</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>28 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12956 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12956</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biological nanoparticles (BNPs) are of high interest due to their key role in
various biological processes and use as biomarkers. BNP size and molecular
composition are decisive for their functions, but simultaneous determination of
both properties with high accuracy remains challenging, which is a severe
limitation. Surface-sensitive microscopy allows one to precisely determine
fluorescence or scattering intensity, but not the size of individual BNPs. The
latter is better determined by tracking their random motion in bulk, but the
limited illumination volume for tracking this motion impedes reliable intensity
determination. We here show that attaching BNPs (specifically, vesicles and
functionalized gold NPs) to a supported lipid bilayer, subjecting them to a
hydrodynamic flow, and tracking their motion via surface-sensitive imaging
enable to determine their diffusion coefficients and flow-induced drift
velocities and to accurately quantify both BNP size and emission intensity. For
vesicles, the high accuracy is demonstrated by resolving the expected
radius-squared dependence of their fluorescence intensity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06780</id><created>2016-04-22</created><updated>2016-04-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dmytruk</keyname><forenames>Olesia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trif</keyname><forenames>Mircea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson effect in topological superconducting rings coupled to a
  microwave cavity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, extra references added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115423 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study a one dimensional p-wave superconducting mesoscopic
ring interrupted by a weak link and coupled inductively to a microwave cavity.
We establish an input-output description for the cavity field in the presence
of the ring, and identify the electronic contributions to the cavity response
and their dependence on various parameters, such as the magnetic flux, chemical
potential, and cavity frequency. We show that the cavity response is $4\pi$
periodic as a function of the magnetic flux in the topological region, stemming
from the so called fractional Josephson current carried by the Majorana
fermions, while it is $2\pi$ periodic in the non-topological phase, consistent
with the normal Josephson effect. We find a strong dependence of the signal on
the cavity frequency, as well as on the parity of the ground state. Our model
takes into account fully the interplay between the low-energy Majorana modes
and the gaped bulks states, which we show is crucial for visualizing the
evolution of the Josephson effect during the transition from the topological to
the trivial phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08140</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boyle</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>How should spin-weighted spherical functions be defined?</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Final version as published</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 092504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962723</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin-weighted spherical functions provide a useful tool for analyzing
tensor-valued functions on the sphere. A tensor field can be decomposed into
complex-valued functions by taking contractions with tangent vectors on the
sphere and the normal to the sphere. These component functions are usually
presented as functions on the sphere itself, but this requires an implicit
choice of distinguished tangent vectors with which to contract. Thus, we may
more accurately say that spin-weighted spherical functions are functions of
both a point on the sphere and a choice of frame in the tangent space at that
point. The distinction becomes extremely important when transforming the
coordinates in which these functions are expressed, because the implicit choice
of frame will also transform. Here, it is proposed that spin-weighted spherical
functions should be treated as functions on the spin group. This approach more
cleanly reflects the geometry involved, and allows for a more elegant
description of the behavior of spin-weighted functions. In this form, the
spin-weighted spherical harmonics have simple expressions as elements of the
Wigner $\mathfrak{D}$ representations, and transformations under rotation are
simple. Two variants of the angular-momentum operator are defined directly in
terms of the spin group; one is the standard angular-momentum operator
$\mathbf{L}$, while the other is shown to be related to the spin-raising
operator $\eth$. Computer code is also included, providing an explicit
implementation of the spin-weighted spherical harmonics in this form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00925</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetry Breaking as a new source for the Generalized Uncertainty
  Principle</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, Accepted in Phys. Lett. B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 757, 244 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.03.074</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we will demonstrate that the breaking of supersymmetry by a
non-anticommutative deformation can be used to generate the generalized
uncertainty principle. We will analyse the physical reasons for this
observation, in the framework of string theory. We also discuss the relation
between the generalized uncertainty principle and the Lee-Wick field theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00949</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Cacucciolo</keyname><forenames>Vito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renda</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poccia</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laschi</keyname><forenames>Cecilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cianchetti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the Nonlinear Response of Fibre-reinforced Bending Fluidic
  Actuators</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft cs.RO</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures. Submitted to Smart Materials and Structures</comments><msc-class>74B20</msc-class><doi>10.1088/0964-1726/25/10/105020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Soft actuators are receiving increasing attention from the engineering
community, not only in research but even for industrial applications. Among
soft actuators, fibre-reinforced Bending Fluidic Actuators (BFAs) became very
popular thanks to features such as robustness and easy design and fabrication.
However, an accurate modelling of these smart structures, taking into account
all the nonlinearities involved, is a challenging task. In this effort, we
propose an analytical mechanical model to capture the quasi-static response of
fibre-reinforced BFAs. The model is fully 3D and for the first time includes
the effect of the pressure on the lateral surface of the chamber as well as the
non-constant torque produced by the pressure at the tip. The presented model
can be used for design and control, while providing information about the
mechanics of these complex actuators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06635</id><created>2016-05-21</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Good</keyname><forenames>Michael R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Paul R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Charles R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mirror Reflections of a Black Hole</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 065010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.065010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An exact correspondence between a black hole and an accelerating mirror is
demonstrated. It is shown that for a massless minimally coupled scalar field
the same Bogolubov coefficients connecting the &quot;in&quot; and &quot;out&quot; states occur for
a (1+1)D flat spacetime with a particular perfectly reflecting accelerating
boundary trajectory and a (1+1)D curved spacetime in which a null shell
collapses to form a black hole. Generalization of the latter to the (3+1)D case
is discussed. The spectral dynamics is computed in both (1+1)-dimensional
spacetimes along with the energy flux in the spacetime with a mirror. It is
shown that the approach to equilibrium is monotonic, asymmetric in terms of the
rate, and there is a specific time which characterizes the system when it is
the most out-of-equilibrium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07965</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-07-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Godec</keyname><forenames>Aljaz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Active transport improves the precision of linear long distance
  molecular signalling</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>revised version accepted in J. Phys. A: Math. Theor</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A 49, 364001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/36/364001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular signalling in living cells occurs at low copy numbers and is
thereby inherently limited by the noise imposed by thermal diffusion. The
precision at which biochemical receptors can count signalling molecules is
intimately related to the noise correlation time. In addition to passive
thermal diffusion, messenger RNA and vesicle-engulfed signalling molecules can
transiently bind to molecular motors and are actively transported across
biological cells. Active transport is most beneficial when trafficking occurs
over large distances, for instance up to the order of 1 metre in neurons. Here
we explain how intermittent active transport allows for faster equilibration
upon a change in concentration triggered by biochemical stimuli. Moreover, we
show how intermittent active excursions induce qualitative changes in the noise
in effectively one-dimensional systems such as dendrites. Thereby they allow
for significantly improved signalling precision in the sense of a smaller
relative deviation in the concentration read-out by the receptor. On the basis
of linear response theory we derive the exact mean field precision limit for
counting actively transported molecules. We explain how intermittent active
excursions disrupt the recurrence in the molecular motion, thereby facilitating
improved signalling accuracy. Our results provide a deeper understanding of how
recurrence affects molecular signalling precision in biological cells and novel
diagnostic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09127</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pethes</keyname><forenames>Ildik&#xf3;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaban</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoica</keyname><forenames>Mihai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beuneu</keyname><forenames>Brigitte</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xf3;v&#xe1;ri</keyname><forenames>P&#xe1;l</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical ordering in Pd$_{81}$Ge$_{19}$ metallic glass studied by
  reverse Monte-Carlo modelling of XRD, ND and EXAFS experimental data</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, submitted to Physica Scripta</comments><journal-ref>Physica Scripta 91, 104004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-8949/91/10/104004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pd$_{81}$Ge$_{19}$ metallic glass was investigated by neutron diffraction,
X-ray diffraction and extended X-ray absorption fine structure spectroscopy
(EXAFS) at the Ge K-edge. Large scale structural models were obtained by
fitting the three measurements simultaneously in the framework of the reverse
Monte Carlo simulation technique. It was found that the experimental data sets
can be adequately fitted without Ge-Ge nearest neighbours. Mean Pd-Pd and Pd-Ge
distances are 2.80$\pm$0.02 {\AA} and 2.50$\pm$0.02 {\AA}, respectively. The
total average coordination number of Pd is 12.1$\pm$0.5 while Ge is surrounded
by 10.6$\pm$1.1 Pd atoms. The coordination numbers calculated from partial pair
correlation functions were compared to those obtained by Voronoi tessellation
method. It was found that the latter technique overestimates the number of
nearest neighbours by about 20% due to the significant contribution of distant
pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09743</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-08-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dev</keyname><forenames>P. S. Bhupal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Dilip Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodejohann</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>R-parity Violating Supersymmetry at IceCube</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE hep-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures; minor changes, version to appear in Phys. Lett.
  B</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 762, 116 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.066</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The presence of $R$-parity violating (RPV) supersymmetric interactions
involving high-energy neutrinos can lead to resonant production of TeV-scale
squarks inside large-volume neutrino detectors. Using the ultra-high energy
neutrino events observed recently at the IceCube, with the fact that for a
given power-law flux of astrophysical neutrinos, there is no statistically
significant deviation in the current data from the Standard Model expectations,
we derive robust upper limits on the RPV couplings as a function of the
resonantly-produced squark mass, independent of the other unknown model
parameters, as long as the squarks decay dominantly to 2-body final states
involving leptons and quarks through the RPV couplings. With more statistics,
we expect these limits to be comparable/complementary to the existing limits
from direct collider searches and other low-energy processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01033</id><created>2016-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denlinger</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>X. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disentangling the surface and bulk electronic structures of LaOFeAs</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104517 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We performed a comprehensive angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy study
of the electronic band structure of LaOFeAs single crystals. We found that
samples cleaved at low temperature show an unstable and highly complicated band
structure, whereas samples cleaved at high temperature exhibit a stable and
clearer electronic structure. Using \emph{in-situ} surface doping with K and
supported by first-principles calculations, we identify both surface and bulk
bands. Our assignments are confirmed by the difference in the temperature
dependence of the bulk and surface states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04017</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the $W^{\pm}Z$ boson pair-production cross section in
  $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}=13$ TeV with the ATLAS Detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>21 pages plus author list + cover pages (39 pages total), 4 figures,
  4 tables, published in Phys. Lett. B. All figures including auxiliary figures
  are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2015-19</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-108</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 762 (2016) 1</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of $W^{\pm}Z$ events in proton--proton collisions at a
centre-of-mass energy of 13 TeV is measured with the ATLAS detector at the LHC.
The collected data correspond to an integrated luminosity of 3.2 fb$^{-1}$. The
$W^{\pm}Z$ candidates are reconstructed using leptonic decays of the gauge
bosons into electrons or muons. The measured inclusive cross section in the
detector fiducial region for leptonic decay modes is $\sigma_{W^\pm Z
\rightarrow \ell^{'} \nu \ell \ell}^{\textrm{fid.}} = 63.2 \pm 3.2$ (stat.)
$\pm 2.6$ (sys.) $\pm 1.5$ (lumi.) fb. In comparison, the next-to-leading-order
Standard Model prediction is $53.4^{+3.6}_{-2.8}$ fb. The extrapolation of the
measurement from the fiducial to the total phase space yields
$\sigma_{W^{\pm}Z}^{\textrm{tot.}} = 50.6 \pm 2.6$ (stat.) $\pm 2.0$ (sys.)
$\pm 0.9$ (th.) $\pm 1.2$ (lumi.) pb, in agreement with a recent
next-to-next-to-leading-order calculation of $48.2^{+1.1}_{-1.0}$ pb. The cross
section as a function of jet multiplicity is also measured, together with the
charge-dependent $W^+Z$ and $W^-Z$ cross sections and their ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05524</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05524</id><created>2016-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Reich</keyname><forenames>Daniel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>Lars Bojer</forenames></author></authors><title>Illuminating Molecular Symmetries with Bicircular High-Order-Harmonic
  Generation</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 133902 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.133902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a complete theory of bicircular high-order-harmonic emission from
N-fold rotationally symmetric molecules. Using a rotating frame of reference we
predict the complete structure of the high-order-harmonic spectra for arbitrary
driving frequency ratios and show how molecular symmetries can be directly
identified from the harmonic signal. Our findings reveal that a characteristic
fingerprint of rotational molecular symmetries can be universally observed in
the ultrafast response of molecules to strong bicircular fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08276</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ostilli</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Presilla</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermi's golden rule for $N$-body systems in a black-body radiation</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032514 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032514</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the calculation of Fermi's golden rule for a system of $N$-body
dipoles, magnetic or electric, weakly interacting with a blackbody radiation.
By using the magnetic or electric field-field correlation function evaluated in
the 1960s for the black body radiation, we deduce a general formula for the
transition rates and study its limiting, fully coherent or fully incoherent,
regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00134</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Addis</keyname><forenames>Carole</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpat</keyname><forenames>G&#xf6;ktu&#x11f;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macchiavello</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maniscalco</keyname><forenames>Sabrina</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Memory Effects in Correlated Quantum Channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032121 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Memory effects play a fundamental role in the study of the dynamics of open
quantum systems. There exist two conceptually distinct notions of memory
discussed for quantum channels in the literature. In quantum information theory
quantum channels with memory are characterised by the existence of correlations
between successive applications of the channel on a sequence of quantum
systems. In open quantum systems theory memory effects arise dynamically during
the time evolution of quantum systems, and define non-Markovian dynamics. Here
we relate and combine these two different concepts of memory. In particular, we
study the interplay between correlations between multiple uses of quantum
channels and non-Markovianity as non-divisibility of the $t$-parametrized
family of channels defining the dynamical map.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01084</id><created>2016-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Humble</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCaskey</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schrock</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seddiqi</keyname><forenames>Hadayat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britt</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imam</keyname><forenames>Neena</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance Models for Split-execution Computing Systems</title><categories>cs.ET cs.DC quant-ph</categories><comments>Presented at 18th Workshop on Advances in Parallel and Distributed
  Computational Models [APDCM2016] on 23 May 2016; 10 pages</comments><journal-ref>2016 IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing
  Symposium Workshops, pp. 545-554 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/IPDPSW.2016.113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Split-execution computing leverages the capabilities of multiple
computational models to solve problems, but splitting program execution across
different computational models incurs costs associated with the translation
between domains. We analyze the performance of a split-execution computing
system developed from conventional and quantum processing units (QPUs) by using
behavioral models that track resource usage. We focus on asymmetric processing
models built using conventional CPUs and a family of special-purpose QPUs that
employ quantum computing principles. Our performance models account for the
translation of a classical optimization problem into the physical
representation required by the quantum processor while also accounting for
hardware limitations and conventional processor speed and memory. We conclude
that the bottleneck in this split-execution computing system lies at the
quantum-classical interface and that the primary time cost is independent of
quantum processor behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02933</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2016-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lazar</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pellegrini</keyname><forenames>Yves-Patrick</forenames></author></authors><title>Distributional and regularized radiation fields of non-uniformly moving
  straight dislocations, and elastodynamic Tamm problem</title><categories>physics.class-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages, 6 figures. v2: metadata amended. v3: a few minor typos
  corrected in the text, and better-looking hyperlinks</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Mechanics and Physics of Solids 96, 632-659 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmps.2016.07.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work introduces original explicit solutions for the elastic fields
radiated by non-uniformly moving, straight, screw or edge dislocations in an
isotropic medium, in the form of time-integral representations in which
acceleration-dependent contributions are explicitly separated out. These
solutions are obtained by applying an isotropic regularization procedure to
distributional expressions of the elastodynamic fields built on the Green
tensor of the Navier equation. The obtained regularized field expressions are
singularity-free, and depend on the dislocation density rather than on the
plastic eigenstrain. They cover non-uniform motion at arbitrary speeds,
including faster-than-wave ones. A numerical method of computation is
discussed, that rests on discretizing motion along an arbitrary path in the
plane transverse to the dislocation, into a succession of time intervals of
constant velocity vector over which time-integrated contributions can be
obtained in closed form. As a simple illustration, it is applied to the
elastodynamic equivalent of the Tamm problem, where fields induced by a
dislocation accelerated from rest beyond the longitudinal wave speed, and
thereafter put to rest again, are computed. As expected, the proposed
expressions produce Mach cones, the dynamic build-up and decay of which is
illustrated by means of full-field calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04835</id><created>2016-07-17</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Qi-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Rong</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Aubry-Andr\'e-Harper model with p-wave superconducting
  pairing</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.other</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125408 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a generalized Aubry-Andr\'e-Harper (AAH) model with p-wave
superconducting pairing. Both the hopping amplitudes between the nearest
neighboring lattice sites and the on-site potentials in this system are
modulated by a cosine function with a periodicity of $1/\alpha$. In the
incommensurate case [$\alpha=(\sqrt{5}-1)/2$], due to the modulations on the
hopping amplitudes, the critical region of this quasiperiodic system is
significantly reduced and the system becomes more easily to be turned from
extended states to localized states. In the commensurate case ($\alpha = 1/2$),
we find that this model shows three different phases when we tune the system
parameters: Su-Schrieffer-Heeger (SSH)-like trivial, SSH-like topological, and
Kitaev-like topological phases. The phase diagrams and the topological quantum
numbers for these phases are presented in this work. This generalized AAH model
combined with superconducting pairing provides us with a useful testfield for
studying the phase transitions from extended states to Anderson localized
states and the transitions between different topological phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06091</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Woo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carollo</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faber</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dekel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacchella</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Satellite Quenching, Galaxy Inner Density and the Halo Environment</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages + Appendix, 12 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the Sloan Digital Sky Survey, we adopt the sSFR-$\Sigma_{1kpc}$ diagram
as a diagnostic tool to understand quenching in different environments. sSFR is
the specific star formation rate, and $\Sigma_{1kpc}$ is the stellar surface
density in the inner kpc. Although both the host halo mass and group-centric
distance affect the satellite population, we find that these can be
characterised by a single number, the quenched fraction, such that key features
of the sSFR-$\Sigma_{1kpc}$ diagram vary smoothly with this proxy for the
&quot;environment&quot;. Particularly, the sSFR of star-forming galaxies decreases
smoothly with this quenched fraction, the sSFR of satellites being 0.1 dex
lower than in the field. Furthermore, $\Sigma_{1kpc}$ of the transition
galaxies (i.e., the &quot;green valley&quot; or GV) decreases smoothly with the
environment, by as much as 0.2 dex for $M_* = 10^{9.75-10} M_{\odot}$ from the
field, and decreasing for satellites in larger halos and at smaller radial
distances within same-mass halos. We interpret this shift as indicating the
relative importance of today's field quenching track vs. the cluster quenching
track. These environmental effects in the sSFR-$\Sigma_{1kpc}$ diagram are most
significant in our lowest mass range ($9.75 &lt; \log M_{*}/M_{\odot} &lt; 10$). One
feature that is shared between all environments is that at a given $M_{*}$
quenched galaxies have about 0.2-0.3 dex higher $\Sigma_{1kpc}$ than the
star-forming population. These results indicate that either $\Sigma_{1kpc}$
increases (subsequent to satellite quenching), or $\Sigma_{1kpc}$ for
individual galaxies remains unchanged, but the original $M_*$ or the time of
quenching is significantly different from those now in the GV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08787</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08787</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matzner</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Phuc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciufolini</keyname><forenames>Ignazio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolozzi</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlis</keyname><forenames>Erricos C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenig</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ries</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurzadyan</keyname><forenames>Vahe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penrose</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sindoni</keyname><forenames>Giampiero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khachatryan</keyname><forenames>Harutyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirzoyan</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author></authors><title>LARES Satellite Thermal Forces and a Test of General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, multiple figures in Proceedings of Metrology for Aerospace
  (MetroAeroSpace), 2016 IEEE</comments><report-no>UTTG-07-16</report-no><doi>10.1109/MetroAeroSpace.2016.7573269</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We summarize a laser-ranged satellite test of frame-dragging, a prediction of
General Relativity, and then concentrate on the estimate of thermal thrust, an
important perturbation affecting the accuracy of the test. The frame dragging
study analysed 3.5 years of data from the LARES satellite and a longer period
of time for the two LAGEOS satellites. Using the gravity field GGM05S obtained
via the Grace mission, which measures the Earth's gravitational field, the
prediction of General Relativity is confirmed with a 1-$\sigma$ formal error of
0.002, and a systematic error of 0.05. The result for the value of the frame
dragging around the Earth is $\mu$ = 0.994, compared to $\mu$ = 1 predicted by
General Relativity. The thermal force model assumes heat flow from the sun
(visual) and from Earth (IR) to the satellite core and to the fused silica
reflectors on the satellite, and reradiation into space. For a roughly current
epoch (days 1460 - 1580 after launch) we calculate an average along-track drag
of -0.50 $pm/s^{2}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01416</id><created>2016-08-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Humble</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ericson</keyname><forenames>M. Nance</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakowski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jingsong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britton</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curtis</keyname><forenames>Franklin G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumitrescu</keyname><forenames>Eugene F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohiyaddin</keyname><forenames>Fahd A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumpter</keyname><forenames>Bobby G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Computational Workflow for Designing Silicon Donor Qubits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cs.ET</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures; A smart model is a good model</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 424002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/42/424002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Developing devices that can reliably and accurately demonstrate the
principles of superposition and entanglement is an on-going challenge for the
quantum computing community. Modeling and simulation offer attractive means of
testing early device designs and establishing expectations for operational
performance. However, the complex integrated material systems required by
quantum device designs are not captured by any single existing computational
modeling method. We examine the development and analysis of a multi-staged
computational workflow that can be used to design and characterize silicon
donor qubit systems with modeling and simulation. Our approach integrates
quantum computational chemistry calculations with electrostatic field solvers
to perform detailed simulations of a phosphorus dopant in silicon. We show how
atomistic details can be synthesized into an operational model for the logical
gates that define quantum computation in this particular technology. The
resulting computational workflow realizes a design tool for silicon donor
qubits that can help verify and validate current and near-term experimental
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03362</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reisizadeh</keyname><forenames>Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manjegani</keyname><forenames>S. Mahmoud</forenames></author></authors><title>Some applications of matrix inequalities in R\'enyi entropy</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The R{\'e}nyi entropy is one of the important information measures that
generalizes Shannon's entropy. The quantum R{\'e}nyi entropy has a fundamental
role in quantum information theory, therefore, bounding this quantity is of
vital importance. Another important quantity is R{\'e}nyi relative entropy on
which R{\'e}nyi generalization of the conditional entropy, and mutual
information are defined based. Thus, finding lower bound for R{\'e}nyi relative
entropy is our goal in this paper. We use matrix inequalities to prove new
bounds on the entropy of type $\beta$, R{\'e}nyi entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04385</id><created>2016-08-15</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hinterbichler</keyname><forenames>Kurt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joyce</keyname><forenames>Austin</forenames></author></authors><title>Manifest Duality for Partially Massless Higher Spins</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>46 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2016) 141</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In four dimensions, partially massless fields of all spins and depths possess
a duality invariance akin to electric-magnetic duality. We construct
metric-like gauge invariant curvature tensors for partially massless fields of
all integer spins and depths, and show how the partially massless equations of
motion can be recovered from first order field equations and Bianchi identities
for these curvatures. This formulation displays duality in its manifestly local
and covariant form, in which it acts to interchange the field equations and
Bianchi identities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06388</id><created>2016-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Sim</keyname><forenames>Jae-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Hongkee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Sang Hyeon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Myung Joon</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculating branching ratio and spin-orbit coupling from
  first-principles: A formalism and its application to iridates</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115149 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple technique to calculate spin-orbit coupling, $\langle {\bf
L}\cdot{\bf S} \rangle$, and branching ratio measured in x-ray absorption
spectroscopy. Our method is for first-principles electronic structure
calculation and its implementation is straightforward for any of standard
formulations and codes. We applied this technique to several different large
spin-orbit coupling iridates. The calculated $\langle{ {\bf L}\cdot{\bf S}}
\rangle$ and branching ratio of a prototype $j_{\rm eff}$=1/2 Mott insulator,
Sr$_2$IrO$_4$, are in good agreement with recent experimental data over the
wide range of Rh-doping. Three different double perovskite iridates (namely,
Sr$_2$MgIrO$_6$, Sr$_2$ScIrO$_6$, and Sr$_2$TiIrO$_6$) are also well described.
This technique can serve as a promising tool for studying large spin-orbit
coupling materials from first-principles and for understanding experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00067</id><created>2016-08-31</created><updated>2016-09-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Young-Joon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Kyo-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickett</keyname><forenames>W. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K. -W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tuning ferromagnetic BaFe$_2$(PO$_4$)$_2$ through a high Chern number
  topological phase</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is strong interest in discovering or designing wide gap Chern
insulators. Here we follow a Chern insulator to trivial Mott insulator
transition versus interaction strength U in a honeycomb lattice Fe-based
transition metal oxide, discovering that a spin-orbit coupling energy scale
$\xi$=40 meV can produce and maintain a topologically entangled Chern
insulating state against large band structure changes arising from an
interaction strength U up to 60 times as large. Within the Chern phase the
minimum gap switches from the zone corner K to the zone center $\Gamma$ while
maintaining the topological structure. At a critical strength $U_c$, the
continuous evolution of the electronic structure encounters a gap closing then
reopening, upon which the system reverts to a trivial Mott insulating phase.
This Chern insulator phase of honeycomb lattice Fe$^{2+}$ BaFe$_2$(PO$_4$)$_2$
corresponds to a large Chern number C=-3 that will provide enhanced anomalous
Hall conductivity due to the associated three edge states threading through the
bulk gap of 80 meV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00958</id><created>2016-09-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Dittmann</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient ray tracing on 3D regular grids for fast generation of
  digitally reconstructed radiographs in iterative tomographic reconstruction
  techniques</title><categories>physics.med-ph cs.GR</categories><comments>manuscript for review</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cone beam projection is an essential and particularly time consuming part of
any iterative tomographic reconstruction algorithm. On current graphics
hardware especially the amount and pattern of memory accesses is a limiting
factor when read-only textures cannot be used. With the final objective of
accelerating iterative reconstruction techniques, a non-oversampling
Joseph-like raytracing projection algorithm for three dimensions featuring both
a branchless sampling loop and a cache friendly memory access pattern is
presented. An interpretation of the employed interpolation scheme is given with
respect to the effective beam and voxel models implied. The method is further
compared to existing techniques, and the modifications required to implement
further voxel and beam shape models are outlined. Both memory access rates and
total run time are benchmarked on a current consumer grade graphics processing
unit and explicitly compared to the performance of a classic Digital
Differential Analyzer (DDA) algorithm. The presented raytracer achieves memory
access rates of 292 GB/s in read-and-write memory and 502 GB/s in read-only
texture memory. It outperforms the DDA in terms of total run time by a factor
of up to five and achives 170 to 300 projections of a $512^{3}$ voxel volume
per second.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01735</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duarte</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotically anti-de Sitter Proca Stars</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures. v2: references added, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.D94, 064055 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that complex, massive spin-1 fields minimally coupled to Einstein's
gravity with a negative cosmological constant, admit asymptotically anti-de
Sitter self-gravitating solutions. Focusing on 4-dimensional spacetimes, we
start by obtaining analytical solutions in the test-field limit, where the
Proca field equations can be solved in a fixed anti-de Sitter background, and
then find fully non-linear solutions numerically. These solutions are a natural
extension of the recently found asymptotically flat Proca stars and share
similar properties with scalar boson stars. In particular, we show that they
are stable against spherically symmetric linear perturbations for a range of
fundamental frequencies limited by their point of maximum mass. We finish with
an overview of the behavior of Proca stars in $5$ dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01757</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jin-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhaoyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting photon pulses in Rydberg medium</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures including the supplementary material; Optica in
  press</comments><journal-ref>Optica 3, 1095 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.001095</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The understanding of dynamical evolutions of interacting photon pulses in
Rydberg atomic ensemble is the prerequisite for realizing quantum devices with
such system. We present an approach that efficiently simulates the dynamical
processes, using a set of local functions we construct to reflect the profiles
of narrowband pulses. For two counter-propagating photon pulses, our approach
predicts the distinct phenomena from the widely concerned Rydberg blockade to
the previously less noticed significant absorption in the anomalous dispersion
regime, which can occur by respectively setting the pulse frequency to the
appropriate values. Our numerical simulations also demonstrate how spatially
extending photon pulses become deformed under realistic non-uniform interaction
over their distributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03505</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Jason T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigurdsson</keyname><forenames>Steinn</forenames></author></authors><title>Families of Plausible Solutions to the Puzzle of Boyajian's Star</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, accepted to ApJL, 3 color figures. See also
  http://sites.psu.edu/astrowright/tabbys-star-posts/ for a popular summary of
  the article v2: Typos fixed</comments><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/829/1/L3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Good explanations for the unusual light curve of Boyajian's Star have been
hard to find. Recent results by Montet &amp; Simon lend strength and plausibility
to the conclusion of Schaefer that in addition to short-term dimmings, the star
also experiences large, secular decreases in brightness on decadal timescales.
This, combined with a lack of long-wavelength excess in the star's spectral
energy distribution, strongly constrains scenarios involving circumstellar
material, including hypotheses invoking a spherical cloud of artifacts. We show
that the timings of the deepest dimmings appear consistent with being randomly
distributed, and that the star's reddening and narrow sodium absorption is
consistent with the total, long-term dimming observed. Following Montet &amp;
Simon's encouragement to generate alternative hypotheses, we attempt to
circumscribe the space of possible explanations with a range of plausibilities,
including: a cloud in the outer solar system, structure in the ISM, natural and
artificial material orbiting Boyajian's Star, an intervening object with a
large disk, and variations in Boyajian's Star itself. We find the ISM and
intervening disk models more plausible than the other natural models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04248</id><created>2016-09-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>Aritro</forenames></author></authors><title>On the electrostatic equilibrium of charges and cavities in a conductor</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for Publication in a forthcoming issue of European Journal
  of Physics, as listed in the link below.
  http://iopscience.iop.org/journal/0143-0807/page/forthcomingArticles</comments><journal-ref>European Journal of Physics, Volume 37, Issue 6, November 2016,
  065203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0143-0807/37/6/065203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a charged conductor of arbitrary shape, in electrostatic
equilibrium, with one or more cavities inside it, and with fixed charges placed
outside the conductors and inside the cavities. The field inside a particular
cavity is then only due to charges within that cavity itself and to the surface
charge induced on the surface of the same cavity. A similar statement holds for
the exterior of the conductor. Although this is an elementary property of
conductors, it is not a trivial statement, as explained in this article.
Undergraduate texts in electrodynamics do not discuss at length or provide a
complete argument for an important problem such as this. Two simple and
complete proofs are provided in this note with the help of the standard
electrostatic uniqueness theorems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05444</id><created>2016-09-18</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thakkar</keyname><forenames>Kaushal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majethiya</keyname><forenames>Ajay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinodkumar</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Moments of Baryons containing all heavy quarks in Quark-Diquark
  Model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131: 339</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16339-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The triply heavy flavour baryons are studied using the Quark-diquark
description of the three-body system. The confinement potential for present
study of triply heavy flavour baryons is assumed as coulomb plus power
potential with power index $\nu$. We have solved Schrodinger equation
numerically to calculate the masses of triply heavy flavour baryons. The masses
and magnetic moments of triply heavy flavour baryons are computed for different
power indices, $\nu$, starting from 0.4 to 1.0. The predicted masses and
magnetic moments are in good agreement with other theoretical predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05914</id><created>2016-09-19</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grassi</keyname><forenames>Alba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>BPS relations from spectral problems and blowup equations</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables, a few typos corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently an exact duality between topological string and the spectral theory
of operators constructed from mirror curves to toric Calabi-Yau threefolds has
been proposed. At the same time an exact quantization condition for the cluster
integrable systems associated to these geometries has been conjectured. The
consistency between the two approaches leads to an infinite set of constraints
for the refined BPS invariants of the toric Calabi-Yau threefolds. We show
that, for the Y^{N,m} geometries, these constraints can be derived from the
K-theoretic blowup equations for SU(N) SYM with generic Chern-Simons invariant
m. In particular this furnishes a proof of the BPS constraints in the case of m
= 0.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06439</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gurau</keyname><forenames>Razvan</forenames></author></authors><title>Invitation to Random Tensors</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 094, 12 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.094</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This article is preface to the SIGMA special issue &quot;Tensor Models, Formalism
and Applications&quot;, http://www.emis.de/journals/SIGMA/Tensor_Models.html. The
issue is a collection of eight excellent, up to date reviews on random tensor
models. The reviews combine pedagogical introductions meant for a general
audience with presentations of the most recent developments in the field. This
preface aims to give a condensed panoramic overview of random tensors as the
natural generalization of random matrices to higher dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06718</id><created>2016-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Matr&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dent</keyname><forenames>W. R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyatt</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kral</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilner</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pani&#x107;</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Gregorio-Monsalvo</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hales</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Augereau</keyname><forenames>J. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greaves</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberge</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exocometary gas structure, origin and physical properties around $\beta$
  Pictoris through ALMA CO multi-transition observations</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>21 pages, 13 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent ALMA observations unveiled the structure of CO gas in the 23 Myr-old
$\beta$ Pictoris planetary system, a component that has been discovered in many
similarly young debris disks. We here present ALMA CO J=2-1 observations, at an
improved spectro-spatial resolution and sensitivity compared to previous CO
J=3-2 observations. We find that 1) the CO clump is radially broad, favouring
the resonant migration over the giant impact scenario for its dynamical origin,
2) the CO disk is vertically tilted compared to the main dust disk, at an angle
consistent with the scattered light warp. We then use position-velocity
diagrams to trace Keplerian radii in the orbital plane of the disk. Assuming a
perfectly edge-on geometry, this shows a CO scale height increasing with radius
as $R^{0.75}$, and an electron density (derived from CO line ratios through
NLTE analysis) in agreement with thermodynamical models. Furthermore, we show
how observations of optically thin line ratios can solve the primordial versus
secondary origin dichotomy in gas-bearing debris disks. As shown for $\beta$
Pictoris, subthermal (NLTE) CO excitation is symptomatic of H$_2$ densities
that are insufficient to shield CO from photodissociation over the system's
lifetime. This means that replenishment from exocometary volatiles must be
taking place, proving the secondary origin of the disk. In this scenario,
assuming steady state production/destruction of CO gas, we derive the CO+CO$_2$
ice abundance by mass in $\beta$ Pic's exocomets to be at most $\sim$6%,
consistent with comets in our own Solar System and in the coeval HD181327
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06956</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Xiangang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Quantum Hall effects in Rarita-Schwinger gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages,3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Emergence of higher spin relativistic fermionic materials becomes a new
favorite in the study of condensed matter physics. Massive Rarita-Schwinger
3/2-spinor was known owning very exotic properties, such as the superluminal
fermionic modes and even being unstable in an external magnetic field. Due to
the superluminal modes and the non-trivial constraints on the Rarita-Schwinger
gas, we exposit anomalous properties of the Hall effects in (2+1)-dimensions
which subvert the well-known quantum Hall paradigms. First, the Hall
conductance of a pure Rarita-Schwinger gas is step-like but not
plateau-quantized, instead of the linear dependence on the filling factor for a
pure spin-1/2 Dirac gas. In reality, the Hall conductance of the Dirac gas is
of quantized integer plateaus with the unit $\frac{e^2}h$ due to the
localization away from the Landau level centers. If the general localization
rule is applicable to the disordered Rarita-Schwinger gas, the Hall plateaus
are also expected to appear but they are nonlinearly dependent on the Landau
level index. Furthermore, there is a critical magnetic field beyond which
higher Landau levels become unstable. This confines the filling factor of the
system. We also show that the non-hermitness of the effective Hamiltonian is
not crucial to the nonlinearity of the quantum Hall conductance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07145</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Massaro</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UniTO, INFN-TO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liuzzo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames><affiliation>INAF-IRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Orienti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>INAF-IRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paladino</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>INAF-IRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paggi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames><affiliation>Yale</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wilkes</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kuraszkiewicz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>SAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baum</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Manitoba</affiliation></author><author><keyname>O'Dea</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Manitoba, RIT</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Chandra Survey of Extragalactic Sources in the 3CR Catalog: X-ray
  Emission from Nuclei, Jets, and Hotspots in the Chandra Archival Observations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figure in the manuscript while the rest available
  on-line, 8 tables, pre-proof version, published on the Astrophysical Journal
  Supplement series</comments><journal-ref>ApJS, 220, 5 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0067-0049/220/1/5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As part of our program to build a complete radio and X-ray database of all
the 3CR extragalactic radio sources, we present an analysis of 93 sources for
which Chandra archival data are available. Most of these sources have been
already published. Here we provide a uniform re-analysis and present nuclear
X-ray fluxes and X-ray emission associated with radio jet knots and hotspots
using both publicly available radio images and new radio images that have been
constructed from data available in the VLA archive. For about 1/3 of the
sources in the selected sample a comparison between the Chandra and the radio
observations was not reported in the literature: we find X-ray detections of 2
new radio jet knots and 17 hotspots. We also report the X-ray detection of
extended emission from the intergalactic medium of 15 galaxy clusters, two of
which were most likely unknown previously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07157</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Michael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>William A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis of Disparate Optical Imaging Data for Space Domain Awareness</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, contribution to Advanced Maui Optical and Space
  Surveillance Technologies Conference 2016</comments><report-no>LLNL-CONF-836209</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Bayesian algorithm to combine optical imaging of unresolved
objects from distinct epochs and observation platforms for orbit determination
and tracking. By propagating the non-Gaussian uncertainties we are able to
optimally combine imaging of arbitrary signal-to-noise ratios, allowing the
integration of data from low-cost sensors. Our Bayesian approach to image
characterization also allows large compression of imaging data without loss of
statistical information. With a computationally efficient algorithm to combine
multiple observation epochs and multiple telescopes, we show statistically
optimal orbit inferences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07158</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Dawson</keyname><forenames>William A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Michael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamath</keyname><forenames>Chandrika</forenames></author></authors><title>Blind Detection of Ultra-faint Streaks with a Maximum Likelihood Method</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, contribution to the Advanced Maui Optical and
  Space Surveillance Technologies Conference 2016</comments><report-no>LLNL-CONF-703048</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a maximum likelihood source detection method capable of
detecting ultra-faint streaks with surface brightnesses approximately an order
of magnitude fainter than the pixel level noise. Our maximum likelihood
detection method is a model based approach that requires no a priori knowledge
about the streak location, orientation, length, or surface brightness. This
method enables discovery of typically undiscovered objects, and enables the
utilization of low-cost sensors (i.e., higher-noise data). The method also
easily facilitates multi-epoch co-addition. We will present the results from
the application of this method to simulations, as well as real low earth orbit
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07168</id><created>2016-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Miceli</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutter</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquarello</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author></authors><title>Liquid Water through Density-Functional Molecular Dynamics: Plane-Wave
  vs Atomic-Orbital Basis Sets</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine and compare structural, dynamical, and electronic properties of
liquid water at near ambient conditions through density-functional molecular
dynamics simulations, when using either plane-wave or atomic-orbital basis
sets. In both frameworks, the electronic structure and the atomic forces are
self-consistently determined within the same theoretical scheme based on a
nonlocal density functional accounting for van der Waals interactions. The
overall properties of liquid water achieved within the two frameworks are in
excellent agreement with each other. Thus, our study supports that
implementations with plane-wave or atomic-orbital basis sets yield equivalent
results and can be used indiscriminately in study of liquid water or aqueous
solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07175</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Decolvenaere</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van der Ven</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Recovering 0 Kelvin Effective Hamiltonian Parameters from
  High-Temperature Disordered Phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures, 3 appendices</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effective Hamiltonians, when used in tandem with statistical mechanics
techniques, offer a rigorous connection between 0 Kelvin ab-initio predictions
and finite temperature experimental observations. For alloys, cluster expansion
Hamiltonians can coarse-grain out the complex, many-body electron problem of
density functional theory, yielding a series of simple site-wise basis
functions (e.g., products of site occupancy variables) on an atomic scale. The
resulting energy polynomial is computationally inexpensive, and hence suitable
for the (tens of) thousands of calculations of large systems required by
stochastic methods. We present a new method to run the statical mechanics
problem &quot;in reverse&quot;, using high-temperature observations and thermodynamic
connections to construct an effective Hamiltonian and thereby predict the 0
Kelvin energy spectrum and associated ground states. By re-examining the
cluster expansion formalism through the lens of entropy-maximization
approaches, we develop an algorithm to select clusters and determine cluster
interactions using only a few, high-temperature experiments on disordered
phases. We demonstrate that our approach can recover not only the stable ground
states at 0 Kelvin, but also the full phase behavior for three realistic
two-dimensional and three-dimensional alloy test-cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07187</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkerson</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liechti</keyname><forenames>Kenneth M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavitation of Water by Volume-Controlled Stretching</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A liquid subjected to negative pressure is thermodynamically metastable.
Confined within a small volume, negative pressure can build up until cavities
form spontaneously. The critical negative pressure for cavitation in water has
been theoretically predicted to be in the range of -100 to -200 MPa at room
temperature, whereas values around -30 MPa have been obtained by many
experiments. The discrepancy has yet to be resolved. In this study we perform
molecular dynamics simulations to study cavitation of water under volume
controlled stretching. It is found that liquid water exhibits a nonlinear
elastic compressibility (or stretchability) under hydrostatic tension and
remains stable within the confined volume until spontaneous cavitation occurs
at a critical strain. Subsequently, as the volume-controlled stretching
continues, the cavity grows stably and the hydrostatic tension decreases
continuously until the box volume is large enough for another transition to
form a water droplet. A modified nucleation theory is proposed to predict the
critical condition for cavitation. In particular, a strong dependence of the
critical strain and stress for cavitation on the initial liquid volume is
predicted by the modified nucleation theory, which may offer a possible
explanation for the discrepancies in the values of the critical negative
pressure obtained from experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07205</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Skands</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Nadine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prestel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritzmann</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author></authors><title>The VINCIA Antenna Shower for Hadron Colliders</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages. Presented at ICHEP 2016, Chicago</comments><report-no>CoEPP-MN-16-22</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We summarise the main features of VINCIA's antenna-based treatment of QCD
initial- and final-state showers, which includes iterated tree-level
matrix-element corrections and automated evaluations of perturbative shower
uncertainties. The latter are computed on the fly and are cast as a set of
alternative weights for each generated event. The resulting algorithm has been
made publicly available as a plug-in to the PYTHIA 8 event generator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07240</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Fukasawa</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensitivity of atmospheric neutrino experiments to neutrino non-standard
  interactions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures; proceedings of Neutrino 2016, XXVII International
  Conference on Neutrino Physics and Astrophysics, 4-9 July 2016, London, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the sensitivity of atmospheric neutrino experiments to the neutrino
non-standard interactions (NSI) which is motivated by the tension between the
two mass squared differences extracted from the KamLAND and solar neutrino
experiments. In this study the sensitivity of the future Hyper-Kamiokande
experiments for 4438 days to NSI is shown. Assuming that the mass hierarchy is
known, we find that the best-fit value from the solar neutrino and KamLAND data
can be tested at more than 8 $\sigma$, while the one from the global analysis
can be examined at 5.0 $\sigma$ (1.4 $\sigma$) for the normal (inverted) mass
hierarchy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07250</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bodrova</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chechkin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherstvy</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Safdari</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Underdamped scaled Brownian motion: (non-)existence of the overdamped
  limit in anomalous diffusion</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>32 pages, 5 figures, RevTeX</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 30520 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is quite generally assumed that the overdamped Langevin equation provides
a quantitative description of the dynamics of a classical Brownian particle in
the long time limit. We establish and investigate a paradigm anomalous
diffusion process governed by an underdamped Langevin equation with an explicit
time dependence of the system temperature and thus the diffusion and damping
coefficients. We show that for this underdamped scaled Brownian motion (UDSBM)
the overdamped limit fails to describe the long time behaviour of the system
and may practically even not exist at all for a certain range of the parameter
values. Thus persistent inertial effects play a non-negligible role even at
significantly long times. From this study a general questions on the
applicability of the overdamped limit to describe the long time motion of an
anomalously diffusing particle arises, with profound consequences for the
relevance of overdamped anomalous diffusion models. We elucidate our results in
view of analytical and simulations results for the anomalous diffusion of
particles in free cooling granular gases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07251</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmad</keyname><forenames>Shoaib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>Uzair</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mubarik</keyname><forenames>Farrukh E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>Tousif</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation and transformation of low density, onion-like carbon cages</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>28 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel growth technique for low density, non-icosahedral carbon onion-like
structures on Cu surface is described. The technique differs with the formation
of carbon onions inside the C1+ implanted metal surfaces at high temperatures
with densities ~ 2 g cm-3 in the form of multishelled icosahedral fullerenes
wrapped around C60. We report spheroidal cage formation of shell with variable
shell thickness, radii and curvature on C1+-irradiated Cu surfaces by the
accumulating C atoms which emerge out of the edges of the implanted sheets and
grids. Atom-by-atom C accreting structures grow along the edges, corners and
crevices. These, in turn, form the open and closed multiple-shelled cages.
Variable curvature is the most common feature of the growing structures. The
growth at room temperature does not ensure sphericity of the cages due to the
absence of high temperature annealing. These cages have very low density,
hollow interiors and often exhibit the conspicuous cage-inside-cage structures.
Another feature of the as-grown, non-spherical onions is the existence of
spherical protrusions with different local radii within the same cage.
Formation of cages with sizes ~ few nanometer to hundreds of nanometer depends
upon the irradiation rate of C1+. In situ formation and transformations of the
cages observed under 120 keV electron beam irradiation is described by using a
nanoelastic model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07267</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07267</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Deroy</keyname><forenames>Claire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Destrade</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alinden</keyname><forenames>Aidan Mc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Annaidh</keyname><forenames>Aisling Ni</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-invasive evaluation of skin tension lines with elastic waves</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.bio-ph q-bio.TO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: Since their discovery by Karl Langer in the 19th Century, Skin
Tension Lines (STLs) have been used by surgeons to decide the location and
orientation of an incision. Although these lines are patient-specific, most
surgeons rely on generic maps to determine their orientation. Beyond the
imprecise pinch test, there remains no accepted method for determining STLs in
vivo.
  Methods: (i) The speed of an elastic motion travelling radially on the skin
of canine cadavers was measured with a commercial device called the
Reviscometer. (ii) Similar to the original experiments conducted by Karl
Langer, circular excisions were made on the skin and the geometric changes to
the resulting wounds and excised samples were used to determine the orientation
of STLs.
  Results: A marked anisotropy in the speed of the elastic wave travelling
radially was observed. The orientation of the fastest wave was found to
correlate with the orientation of the elongated wound (P&lt;0.001, R^2 = 74%).
Similarly, the orientation of fastest wave was the same for both in vivo and
excised isolated samples, indicating that the STLs have a structural basis.
Resulting wounds expanded by an average area of 9% (+16% along STL and -10%
across) while excised skin shrunk by an average area of 33% (23% along STL and
10% across).
  Conclusion: Elastic surface wave propagation has been validated
experimentally as a robust method for determining the orientation of STLs
non-destructively and non-invasively. This study has implications for the
identification of STLs and for the prediction of skin tension levels, both
important factors in both human and veterinary reconstructive surgery.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07300</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Gransee</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Spacetime Dependence of Local Temperature in Relativistic Quantum Field
  Theory</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages; comments very welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spacetime dependence of the inverse temperature four-vector
$\boldsymbol{\beta}$ for certain states of the quantized Klein-Gordon field on
(parts of) Minkowski spacetime is discussed. These states fulfill a recently
proposed version of the Kubo-Martin-Schwinger (KMS) boundary value condition,
the so-called &quot;local KMS (LKMS) condition&quot;. It turns out that, depending on the
mass parameter $m\geq 0$, any such state can be extended either (i) to a LKMS
state on some forward or backward lightcone, with $\boldsymbol{\beta}$
depending linearily on spacetime, or (ii) to a thermal equilibrium (KMS) state
on all of Minkowski space with constant $\boldsymbol{\beta}$. This parallels
previously known results for local thermal equilibrium (LTE) states of the
quantized Klein-Gordon field. Furthermore, in the case of a massless field our
results point to a discrepancy with some classic results in general approaches
to (non-quantum) relativistic thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07311</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Arthur</keyname><forenames>Jake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearce</keyname><forenames>Frazer R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gray</keyname><forenames>Meghan E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elahi</keyname><forenames>Pascal J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knebe</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>Alexander M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Weiguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunnama</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dav&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Romeel</forenames></author><author><keyname>February</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Shuiyao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katz</keyname><forenames>Neal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kay</keyname><forenames>Scott T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>Ian G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murante</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perret</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Power</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puchwein</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saro</keyname><forenames>Alexandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sembolini</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teyssier</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yepes</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author></authors><title>nIFTy galaxy cluster simulations V: Investigation of the Cluster Infall
  Region</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures, 1 table; accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the properties of the galaxies and dark matter haloes residing in
the cluster infall region surrounding the simulated $\Lambda$CDM galaxy cluster
studied by Elahi et al. (2016) at z=0. The
$1.1\times10^{15}h^{-1}\text{M}_{\odot}$ galaxy cluster has been simulated with
eight different hydrodynamical codes containing a variety of hydrodynamic
solvers and subgrid schemes. All models completed a dark-matter only,
non-radiative and full-physics run from the same initial conditions. The
simulations contain dark matter and gas with mass resolution
$m_{\text{DM}}=9.01\times 10^8h^{-1}\text{M}_{\odot}$ and
$m_{\text{gas}}=1.9\times 10^8h^{-1}\text{M}_{\odot}$ respectively. We find
that the synthetic cluster is surrounded by clear filamentary structures that
contain ~60% of haloes in the infall region with mass ~$10^{12.5} - 10^{14}
h^{-1}\text{M}_{\odot}$, including 2-3 group-sized haloes ($&gt;
10^{13}h^{-1}\text{M}_{\odot}$). However, we find that only ~10% of objects in
the infall region are subhaloes residing in haloes, which may suggest that
there is not much ongoing preprocessing occurring in the infall region at z=0.
By examining the baryonic content contained within the haloes, we also show
that the code-to-code scatter in stellar fraction across all halo masses is
typically ~2 orders of magnitude between the two most extreme cases, and this
is predominantly due to the differences in subgrid schemes and calibration
procedures that each model uses. Models that do not include AGN feedback
typically produce too high stellar fractions compared to observations by at
least ~1 order of magnitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07325</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Hobbs</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf8;g</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>Alcione</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crowley</keyname><forenames>Cian</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMillan</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ranalli</keyname><forenames>Piero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heiter</keyname><forenames>Ulrike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jordi</keyname><forenames>Carme</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hambly</keyname><forenames>Nigel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Church</keyname><forenames>Ross</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthony</keyname><forenames>Brown</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanga</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chemin</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portail</keyname><forenames>Jordi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jim&#xe9;nez-Esteban</keyname><forenames>Fran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klioner</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mignard</keyname><forenames>Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fynbo</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyrzykowski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;ukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybicki</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Richard I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cellino</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabricius</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davidson</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindegren</keyname><forenames>Lennart</forenames></author></authors><title>GaiaNIR: Combining optical and Near-Infra-Red (NIR) capabilities with
  Time-Delay-Integration (TDI) sensors for a future Gaia-like mission</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>27 Pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ESA recently called for new &quot;Science Ideas&quot; to be investigated in terms of
feasibility and technological developments -- for technologies not yet
sufficiently mature. These ideas may in the future become candidates for M or L
class missions within the ESA Science Program.
  With the launch of Gaia in December 2013, Europe entered a new era of space
astrometry following in the footsteps of the very successful Hipparcos mission
from the early 1990s. Gaia is the successor to Hipparcos, both of which
operated in optical wavelengths, and Gaia is two orders of magnitude more
accurate in the five astrometric parameters and is surveying four orders of
magnitude more stars in a vast volume of the Milky Way. The combination of the
Hipparcos/Tycho-2 catalogues with the first early Gaia data release will give
improved proper motions over a long ~25 year baseline. The final Gaia solution
will also establish a new optical reference frame by means of quasars, by
linking the optical counterparts of radio (VLBI) sources defining the
orientation of the reference frame, and by using the zero proper motion of
quasars to determine a non-rotating frame.
  A weakness of Gaia is that it only operates at optical wavelengths. However,
much of the Galactic centre and the spiral arm regions, important for certain
studies, are obscured by interstellar extinction and this makes it difficult
for Gaia to deeply probe. Traditionally, this problem is overcome by switching
to the infra-red but this was not possible with Gaia's CCDs. Additionally, to
scan the entire sky and make global absolute parallax measurements the
spacecraft must have a constant rotation and this requires that the CCDs
operate in TDI mode, increasing their complexity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07328</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07328</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Richner</keyname><forenames>Patrizia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eghlidi</keyname><forenames>Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kress</keyname><forenames>Stephan J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmid</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poulikakos</keyname><forenames>Dimos</forenames></author></authors><title>Printable Nanoscopic Metamaterial Absorbers and Images with
  Diffraction-Limited Resolution</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>ACS applied materials &amp; interfaces 8 (2016) 11690-11697</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsami.6b01585</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fabrication of functional metamaterials with extreme feature resolution
finds a host of applications such as the broad area of surface/light
interaction. Non-planar features of such structures can significantly enhance
their performance and tunability, but their facile generation remains a
challenge. Here, we show that carefully designed out-of-plane nanopillars made
of metal-dielectric composites integrated in a metal-dielectric-nanocomposite
configuration, can absorb broadband light very effectively. We further
demonstrate that electrohydrodynamic printing in a rapid nanodripping mode, is
able to generate precise out-of-plane forests of such composite nanopillars
with deposition resolutions at the diffraction limit on flat and non-flat
substrates. The nanocomposite nature of the printed material allows the
fine-tuning of the overall visible light absorption from complete absorption to
complete reflection by simply tuning the pillar height. Almost perfect
absorption (~95%) over the entire visible spectrum is achieved by a nanopillar
forest covering only 6% of the printed area. Adjusting the height of individual
pillar groups by design, we demonstrate on-demand control of the gray scale of
a micrograph with a spatial resolution of 400 nm. These results constitute a
significant step forward in ultra-high resolution facile fabrication of
out-of-plane nanostructures, important to a broad palette of light design
applications. nanostructures, important to a broad palette of light design
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07334</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Gronefeld</keyname><forenames>Julius</forenames><affiliation>for the ALICE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>The nuclear modification of charged particles in Pb-Pb at
  $\sqrt{\text{s}_\text{NN}} = \text{5.02}\,\text{TeV}$ measured with ALICE</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures,Proceedings of science, Fourth Annual Large
  Hadron Collider Physics, Lund, 13-18 June 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of inclusive charged-particle production in heavy-ion collisions
provides insights into the density of the medium and the energy-loss
mechanisms. The observed suppression of high-$\textit{p}_\text{T}$ yield is
generally attributed to energy loss of partons as they propagate through a
deconfined state of quarks and gluons - Quark-Gluon Plasma (QGP) - predicted by
QCD. Such measurements allow the characterization of the QGP by comparison with
models. In these proceedings, results on high-$\textit{p}_\text{T}$ particle
production measured by ALICE in Pb-Pb collisions at $
\sqrt{\text{s}_\text{NN}}\, = 5.02\ \rm{TeV}$ as well as well in pp at
$\sqrt{\text{s}}\,=5.02\ \rm{TeV}$ are presented for the first time. The
nuclear modification factors ($\text{R}_\text{AA}$) in Pb-Pb collisions are
presented and compared with model calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07336</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07336</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Arkhipov</keyname><forenames>Ievgen I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pe&#x159;ina</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Haderka</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allevi</keyname><forenames>Alessia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bondani</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement and nonclassicality in four-mode Gaussian states generated
  via parametric down-conversion and frequency up-conversion</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 33802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep33802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multipartite entanglement and nonclassicality of four-mode Gaussian states
generated in two simultaneous nonlinear processes involving parametric
down-conversion and frequency up-conversion are analyzed assuming the vacuum as
the initial state. Suitable conditions for the generation of highly entangled
states are found. Transfer of the entanglement from the down-converted modes
into the up-converted ones is also suggested. The analysis of the whole set of
states reveals that sub-shot-noise intensity correlations between the
equally-populated down-converted modes, as well as the equally-populated
up-converted modes, uniquely identify entangled states. They represent a
powerful entanglement identifier also in other cases with arbitrarily populated
modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07346</id><created>2016-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Escarguel</keyname><forenames>A</forenames><affiliation>PIIM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Upgrade of the pedagogic and popular science tool for holography to a
  colour version</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2012, a pedagogic tool for monochromatic holography was realized for
pedagogic and popular science purposes [Th. Voslion and A. Escarguel, Eur. J.
Phys 33, 1803 (2012)]. Following its success, we decided to upgrade it to make
larger colour holograms and new pedagogic experiments. The resulting kit
includes all the necessary equipment to produce 4 &quot;x 5&quot; colour holograms with a
simple optical assembly and with an excellent vibration tolerance. The
resulting holograms, in colour and bigger, are much more spectacular for
science outreach purposes. For teaching purposes, some of the existing
experiments have been upgraded, and new ones have been developed for university
students and continuing education of teachers: colour reflection Denisyuk
holograms, single shot transmission/reflection holograms, angular and
wavelength multiplexing, holographic diffraction gratings with improved setup.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07366</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Henao</keyname><forenames>Duvan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodiac</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;my</forenames></author></authors><title>On the existence of minimizers for the neo-Hookean energy in the
  axisymmetric setting</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $\Omega$ be a smooth bounded axisymmetric set in $\R^3$. In this paper we
investigate the existence of minimizers of the so-called neo-Hookean energy
among a class of axisymmetric maps. Due to the appearance of a critical
exponent in the energy we must face a problem of lack of compactness. Indeed as
shown by an example of Conti-De Lellis, a phenomenon of concentration of energy
can occur preventing the strong convergence in $W^{1,2}(\Omega,\mathbb{R}^3)$
of a minimizing sequence along with the equi-integrability of the cofactors of
that sequence. We prove that this phenomenon can only take place on the axis of
symmetry of the domain. Thus if we consider domains that do not contain the
axis of symmetry then minimizers do exist. We also provide a partial
description of the lack of compactness in terms of Cartesian currents. Then we
study the case where $\Omega$ is not necessarily axisymmetric but the boundary
data is affine. In that case if we do not allow cavitation (nor in the interior
neither at the boundary) then the affine extension is the unique minimizer,
that is, quadratic polyconvex energies are $W^{1,2}$-quasiconvex in our
admissible space. At last, in the case of an axisymmetric domain not containing
its symmetry axis, we obtain for the first time the existence of weak solutions
of the energy-momentum equations for $3$D neo-Hookean materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07378</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bezuglov</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanton</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>Reinaldo</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-Output Artificial Neural Network for Storm Surge Prediction in
  North Carolina</title><categories>cs.NE physics.ao-ph stat.AP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During hurricane seasons, emergency managers and other decision makers need
accurate and `on-time' information on potential storm surge impacts. Fully
dynamical computer models, such as the ADCIRC tide, storm surge, and wind-wave
model take several hours to complete a forecast when configured at high spatial
resolution. Additionally, statically meaningful ensembles of high-resolution
models (needed for uncertainty estimation) cannot easily be computed in near
real-time. This paper discusses an artificial neural network model for storm
surge prediction in North Carolina. The network model provides fast, real-time
storm surge estimates at coastal locations in North Carolina. The paper studies
the performance of the neural network model vs. other models on synthetic and
real hurricane data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07380</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Chyi-Lung</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct manifestation of Ehrenfest's theorem in the infinite square well
  model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ehrenfest's theorem in the infinite square well is up to now only manifested
indirectly. The manifestation of this theorem is first done in the finite
square well, and then consider the infinite square well as the limit of the
finite well. For a direct manifestation, we need a more precise formula to
describe the degree of infiniteness of the divergent potential energy. We show
that the potential energy term term, which is the product of the potential
energy and the energy eigenfunction, is a well defined function which can be
expressed in terms of Dirac delta functions. This means that the infinity in
this model is not that vague but has obtained a specification. This results
that expectation values can be calculated precisely and Ehrenfest's thereom can
be confirmed directly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07395</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Spiewak</keyname><forenames>Russell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buldyrev</keyname><forenames>Sergey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forman</keyname><forenames>Yakir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soltan</keyname><forenames>Saleh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zussman</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author></authors><title>A study of cascading failures in real and synthetic power grid
  topologies using DC power flows</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>42 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the linearized DC power flow model, we study cascading failures and
their spatial and temporal properties in the US Western Interconnect (USWI)
power grid. We also introduce the preferential Degree And Distance Attachment
(DADA) model, with similar degree distributions, resistances, and currents to
the USWI. We investigate the behavior of both grids resulting from the failure
of a single line. We find that the DADA model and the USWI model react very
similarly to that failure, and that their blackout characteristics resemble
each other. In many cases, the failure of a single line can cause cascading
failures, which impact the entire grid. We characterize the resilience of the
grid by three parameters, the most important of which is tolerance ${\alpha}$,
which is the ratio of the maximal load a line can carry to its initial load. We
characterize a blackout by its yield, which we define as the ratio of the final
to the initial consumed currents. We find that if ${\alpha}\leq2$, the
probability of a large blackout occurring is very small. By contrast, in a
broad range of $1 &lt; {\alpha} &lt; 2$, the initial failure of a single line can
result, with a high probability, in cascading failures leading to a massive
blackout with final yield less than 80%. The yield has a bimodal distribution
typical of a first-order transition, i.e., the failure of a randomly selected
line leads either to an insignificant current reduction or to a major blackout.
We find that there is a latent period in the development of major blackouts
during which few lines are overloaded, and the yield remains high. The duration
of this latent period is proportional to the tolerance. The existence of the
latent period suggests that intervention during early time steps of a cascade
can significantly reduce the risk of a major blackout.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07397</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruiz-Rivas</keyname><forenames>Joaquin</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Valc&#xe1;rcel</keyname><forenames>Germ&#xe1;n J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navarrete-Benlloch</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Active locking and entanglement in type II optical parametric
  oscillators</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Comments and constructive criticism are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type II optical parametric oscillators are amongst the highest-quality
sources of quantum-correlated light. In particular, when pumped above
threshold, such devices generate a pair of bright orthogonally-polarized beams
with strong continuous-variable entanglement. However, these sources are of
limited practical use, because the entangled beams emerge with different
frequencies and a diffusing phase-difference. It has been proven that the use
of an internal wave-plate coupling the modes with orthogonal polarization is
capable of locking the frequencies of the emerging beams to half the pump
frequency, as well as reducing the phase-difference diffusion, at the expense
of reducing the entanglement levels. In this work we characterize theoretically
an alternative locking mechanism: the injection of a laser at half the pump
frequency. Apart from being less invasive, this method should allow for an
easier real-time experimental control. We show that such an injection is
capable of generating the desired phase locking between the emerging beams,
while still allowing for large levels of entanglement. Moreover, we find an
additional region of the parameter space (at relatively large injections) where
a mode with well defined polarization is in a highly squeezed vacuum state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07404</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Kidonakis</keyname><forenames>Nikolaos</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical results for top-quark cross sections and distributions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures; presented at the 38th International Conference on
  High Energy Physics (ICHEP 2016), Chicago, Illinois, August 3-10, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I present new results and updates for total cross sections and differential
distributions in top-antitop pair and single-top production. Soft-gluon
corrections are added to exact fixed-order results to provide the best
predictions at approximate N$^3$LO for $t{\bar t}$ production and approximate
NNLO for single-top production. Total cross sections and top-quark
transverse-momentum and rapidity distributions are presented and compared with
data at LHC and Tevatron energies. The cusp anomalous dimension at three and
higher loops is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07405</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruiz-Rivas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navarrete-Benlloch</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rold&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Eugenio</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Valc&#xe1;rcel</keyname><forenames>Germ&#xe1;n J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative structures in an optomechanical cavity model with a
  microstructured oscillating end mirror</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>Comments and constructive criticism are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically consider the possibility of generating nonlinear transverse
patterns in an optomechanical system in which the mechanical element is a
microstructured oscillating end-mirrror consisting in an array of
weakly-coupled micromirrors. While in the limit of large number of
micro-mirrors we naturally recover the continuous model that we recently
studied in [Ruiz-Rivas et al., Phys. Rev. A 93, 033850 (2015)], we pay special
numerical attention to the opposite limit, showing that the structures
predicted with the continuous model can be observed for a number of
micro-mirrors as low as ten or less. This opens new venues for experimental
approaches to the subject.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07414</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Vescovi</keyname><forenames>Dalila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luding</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Merging fluid and solid granular behavior</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>37 pages, 14 figures, submitted to Soft Matter</comments><doi>10.1039/c6sm01444e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simple homogeneous shear flows of frictionless, deformable particles are
studied by particle simulations at large shear rates and for differently soft,
deformable particles. The particle stiffness sets a time-scale that can be used
to scale the physical quantities; thus the dimensionless shear rate, i.e. the
inertial number (inversely proportional to pressure), can alternatively be
expressed as inversely proportional to the square root of the particle
stiffness. Asymptotic scaling relations for the field variables pressure, shear
stress and granular temperature are inferred from simulations in both fluid and
solid regimes, corresponding to unjammed and jammed conditions. Then the limit
cases are merged to unique constitutive relations that cover also the
transition zone in proximity of jamming. By exploiting the diverging behavior
of the scaling laws at the jamming density, we arrive at continuous and
differentiable phenomenological constitutive relations for the stresses and the
granular temperature as functions of the volume fraction, shear rate, particle
stiffness and distance from jamming. In contrast to steady shear flows of hard
particles the (shear) stress ratio does not collapse as a function of the
inertial number, indicating the need for an additional control parameter. In
the range of particle stiffnesses investigated, in the solid regime, only the
pressure is rate independent, whereas the shear stress exhibits a slight shear
rate- and stiffness-dependency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07426</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denaro</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giarratana</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuffrida</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzola</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basilone</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aronica</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonanno</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spagnolo</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling of Sensory Characteristics Based on the Growth of Food Spoilage
  Bacteria</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>25 pages, 12 figures, 1 table; to be published in Math. Model. Nat.
  Phenom</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During last years theoretical works shed new light and proposed new
hypothesis on the mechanisms which regulate the time behaviour of biological
populations in different natural systems. Despite of this, the role of
environmental variables in ecological systems is still an open question.
Filling this gap of knowledge is a crucial task for a deeper comprehension of
the dynamics of biological populations in real ecosystems. In this work we
study how the dynamics of food spoilage bacteria influences the sensory
characteristics of fresh fish specimens. This topic is crucial for a better
understanding of the role played by the bacterial growth on the organoleptic
properties, and for the quality evaluation and risk assessment of food
products. We therefore analyze the time behaviour, in fresh fish specimens, of
sensory characteristics starting from the growth curves of two spoilage
bacterial communities. The theoretical study, initially based on a
deterministic model, exploits experimental temperature profiles. As a first
step, a model of predictive microbiology is used to reproduce the experimental
behaviour of the two bacterial populations. Afterwards, the theoretical
bacterial growths are converted, through suitable differential equations, into
&quot;sensory&quot; scores, based on the Quality Index Method (QIM), a scoring system for
freshness and quality sensory estimation of fishery products. As a third step,
the theoretical curves of QIM scores are compared with the experimental data
obtained by sensory analysis. Finally, the differential equations for QIM
scores are modified by adding terms of multiplicative white noise, which mimics
the effects of uncertainty and variability in sensory analysis. A better
agreement between experimental and theoretical QIM scores is observed, in some
cases, in the presence of suitable values of noise intensity respect to the
deterministic analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07442</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Vignolo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massa</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>A vielbein formulation of unified Einstein-Maxwell theory</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 23 (2006) 6781-6791</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/23/23/011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of J-bundles a vielbein formulation of unified
Einstein-Maxwell theory is proposed. In the resulting scheme, field equations
matching the gravitational and electromagnetic fields are derived by
constraining a five-dimensional variational principle. No dynamical scalar
field is involved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07447</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Massa</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignolo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational techniques in general relativity: A metric-affine approach
  to Kaluza's theory</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 48, 022501 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.2435087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new variational principle for General Relativity, based on an action
functional $I\/(\Phi,\nabla)\/$ involving both the metric $\Phi\/$ and the
connection $\nabla\/$ as independent, \emph{unconstrained\/} degrees of freedom
is presented. The extremals of $I\/$ are seen to be pairs $\/(\Phi,\nabla)\/$
in which $\Phi\/$ is a Ricci flat metric, and $\nabla\/$ is the associated
Riemannian connection. An application to Kaluza's theory of interacting
gravitational and electromagnetic fields is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07458</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Najafi</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nezhadhaghighi</keyname><forenames>M. Ghasemi</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal symmetry of electron-hole puddles in ungated graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, two figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1609.07096</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the mono-layer graphene at the charge neutrality point is
considered whithin Thomas-Fermi-Dirac theory, treating inhomogeneous external
potentials and electron-electron interactions on equal footing. We present some
general considerations concerning the probability measure of the ground state
charge density. The system shows degrees of self-similarity. By analyzing the
ground state carrier density profile, we show that although it is not Gaussian,
the critical exponents are consistent with Kondev hyper-scaling relations.
Using Schramm-Loewner (SLE) evolution we show that the ungated graphene has
conformal invariance and the random zero-charge density contours are
SLE$_{\kappa}$ with $\kappa=1.8\pm 0.2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07471</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ariturk</keyname><forenames>Sinan</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenvalue estimates on quantum graphs</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>34B45, 34L15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On a finite connected metric graph, we establish upper bounds for the
eigenvalues of the Laplacian. These bounds depend on the length, the Betti
number, and the number of pendant vertices. For trees, these estimates are
sharp. We also establish sharp upper bounds for the spectral gap of the
complete graph $K_4$. The proofs are based on estimates for eigenvalues on
graphs with Dirichlet conditions imposed at the pendant vertices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07473</id><created>2016-09-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thapliyal</keyname><forenames>Kishore</forenames></author></authors><title>A Comment on the One Step Quantum Key Distribution Based on EPR
  Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages. no figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, in Sci. Rep. \textbf{6} (2016) 28767, Li et al., have proposed a
scheme for quantum key distribution using Bell states. This comment provides a
proof that the proposed scheme of Li et al., is insecure as it involves leakage
of information. Further, it is also shown that all the error rates computed in
the Li et al.'s paper are incorrect as the authors failed to recognize the fact
that any eavesdropping effort will lead to entanglement swapping. Finally, it
is established that Li et al.'s scheme can be viewed as an incrementally (but
incorrectly)modified version of the existing schemes based on Goldenberg
Vaidman (GV) subroutine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ex/0404013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ex/0404013</id><created>2004-04-09</created><authors><author><keyname>The DELPHI Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abdallah</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for B0_s - anti-B0_s oscillations in DELPHI using high-p_t
  leptons</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>36 pages, 14 figures, Accepted by Eur. Phys. J. C</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2003-089</report-no><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J.C35:35-52,2004</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s2004-01827-0</doi><abstract>  Oscillations in the B0_s - anti-B0_s system were studied in events selected
from about 4.3 million hadronic Z^0 decays registered by DELPHI between 1992
and 2000. This paper presents updates of two published analyses ([11,12]). The
first analysis, which utilizes leptons emitted with large momentum transverse
to a jet, was improved by means of a better algorithm for the vertex
reconstuction and a new algorithm for flavour-tagging at production time. The
second analysis, which utilizes D_s-lepton events, was improved by optimizing
the treatment of proper time resolution. No signal of B0_s oscillations was
observed and limits on the mass difference between the physical B0_s states
were obtained to be:
  \Delta m_s &gt; 8.0 ps^{-1} at the 95% C.L. with a sensitivity of \Delta m_s =
9.1 ps^{-1} in the high p_t lepton analysis and \Delta m_s &gt; 4.9 ps^{-1} at the
95% C.L. with a sensitivity of \Delta m_s = 8.6 ps^{-1} in the D_s-lepton
analysis. Previously published results on these analyses are superseed. The
combination of these results with those obtained in other independent analyses
previously performed in DELPHI (D_s-hadron, exclusive B0_s, inclusive vertex)
gives: \Delta m_s &gt; 8.5 ps^{-1} at the 95% C.L. with a sensitivity of \Delta
m_s = 12.0 ps^{-1}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ph/0308196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ph/0308196</id><created>2003-08-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Navarro</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of low-scale supersymmetry breaking models</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, invited brief review for Modern Physics Letters
  A</comments><journal-ref>Mod.Phys.Lett.A18:2227-2242,2003</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732303011897</doi><abstract>  In this letter we consider the distinctive phenomenology of supersymmetric
models in which the scale of SUSY breaking is very low, \sqrt{F}= O(TeV),
focusing on the Higgs sector and the process of electroweak breaking. Using an
effective Lagrangian description of the interactions between the observable
fields and the SUSY breaking sector, it is shown how the conventional MSSM
picture can be substantially modified. For instance, the Higgs potential has
non-negligible SUSY breaking quartic couplings that can modify completely the
pattern of electroweak breaking and the Higgs spectrum with respect to that of
conventional MSSM-like models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
