<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:08:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-04" from="2016-09-04" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08809</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Constantin</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabiano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Sala</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hartree potential dependent exchange functional</title><categories>cond-mat.other physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 084110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4961300</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a novel non-local ingredient for the construction of exchange
density functionals: the reduced Hartree parameter, which is invariant under
the uniform scaling of the density and represents the exact exchange
enhancement factor for one- and two-electron systems. The reduced Hartree
parameter is used together with the conventional meta-generalized gradient
approximation (meta-GGA) semilocal ingredients (i.e. the electron density, its
gradient and the kinetic energy density) to construct a new generation exchange
functional, termed u-meta-GGA. This u-meta-GGA functional is exact for {the
exchange of} any one- and two-electron systems, is size-consistent and
non-empirical, satisfies the uniform density scaling relation, and recovers the
modified gradient expansion derived from the semiclassical atom theory. For
atoms, ions, jellium spheres, and molecules, it shows a good accuracy, being
often better than meta-GGA exchange functionals. Our construction validates the
use of the reduced Hartree ingredient in exchange-correlation functional
development, opening the way to an additional rung in the Jacob's ladder
classification of non-empirical density functionals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08818</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Ashok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Archana</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for Dark Matter with LHC proton Beam Dump</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark Matter (DM) comprising particles in the mass range of a few MeV to GeV
is waiting to be explored, given the many theoretical models accommodating
cosmological abundance. We hereby propose an experiment with the LHC proton
beam of 7 TeV striking onto the beam dump target, emitting neutrinos and
possibly, Dark Matter candidates. This experiment would also permit to observe
signatures involving elastic and inelastic processes involving DM candidates,
electrons and strongly interacting particles present in nuclei of the dump
target. There will be residual neutrino background present in each of these
signatures, hence the proposed experimental detector sub-systems would be such
that they would involve as final states, elastically or inelasticity scattered,
standard model particles. The bump or the excess in the tail of the kinematic
distributions will eventually give us glimpse of presence of new particles
which could possibly be Dark Matter candidates. Given the parameters of the LHC
machine, the sensitivity of such an experiment is unique in the energy region
it is supposed to exploit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08827</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08827</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Zhenjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hu</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous dehydrogenation of methanol over defect-free MgO(100) thin
  film deposited on molybdenum</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dehydrogenation reaction of methanol on metal supported MgO(100) films
has been studied by employing periodic density functional calculations. As far
as we know, the dehydrogenation of single methanol molecule over inert oxide
insulators such as MgO has never been realized before without the introduction
of defects and low coordinated atoms. By depositing the very thin oxide films
on Mo substrate we have successfully obtained the dissociative state of
methanol. The dehydrogenation reaction is energetically exothermic and nearly
barrierless. The metal supported thin oxide films studied here provide a
versatile approach to enhance the activity and properties of oxides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08877</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Hickson</keyname><forenames>Kevin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loison</keyname><forenames>Jean-Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunez-Reyes</keyname><forenames>Dianailys</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mereau</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Tunneling Enhancement of the C + H2O and C + D2O Reactions at
  Low Temperature</title><categories>physics.chem-ph astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted to the Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies of neutral gas-phase reactions characterized by barriers show
that certain complex forming processes involving light atoms are enhanced by
quantum mechanical tunneling at low temperature. Here, we performed kinetic
experiments on the activated C(3P) + H2O reaction, observing a surprising
reactivity increase below 100 K, an effect which is only partially reproduced
when water is replaced by its deuterated analogue. Product measurements of H-
and D-atom formation allowed us to quantify the contribution of complex
stabilization to the total rate while confirming the lower tunneling efficiency
of deuterium. This result, which is validated through statistical calculations
of the intermediate complexes and transition states has important consequences
for simulated interstellar water abundances and suggests that tunneling
mechanisms could be ubiquitous in cold dense clouds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08886</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Naef</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author></authors><title>Poisson Brackets in Kontsevich's &quot;Lie World&quot;</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note the notion of Poisson brackets in Kontsevich's &quot;Lie World&quot; is
developed. These brackets can be thought of as &quot;universally&quot; defined classical
Poisson structures, namely formal expressions only involving the structure maps
of a quadratic Lie algebra. We prove a uniqueness statement about these Poisson
brackets with a given moment map. As an application we get formulae for the
linearization of the quasi-Poisson structure of the moduli space of flat
connections on a punctured sphere, and thereby identify their symplectic leaves
with the reduction of coadjoint orbits. Equivalently, we get linearizations for
the Goldman double Poisson bracket, our definition of Poisson brackets
coincides with that of Van Den Bergh in this case. This can furthermore be
interpreted as giving a monoidal equivalence between Hamiltonian quasi-Poisson
spaces and Hamiltonian spaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
