<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:09:06Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-05" from="2016-09-05" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.0768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.0768</id><created>2010-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kyriakou</keyname><forenames>Kyriakos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moulopoulos</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghazaryan</keyname><forenames>Areg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djotyan</keyname><forenames>Anahit</forenames></author></authors><title>Arbitrary mixture of two charged interacting particles in a magnetic
  Aharonov-Bohm ring: persistent currents and Berry's phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, accepted in Journal of Physics A for the Special
  Issue on Geometric Phases</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/43/35/354018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aharonov-Bohm Physics at the two-particle level is investigated for
distinguishable interacting charged particles through the exact solution of a
toy model with confined states. The effect of the inaccessible magnetic flux is
distributed between the center-of-mass and the internal pair level, and the
nontrivial manner in which the two levels are mutually affecting each other
demonstrates the interplay between interactions, nontrivial topology, the
Aharonov-Bohm flux and the characteristics of a charged quantal mixture.
Analytical expressions for energy spectra, wavefunctions, (flux-dependent)
critical interactions for binding and current densities are derived, and these
offer the rare possibility to study persistent currents from the point of view
of an interacting nanoscopic system. Two cyclic adiabatic processes are
identified, one coupled to the center-of-mass behavior and the other defined on
the two-body interaction potential, with the associated Berry's phases also
analytically determined; these are found to be directly linked to the electric
and probability (persistent) currents in nontrivial ways that are shown to be
universal (independent of the actual form of the interaction). The direct
connection of the two-body Berry's phase to the electric current for a neutral
system is found to disappear in case of identical particles - hence revealing
the character of a charged mixture as being crucial for exhibiting these
universal behaviors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1103.6056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1103.6056</id><created>2011-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jusang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beach</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erskine</keyname><forenames>James L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic domain-wall velocity enhancement induced by a transverse
  magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2015.08.071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin dynamics of field-driven domain walls (DWs) guided by Permalloy
nanowires are studied by high-speed magneto-optic polarimetry and numerical
simulations. DW velocities and spin configurations are determined as functions
of longitudinal drive field, transverse bias field, and nanowire width.
Nanowires having cross-sectional dimensions large enough to support vortex wall
structures exhibit regions of drive-field strength (at zero bias field) that
have enhanced DW velocity resulting from coupled vortex structures that
suppress oscillatory motion. Factor of ten enhancements of the DW velocity are
observed above the critical longitudinal drive-field (that marks the onset of
oscillatory DW motion) when a transverse bias field is applied. Nanowires
having smaller cross-sectional dimensions that support transverse wall
structures also exhibit a region of higher mobility above the critical field,
and similar transverse-field induced velocity enhancement but with a smaller
enhancement factor. The bias-field enhancement of DW velocity is explained by
numerical simulations of the spin distribution and dynamics within the
propagating DW that reveal dynamic stabilization of coupled vortex structures
and suppression of oscillatory motion in the nanowire conduit resulting in
uniform DW motion at high speed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.1661</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.1661</id><created>2011-10-07</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Talbert</keyname><forenames>Samuel H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Timeless Relativistic Approach to Classical Mechanics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reformulate Classical Mechanics as a timeless relativistic theory. Readers
are introduced to a new class of reference systems, the binate frames, where
physical events are identified with four position-coordinates -- no clocks are
used. The binate frames are inertial and adaptable to relative motions.
Analyses that use binate frames are valid at all energy levels. When desirable
to do so, the results are easily expressed as in special relativity, in terms
of space and time coordinates of inertial observers. Given the importance of
mass-and-spring systems to theoretical physics, we analyzed such a system.
Published special relativistic solutions predict anharmonic oscillations, but
in the inertial frame where the mass-and-spring system (as a whole) is at rest,
our solution is harmonic with energy-dependent angular frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1209.2031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1209.2031</id><created>2012-09-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Cinzano</keyname><forenames>Pierantonio</forenames><affiliation>Istituto di Scienza e Tecnologia dell'Inquinamento Luminoso</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Falchi</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames><affiliation>Istituto di Scienza e Tecnologia dell'Inquinamento Luminoso</affiliation><affiliation>CieloBuio, Coordinamento per la protezione del cielo notturno, Italy</affiliation></author></authors><title>The propagation of light pollution in the atmosphere</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP physics.ao-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>25 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS, 7 august
  2012</comments><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2012.21884.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Methods to map artificial night sky brightness and stellar visibility across
large territories or their distribution over the entire sky at any site are
based on the computation of the propagation of light pollution with Garstang
models, a simplified solution of the radiative transfer problem in the
atmosphere which allows a fast computation by reducing it to a ray-tracing
approach. We present here up-to-date Extended Garstang Models (EGM) which
provide a more general numerical solution for the radiative transfer problem
applied to the propagation of light pollution in the atmosphere. We also
present the LPTRAN software package, an application of EGM to high-resolution
DMSP-OLS satellite measurements of artificial light emissions and to GTOPO30
digital elevation data, which provides an up-to-date method to predict the
artificial brightness distribution of the night sky at any site in the World at
any visible wavelength for a broad range of atmospheric situations and the
artificial radiation density in the atmosphere across the territory. EGM
account for (i) multiple scattering, (ii) wavelength from 250 nm to infrared,
(iii) Earth curvature and its screening effects, (iv) sites and sources
elevation, (v) many kinds of atmosphere with the possibility of custom setup
(e.g. including thermal inversion layers), (vi) mix of different boundary layer
aerosols and tropospheric aerosols, with the possibility of custom setup, (vii)
up to 5 aerosol layers in upper atmosphere including fresh and aged volcanic
dust and meteoric dust, (viii) variations of the scattering phase function with
elevation, (ix) continuum and line gas absorption from many species, ozone
included, (x) up to 5 cloud layers, (xi) wavelength dependant bidirectional
reflectance of the ground surface from NASA/MODIS satellites, main models or
custom data (snow included), (xii) geographically variable upward light
emission function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.2876</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.2876</id><created>2013-01-14</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garban</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhodes</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;mi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vargas</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Liouville Brownian motion</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Published at http://dx.doi.org/10.1214/15-AOP1042 in the Annals of
  Probability (http://www.imstat.org/aop/) by the Institute of Mathematical
  Statistics (http://www.imstat.org)</comments><proxy>vtex</proxy><report-no>IMS-AOP-AOP1042</report-no><journal-ref>Annals of Probability 2016, Vol. 44, No. 4, 3076-3110</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/15-AOP1042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a stochastic process, called the Liouville Brownian motion,
which is the Brownian motion associated to the metric $e^{\gamma X(z)}\,dz^2$,
$\gamma&lt;\gamma_c=2$ and $X$ is a Gaussian Free Field. Such a process is
conjectured to be related to the scaling limit of random walks on large planar
maps eventually weighted by a model of statistical physics which are embedded
in the Euclidean plane or in the sphere in a conformal manner. The construction
amounts to changing the speed of a standard two-dimensional Brownian motion
$B_t$ depending on the local behavior of the Liouville measure
&quot;$M_{\gamma}(dz)=e^{\gamma X(z)}\,dz$&quot;. We prove that the associated Markov
process is a Feller diffusion for all $\gamma&lt;\gamma_c=2$ and that for all
$\gamma&lt;\gamma_c$, the Liouville measure $M_{\gamma}$ is invariant under
$P_{\mathbf{t}}$. This Liouville Brownian motion enables us to introduce a
whole set of tools of stochastic analysis in Liouville quantum gravity, which
will be hopefully useful in analyzing the geometry of Liouville quantum
gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.0212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.0212</id><created>2013-12-01</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fyodorov</keyname><forenames>Y. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khoruzhenko</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simm</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractional Brownian motion with Hurst index $H=0$ and the Gaussian
  Unitary Ensemble</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>Published at http://dx.doi.org/10.1214/15-AOP1039 in the Annals of
  Probability (http://www.imstat.org/aop/) by the Institute of Mathematical
  Statistics (http://www.imstat.org)</comments><proxy>vtex</proxy><report-no>IMS-AOP-AOP1039</report-no><journal-ref>Annals of Probability 2016, Vol. 44, No. 4, 2980-3031</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/15-AOP1039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The goal of this paper is to establish a relation between characteristic
polynomials of $N\times N$ GUE random matrices $\mathcal{H}$ as $N\to\infty$,
and Gaussian processes with logarithmic correlations. We introduce a
regularized version of fractional Brownian motion with zero Hurst index, which
is a Gaussian process with stationary increments and logarithmic increment
structure. Then we prove that this process appears as a limit of
$D_N(z)=-\log|\det(\mathcal{H}-zI)|$ on mesoscopic scales as $N\to\infty$. By
employing a Fourier integral representation, we use this to prove a continuous
analogue of a result by Diaconis and Shahshahani [J. Appl. Probab. 31A (1994)
49-62]. On the macroscopic scale, $D_N(x)$ gives rise to yet another type of
Gaussian process with logarithmic correlations. We give an explicit
construction of the latter in terms of a Chebyshev-Fourier random series.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.3344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.3344</id><created>2014-04-13</created><updated>2015-11-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Yanhui</forenames></author></authors><title>The spectral properties of the strongly coupled Sturm Hamiltonian of
  eventually constant type</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This is a revised version. We generalize the results for all the
  frequencies of eventurally constant type. Accepted by Annales Henri Poincare</comments><msc-class>28A78, 37C45, 81Q10</msc-class><journal-ref>Ann. Henri Poincare 17 (2016) no. 9 2475-2511</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-016-0462-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spectral properties of the Sturm Hamiltolian of eventually
constant type, which includes the Fibonacci Hamiltonian. Let $s$ be the
Hausdorff dimension of the spectrum. For $V&gt;20$, we show that the restriction
of the $s$-dimensional Hausdorff measure to the spectrum is a Gibbs type
measure; the density of states measure is a Markov measure. Based on the fine
structures of these measures, we show that both measures are exact dimensional;
we obtain exact asymptotic behaviors for the optimal H\&quot;older exponent and the
Hausdorff dimension of the density of states measure and for the Hausdorff
dimension of the spectrum. As a consequence, if the frequency is not silver
number type, then for $V$ big enough, we establish strict inequalities between
these three spectral characteristics.
  We achieve them by introducing an auxiliary symbolic dynamical system and
applying the thermodynamical and multifractal formalisms of almost additive
potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3670</id><created>2014-05-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Mercurio</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leyssner</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tegeder</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkatchenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soubatch</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tautz</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantification of finite-temperature effects on adsorption geometries of
  $\pi$-conjugated molecules</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 88, 035421 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.88.035421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The adsorption structure of the molecular switch azobenzene on Ag(111) is
investigated by a combination of normal incidence x-ray standing waves and
dispersion-corrected density functional theory. The inclusion of non-local
collective substrate response (screening) in the dispersion correction improves
the description of dense monolayers of azobenzene, which exhibit a substantial
torsion of the molecule. Nevertheless, for a quantitative agreement with
experiment explicit consideration of the effect of vibrational mode
anharmonicity on the adsorption geometry is crucial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.0486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.0486</id><created>2014-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Diller</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klappenberger</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allegretti</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papageorgiou</keyname><forenames>Anthoula C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Sybille</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duncan</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Julian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Seung Cheol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barth</keyname><forenames>Johannes V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature-dependent templated growth of porphine thin films on the
  (111) facets of copper and silver</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4896605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The templated growth of the basic porphyrin unit, free-base porphine (2H-P),
is characterized by means of X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) and
near-edge X-ray absorption fine-structure (NEXAFS) spectroscopy measurements
and density functional theory (DFT). The DFT simulations allow the
deconvolution of the complex XPS and NEXAFS signatures into contributions
originating from five inequivalent carbon atoms, which can be grouped into C-N
and C-C bonded species. Polarization-dependent NEXAFS measurements reveal an
intriguing organizational behavior: On both Cu(111) and Ag(111), for coverages
up to one monolayer, the molecules adsorb undeformed and parallel to the
respective metal surface. Upon increasing the coverage, however, the
orientation of the molecules in the thin films depends on the growth
conditions. Multilayers deposited at low temperatures (LT) exhibit a similar
average tilting angle (30 degree relative to the surface plane) on both
substrates. Conversely, for multilayers grown at room temperature a markedly
different scenario exists. On Cu(111) the film thickness is self-limited to a
coverage of approximately two layers, while on Ag(111) multilayers can be grown
easily and, in contrast to the bulk 2H-P crystal, the molecules are oriented
perpendicular to the surface. This difference in molecular orientation results
in a modified line-shape of the C 1s XPS signatures that is dependent on the
incident photon energy, which is explained by comparison with depth-resolved
DFT calculations. Simulations of ionization energies for differently stacked
molecules show no indication for a packing-induced modification of the
multilayer XP spectra, thus indicating that the comparison of single molecule
calculations to multilayer data is justified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6494</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6494</id><created>2014-11-24</created><updated>2015-09-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frydel</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author></authors><title>Introduction to statistical field-theory: from a toy model to a
  one-component plasma</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Eur. J. Phys. 36 065050 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0143-0807/36/6/065050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Working with a toy model whose partition function consists of a discrete
summation, we introduce the statistical field-theory methodology by
transforming a partition function via a formal Gaussian integral relation (the
Hubbard-Stratonovich transformation). We then consider Gaussian type of
approximations, wherein correlational contributions enter as harmonic
fluctuations around the saddle-point solution. The work focuses on how to
construct a self-consistent, non-perturbative approximation without recourse to
a variational construction based on the Gibbs-Bogolyubov-Feynman inequality
that is inapplicable to a complex action. To address this problem, we propose a
construction based on a selective satisfaction of a set of exact relations
generated by considering a dual representation of a partition function, in its
original and transformed form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7577</id><created>2014-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Frydel</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author></authors><title>Mean-field electrostatics beyond the point-charge description</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Advances in Chemical Physics 160, chapter 4 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/9781119165156.ch4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This review explores the number of mean-field constructions for ions whose
structure goes beyond the point-charge description, a representation used in
the standard Poisson-Boltzmann equation. The exploration is motivated by a body
of experimental work which indicates that ion-specific effects play a
significant role, where ions of the same valence charge but different size,
polarizability, or shape yield quite different, and sometimes surprising
results. Furthermore, there are many large ions encountered in soft-matter and
biophysics that do not fit into a point-charge description, and their extension
in space and shape must be taken into account of any reasonable representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03995</id><created>2015-03-13</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ulrich</keyname><forenames>Jascha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otten</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassler</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of supersymmetric quantum mechanics in a Cooper-pair box
  shunted by a Josephson rhombus</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 245444 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.245444</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetries in quantum mechanics offer a way to obtain degeneracies in
the excitation spectrum which do not originate from selection rules. The
mechanism behind the degeneracies is the same as the one that leads to the
miraculous cancellations of divergences in supersymmetric field theories found
in the high energy physics context. Even though of importance, there is up to
now no realistic proposal of non-integrable systems that show level
degeneracies due to a supersymmetric structure. Here, we propose an
implementation of a quantum-mechanical supersymmetry in a Cooper-pair box
shunted by a Josephson junction rhombus which is effectively $\pi$-periodic in
the superconducting phase difference. For a characteristic ratio between the
strength of the $2\pi$- and the $\pi$-periodic junction, we find a two-fold
degeneracy of all the energy levels all the way from the weak junction/charge
qubit limit to the strong junction/transmon regime. We provide explicit values
for the parameters of the rhombus and show that tuning in and out of the
supersymmetric point is easily achieved by varying an external gate voltage. We
furthermore discuss a microwave experiment to detect the supersymmetry and
conclude that it could indeed be simulated with currently existing Josephson
junction technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01699</id><created>2015-05-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lakhno</keyname><forenames>V. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pekar's Ansatz and the Strong Coupling Problem in Polaron Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>35 pages, 4 figures. Physics-Uspekhi (Advances in Physical Sciences),
  2015, accepted. Draft version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.-Usp. 58, 295 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.3367/UFNe.0185.201503d.0317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed consideration is given to the translation-invariant theory of
Tulub polaron constructed without the use of Pekar ansatz. A fundamental result
of the theory is that the value of the polaron energy is lower than that
obtained on the basis of Pekar ansatz which was considered as an asymptotically
exact solution in the strong coupling limit. In the case of bipolarons the
theory yields the best values of the coupling energy and critical parameters of
their stability. Numerous physical consequences of the existence of
translation-invariant polarons and bipolarons are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04722</id><created>2015-05-18</created><updated>2015-10-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cirillo</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taleb</keyname><forenames>Nassim Nicholas</forenames></author></authors><title>On the statistical properties and tail risk of violent conflicts</title><categories>stat.AP physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications 429,
  252-260, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.01.050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine statistical pictures of violent conflicts over the last 2000
years, finding techniques for dealing with incompleteness and unreliability of
historical data. We introduce a novel approach to apply extreme value theory to
fat-tailed variables that have a remote, but nonetheless finite upper bound, by
defining a corresponding unbounded dual distribution (given that potential war
casualties are bounded by the world population). We apply methods from extreme
value theory on the dual distribution and derive its tail properties. The dual
method allows us to calculate the real mean of war casualties, which proves to
be considerably larger than the sample mean, meaning severe underestimation of
the tail risks of conflicts from naive observation. We analyze the robustness
of our results to errors in historical reports, taking into account the
unreliability of accounts by historians and absence of critical data. We study
inter-arrival times between tail events and find that no particular trend can
be asserted. All the statistical pictures obtained are at variance with the
prevailing claims about &quot;long peace&quot;, namely that violence has been declining
over time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03480</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2015-06-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Victor G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkatchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Many-body dispersion effects in the binding of adsorbates on metal
  surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 102808 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4922688</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A correct description of electronic exchange and correlation effects for
molecules in contact with extended (metal) surfaces is a challenging task for
first-principles modeling. In this work we demonstrate the importance of
collective van der Waals dispersion effects beyond the pairwise approximation
for organic--inorganic systems on the example of atoms, molecules, and
nanostructures adsorbed on metals. We use the recently developed many-body
dispersion (MBD) approach in the context of density-functional theory [Phys.
Rev. Lett. 108, 236402 (2012); J. Chem. Phys. 140, 18A508 (2014)] and assess
its ability to correctly describe the binding of adsorbates on metal surfaces.
We briefly review the MBD method and highlight its similarities to
quantum-chemical approaches to electron correlation in a quasiparticle picture.
In particular, we study the binding properties of xenon,
3,4,9,10-perylene-tetracarboxylic acid (PTCDA), and a graphene sheet adsorbed
on the Ag(111) surface. Accounting for MBD effects we are able to describe
changes in the anisotropic polarizability tensor, improve the description of
adsorbate vibrations, and correctly capture the adsorbate--surface interaction
screening. Comparison to other methods and experiment reveals that inclusion of
MBD effects improves adsorption energies and geometries, by reducing the
overbinding typically found in pairwise additive dispersion-correction
approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01502</id><created>2015-08-06</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Cristopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om-(A)dS Black Hole in Asymptotic Safety</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>V1:23 pages, 9 figures. V2:28 pages, 12 figures. Incorporation of
  references in introduction section and consideration of another analysis in
  section 5, without changes in the conclusions. V3:28 pages, 12 figures. Some
  redaction corrections. Accepted in International Journal of Modern Physics A</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper studies the quantum modifications of the
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m-(A)dS black hole within Quantum Einstein Gravity,
coupled to an electromagnetic sector. Quantum effects are introduced on the
level of the improvements of the classical solution, where the originally
constant couplings ($G_0$, $\Lambda_0$, and $\alpha_0$) are promoted to scale
dependent quantities ($G_k$, $\Lambda_k$, and $\alpha_k$). Those running
couplings are calculated in the functional renormalization group approach. A
crucial point of this, so called &quot;improving solutions&quot; procedure is the scale
setting where the arbitrary scale $k$ acquires physical meaning due to a
relation to the coordinate scale $r$. It is proposed to use such scale settings
which are stable after iterative improvements. Using this method one finds that
for those improved solutions, there is no stable remnant and due to the
appearance of a new internal horizon, there is also no necessity to impose a
minimal black hole mass for charged black holes, in order to avoid the the
cosmic censorship hypothesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06647</id><created>2015-08-26</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fritz</keyname><forenames>Tobias K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kallivayalil</keyname><forenames>Nitya</forenames></author></authors><title>The proper motion of Palomar 5</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures, accepted by ApJ, typo in table 1 corrected</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/811/2/123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Palomar 5 (Pal 5) is a faint halo globular cluster associated with narrow
tidal tails. It is a useful system to understand the process of tidal
dissolution, as well as to constrain the potential of the Milky Way. A
well-determined orbit for Pal 5 would enable detailed study of these open
questions. We present here the first CCD-based proper motion measurement of Pal
5 obtained using SDSS as a first epoch and new LBT/LBC images as a second,
giving a baseline of 15 years. We perform relative astrometry, using SDSS as a
distortion-free reference, and images of the cluster and also of the Pal 5
stream for the derivation of the distortion correction for LBC. The reference
frame is made up of background galaxies. We correct for differential chromatic
refraction using relations obtained from SDSS colors as well as from
flux-calibrated spectra, finding that the correction relations for stars and
for galaxies are different. We obtain mu_alpha=-2.296+/-0.186 mas/yr and
mu_delta=-2.257+/-0.181 mas/yr for the proper motion of Pal 5. We use this
motion, and the publicly available code galpy, to model the disruption of Pal 5
in different Milky Way models consisting of a bulge, a disk and a spherical
dark matter halo. Our fits to the observed stream properties (streak and radial
velocity gradient) result in a preference for a relatively large Pal 5 distance
of around 24 kpc. A slightly larger absolute proper motion than what we measure
also results in better matches but the best solutions need a change in
distance. We find that a spherical Milky Way model, with V_0=220 km/s and V_(20
kpc), i.e., approximately at the apocenter of Pal 5, of 218 km/s, can match the
data well, at least for our choice of disk and bulge parametrization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07011</id><created>2015-08-27</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigol</keyname><forenames>Marcos</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal scaling of density and momentum distributions in Lieb-Liniger
  gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>13 pages,12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 063623 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.063623</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an exact numerical study of the scaling of density and momentum
distribution functions of harmonically trapped one-dimensional bosons with
repulsive contact interactions at zero and finite temperatures. We use path
integral quantum Monte Carlo with worm updates in our calculations at finite
interaction strengths, and the Bose-Fermi mapping in the Tonks-Girardeau
regime. We discuss the homogeneous case and, within the local density
approximation, use it to motivate the scaling in the presence of a harmonic
trap. For the momentum distribution function, we pay special attention to the
high momentum tails and their $k^{-4}$ asymptotic behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00346</id><created>2015-09-01</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Szybka</keyname><forenames>Sebastian J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyr&#x229;bowski</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142; J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Backreaction for Einstein-Rosen waves coupled to a massless scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>26 pages; minor changes to match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 024059 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a one-parameter family of exact solutions to Einstein equations
that may be used to study the nature of the Green-Wald backreaction framework.
Our explicit example is a family of Einstein-Rosen waves coupled to a massless
scalar field. This solution may be reinterpreted as a generalized three-torus
polarized Gowdy cosmology with scalar and gravitational waves. We use it to
illustrate essential properties of the Green-Wald approach. Among other things
we show that within our model the Green-Wald framework uniquely determines
backreaction for finite size inhomogeneities on a predefined background. The
results agree with those calculated in the Charach-Malin approach. In the
vacuum limit, the Green-Wald, the Charach-Malin and the Isaacson method imply
identical backreaction as expected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03745</id><created>2015-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>Carolina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitelli</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dauchot</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author></authors><title>Orientational order at finite temperature on undulated surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Submitted to Soft Matter</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment, 2016 (3)
  033208 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/03/033208</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of thermal fluctuations in the XY-model on a surface with
non vanishing mean curvature and zero Gaussian curvature. Unlike Gaussian
curvature that typically frustrates orientational order, the extrinsic
curvature of the surface can act as a local field that promotes long range
order at low temperature. We find numerically that the transition from the high
temperature isotropic phase to the true long range ordered phase is
characterized by critical exponents consistent with those of the flat space
Ising model in two dimensions, up to finite size effects. Our results suggest a
versatile strategy to achieve geometric control of liquid crystal order by
suitable design of the underlying curvature of a substrate or bounding surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04030</id><created>2015-10-14</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cadoni</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franzin</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mignemi</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation as de Sitter instability</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures. Matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016) 483</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4322-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider cosmological inflation generated by a scalar field slowly rolling
off from a de Sitter maximum of its potential. The models belong to the class
of hilltop models and represent the most general model of this kind in which
the scalar potential can be written as the sum of two exponentials. The
minimally coupled Einstein-scalar gravity theory obtained in this way is the
cosmological version of a two-scale generalization of known holographic models,
allowing for solitonic solutions interpolating between an AdS spacetime in the
infrared and scaling solutions in the ultraviolet. We then investigate
cosmological inflation in the slow-roll approximation. Our model reproduces
correctly, for a wide range of its parameters, the most recent experimental
data for the power spectrum of primordial perturbations. Moreover, it predicts
inflation at energy scales of four to five orders of magnitude below the Planck
scale. At the onset of inflation, the mass of the tachyonic excitation, i.e. of
the inflaton, turns out to be seven to eight orders of magnitude smaller than
the Planck mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05508</id><created>2015-09-30</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lidon</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Lecture notes on surface tension</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>in French</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lecture notes in french of the lecture on surface tension given in 2015 and
2016 at the preparation to &quot;Agr\'egation de physique&quot; in the Ecole Normale
Sup\'erieure de Lyon
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05812</id><created>2015-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Lakhno</keyname><forenames>Victor D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon interaction of electron in the translation-invariant
  strong-coupling theory</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>Modern Physics Letters B, accepted. 5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. B, 30, 1650031 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217984916500317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A dependence of phonon interaction on the interelectronic distance is found
for a translation-invariant (TI) strong-coupling bipolaron. It is shown that
the charge induced by the electrons in a TI-bipolaron state is always greater
than that in a bipolaron with spontaneously broken symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01736</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mondal</keyname><forenames>Chandan</forenames></author></authors><title>Longitudinal momentum densities in transverse plane for nucleons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures; text modified</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76, 74 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-3922-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a study of longitudinal momentum densities ($p^+ \rm densities$)
in the transverse impact parameter space for $u$ and $d$ quarks in both
unpolarized and transversely polarized nucleons by taking a two dimensional
Fourier transform of the gravitational form factors with respect to the
momentum transfer in the transverse direction. The gravitational form factors
are obtained by the second moments of GPDs. Here we consider the GPDs of two
different soft-wall models in AdS/QCD correspondence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04149</id><created>2015-11-12</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Igata</keyname><forenames>Takahisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomizawa</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational two solitons in Levi-Civita spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures, version to be published in Classical and Quantum
  Gravity</comments><report-no>RUP-15-25</report-no><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 33, 185005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/18/185005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Applying the Pomeransky inverse scattering method to the four-dimensional
vacuum Einstein equations and using the Levi-Civita solution as a seed, we
construct a two-soliton solution with cylindrical symmetry. In our previous
work, we constructed the one-soliton solution with a real pole and showed that
the singularities that the Levi-Civita background has on an axis can be removed
by the choice of certain special parameters, but it still has unavoidable null
singularities, as usual one-solitons do. In this work, we show that for the
two-soliton solutions, any singularities can be removed by suitable
parameter-setting and such solutions describe the propagation of gravitational
wave packets. Moreover, in terms of the two-soliton solutions, we mention a
time shift phenomenon, the coalescence and the split of solitons as the
nonlinear effect of gravitational waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01987</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diller</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Interfacial charge rearrangement and intermolecular interactions:
  Density-functional theory study of free-base porphine adsorbed on Ag(111) and
  Cu(111)</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures, 3 tables</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4938259</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We employ dispersion-corrected density-functional theory to study the
adsorption of tetrapyrrole 2H-porphine (2H-P) at Cu(111) and Ag(111). Various
contributions to adsorbate-substrate and adsorbate-adsorbate interactions are
systematically extracted to analyze the self-assembly behavior of this basic
building block to porphyrin-based metal-organic nanostructures. This analysis
reveals a surprising importance of substrate-mediated van der Waals
interactions between 2H-P molecules, in contrast to negligible direct
dispersive interactions. The resulting net repulsive interactions rationalize
the experimentally observed tendency for single molecule adsorption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02224</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Schaffer</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Eric Kin-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Bohm-Jung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong Baek</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent progress on correlated electron systems with strong spin-orbit
  coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>19 pages plus references, submitted to Reports on Progress in Physics</comments><journal-ref>Reports on Progress in Physics 79, 9, 094504 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0034-4885/79/9/094504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Emergence of novel quantum ground states in correlated electron systems with
strong spin-orbit coupling has been a recent subject of intensive studies.
While it has been realized that spin-orbit coupling can provide non-trivial
band topology in weakly interacting electron systems, as in topological
insulators and semi-metals, the role of electron-electron interaction in
strongly spin-orbit coupled systems has not been fully understood. The
availability of new materials with significant electron correlation and strong
spin-orbit coupling now makes such investigations possible. Many of these
materials contain 5d or 4d transition metal elements; the prominent examples
are iridium oxides or iridates. In this review, we succinctly discuss recent
theoretical and experimental progress on this subject. After providing a brief
overview, we focus on pyrochlore iridates and three-dimensional honeycomb
iridates. In pyrochlore iridates, we discuss the quantum criticality of the
bulk and surface states, and the relevance of the surface/boundary states in a
number of topological and magnetic ground states, both in the bulk and thin
film configurations. Experimental signatures of these boundary and bulk states
are discussed. Domain wall formation and strongly-direction-dependent
magneto-transport are also discussed. Regarding the three-dimensional honeycomb
iridates, we consider possible quantum spin liquid phases and unusual magnetic
orders in theoretical models with strongly bond-dependent interactions. These
theoretical ideas and results are discussed in light of recent resonant X-ray
scattering experiments on three-dimensional honeycomb iridates. We also
contrast these results with the situation in two-dimensional honeycomb
iridates. We conclude with the outlook on other related systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02468</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>The nine ways of four qubit entanglement and their threetangle</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>9 pages, 13 figures, revtex 4</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012323 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I calculate the mixed threetangle $\tau_3[\rho]$ for the reduced density
matrices of the four-qubit representant states found in Phys. Rev. A {\bf 65},
052112 (2002). In most of the cases, the convex roof is obtained, except for
one class, where I provide with a new upper bound, which is assumed to be very
close to the convex roof. I compare with results published in Phys. Rev. Lett.
{\bf 113}, 110501 (2014). Since the method applied there usually results in
higher values for the upper bound, in certain cases it can be understood that
the convex roof is obtained exactly, namely when the zero-polytope where
$\tau_3$ vanishes shrinks to a single point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04253</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04253</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholtz</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A manifestly Lorentz covariant, interacting and non-commutative Dirac
  equation</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a manifestly Lorentz covariant, non-commutative Dirac equation for
charged particles interacting with an electromagnetic field. The equation is
formulated on the operator level, but operators are not composed through the
normal operator product, but a modified product that restores the Lorentz
covariance. This equation is solved for the free particle and a particle moving
in a constant magnetic field. An abstract action, constructed on the operator
level, that yields this equation as equation of motion is also derived. To
relate this formalism to current formulations of non-commutative quantum field
theories, this action is written in a coherent state basis, leading to an
action in 4-dimensional Minkowski space-time. The resulting action differs from
existing non-commutative actions, but still exhibits non-commutative effects
through non-locality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04292</id><created>2015-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Richardson</keyname><forenames>Jeremy O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Derivation of instanton rate theory from first principles</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 114106 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4943866</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Instanton rate theory is used to study tunneling events in a wide range of
systems including low-temperature chemical reactions. Despite many successful
applications, the method has never been obtained from first principles, relying
instead on the &quot;ImF&quot; premise. In this paper, the same expression for the rate
of barrier penetration at finite temperature is rederived from quantum
scattering theory [W. H. Miller, S. D. Schwartz, and J. W. Tromp, J. Chem.
Phys. 79, 4889 (1983)] using a semiclassical Green's function formalism. This
justifies the instanton approach and provides a route to deriving the rate of
other processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04576</id><created>2015-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Karan</keyname><forenames>Sujoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yajie</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>I-Po</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Huanjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Jing-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yongfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Lianmao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michelitsch</keyname><forenames>Georg S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diller</keyname><forenames>Katharina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weismann</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berndt</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Manipulation by Creation of Single-Molecule Radical Cations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 027201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.027201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  All-trans-retinoic acid (ReA), a closed-shell organic molecule comprising
only C, H, and O atoms, is investigated on a Au(111) substrate using scanning
tunneling microscopy and spectroscopy. In dense arrays single ReA molecules are
switched to a number of states, three of which carry a localized spin as
evidenced by conductance spectroscopy in high magnetic fields. The spin of a
single molecule may be reversibly switched on and off without affecting its
neighbors. We suggest that ReA on Au is readily converted to a radical by the
abstraction of an electron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05987</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Upper bound for SL-invariant entanglement measures of mixed states</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, revtex4</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 052322 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.052322</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An algorithm is proposed that serves to handle full rank density matrices,
when coming from a lower rank method to compute the convex-roof. This is in
order to calculate an upper bound for any polynomial SL invariant multipartite
entanglement measure E. Here, it is exemplifyed how this algorithm works, based
on a method for calculating convex-roofs of rank two density matrices. It
iteratively considers the decompositions of the density matrix into two states
each, exploiting the knowledge for the rank-two case. The algorithm is
therefore quasi exact as far as the two rank case is concerned, and it also
gives hints where it should include more states in the decomposition of the
density matrix. Focusing on the threetangle, I show the results the algorithm
gives for two states, one of which being the $GHZ$-Werner state, for which the
exact convex roof is known. It overestimates the threetangle in the state,
thereby giving insight into the optimal decomposition the $GHZ$-Werner state
has. As a proof of principle, I have run the algorithm for the threetangle on
the transverse quantum Ising model. I give qualitative and quantitative
arguments why the convex roof should be close to the upper bound found here.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06039</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06039</id><created>2015-12-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Darmon</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benzaquen</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dauchot</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez-Leon</keyname><forenames>Teresa</forenames></author></authors><title>Waltzing route towards double-helix formation in cholesteric shells</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>PNAS 113 (34) 9469-9474, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1525059113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study cholesteric order in liquid crystal shells with planar degenerate
anchoring. We observe that the bipolar and radial configurations intensively
reported for bulk droplets have a higher degree of complexity when the liquid
crystal is confined to a spherical shell. The bipolar configuration is replaced
by a structure where the boojums are linked to a stack of disclination rings
that spans the shell, while the radial configuration exhibits a double helix
structure where two disclinations wind around each other. Our results confirm
recent numerical simulations and highlight the complexity of the defect
structures arising when cholesteric liquid crystals are confined to spherical
geometries. We also show that the position of the boojums is only ruled by the
shell geometry, independently of the cholesteric pitch. To understand
quantitatively this behavior, we develop a simple yet insightful theoretical
framework which captures the essence of the observed phenomenology. We also
show that the transition between the two configurations is solely governed by
the confinement ratio c = h/p, where h is the average shell thickness and p is
the cholesteric pitch. Finally, we perform a dynamical study of this
transition, and report a fascinating defect waltz due to a chemical Lehmann
effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07774</id><created>2015-12-24</created><updated>2016-08-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Qianqian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Maodu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xianzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Yingqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Wenjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Mengtao</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast Dynamics of Plasmon-Exciton Interaction of Ag
  Nanowire-Graphene Hybrids for Surface Catalytic Reactions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports, 2016, 6, 32724</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep32724</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the ultrafast pump-probe transient absorption spectroscopy, the
femtosecond-resolved plasmon-exciton interaction of graphene-Ag nanowire
hybrids is experimentally investigated, in the VIS-NIR region. The plasmonic
lifetime of Ag nanowire is about 150 femtosecond (fs). For a single layer of
graphene, the fast dynamic process at 275 fs is due to the excitation of
graphene excitons, and the slow process at 1.4 picosecond (ps) is due to the
plasmonic hot electron interaction with phonons of graphene. For the
graphene-Ag nanowire hybrids, the time scale of the plasmon-induced hot
electron transferring to graphene is 534 fs, and the metal plasmon enhanced
graphene plasmon is about 3.2 ps in the VIS region. The graphene-Ag nanowire
hybrids can be used for plasmon-driven chemical reactions. This
graphene-mediated surface-enhanced Raman scattering substrate significantly
increases the probability and efficiency of surface catalytic reactions
co-driven by graphene-Ag nanowire hybridization, in comparison with reactions
individually driven by monolayer graphene or single Ag nanowire. This implies
that the graphene-Ag nanowire hybrids can not only lead to a significant
accumulation of high-density hot electrons, but also significantly increase the
plasmon-to-electron conversion efficiency, due to strong plasmon-exciton
coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08033</id><created>2015-12-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Boyer</keyname><forenames>Timothy H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Understanding Zero-Point Energy in the Context of Classical
  Electromagnetism</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><journal-ref>European Journal of Physics 37, 055206 (14) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0143-0807/37/5/055206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Today's textbooks of electromagnetism give the particular solution to
Maxwell's equations involving the integral over the charge and current sources
at retarded times. However, the texts fail to emphasize the role played by the
choice of the boundary conditions corresponding to solutions of the homogeneous
Maxwell equations. Here we discuss the role of these boundary conditions for an
experimenter with a hypothetical charged harmonic oscillator as his equipment.
We describe the observations of the experimenter when located near a radio
station or immersed in thermal radiation at temperature T. The classical
physicists at the end of the 19th century chose the homogeneous boundary
conditions for Maxwell's equation based upon the experimental observations of
Lummer and Pringsheim which measured only the thermal radiation which exceeded
the random radiation surrounding their measuring equipment. Today at the
beginning of the 21st century, classical physicists must choose the homogeneous
boundary conditions for Maxell's equations to correspond to the full radiation
spectrum revealed by the recent Casimir force measurements which detect all the
radiation surrounding conducting parallel plates, including the radiation
absorbed and emitted by the plates themselves. The random classical radiation
spectrum revealed by the Casimir force measurements includes electromagnetic
zero-point radiation, which is missing from the spectrum measured by Lummer and
Pringsheim, and which cannot be eliminated by going to zero temperature. This
zero-point radiation will lead to zero-point energy for all systems which have
electromagnetic interactions. Thus the choice of the boundary conditions on the
homogeneous Maxwell equations is intimately related to the ideas of zero-point
energy and non-radiating ground states which are introduced in classes of
modern physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00589</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Palmese</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahav</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerji</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jouvel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchior</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aleksi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Annis</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>H. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeltema</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romer</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seitz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suchyta</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbott</keyname><forenames>T. M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allam</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benoit-L&#xe9;vy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buckley-Geer</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capozzi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosell</keyname><forenames>A. Carnero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kind</keyname><forenames>M. Carrasco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretero</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crocce</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Costa</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Estrada</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evrard</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaugher</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frieman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerdes</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruendl</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honscheid</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuropatkin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maia</keyname><forenames>M. A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miquel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogando</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plazas</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roodman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarpine</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla-Noarbe</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares-Santos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreira</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swanson</keyname><forenames>M. E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarle</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vikram</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing Dark Energy Survey and HST-CLASH observations of the galaxy
  cluster RXC J2248.7-4431: implications for stellar mass versus dark matter</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures. Changed to matched the version accepted on
  MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2062</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the stellar mass fraction in the galaxy cluster RXC J2248.7-4431
observed with the Dark Energy Survey (DES) during the Science Verification
period. We compare the stellar mass results from DES (five filters) with those
from the Hubble Space Telescope Cluster Lensing And Supernova Survey (CLASH; 17
filters). When the cluster spectroscopic redshift is assumed, we show that
stellar masses from DES can be estimated within 25% of CLASH values. We compute
the stellar mass contribution coming from red and blue galaxies, and study the
relation between stellar mass and the underlying dark matter using weak lensing
studies with DES and CLASH. An analysis of the radial profiles of the DES total
and stellar mass yields a stellar-to-total fraction of f*=(6.8+-1.7)x10^-3
within a radius of r_200c~2 Mpc. Our analysis also includes a comparison of
photometric redshifts and star/galaxy separation efficiency for both data sets.
We conclude that space-based small field imaging can be used to calibrate the
galaxy properties in DES for the much wider field of view. The technique
developed to derive the stellar mass fraction in galaxy clusters can be applied
to the ~100 000 clusters that will be observed within this survey and yield
important information about galaxy evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07711</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07711</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawaguchi</keyname><forenames>Kyohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyutoku</keyname><forenames>Koutarou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>Masaru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Masaomi</forenames></author></authors><title>Models of Kilonova/macronova emission from black hole-neutron star
  mergers</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables, published in ApJ. Online lightcurve
  calculator of our model is available at
  http://www2.yukawa.kyoto-u.ac.jp/~kyohei.kawaguchi/kn_calc/main.html</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 825, Issue 1, article id. 52,
  pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/1/52</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Black hole-neutron star mergers are among the promising gravitational-wave
sources for ground-based detectors, and gravitational waves from black
hole-neutron star mergers are expected to be detected in the next few years.
Simultaneous detection of electromagnetic counterparts with gravitational-wave
detection provides rich information about the merger events. Among the possible
electromagnetic counterparts from the black hole-neutron star merger, the
emission powered by the decay of radioactive r-process nuclei, so called
kilonova/macronova, is one of the best targets for follow-up observation. We
derive fitting formulas for the mass and the velocity of ejecta from a generic
black hole-neutron star merger based on recently performed numerical relativity
simulations. We combined these fitting formulas with a new semi-analytic model
for a black hole-neutron star kilonova/macronova lightcurve which reproduces
the results of radiation-transfer simulations. Specifically, the semi-analytic
model reproduces the result of each band magnitude obtained by the radiation
transfer simulations within ~1 mag. By using this semi-analytic model, we found
that, at 400 Mpc, the kilonova/macronova is as bright as 22-24 mag for the
cases with a small chirp mass and a high black hole spin, and &gt;28 mag for a
large chirp mass and a low black hole spin. We also apply our model to
GRB130603B as an illustration, and show that a black hole-neutron star merger
with a rapidly spinning black hole and a large neutron star radius is favored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02767</id><created>2016-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ringbauer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giarmatzi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaves</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedrizzi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Test of Nonlocal Causality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Science Advances, Vol. 2, no. 8, e1600162 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1600162</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Explaining observations in terms of causes and effects is central to all of
empirical science. Correlations between entangled quantum particles, however,
seem to defy such an explanation. To recover a causal picture in this case,
some of the fundamental assumptions of causal explanations have to give way.
Here we consider a broad class of models where one of these assumptions, Bell's
local causality, is relaxed by allowing a direct influence from one measurement
outcome to the other. We use interventional and observational data from a
photonic experiment to bound the strength of this causal influence in a
two-party Bell scenario and test a novel Bell-type inequality for the
considered models. Our results demonstrate the incompatibility of quantum
mechanics with an important class of nonlocal causal models, which includes
Bell's original model as a special case. Recovering a classical causal picture
of quantum correlations thus requires an even more counter-intuitive
modification of our classical notion of cause and effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03433</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2016-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Haro</keyname><forenames>Jaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elizalde</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflation and late-time acceleration from a double-well potential with
  cosmological constant</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure. Version accepted for publication in GERG</comments><report-no>1602.03433</report-no><journal-ref>GERG 48, (2016) 77</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2072-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model of a universe without big bang singularity is presented, which
displaysanearly inflationary period ending just before a phase transition to a
deflationary epoch. The model produces enough heavy particles so as to reheat
the universe at temperatures in the MeV regime. After the reheating, it
smoothly matches the standard $\Lambda$CDM scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07596</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Pardeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Shubhrangshu</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical switching and bistability in a four-level atomic systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 023851 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.023851</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the coherent control of nonlinear absorption of intense laser
fields in four-level atomic systems. For instance, in a four-level ladder
system, a coupling field creates electromagnetically induced transparency (EIT)
with Aulter-Townes doublet for the probe field while the control field is
absent. A large absorption peak appears at resonance as the control field is
switched on. We show how such a large absorption leads to optical switching.
Further, this large absorption gets diminished and a transparency window
appears due to the saturation effects as the strength of the probe field is
increased. We further demonstrate that the threshold of the optical bistability
can be modified by suitable choices of the coupling and the control fields. In
a four-level Y-type configuration, the effect of the control field on saturable
absorption (SA) and reverse saturable absorption (RSA) is highlighted in the
context of nonlinear absorption of the probe field. We achieve RSA and SA in a
simple atomic system just by applying a control field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07728</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gavryusev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Signoles</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira-Cao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xfc;rn</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;nter</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schempp</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert-de-Saint-Vincent</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitlock</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidem&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Density matrix reconstruction of three-level atoms via Rydberg
  electromagnetically induced transparency</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 164002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/16/164002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present combined measurements of the spatially-resolved optical spectrum
and the total excited-atom number in an ultracold gas of three-level atoms
under electromagnetically induced transparency conditions involving high-lying
Rydberg states. The observed optical transmission of a weak probe laser at the
center of the coupling region exhibits a double peaked spectrum as a function
of detuning, whilst the Rydberg atom number shows a comparatively narrow single
resonance. By imaging the transmitted light onto a charge-coupled-device
camera, we record hundreds of spectra in parallel, which are used to map out
the spatial profile of Rabi frequencies of the coupling laser. Using all the
information available we can reconstruct the full one-body density matrix of
the three-level system, which provides the optical susceptibility and the
Rydberg density as a function of spatial position. These results help elucidate
the connection between three-level interference phenomena, including the
interplay of matter and light degrees of freedom and will facilitate new
studies of many-body effects in optically driven Rydberg gases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02325</id><created>2016-02-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Doppler</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mailybaev</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Girschik</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libisch</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milburn</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moiseyev</keyname><forenames>Nimrod</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamically encircling exceptional points in a waveguide: asymmetric
  mode switching from the breakdown of adiabaticity</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nature 537, 76 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature18605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical systems with loss or gain feature resonant modes that are decaying
or growing exponentially with time. Whenever two such modes coalesce both in
their resonant frequency and their rate of decay or growth, a so-called
&quot;exceptional point&quot; occurs, around which many fascinating phenomena have
recently been reported to arise. Particularly intriguing behavior is predicted
to appear when encircling an exceptional point sufficiently slowly, like a
state-flip or the accumulation of a geometric phase. Experiments dedicated to
this issue could already successfully explore the topological structure of
exceptional points, but a full dynamical encircling and the breakdown of
adiabaticity inevitably associated with it remained out of reach of any
measurement so far. Here we demonstrate that a dynamical encircling of an
exceptional point can be mapped onto the problem of scattering through a
two-mode waveguide, which allows us for the first time to access the elusive
effects occurring in this context. Specifically, we present experimental
results from a waveguide structure that steers incoming waves around an
exceptional point during the transmission process. In this way mode transitions
are induced that make this device perfectly suited as a robust and asymmetric
switch between different waveguide modes. Our work opens up new and exciting
avenues to explore exceptional point physics at the crossroads between
fundamental research and practical applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03363</id><created>2016-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poltavsky</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stecher</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oberhofer</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkatchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal and electronic fluctuations of flexible adsorbed molecules:
  Azobenzene on Ag(111)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.146101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the thermal and electronic collective fluctuations that
contribute to the finite-temperature adsorption properties of flexible
adsorbates on surfaces on the example of the molecular switch azobenzene
C$_{12}$H$_{10}$N$_{2}$ on the Ag(111) surface. Using first-principles
molecular dynamics simulations we obtain the free energy of adsorption that
accurately accounts for entropic contributions, whereas the inclusion of
many-body dispersion interactions accounts for the electronic correlations that
govern the adsorbate binding. We find the adsorbate properties to be strongly
entropy-driven, as can be judged by a kinetic molecular desorption prefactor of
10$^{24}$ s$^{-1}$ that largely exceeds previously reported estimates. We
relate this effect to sizable fluctuations across structural and electronic
observables. Comparison of our calculations to temperature-programmed
desorption measurements demonstrates that finite-temperature effects play a
dominant role for flexible molecules in contact with polarizable surfaces, and
that recently developed first-principles methods offer an optimal tool to
reveal novel collective behavior in such complex systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06320</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brandsen</keyname><forenames>Sarah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dall'Arno</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymusiak</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Communication capacity of mixed quantum t designs</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, improved presentation, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 022335 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.022335</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We operationally introduce mixed quantum t-designs as the most general
arbitrary-rank extension of projective quantum t-designs which preserves
indistinguishability from the uniform distribution for t copies. First, we
derive upper bounds on the classical communication capacity of any mixed
t-design measurement for t in [1,5]. Second, we explicitly compute the
classical communication capacity of several mixed t-design measurements,
including the depolarized version of any qubit and qutrit symmetric,
informationally complete (SIC) measurement and complete mutually unbiased
bases, the qubit icosahedral measurement, the Hoggar SIC measurement, any
anti-SIC (where each element is proportional to the projector on the subspace
orthogonal to one of the elements of the original SIC), and the uniform
distribution over pure effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06574</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rix</keyname><forenames>Hans-Walter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ting</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conroy</keyname><forenames>Charlie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogg</keyname><forenames>David W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constructing Polynomial Spectral Models for Stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, ApJL (Accepted for publication- 2016 May 9)</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 826, L25 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/826/2/L25</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stellar spectra depend on the stellar parameters and on dozens of
photospheric elemental abundances. Simultaneous fitting of these
$\mathcal{N}\sim 10-40$ model labels to observed spectra has been deemed
unfeasible, because the number of ab initio spectral model grid calculations
scales exponentially with $\mathcal{N}$. We suggest instead the construction of
a polynomial spectral model (PSM) of order $\mathcal{O}$ for the model flux at
each wavelength. Building this approximation requires a minimum of only
${\mathcal{N}+\mathcal{O}\choose\mathcal{O}}$ calculations: e.g. a quadratic
spectral model ($\mathcal{O}=2$) to fit $\mathcal{N}=20$ labels simultaneously,
can be constructed from as few as $231$ ab initio spectral model calculations;
in practice, a somewhat larger number ($\sim 300-1000$) of randomly chosen
models lead to a better performing PSM. Such a PSM can be a good approximation
only over a portion of label space, which will vary case by case. Yet, taking
the APOGEE survey as an example, a single quadratic PSM provides a remarkably
good approximation to the exact ab initio spectral models across much of this
survey: for random labels within that survey the PSM approximates the flux to
within $10^{-3}$, and recovers the abundances to within $\sim 0.02$ dex rms of
the exact models. This enormous speed-up enables the simultaneous many-label
fitting of spectra with computationally expensive ab initio models for stellar
spectra, such as non-LTE models. A PSM also enables the simultaneous fitting of
observational parameters, such as the spectrum's continuum or line-spread
function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08646</id><created>2016-03-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Chotibut</keyname><forenames>Thiparat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Succi</keyname><forenames>Sauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Striated Populations in Disordered Environments with Advection</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>30 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.08.059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Growth in static and controlled environments such as a Petri dish can be used
to study the spatial population dynamics of microorganisms. However, natural
populations such as marine microbes experience fluid advection and often grow
up in heterogeneous environments. We investigate a generalized
Fisher-Kolmogorov-Petrovsky-Piscounov (FKPP) equation describing single species
population subject to a constant flow field and quenched random spatially
inhomogeneous growth rates with a fertile overall growth condition. We
analytically and numerically demonstrate that the non-equilibrium steady-state
population density develops a flow-driven striation pattern. The striations are
highly asymmetric with a longitudinal correlation length that diverges linearly
with the flow speed and a transverse correlation length that approaches a
finite velocity-independent value. Linear response theory is developed to study
the statistics of the steady states. Theoretical predictions show excellent
agreement with the numerical steady states of the generalized FKPP equation
obtained from Lattice Boltzmann simulations. These findings suggest that,
although the growth disorder can be spatially uncorrelated, correlated
population structures with striations emerge naturally at sufficiently strong
advection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09604</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Ambrosetti</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salasnich</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silvestrelli</keyname><forenames>Pier Luigi</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical spin properties of confined Fermi and Bose systems in presence
  of spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Low Temperature Physics, (2016) 185: 3</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10909-016-1610-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to the recent experimental progress, tunable spin-orbit (SO) interactions
represent ideal candidates for the control of polarization and dynamical spin
properties in both quantum wells and cold atomic systems. A detailed
understanding of spin properties in SO coupled systems is thus a compelling
prerequisite for possible novel applications or improvements in the context of
spintronics and quantum computers. Here we analyze the case of equal Rashba and
Dresselhaus couplings in both homogeneous and laterally confined
two-dimensional systems. Starting from the single-particle picture and
subsequently introducing two-body interactions we observe that periodic spin
fluctuations can be induced and maintained in the system. Through an analytical
derivation we show that the two-body interaction does not involve decoherence
effects in the bosonic dimer, and, in the repulsive homogeneous Fermi gas it
may be even exploited in combination with the SO coupling to induce and tune
standing currents. By further studying the effects of a harmonic lateral
confinement --a particularly interesting case for Bose condensates-- we
evidence the possible appearance of non-trivial {\it spin textures}, whereas
the further application of a small Zeeman-type interaction can be exploited to
fine-tune the system polarizability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01203</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hemingway</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchetti</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fielding</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation lengths in hydrodynamic models of active nematics</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures v2 updated to post-referee version (published in
  Soft Matter)</comments><doi>10.1039/C6SM00812G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the scaling with activity of the emergent length scales that
control the nonequilibrium dynamics of an active nematic liquid crystal, using
two popular hydrodynamic models that have been employed in previous studies. In
both models we find that the chaotic spatio-temporal dynamics in the regime of
fully developed active turbulence is controlled by a single active scale
determined by the balance of active and elastic stresses, regardless of whether
the active stress is extensile or contractile in nature. The observed scaling
of the kinetic energy and enstropy with activity is consistent with our
single-length scale argument and simple dimensional analysis. Our results
provide a unified understanding of apparent discrepancies in the previous
literature and demonstrate that the essential physics is robust to the choice
of model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02493</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>St&#xf6;hr</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michelitsch</keyname><forenames>Georg S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tully</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Communication: Charge-Population Based Dispersion Interactions for
  Molecules and Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, accepted for publication in J. Chem. Phys as a
  communication</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4947214</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a system-independent method to derive effective atomic C$_6$
coefficients and polarizabilities in molecules and materials purely from charge
population analysis. This enables the use of dispersion-correction schemes in
electronic structure calculations without recourse to electron-density
partitioning schemes and expands their applicability to semi-empirical methods
and tight-binding Hamiltonians. We show that the accuracy of our method is en
par with established electron-density partitioning based approaches in
describing intermolecular C$_6$ coefficients as well as dispersion energies of
weakly bound molecular dimers, organic crystals, and supramolecular complexes.
We showcase the utility of our approach by incorporation of the recently
developed many-body dispersion (MBD) method [Tkatchenko et al., Phys. Rev.
Lett. 108, 236402 (2012)] into the semi-empirical Density Functional
Tight-Binding (DFTB) method and propose the latter as a viable technique to
study hybrid organic-inorganic interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03106</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khatri</keyname><forenames>Rishi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaspari</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal SZ fluctuations in the ICM: probing turbulence and
  thermodynamics in Coma cluster with ${\it Planck}$</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE physics.flu-dyn physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Accepted version</comments><report-no>TIFR/TH/16-14</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the detection of thermal Sunyaev-Zeldovich effect (SZ) fluctuations
in the intracluster medium (ICM) of Coma cluster observed with ${\it Planck}$.
The SZ data links the maximum observable X-ray scale to the large Mpc scale,
extending our knowledge of the power spectrum of ICM fluctuations. Deprojecting
the 2-d SZ perturbations into 3-d pressure fluctuations, we find an amplitude
spectrum which peaks at $\delta P/P = 33\pm 12\%$ and $74\pm19\%$ in the $15'$
and $40'$ radius region, respectively. We perform tests to ensure fluctuations
are intrinsic to the cluster and not due to noise contamination. By using
high-resolution hydrodynamical models, we improve the ICM turbulence
constraints in Coma, finding 3-d Mach number ${\rm Ma_{3d}}= 0.8\pm0.3$ (15'
region), increasing to supersonic values at larger radii (40'), and an
injection scale $L_{\rm inj}\approx 500$ kpc. Such properties are consistent
with driving due to mergers, in particular tied to internal galaxy groups. The
large pressure fluctuations show that Coma is in adiabatic mode (mediated by
sound waves), rather than isobaric mode (mediated by buoyancy waves). As
predicted by turbulence models, the distribution of SZ fluctuations is
log-normal with mild non-Gaussianities (heavy tails). The substantial
non-thermal pressure support implies hydrostatic mass bias $b_M=-15\%$ to
$-45\%$ from the core to the outskirt region, respectively. While total SZ
power probes the thermal energy content, the SZ fluctuations constrain the
non-thermal deviations important for precision cosmology. The proposed, novel
approach can be exploited by multifrequency observations using ground based
interferometers and future space CMB missions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06353</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khorasani</keyname><forenames>Sina</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupled Mode Theory of Optomechanical Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>to appear in IEEE Journal of Quantum Electronics</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Journal of Quantum Electronics, vol. 52, no. 10, 6100406
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/JQE.2016.2602058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Acousto-optic interaction in optomechanical crystals allows unidirectional
control of elastic waves over optical waves. However, as a result of this
nonlinear interaction, infinitely many optical modes are born. This article
presents an exact formulaion of coupled mode theory for interaction between
elastic and photonic Bloch waves moving along an optomechanical waveguide. In
general, an optical wavefront is strongly diffracted by an elastic wave in
frequency and wavevector, and thus infinite modes with different frequencies
and wavevectors appear. We discuss resonance and mode conversion conditions,
and present a rigorous method to derive coupling rates and mode profiles. We
also find a conservation law which rules over total optical power from
interacting individual modes. We present application examples to the theory to
optomechanical waveguides and cavities, as well as non-reciprocal transmission
of light and optomechanical switches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06405</id><created>2016-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Intravaia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behunin</keyname><forenames>R. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henkel</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busch</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalvit</keyname><forenames>D. A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Failure of local thermal equilibrium in quantum friction</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5+2 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: portions of this article
  previously appeared as arXiv:1603.05165v1, which has been updated</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 100402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.100402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent progress in manipulating atomic and condensed matter systems has
instigated a surge of interest in non-equilibrium physics, including many-body
dynamics of trapped ultracold atoms and ions, near-field radiative heat
transfer, and quantum friction. Under most circumstances the complexity of such
non-equilibrium systems requires a number of approximations to make theoretical
descriptions tractable. In particular, it is often assumed that spatially
separated components of a system thermalize with their immediate surroundings,
although the global state of the system is out of equilibrium. This powerful
assumption reduces the complexity of non-equilibrium systems to the local
application of well-founded equilibrium concepts. While this technique appears
to be consistent for the description of some phenomena, we show that it fails
for quantum friction by underestimating by approximately $80 \%$ the magnitude
of the drag force. Our results show that the correlations among components of
driven, but steady-state, quantum systems invalidate the assumption of local
thermal equilibrium, calling for a critical reexamination of this approach for
describing the physics of non-equilibrium systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08766</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08766</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>David J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheel</keyname><forenames>Arnd</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuation and Bifurcation of Grain Boundaries in the Swift-Hohenberg
  Equation</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>38 pages, 28 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study grain boundaries between striped phases in the prototypical
Swift-Hohenberg equation. We propose an analytical and numerical far-field-core
decomposition that allows us to study existence and bifurcations of grain
boundaries analytically and numerically using continuation techniques. This
decomposition overcomes problems with computing grain boundaries in a large
doubly periodic box with phase conditions. Using the spatially conserved
quantities of the time-independent Swift-Hohenberg equation, we show that
symmetric grain boundaries must select the marginally zig-zag stable stripes.
We find that as the angle between the stripes is decreased, the symmetric grain
boundary undergoes a parity-breaking pitchfork bifurcation where dislocations
at the grain boundary split into disclination pairs. A plethora of asymmetric
grain boundaries (with different angles of the far-field stripes either side of
the boundary) is found and investigated. The energy of the grain boundaries is
then mapped out. We find that when the angle between the stripes is greater
than a critical angle, the symmetric grain boundary is energetically preferred
while when the angle is less than the critical angle, the grain boundaries
where stripes on one side are parallel to the interface are energetically
preferred. Finally, we propose a classification of grain boundaries that allows
us to predict various non-standard asymmetric grain boundaries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00094</id><created>2016-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Campo</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Speck</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Polydisperse hard spheres: Crystallization kinetics in small systems and
  role of local structure</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 084007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/8/084007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically the crystallization of a hard-sphere mixture with 8\%
polydispersity. Although often used as a model glass former, for small system
sizes we observe crystallization in molecular dynamics simulations. This opens
the possibility to study the competition between crystallization and structural
relaxation of the melt, which typically is out of reach due to the disparate
timescales. We quantify the dependence of relaxation and crystallization times
on density and system size. For one density and system size we perform a
detailed committor analysis to investigate the suitability of local structures
as order parameters to describe the crystallization process. We find that local
structures are strongly correlated with generic bond order and add little
information to the reaction coordinate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00754</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Batalin</keyname><forenames>Igor A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavrov</keyname><forenames>Peter M.</forenames></author></authors><title>General quantum-mechanical setting for field-antifield formalism as a
  hyper-gauge theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, new Section added, published version</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A31 (2016) 1650167</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501674</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general quantum-mechanical setting is proposed for the field-antifield
formalism as a unique hyper-gauge theory in the field-antifield space. We
formulate a Schr\&quot;odinger-type equation to describe the quantum evolution in a
&quot;current time&quot; purely formal in its nature. The corresponding Hamiltonian is
defined in the form of a supercommutator of the delta-operator with a
hyper-gauge Fermion. The initial wave function is restricted to be annihilated
with the delta-operator. The Schr\&quot;odinger's equation is resolved in a closed
form of the path integral, whose action contains the symmetric Weyl's symbol of
the Hamiltonian. We take the path integral explicitly in the case of being a
hyper-gauge Fermion an arbitrary function rather than an operator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01545</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kunduri</keyname><forenames>Hari K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucietti</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Black lenses in string theory</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>v2. 11 pages, 1 figure, substantial additions: new result which
  relates a special case of the black lens to a black ring by spectral flow;
  section on domain of outer communication; minor edits and additions in the
  main text; included Appendix on black lens solution to U(1)^N supergravity
  with detailed regularity analysis; references added</comments><report-no>EMPG-16-12</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new supersymmetric, asymptotically flat, black hole solution to
five-dimensional U(1)^3-supergravity which is regular on and outside an event
horizon of lens space topology L(2,1). The solution has seven independent
parameters and uplifts to a family of 1/8-supersymmetric D1-D5-P black brane
solutions to Type IIB supergravity. The decoupling limit is asymptotically
AdS(3) x S^3 x T^4, with a near-horizon geometry that is a twisted product of
the near-horizon geometry of the extremal BTZ black hole and L(2,1) x T^4,
although it is not (locally) a product space in the bulk. We show that the
decoupling limit of a special case of the black lens is related to that of a
black ring by spectral flow, thereby supplying an account of its entropy.
Analogous solutions of U(1)^N-supergravity are also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01615</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guzzetti</keyname><forenames>Maria Chiara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartolo</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liguori</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matarrese</keyname><forenames>Sabino</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational waves from inflation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>85 pages, 4 tables, 9 figures; table 2 added, references added;
  matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Rivista del Nuovo Cimento, Vol. 39, Issue 9 (2016), 399-495</journal-ref><doi>10.1393/ncr/i2016-10127-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of a stochastic background of gravitational waves is a
fundamental prediction of any cosmological inflationary model. The features of
such a signal encode unique information about the physics of the Early Universe
and beyond, thus representing an exciting, powerful window on the origin and
evolution of the Universe. We review the main mechanisms of gravitational-wave
production, ranging from quantum fluctuations of the gravitational field to
other mechanisms that can take place during or after inflation. These include
e.g. gravitational waves generated as a consequence of extra particle
production during inflation, or during the (p)reheating phase. Gravitational
waves produced in inflation scenarios based on modified gravity theories and
second-order gravitational waves are also considered. For each analyzed case,
the expected power-spectrum is given. We discuss the discriminating power among
different models, associated with the validity/violation of the standard
consistency relation between tensor-to-scalar ratio $r$ and tensor spectral
index $n_{\rm T}$. In light of the prospects for (directly/indirectly)
detecting primordial gravitational waves, we give the expected present-day
gravitational radiation spectral energy-density, highlighting the main
characteristics imprinted by the cosmic thermal history, and we outline the
signatures left by gravitational waves on the Cosmic Microwave Background and
some imprints in the Large-Scale Structure of the Universe. Finally, current
bounds and prospects of detection for inflationary gravitational waves are
summarized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02357</id><created>2016-05-08</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petkovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Aleksandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ristivojevic</keyname><forenames>Zoran</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of a Mobile Impurity in a One-Dimensional Bose Liquid</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages and 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 105301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.105301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a microscopic theory of a quantum impurity propagating in a
one-dimensional Bose liquid. As a result of scattering off thermally excited
quasiparticles, the impurity experiences the friction. We find that, at low
temperatures, the resulting force scales either as the fourth or the eighth
power of temperature, depending on the system parameters. For temperatures
higher than the chemical potential of the Bose liquid, the friction force is a
linear function of temperature. Our approach enables us to find the friction
force in the crossover region between the two limiting cases. In the integrable
case, corresponding to the Yang-Gaudin model, the impurity becomes transparent
for quasiparticles and thus the friction force is absent. Our results could be
further generalized to study other kinetic phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02439</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guerin</keyname><forenames>W</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rouabah</keyname><forenames>M. -T</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>R</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Light interacting with atomic ensembles: collective, cooperative and
  mesoscopic effects</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.dis-nn physics.optics</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1080/09500340.2016.1215564</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cooperative scattering has been the subject of intense research in the last
years. In this article, we discuss the concept of cooperative scattering from a
broad perspective. We briefly review the various collective effects that occur
when light interacts with an ensemble of atoms. We show that some effects that
have been recently discussed in the context of 'single-photon superradiance',
or cooperative scattering in the linear-optics regime, can also be explained by
'standard optics', i.e., using macroscopic quantities such as the
susceptibility or the diffusion coefficient. We explain why some collective
effects depend on the atomic density, and others on the optical depth. In
particular, we show that, for a large and dilute atomic sample driven by a
far-detuned laser, the decay of the fluorescence, which exhibits superradiant
and subradiant dynamics, depends only on the on-resonance optical depth. We
also discuss the link between concepts that are independently studied in the
quantum-optics community and in the mesoscopic-physics community. We show that
the coupled-dipole model predicts a departure from Ohm's law for the diffuse
light, that incoherent multiple scattering can induce a saturation of
fluorescence and we also show the similarity between the weak-localization
correction to the diffusion coefficient and the inaccuracy of Lorentz local
field correction to the susceptibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03080</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Briand</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dauchot</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Crystallization of self-propelled hard-discs : a new scenario</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, 1 Supp Matt</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 098004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.098004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally study the crystallization of a monolayer of vibrated discs
with a built-in polar asymmetry, a model system of active liquids, and contrast
it with that of vibrated isotropic discs. Increasing the packing fraction
$\phi$, the quasi-continuous crystallization reported for isotropic discs is
replaced by a transition, or a crossover towards a &quot;self-melting&quot; crystal.
Increasing the packing fraction from the liquid phase, clusters of dense
hexagonally-ordered packed discs spontaneously form, melt, split and merge
leading to a highly intermittent and heterogeneous dynamics. The resulting
steady state cluster size distribution decreases monotonically. For packing
fraction larger than $\phi^*$, a few large clusters span the system size and
the cluster size distribution becomes non monotonic, the transition being
signed by a power-law. The system is however never dynamically arrested. The
clusters permanently melt from place to place forming droplets of active liquid
which rapidly propagate across the system. This state of affair remains up to
the highest possible packing fraction questioning the stability of the crystal
for active discs, unless at ordered close packing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03739</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Xizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Yongguan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Chaohong</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster Mean-Field Signature of Entanglement Entropy in Bosonic
  Superfluid-Insulator Transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>accepted for publication in Physical Review A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 023634 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.023634</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entanglement entropy (EE), a fundamental conception in quantum information
for characterizing entanglement, has been extensively employed to explore
quantum phase transitions (QPTs). Although the conventional single-site
mean-field (MF) approach successfully predicts the emergence of QPTs, it fails
to include any entanglement. Here, for the first time, in the framework of a
cluster MF treatment, we extract the signature of EE in the bosonic
superfluid-insulator transitions. We consider a trimerized Kagome lattice of
interacting bosons, in which each trimer is treated as a cluster, and implement
the cluster MF treatment by decoupling all inter-trimer hopping. In addition to
superfluid and integer insulator phases, we find that fractional insulator
phases appear when the tunneling is dominated by the intra-trimer part. To
quantify the residual bipartite entanglement in a cluster, we calculate the
second-order Renyi entropy, which can be experimentally measured by quantum
interference of many-body twins. The second-order Renyi entropy itself is
continuous everywhere, however, the continuousness of its first-order
derivative breaks down at the phase boundary. This means that the bosonic
superfluid-insulator transitions can still be efficiently captured by the
residual entanglement in our cluster MF treatment. Besides to the bosonic
superfluid-insulator transitions, our cluster MF treatment may also be used to
capture the signature of EE for other QPTs in quantum superlattice models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05376</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>Simon B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spencer</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benecchi</keyname><forenames>Susan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verbiscer</keyname><forenames>Anne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zangari</keyname><forenames>Amanda M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weaver</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauer</keyname><forenames>Tod R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>Alex H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buie</keyname><forenames>Marc W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Andrew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Leslie A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olkin</keyname><forenames>Cathy B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ennico</keyname><forenames>Kimberly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>S. Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Team</keyname><forenames>the New Horizons Science</forenames></author></authors><title>The First High-Phase Observations of a KBO: New Horizons Imaging of
  (15810) 1994 JR1 from the Kuiper Belt</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>7 pages, published in ApJL</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters (2016), Volume 828, Number 2</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/828/2/L15</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NASA's New Horizons spacecraft observed (15810) 1994 JR$_1$, a 3:2 resonant
Kupier Belt Object (KBO), using the LOng Range Reconnaissance Imager (LORRI) on
November 2, 2015 from a distance of 1.85 AU, and again on April 7, 2016 from a
distance of 0.71 AU. These were the first close observations of any KBO other
than Pluto. Combining ground-based and Hubble Space Telecope (HST) observations
at small phase angles and the LORRI observations at higher phase angles, we
produced the first disk-integrated solar phase curve of a typical KBO from
$\alpha$=0.6-58$^\circ$. Observations at these geometries, attainable only from
a spacecraft in the outer Solar System, constrain surface properties such as
macroscopic roughness and the single particle phase function. 1994 JR$_1$ has a
rough surface with a 37$\pm$5$^\circ$ mean topographic slope angle and has a
relatively rapid rotation period of 5.47$\pm$0.33 hours. 1994 JR$_1$ is
currently 2.7 AU from Pluto; our astrometric points enable high-precision orbit
determination and integrations which show that it comes this close to Pluto
every 2.4 million years (10$^4$ heliocentric orbits), causing Pluto to perturb
1994 JR$_1$. During the November spacecraft observation, the KBO was
simultaneously observed using HST in two colors, confirming its very red
spectral slope. These observations have laid the groundwork for numerous
potential future distant KBO observations in the New Horizons-Kuiper Belt
Extended Mission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05763</id><created>2016-05-18</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wcislo</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morzynski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bober</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cygan</keyname><forenames>Agata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisak</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciurylo</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zawada</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching for topological defect dark matter with optical atomic clocks</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The total mass density of the Universe appears to be dominated by dark
matter. However, beyond its gravitational interactions at the galactic scale,
little is known about its nature. Extensions of the quantum electrodynamics
Lagrangian with dark-matter coupling terms may result in changes to Standard
Model parameters. Recently, it was proposed that a network of atomic clocks
could be used to search for transient signals of a hypothetical dark matter in
the form of stable topological defects. The clocks become desynchronized when a
dark-matter object sweeps through the network. This pioneering approach, which
is applicable only for distant clocks, is limited by the quality of the fibre
links. Here, we present an alternative experimental approach that is applicable
to both closely spaced and distant optical atomic clocks and benefits from
their individual susceptibilities to dark matter, hence not requiring fibre
links. We explore a new dimension of astrophysical observations by constraining
the strength of atomic coupling to the hypothetical dark-matter cosmic objects.
Our experimental constraint exceeds the previous limits; in fact, it not only
reaches the ultimate level expected to be achievable with a constellation of
GPS atomic clocks but also has a large potential for improvement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05781</id><created>2016-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>Reinhard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Victor G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camarillo-Cisneros</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferri</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkatchenko</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>Adsorption structures and energetics of molecules on metal surfaces:
  Bridging experiment and theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 7 figures in Progress in Surface Science, 2016</comments><doi>10.1016/j.progsurf.2016.05.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adsorption geometry and stability of organic molecules on surfaces are key
parameters that determine the observable properties and functions of hybrid
inorganic/organic systems (HIOSs). Despite many recent advances in precise
experimental characterization and improvements in first-principles electronic
structure methods, reliable databases of structures and energetics for large
adsorbed molecules are largely amiss. In this review, we present such a
database for a range of molecules adsorbed on metal single-crystal surfaces.
The systems we analyze include noble-gas atoms, conjugated aromatic molecules,
carbon nanostructures, and heteroaromatic compounds adsorbed on five different
metal surfaces. The overall objective is to establish a diverse benchmark
dataset that enables an assessment of current and future electronic structure
methods, and motivates further experimental studies that provide ever more
reliable data. Specifically, the benchmark structures and energetics from
experiment are here compared with the recently developed van der Waals (vdW)
inclusive density-functional theory (DFT) method, DFT+vdW$^{\mathrm{surf}}$. In
comparison to 23 adsorption heights and 17 adsorption energies from experiment
we find a mean average deviation of 0.06 \AA{} and 0.16 eV, respectively. This
confirms the DFT+vdW$^{\mathrm{surf}}$ method as an accurate and efficient
approach to treat HIOSs. A detailed discussion identifies remaining challenges
to be addressed in future development of electronic structure methods, for
which the here presented benchmark database may serve as an important
reference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08053</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Rafael N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Peter S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartlett</keyname><forenames>Stephen D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Randomized benchmarking in measurement-based quantum computing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, comments welcome; v2 published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Randomized benchmarking is routinely used as an efficient method for
characterizing the performance of sets of elementary logic gates in small
quantum devices. In the measurement-based model of quantum computation, logic
gates are implemented via single-site measurements on a fixed universal
resource state. Here we adapt the randomized benchmarking protocol for a single
qubit to a linear cluster state computation, which provides partial, yet
efficient characterization of the noise associated with the target gate set.
Applying randomized benchmarking to measurement-based quantum computation
exhibits an interesting interplay between the inherent randomness associated
with logic gates in the measurement-based model and the random gate sequences
used in benchmarking. We consider two different approaches: the first makes use
of the standard single-qubit Clifford group, while the second uses recently
introduced (non-Clifford) measurement-based 2-designs, which harness inherent
randomness to implement gate sequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08539</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kononov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egorov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostarev</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semyagin</keyname><forenames>B. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preobrazhenskii</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putyato</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emelyanov</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deviatov</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Specular Andreev reflection at the edge of an InAs/GaSb double quantum
  well with band inversion</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>As accepted to JETP Letters, vol. 104, issue 1</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, 104, 26 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364016130014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally investigate transport through the side junction between a
niobium superconductor and the mesa edge of a two-dimensional system, realized
in an InAs/GaSb double quantum well with band inversion. We demonstrate, that
different transport regimes can be achieved by variation of the mesa step. We
observe anomalous behavior of Andreev reflection within a finite low-bias
interval, which is invariant for both transport regimes. We connect this
behavior with the transition from retro- (at low biases) to specular (at high
ones) Andreev reflection channels in an InAs/GaSb double quantum well with band
inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08758</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zlotnikov</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Polynomial reduction and evaluation of tree- and loop-level CHY
  amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages, published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a polynomial reduction procedure that transforms any gauge fixed
CHY amplitude integrand for $n$ scattering particles into a $\sigma$-moduli
multivariate polynomial of what we call the $\textit{standard form}$. We show
that a standard form polynomial must have a specific $\textit{ladder type}$
monomial structure, which has finite size at any $n$, with highest multivariate
degree given by $(n-3)(n-4)/2$. This set of monomials spans a complete basis
for polynomials with rational coefficients in kinematic data on the support of
scattering equations. Subsequently, at tree and one-loop level, we employ the
global residue theorem to derive a prescription that evaluates any CHY
amplitude by means of collecting simple residues at infinity only. The
prescription is then applied explicitly to some tree and one-loop amplitude
examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09091</id><created>2016-05-29</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tian-hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Guo-Li</forenames></author></authors><title>The Production of $X(3940)$ and $X(4160)$ in $B_c$ decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys. G43 (2016) no.10, 105002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/10/105002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Considering $X(3940)$ and $X(4160)$ as $\eta_c(3S)$ and $\eta_c(4S)$, we
study the productions of $X(3940)$ and $X(4160)$ in exclusive weak decays of
$B_c$ meson by the improved Bethe-Salpeter(B-S) Method. Using the relativistic
B-S equation and Mandelstam formalism, we calculate the corresponding decay
form factors. The predictions of the corresponding branching ratios are:
$Br(B_c^+\to X(3940)e^+\nu_e)$$=1.0\times10^{-4}$ and $Br(B_c^+\to
X(4160)e^+\nu_e)=2.4\times10^{-5}$. That will provide us a new way to observe
the $X(3940)$ and $X(4160)$ in the future, as well as to improve the knowledge
of $B_c$ meson decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09392</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Honecker</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mila</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Normand</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-triplet bound states and finite-temperature dynamics in highly
  frustrated quantum spin ladders</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>22 pages, 19 figures; published version: many small modifications</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 094402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-dimensional quantum magnets at finite temperatures present a complex
interplay of quantum and thermal fluctuation effects in a restricted phase
space. While some information about dynamical response functions is available
from theoretical studies of the one-triplet dispersion in unfrustrated chains
and ladders, little is known about the finite-temperature dynamics of
frustrated systems. Experimentally, inelastic neutron scattering studies of the
highly frustrated two-dimensional material SrCu$_2$(BO$_3$)$_2$ show an almost
complete destruction of the one-triplet excitation band at a temperature only
1/3 of its gap energy, accompanied by strong scattering intensities for
apparent multi-triplet excitations. We investigate these questions in the
frustrated spin ladder and present numerical results from exact diagonalization
for the dynamical structure factor as a function of temperature. We find
anomalously rapid transfer of spectral weight out of the one-triplet band and
into both broad and sharp spectral features at a wide range of energies,
including below the zero-temperature gap of this excitation. These features are
multi-triplet bound states, which develop particularly strongly near the
quantum phase transition, fall to particularly low energies there, and persist
to all the way to infinite temperature. Our results offer valuable insight into
the physics of finite-temperature spectral functions in SrCu$_2$(BO$_3$)$_2$
and many other highly frustrated spin systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00618</id><created>2016-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Gumrukcuoglu</keyname><forenames>A. Emir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukohyama</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sotiriou</keyname><forenames>Thomas P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Jeans' Ghost</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><report-no>Imperial-TP-2016-AEG-3, YITP-16-66, IPMU16-0079</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a massless canonical scalar field minimally coupled to general
relativity can become a tachyonic ghost at low energies around a background in
which the scalar's gradient is spacelike. By performing a canonical
transformation we demonstrate that this low energy ghost can be recast, at the
level of the action, in a form of a fluid that undergoes a Jeans-like
instability affecting only modes with large wavelength. This illustrates that
low-energy tachyonic ghosts do not lead to a catastrophic quantum vacuum
instability, unlike the usual high-energy ghost degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02678</id><created>2016-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Viet Hung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Huy-Viet</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on arXiv:0709.3700 &quot;Orientation dependence of the optical
  spectra in graphene at high frequencies&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>submitted</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 117401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.117401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zhang et al. reported in [Phys. Rev. B 77, 241402(R) (2008)] a theoretical
study of the optical spectra of monolayer graphene employing the Kubo formula
within a tight-binding model. Their calculations predicted that at high
frequencies the optical conductivity of graphene becomes strongly anisotropic.
In particular, at frequencies comparable to the energy separation of the upper
and lower bands at the $\Gamma$-point, the optical conductivity is strongly
suppressed if the field polarization is along the zigzag direction while it is
significantly high for the armchair one. We find that, unfortunately, this
result is just a consequence of the incorrect determination of the current
operator in k-space. Here, we present the standard scheme to obtain this
operator correctly. As a result, we show that the optical conductivity of
monolayer graphene is indeed isotropic, which is consistent with the results of
other (both theoretical and experimental) studies in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03679</id><created>2016-06-12</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guerin</keyname><forenames>W</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chong</keyname><forenames>Yidong</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baudouin</keyname><forenames>Q</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liertzer</keyname><forenames>M</forenames><affiliation>TU Wien</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rotter</keyname><forenames>S</forenames><affiliation>TU Wien</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>R</forenames><affiliation>INLN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Diffusive to quasi-ballistic random laser: incoherent and coherent
  models</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of the Optical Society of America. B, Optical Physics, The
  Society, 2016, 33, pp.1888</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.33.001888</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the crossover between the diffusive and quasi-ballistic regimes of
random lasers. In particular, we compare incoherent models based on the
diffusion equation and the radiative transfer equation (RTE), which neglect all
wave effects, with a coherent wave model for the random laser threshold. We
show that both the incoherent and the coherent models predict qualitatively
similar thresholds, with a smooth transition from a diffuse to a
quasi-ballistic regime. The shape of the intensity distribution in the sample
as predicted by the RTE model at threshold is also in good agreement with the
coherent model. The approximate incoherent models thus provide useful
analytical predictions for the threshold of random lasers as well as the shape
of the random laser modes at threshold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05372</id><created>2016-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Messina</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ben-Abdallah</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guizal</keyname><forenames>Brahim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antezza</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biehs</keyname><forenames>Svend-Age</forenames></author></authors><title>Hyperbolic waveguide for long-distance transport of near-field heat flux</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 104301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.104301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heat flux exchanged between two hot bodies at subwavelength separation
distances can exceed the limit predicted by the blackbody theory. However this
super-Planckian transfer is restricted to these separation distances. Here we
demonstrate the possible existence of a super-Planckian transfer at arbitrary
large separation distances if the interacting bodies are connected in
near-field with weakly dissipating hyperbolic waveguides. This result opens the
way to long distance transport of near-field thermal energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07582</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiao Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wessel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Zi Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing pairing channels in the doped honeycomb lattice Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Proposals for superconductivity emerging from correlated electrons in the
doped Hubbard model on the honeycomb lattice range from chiral $d+id$ singlet
to $p+ip$ triplet pairing, depending on the considered range of doping and
interaction strength, as well as the approach used to analyze the pairing
instabilities. Here, we consider these scenarios using large-scale dynamic
cluster approximation (DCA) calculations to examine the evolution in the
leading pairing symmetry from weak to intermediate coupling strength. These
calculations focus on doping levels around the van Hove singularity (VHS) and
are performed using DCA simulations with an interaction-expansion
continuous-time quantum Monte Carlo cluster solver. We calculated explicitly
the temperature dependence of different uniform superconducting pairing
susceptibilities and found a consistent picture emerging upon gradually
increasing the cluster size: while at weak coupling the $d+id$ singlet pairing
dominates close to the VHS filling, an enhanced tendency towards $p$-wave
triplet pairing upon further increasing the interaction strength is observed.
The relevance of these systematic results for existing proposals and ongoing
pursuits of odd-parity topological superconductivity are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00770</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00770</id><created>2016-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Matt</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>B. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Junzhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bisti</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Chongde</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nevidomskyy</keyname><forenames>Andriy H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Pengcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patthey</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plumb</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radovic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesot</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>NaFe$_{0.56}$Cu$_{0.44}$As: A pnictide insulating phase induced by
  on-site Coulomb interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 097001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.097001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the studies of iron-pnictides, a key question is whether their bad-metal
state from which the superconductivity emerges lies in close proximity with a
magnetically ordered insulating phase. Recently it was found that at low
temperatures, the heavily Cu-doped NaFe$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$As ($x &gt; 0.3$)
iron-pnictide is an insulator with long-range antiferromagnetic order, similar
to the parent compound of cuprates but distinct from all other iron-pnictides.
Using angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy, we determined the
momentum-resolved electronic structure of NaFe$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$As ($x = 0.44$) and
identified that its ground state is a narrow-gap insulator. Combining the
experimental results with density functional theory (DFT) and DFT+U
calculations, our analysis reveals that the on-site Coulombic (Hubbard) and
Hund's coupling energies play crucial roles in formation of the band gap about
the chemical potential. We propose that at finite temperatures charge carriers
are thermally excited from the Cu-As-like valence band into the conduction
band, which is of Fe $3d$-like character. With increasing temperature, the
number of electrons in the conduction band becomes larger and the hopping
energy between Fe sites increases, and finally the long-range antiferromagnetic
order is destroyed at $T &gt; T_\mathrm{N}$. Our study provides a basis for
investigating the evolution of the electronic structure of a Mott insulator
transforming into a bad metallic phase, and eventually forming a
superconducting state in iron-pnictidesa superconducting state in
iron-pnictides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01308</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Breit</keyname><forenames>Dominic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahl&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>A variational approach to solitary gravity-capillary interfacial waves
  with infinite depth</title><categories>math.AP nlin.PS</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1307.0028</comments><msc-class>76B15 (Primary), 76B25, 76B45, 76B55, 37K45, 35A15 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an existence and stability theory for gravity-capillary solitary
waves on the top surface of and interface between two perfect fluids of
different densities, the lower one being of infinite depth. Exploiting a
classical variational principle, we prove the existence of a minimiser of the
wave energy $\mathcal{E}$ subject to the constraint $\mathcal{I}=2\mu$, where
$\mathcal{I}$ is the wave momentum and $0&lt; \mu &lt; \mu_0$, where $\mu_0$ is
chosen small enough for the validity of our calculations. Since $\mathcal{E}$
and $\mathcal{I}$ are both conserved quantities a standard argument asserts the
stability of the set $D_\mu$ of minimisers: solutions starting near $D_\mu$
remain close to $D_\mu$ in a suitably defined energy space over their interval
of existence. The solitary waves which we construct are of small amplitude and
are to leading order described by the cubic nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation.
They exist in a parameter region in which the `slow' branch of the dispersion
relation has a strict non-degenerate global minimum and the corresponding
nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation is of focussing type. We show that the waves
detected by our variational method converge (after an appropriate rescaling) to
solutions of the model equation as $\mu \downarrow 0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01712</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shahi</keyname><forenames>Maryam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>Marcia M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anthony</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brill</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Resistances of Thin-Films of Small Molecule Organic
  Semiconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, to be published in J. Materials Chemistry C</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the thermal resistances of thin films of the small molecule
organic semiconductors bis(triisopropylsilylethynyl) pentacene (TIPS-pn),
bis(triethylsilylethynyl) anthradithiophene (TES-ADT) and difluoro
bis(triethylsilylethynyl) anthradithiophene (diF-TES-ADT). For each material,
several films of different thicknesses have been measured to separate the
effects of intrinsic thermal conductivity from interface thermal resistance.
For non-crystalline films of all three materials, with thicknesses ranging from
&lt; 100 nm to &gt; 4 microns, the thermal conductivities are similar to that of
polymers and over an order of magnitude smaller than that of the crystals,
reflecting the large reduction in phonon mean-free path in the films. Thin (&lt;
205 nm) crystalline films of TES-ADT, prepared by vapor-annealing spin-cast
films, have also been measured, but for these the thermal resistances are
dominated by interface scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03429</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2016-09-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rosch</keyname><forenames>Thomas W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patrone</keyname><forenames>Paul N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond histograms: efficiently estimating radial distribution functions
  via spectral Monte Carlo</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite more than 40 years of research in condensed-matter physics,
state-of-the-art approaches for simulating the radial distribution function
(RDF) g(r) still rely on binning pair-separations into a histogram. Such
methods suffer from undesirable properties, including subjectivity, high
uncertainty, and slow rates of convergence. Moreover, such problems go
undetected by the metrics often used to assess RDFs. To address these issues,
we propose (I) a spectral Monte Carlo (SMC) method that yields g(r) as an
analytical series expansion; and (II) a Sobolev norm that assesses the quality
of RDFs by quantifying their fluctuations. Using the latter, we show that,
relative to histogram-based approaches, SMC reduces by orders of magnitude both
the noise in g(r) and the number of pair separations needed for acceptable
convergence. Moreover, SMC reduces subjectivity and yields simple,
differentiable formulas for the RDF, which are useful for tasks such as
coarse-grained force-field calibration via iterative Boltzmann inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04605</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jimenez</keyname><forenames>Diego Medrano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vera</keyname><forenames>Agustin Sabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazquez-Mozo</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Planar Zeros in Gauge Theories and Gravity</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 12 figures. v2: minor changes, typos corrected and
  reference added. It matches the version to appear in Journal of High Energy
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1609 (2016) 006</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Planar zeros are studied in the context of the five-point scattering
amplitude for gauge bosons and gravitons. In the case of gauge theories, it is
found that planar zeros are determined by an algebraic curve in the projective
plane spanned by the three stereographic coordinates labelling the direction of
the outgoing momenta. This curve depends on the values of six independent color
structures. Considering the gauge group SU(N) with N=2,3,5 and fixed color
indices, the class of curves obtained gets broader by increasing the rank of
the group. For the five-graviton scattering, on the other hand, we show that
the amplitude vanishes whenever the process is planar, without imposing further
kinematic conditions. A rationale for this result is provided using
color-kinematics duality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04925</id><created>2016-07-17</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Baren</keyname><forenames>Jeremiah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Jia-An</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xi</keyname><forenames>Xiaoxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Zhipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Gaihua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>I-Hsi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leong</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lui</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interlayer breathing and shear modes in NbSe2 atomic layers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>2D Materials 3, 031008 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Atomically thin NbSe2 is a metallic layered transition metal dichalcogenide
(TMD) with considerably different crystallographic structure and electronic
properties from other TMDs, such as MoS2, MoSe2, WS2 and WSe2. Properties of
TMD atomic layers are sensitive to interlayer coupling. Here we investigate the
interlayer phonons of few-layer NbSe2 by ultralow-frequency Raman spectroscopy.
We observe both the interlayer breathing modes and shear modes at frequencies
below 40 cm-1 for samples of 2 to 15 layers. Their frequency, Raman activity,
and environmental instability depend systematically on the layer number. We
account for these results utilizing a combination of the linear-chain model,
group-theory analysis and first-principles calculations. Although NbSe2
possesses different stacking order from MoS2, MoSe2, WS2 and WSe2, it exhibits
the same symmetry and Raman selection rules, as well as similar interlayer
coupling strength and thickness dependence of interlayer phonon modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06925</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Erms</forenames></author></authors><title>Retrieving the saddle-splay elastic constant $K_{24}$ of nematic liquid
  crystals from an algebraic approach</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Accepted to be published in The European Physical Journal E</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. E (2016) 39: 83</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epje/i2016-16083-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physics of light interference experiments is well established for nematic
liquid crystals. Using well-known techniques, it is possible to obtain
important quantities, such as the differential scattering cross section and the
saddl-splay elastic constant $K_{24}$. However, the usual methods to retrieve
the latter involves an adjusting of computational parameters through the visual
comparisons between the experimental light interference pattern or a
$^{2}H-NMR$ spectral pattern produced by an escaped-radial disclination, and
their computational simulation counterparts. To avoid such comparisons, we
develop an algebraic method for obtaining of saddle-splay elastic constant
$K_{24}$. Considering an escaped-radial disclination inside a capillary tube
with radius $R_{0}$ of tens of micrometers, we use a metric approach to study
the propagation of the light (in the scalar wave approximation), near to the
surface of the tube and to determine the light interference pattern due to the
defect. The latter is responsible for the existence of a well-defined
interference peak associated to a unique angle $\phi_{0}$. Since this angle
depends on factors such as refractive indexes, curvature elastic constants,
anchoring regime, surface anchoring strength and radius $R_{0}$, the
measurement of $\phi_{0}$ from the interference experiments involving two
different radii allows us to algebraically retrieve $K_{24}$. Our method
allowed us to give the first reported estimation of $K_{24}$ for the lyotropic
chromonic liquid crystal Sunset Yellow FCF: $K_{24}=2.1\ pN$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08316</id><created>2016-08-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Cisneros</keyname><forenames>Sophia</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oblath</keyname><forenames>Noah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Formaggio</keyname><forenames>Joe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crowley</keyname><forenames>Meagan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikulski</keyname><forenames>Kyler</forenames></author></authors><title>Toward a Zero-Parameter Model for Galaxy Rotation Curve Data</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modeling the luminous mass components of spiral galaxies in standard gravity
poses a challenge due to the missing mass problem. However, with the addition
of cold dark matter, the missing mass problem can be circumvented at the cost
of additional free parameters to the theory. The Luminous Convolution Model
(LCM) reconsiders how we interpret rotation curve data, such that
Doppler-shifted spectra measurements can constrain luminous mass discovery. For
a sample of 25 galaxies of varying morphologies and sizes, we demonstrate an
ansatz for relative galaxy curvatures that can explain the missing mass. We
solve for the LCM free parameter, which we report as a ratio of radial
densities of the emitter, to receiver galaxy baryonic mass, to an exponent of
$1.63$. Here, we show that this exponent is sensitive to which Milky Way
luminous mass model one chooses. We then make a first prediction regarding the
Milky Way mass profile in the inner one kpc.
  Thus, with a bound on the LCM free parameter, we pave the way for future
work, where the LCM will tested as a zero-parameter model to predict luminous
mass from rotation curve data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00380</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Seery</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>CppTransport: a platform to automate calculation of inflationary
  correlation functions</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>128 pages. Matches 2013.3 release version deposited at zenodo.org
  (see linked DOI) up to changes in typesetting and correction of some minor
  typos</comments><doi>10.5281/zenodo.61239</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CppTransport is a numerical platform that can automatically generate and
solve the evolution equations for the 2- and 3-point correlation functions (in
field space and for the curvature perturbation) for any inflationary model with
canonical kinetic terms. It makes no approximations beyond the applicability of
tree-level perturbation theory. Given an input Lagrangian, CppTransport
performs symbolic calculations to determine the 'Feynman rules' of the model
and generates efficient C++ to integrate the correlation functions of interest.
It includes a visualization suite that automates extraction of observable
quantities from the raw n-point functions and generates high quality plots with
minimal manual intervention. It is intended to be used as a collaborative
platform, promoting the rapid investigation of models and systematizing their
comparison with observation. This guide describes how to install and use the
system, and illustrates its use through some simple examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00404</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ilic</keyname><forenames>Velimir M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stankovic</keyname><forenames>Miomir S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments on &quot;On q-non-extensive statistics with non-Tsallisian entropy&quot;</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.08.078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, in [P. Jizba and J. Korbel, Physica A 444, 2016, 808-827], four
generalized Shannon-Khinchin [GSK] axioms have been proposed and a generalized
entropy which uniquely satisfies the GSK axioms has been derived. In this
comment, we show that the unique class of the entropies derived in the
aforementioned paper is not correct, as it violates the fourth GSK axiom, and
we derive the correct one. Nevertheless, the class of entropies proposed in the
commented paper still can serve as a basis for generalized statistical
mechanics. We propose a new axiomatic system which characterizes the class of
entropies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00406</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Jonathan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sjolander</keyname><forenames>Tobias F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>John W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Antisymmetric Couplings Enable Direct Observation of Chirality in
  Nuclear Magnetic Resonance Spectroscopy</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we demonstrate that a term in the nuclear spin Hamiltonian, the
antisymmetric \textit{J}-coupling, is fundamentally connected to molecular
chirality. We propose and simulate a nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR)
experiment to observe this interaction and differentiate between enantiomers
without adding any additional chiral agent to the sample. The antisymmetric
\textit{J}-coupling may be observed in the presence of molecular orientation by
an external electric field. The opposite parity of the antisymmetric coupling
tensor and the molecular electric dipole moment yields a sign change of the
observed coupling between enantiomers. We show how this sign change influences
the phase of the NMR spectrum and may be used to discriminate between
enantiomers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00420</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Dairyko</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogben</keyname><forenames>Leslie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Jephian C. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lockhart</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberson</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Severini</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on von Neumann and R\'enyi entropies of a Graph</title><categories>math.CO quant-ph</categories><msc-class>05C50, 81P45, 94A17</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We conjecture that all connected graphs of order $n$ have von Neumann entropy
at least as great as the star $K_{1,n-1}$ and prove this for almost all graphs
of order $n$. We show that connected graphs of order $n$ have R\'enyi 2-entropy
at least as great as $K_{1,n-1}$ and for $\alpha&gt;1$, $K_n$ maximizes R\'enyi
$\alpha$-entropy over graphs of order $n$. We show that adding an edge to a
graph can lower its von Neumann entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00431</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Chengjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagley</keyname><forenames>E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetry-Breaking Zeeman-Coherence Parametric Wave Mixing Magnetometry</title><categories>physics.optics physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonlinear magneto-optical effect has significantly impacted modern
society with prolific applications ranging from precision mapping of the
Earth's magnetic field to bio-magnetic sensing. Pioneering works on collisional
spin-exchange effects have led to ultra-high magnetic field detection
sensitivities at the level of $fT/\sqrt{Hz}$ using a single linearly-polarized
probe light field. Here we demonstrate a nonlinear Zeeman-coherence parametric
wave-mixing optical-atomic magnetometer using room temperature rubidium vapor
that results in more than a three-order-of-magnitude optical signal-to-noise
ratio (SNR) enhancement for extremely weak magnetic field sensing. This
unprecedented enhancement was achieved with nearly a two-order-of-magnitude
reduction in laser power while preserving the sensitivity of the widely-used
single-probe beam optical-atomic magnetometry method. This new method opens a
myriad of applications ranging from bio-magnetic imaging to precision
measurement of the magnetic properties of subatomic particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00443</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jingbo</forenames></author></authors><title>Counter-term for the Palatini action of general relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we analysis the counter-term for the general relativity in the
Palatini framework. The expression is valid for both the null boundary and
non-null boundary. We show that final results coincide with that in
Ref.\cite{pad1} which starts form the Einstein-Hilbert action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00471</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldburg</keyname><forenames>W. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerbus</keyname><forenames>R. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Turbulence as Information</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A message of any sort can be regarded as a source of information. Claude. E.
Shannon showed in the last century that information (&quot;what we don't already
know&quot;) is equivalent to the entropy as defined in statistical mechanics. A
string of experimental observations is like a succession of words; they both
convey information and can be characterized by their entropy. For the fluid
flow measurements and simulations to be discussed here (pipe and soap film
flow, GOY model), the entropy depends on controllable parameters such as the
Reynolds number. The information theory approach is applicable to measurements
of any type including those governed by intractable equations or systems where
the governing equations are not known. This contribution is dedicated to the
memory of Leo Kadanoff, an inspiring teacher and one of the most important
scientific leaders of the last half century.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00472</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Yedukondalu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghule</keyname><forenames>Vikas D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaitheeswaran</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>High pressure structural, elastic and vibrational properties of green
  energetic oxidizer ammonium dinitramide</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics 145, 064706 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4959900</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ammonium DiNitramide (ADN) is one of the most promising green energetic
oxidizers for future rocket propellant formulations. In the present work, we
report a detailed theoretical study on structural, elastic, and vibrational
properties of the emerging oxidizer under hydrostatic compression using various
dispersion correction methods to capture weak intermolecular (van der Waals and
hydrogen bonding) interactions. The calculated ground state lattice parameters,
axial compressibilities, and equation of state are in good accord with the
available experimental results. Strength of intermolecular interactions has
been correlated using the calculated compressibility curves and elastic moduli.
Apart from this, we also observe discontinuities in the structural parameters
and elastic constants as a function of pressure. Pictorial representation and
quantification of intermolecular interactions are described by the 3D Hirshfeld
surfaces and 2D finger print maps. In addition, the computed infra-red (IR)
spectra at ambient pressure reveal that ADN is found to have more hygroscopic
nature over Ammonium Perchlorate (AP) due to the presence of strong hydrogen
bonding. Pressure dependent IR spectra show blue- and red-shift of bending and
stretching frequencies which leads to weakening and strengthening of the
hydrogen bonding below and above 5 GPa, respectively. The abrupt changes in the
calculated structural, mechanical, and IR spectra suggest that ADN might
undergo a first order structural transformation to a high pressure phase around
5-6 GPa. From the predicted detonation properties, ADN is found to have high
and low performance characteristics when compared with ammonium based energetic
oxidizers and well-known secondary explosives, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00473</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Yedukondalu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaitheeswaran</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab-initio study of structural, vibrational and optical properties of
  solid oxidizers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>32 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Materials Chemistry and Physics 181 (2016) 54-66</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.matchemphys.2016.06.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the structural, elastic and vibrational properties of five
ionic-molecular solid oxidizers MNO$_3$ (M = Li, Na, K) and MClO$_3$ (M = Na,
K). By treating long range electron-correlation effects, dispersion corrected
method leads to more accurate predictions of structural properties and phase
stability of KNO$_3$ polymorphs. The obtained elastic moduli show soft nature
of these materials and are consistent with Ultrasonic Pulse Echo measurements.
We made a complete assignment of vibrational modes which are in good accord
with available experimental results. From calculated IR and Raman spectra, it
is found that the vibrational frequencies show a red-shift from Li -&gt; Na -&gt; K
(Na -&gt; K) and N -&gt; Cl for nitrates (chlorates) due to increase in mass of metal
and non-metal atoms, respectively. The calculated electronic structure using
recently developed Tran-Blaha modified Becke-Johnson potential show that the
materials are wide band gap insulators with predominant ionic bonding between
M$^+$ (metal) and NO$_3^-$ /ClO$_3^-$ ions and covalent bonding (N-O and Cl-O)
within nitrate and chlorate anionic group. From the calculated optical spectra,
we observe that electric-dipole transitions are due to nitrate/chlorate group
below 20 eV and cationic transitions occur above 20 eV. The calculated
reflectivity spectra are consistent with the available experimental spectra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00477</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Lembessis</keyname><forenames>V. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alqarni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alshamari</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siddig</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aldossary</keyname><forenames>O. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rotating artificial gauge magnetic and electric fields</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the creation of artificial gauge magnetic and electric fields
created when a two-level atom interacts with an optical Ferris wheel light
field.These fields have the spatial structure of the optical Ferris wheel field
intensity profile. If this optical field pattern is made to rotate in space
then we have the creation of artificial electromagnetic fields which propagate
in closed paths. The properties of such fields are presented and discussed
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00485</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00485</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Poux</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wasilewski</keyname><forenames>Z. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedland</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hey</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ploog</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Airey</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plochocka</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maude</keyname><forenames>D. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A microscopic model for the magnetic field driven breakdown of the
  dissipationless state in the integer and fractional quantum Hall effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075411 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075411</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intra Landau level thermal activation, from localized states in the tail, to
delocalized states above the mobility edge in the same Landau level, explains
the $B_c(T)$ (half width of the dissipationless state) phase diagram for a
number of different quantum Hall samples with widely ranging carrier density,
mobility and disorder. Good agreement is achieved over $2-3$ orders of
magnitude in temperature and magnetic field for a wide range of filling
factors. The Landau level width is found to be independent of magnetic field.
The mobility edge moves, in the case of changing Landau level overlap to
maintain a sample dependent critical density of states at that energy. An
analysis of filling factor $\nu=2/3$ shows that the composite Fermion Landau
levels have exactly the same width as their electron counterparts. An important
ingredient of the model is the Lorentzian broadening with long tails which
provide localized states deep in the gap which are essential in order to
reproduce the robust high temperature $B_c(T)$ phase observed in experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00486</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Lahiri</keyname><forenames>Sourabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>Arun M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using a Szilard engine to illustrate the validity of the modified
  Jarzynski equality in presence of measurement errors</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has recently been shown that the Jarzynski equality gets modified, when
there are experimental errors in computing work. This modified result also
holds good in presence of feedback. In this work, we use a simple toy model,
that of a Szilard engine, to prove these results both in the presence and in
absence of feedback.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00487</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Tamazian</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malkov</keyname><forenames>O. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Docobo</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chulkov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campo</keyname><forenames>P. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>New distances for a selected set of visual binaries with inconsistent
  dynamical masses</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and Space Science, Volume 361, article id.105, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2693-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have selected a set of 17 visual binaries that demonstrate great
inconsistency between the systemic mass obtained through Kepler's Third Law as
compared to that calculated through standard mass-luminosity and mass-spectrum
relationships. A careful inspection of orbital data and parallaxes showed that
the current orbits of nine binaries (WDS 00155-1608, WDS 00174+0853, WDS
05017+2050, WDS 06410+0954, WDS 16212-2536, WDS 17336-3706, WDS 19217-1557, WDS
20312+1116, and WDS 21118+5959) do not need to be improved, instead we
recommend different parallax (distance) value for them. On the other hand, we
considered that eight orbits (WDS 02366+1227, WDS 02434-6643, WDS 03244-1539,
WDS 08507+1800, WDS 09128-6055, WDS 11532-1540, WDS 17375+2419, and WDS
22408-0333) had to be improved. Due to various reasons mentioned in this paper,
their distances should most likely be corrected unless better orbital solutions
and/or more precise parallaxes are reported. To obtain consistent mass values,
the use of the dynamical parallax is still recommended for 5 out of the 8
improved orbits. For WDS 02434-6643, WDS 09128-6055, and WDS 11532-1540, the
improvement itself yields reasonable mass sums while maintaining {\pi}_{Hip}
within a 1-2{\sigma} margin. New distance estimates for 16 stars (mainly based
on the obtained dynamical parallaxes) and individual comments for all objects
are presented and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00492</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schirmer</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-temperature second-order many-body perturbation theory revisited</title><categories>physics.chem-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>To appear in Chem. Phys. (2016)</comments><doi>10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.08.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an algebraic, nondiagrammatic derivation of finite-temperature
second-order many-body perturbation theory [FT-MBPT(2)], using techniques and
concepts accessible to theoretical chemical physicists. We give explicit
expressions not just for the grand potential but particularly for the mean
energy of an interacting many-electron system. The framework presented is
suitable for computing the energy of a finite or infinite system in contact
with a heat and particle bath at finite temperature and chemical potential.
FT-MBPT(2) may be applied if the system, at zero temperature, may be described
using standard (i.e., zero-temperature) second-order many-body perturbation
theory [ZT-MBPT(2)] for the energy. We point out that in such a situation,
FT-MBPT(2) reproduces, in the zero-temperature limit, the energy computed
within ZT-MBPT(2). In other words, the difficulty that has been referred to as
the Kohn--Luttinger conundrum, does not occur. We comment, in this context, on
a &quot;renormalization&quot; scheme recently proposed by Hirata and He.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00500</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruban</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predictability of the Appearance of Anomalous Waves at Sufficiently
  Small Benjamin-Feir Indices</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>4.5 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, 103(9), 568-572 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364016090083</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The numerical simulation of the nonlinear dynamics of random sea waves at
moderately small Benjamin-Feir indices and its comparison with the linear
dynamics (at the coincidence of spatial Fourier harmonics near a spectral peak
at a certain time $t_p$) indicate that the appearance of a rogue wave can be
predicted in advance. If the linear approximation shows the presence of a
sufficiently extensive and/or high group of waves in the near future after
$t_p$, an anomalous wave is almost necessarily formed in the nonlinear model.
The interval of reliable forecasting covers several hundred wave periods, which
can be quite sufficient in practice for, e.g., avoiding the meeting of a ship
with a giant wave.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00501</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruss</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demirci</keyname><forenames>Tunahan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koester</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelling</keyname><forenames>Thorben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurm</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Failed Growth at the Bouncing Barrier in Planetesimal Formation</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/827/2/110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In laboratory experiments, we studied collisions of ensembles of compact
(filling factor 0.33) millimeter dust aggregates composed of micrometer quartz
grains. We used cylindrical aggregates, triangular aggregates, square
aggregates, and rectangular aggregates. Ensembles of equal size aggregates as
well as ensembles with embedded larger aggregates were studied. The typical
collision velocities are 10-20 mm $\rm s^{-1}$. High spatial and temporal
resolution imaging unambiguously shows that individual collisions lead to
sticking with a high probability of 20 percent. This leads to connected
clusters of aggregates. The contact areas between two aggregates increase with
collision velocity. However, this cluster growth is only temporary, as
subsequent collisions of aggregates and clusters eventually lead to the
detachment of all aggregates from a cluster. The contacts are very fragile as
aggregates cannot be compressed further or fragment under our experimental
conditions to enhance the contact stability. Therefore, the evolution of the
ensemble always leads back to a distribution of individual aggregates of
initial size. This supports and extends earlier experiments showing that a
bouncing barrier in planetesimal formation would be robust against shape and
size variations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00541</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>G</keyname><forenames>Vaitheeswaran</forenames></author><author><keyname>V</keyname><forenames>Kanchana</forenames></author><author><keyname>X</keyname><forenames>Zhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Y</keyname><forenames>Ma</forenames></author><author><keyname>A</keyname><forenames>Svane</forenames></author><author><keyname>NE</keyname><forenames>Christensen</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculated high-pressure structural properties, lattice dynamics and
  quasi particle band structures of perovskite fluorides KZnF 3 , CsCaF 3 and
  BaLiF 3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physics Condensed Matter 28(31):315403 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/31/315403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A detailed study of the high-pressure structural properties, lattice dynamics
and band structures of perovskite structured fluorides KZnF3, CsCaF3 and BaLiF3
has been carried out by means of density functional theory. The calculated
structural properties including elastic constants and equation of state agree
well with available experimental information. The phonon dispersion curves are
in good agreement with available experimental inelastic neutron scattering
data. The electronic structures of these fluorides have been calculated using
the quasi particle self-consistent [Formula: see text] approximation. The
[Formula: see text] calculations reveal that all the fluorides studied are wide
band gap insulators, and the band gaps are significantly larger than those
obtained by the standard local density approximation, thus emphasizing the
importance of quasi particle corrections in perovskite fluorides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00547</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Jingfang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashkenazy</keyname><forenames>Yosef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Havlin</keyname><forenames>Shlomo</forenames></author></authors><title>Climate network suggests enhanced El Ni\~no global impacts in localized
  areas</title><categories>physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct directed and weighted climate networks based on near surface air
temperature to investigate the global impacts of El Nino and La Nina. We find
that regions which are characterized by higher positive or negative network in
weighted links, are exhibiting stronger correlations with the El Nino basin and
are warmer or cooler during El Nino or La Nina periods. These stronger
in-weighted activities are found to be concentrated in localized areas, as
compared to non-El Nino periods, whereas a large fraction of the globe is not
influenced by the events. The regions of localized activity vary from one El
Nino (La Nina) event to another; still some El Nino (La Nina) events are more
similar to each other. We quantify this similarity using network community
structure. The results and methodology reported here may be used to improve the
understanding and prediction of El Nino or La Nina events and also may be
applied in the investigation of other climate variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00548</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bicudo</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheunert</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>Including heavy spin effects in a lattice QCD study of
  static-static-light-light tetraquarks</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, talk given at the 34th International Symposium on
  Lattice Field Theory (Lattice 2016), July 24-30 2016, Southampton, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In previous works we predicted the existence of a $\bar b \bar b u d$
tetraquark with quantum numbers $I(J^P) = 0(1^+)$ using the static
approximation for the $\bar b$ quarks and neglecting heavy spin effects. Since
the binding energy is of the same order as expected for these heavy spin
effects, it is essential to include them in the computation. Here we present a
corresponding method and show evidence that binding is only slightly weakened
and that the $\bar b \bar b u d$ tetraquark persists.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00550</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Martiyanov</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barmashova</keyname><forenames>Tatiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makhalov</keyname><forenames>Vasiliy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turlapov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure profiles of nonuniform two-dimensional atomic Fermi gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 063622 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.063622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spatial profiles of the pressure have been measured in atomic Fermi gases
with primarily 2D kinematics. The in-plane motion of the particles is confined
by a gaussian-shape potential. The two-component deeply-degenerate Fermi gases
are prepared at different values of the s-wave attraction. The pressure profile
is found using the force-balance equation, from the measured density profile
and the trapping potential. The pressure is compared to zero-temperature models
within the local density approximation. In the weakly-interacting regime, the
pressure lies above a Landau Fermi-liquid theory and below the ideal-Fermi-gas
model, whose prediction coincides with that of the Cooper-pair mean-field
theory. The values closest to the data are provided by the approach where the
mean-field of Cooper pairs is supplemented with fluctuations. In the regime of
strong interactions, in response to the increasing attraction, the pressure
shifts below this model reaching lower values calculated within Monte Carlo
methods. Comparison to models shows that interaction-induced departure from 2D
kinematics is either small or absent. In particular, comparison with a lattice
Monte Carlo suggests that kinematics is 2D in the strongly-interacting regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00560</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00560</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>R. M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>Craig A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simha</keyname><forenames>R. Aditi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Welsh</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>The simplest microscopic model of a complex fluid: flow phenomena and
  constitutive relation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It was shown in [PRL 114, 138301 (2015)] that a remarkably simple dynamical
model exhibits many of the complex flow regimes and non-equilibrium phase
transitions characteristic of complex fluids. By removing extraneous detail,
this simplest microscopic model of non-Newtonian flow can reveal the universal
physics relevant to all complex fluids. Here we present more detailed results
and a full derivation of the model's compact mean-field constitutive relation,
with great potential scope for insights into universality and tractable
mathematics. By enforcing local conservation of angular momentum, the
one-dimensional (1D) XY-model (originally used for equilibrium magnetic
systems) can be driven into various flow regimes, including simple Newtonian
behaviour, shear banding, solid-liquid coexistence and slip-plane motion. The
model demonstrates that the phenomenon of shear banding does not rely on
details of tensorial stress fields, but can exist in 1D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00561</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Eckern</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorini</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raimondi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf6;lle</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Room-temperature transport properties of spin-orbit coupled Fermi
  systems: Spin thermoelectric effects, phonon skew scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we summarize our recent results for the temperature dependence
of transport coefficients of metallic films in the presence of spin-orbit
coupling. Our focus is on (i) the spin Nernst and the thermal Edelstein
effects, and (ii) the phonon skew scattering contribution to the spin Hall
conductivity, which is relevant for the temperature dependence of the spin Hall
angle. Depending on the parameters, the latter is expected to show a
non-monotonous behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00567</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Hailong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Dongzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Jianji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Dongxu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Xinlun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Fuli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xinliang</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbital angular momentum complex spectrum analyzer for vortex light
  based on rotational Doppler Effect</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The function to measure orbital angular momentum (OAM) distribution of vortex
light is essential for OAM applications. Although there are lots of works to
measure OAM modes, it is difficult to measure the power distribution of
different OAM modes quantitatively and instantaneously, let alone measure the
phase distribution among them. In this work, we demonstrate an OAM complex
spectrum analyzer, which enables to measure the power and phase distribution of
OAM modes simultaneously by employing rotational Doppler Effect. The original
OAM mode distribution is mapped to electrical spectrum of beating signals with
a photodetector. The power distribution and phase distribution of superimposed
OAM beams are successfully retrieved by analyzing the electrical spectrum. We
also extend the measurement to other spatial modes, such as linear polarization
modes. These results represent a new landmark of spatial mode analysis and show
great potentials in optical communication and OAM quantum state tomography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00568</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Roxburgh</keyname><forenames>Ian W</forenames></author></authors><title>16CygA&amp;B and Kepler Legacy values : Differences between the values of
  frequencies by different fitters</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 37 figures. Seismology of the Sun and Distant Stars 2016,
  Joint TASC2 &amp; KASC9 Workshop - SPACEINN &amp; HELAS8 Conference 11-15 July 2016,
  Angra do Heroismo, Terceira-Azores, Portugal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The differences between the oscillation frequencies and uncertainty estimates
of a star derived by different fitters can be large, sufficiently large so
that, were one to find a stellar model that fitted one frequency set
($\chi^2\sim 1$), it does not fit an alternative set. I give 21 examples,
comparing frequency sets in common between the Kepler Legacy project and
frequency sets from Appourchaux et al (2014) and Davies et al (2015). For
16CygA&amp;B the differences are large; the $\chi^2$ of the fit of Legacy to
Davies's values ranging from 1.64 to 11.47 for 16CygA and 1.62 to 1.79 for
16CygB, depending on which error estimates are used. I analyse both stars in
some detail applying my own mode fitting code to both the Legacy and Davies's
power spectra and find reasonable agreement with Davies's full frequency sets
and very good agreement between values for modes with signal/noise &gt; 1 ($\chi^2
= 0.06, \chi^2_B=0.03$). But the difference with the Legacy values remains
large even for modes with S/N&gt;1. I also examine the effects of different power
spectra (weighted and unweighted) using the kasoc light curves for Q6-17.2 and
Q7-Q16, the effect of different mode height ratios and different rotational
splitting and inclination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00578</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Fajardo</keyname><forenames>Kristel C Meza</forenames><affiliation>IFSTTAR/GERS/SV</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Semblat</keyname><forenames>Jean-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames><affiliation>IFSTTAR/GERS/SV</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chaillat</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phanie</forenames><affiliation>POEMS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lenti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames><affiliation>IFSTTAR/GERS/SV</affiliation></author></authors><title>Seismic Wave Amplification in 3D Alluvial Basins: 3D/1D Amplification
  Ratios from Fast Multipole BEM Simulations</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Bulletin of the Seismological Society of America, Seismological
  Society of America, 2016, 106 (3), pp.1267-1281</journal-ref><doi>10.1785/0120150159</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study seismic wave amplification in alluvial basins having
3D standard geometries through the Fast Multipole Boundary Element Method in
the frequency domain. We investigate how much 3D amplification differs from the
1D (horizontal layering) case. Considering incident fields of plane harmonic
waves, we examine the relationships between the amplification level and the
most relevant physical parameters of the problem (impedance contrast, 3D aspect
ratio, vertical and oblique incidence of plane waves). The FMBEM results show
that the most important parameters for wave amplification are the impedance
contrast and the so-called equivalent shape ratio. Using these two parameters,
we derive simple rules to compute the fundamental frequency for various 3D
basin shapes and the corresponding 3D/1D amplification factor for 5% damping.
Effects on amplification due to 3D basin asymmetry are also studied and
incorporated in the derived rules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00579</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Odd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nilsen</keyname><forenames>Halvor M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasda</keyname><forenames>Sarah E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling Geomechanical Impact of CO2 Injection Using Precomputed
  Response Functions</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>Preprint, ECMOR XV</comments><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When injecting CO2 or other fluids into a geological formation, pressure
plays an important role both as a driver of flow and as a risk factor for
mechanical integrity.
  The full effect of geomechanics on aquifer flow can only be captured using a
coupled flow-geomechanics model. In order to solve this computationally
expensive system, various strategies have been put forwards over the years,
with some of the best current methods based on sequential splitting.
  In the present work, we seek to approximate the full geomechanical effect on
flow without the need of coupling with a geomechanics solver during simulation,
and at a computational cost comparable to that of an uncoupled model. We do
this by means of precomputed pressure response functions. At grid model
generation time, a geomechanics solver is used to compute the mechanical
response of the aquifer for a set of pressure fields. The relevant information
from these responses is then stored in a compact form and embedded with the
grid model.
  We test the accuracy and computational performance of our approach on a
simple 2D and a more complex 3D model, and compare the results with those
produced by a fully coupled approach as well as from a simple decoupled method
based on Geertsma's uniaxial expansion coefficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00592</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Hypolite</keyname><forenames>Delphine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathis</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieutord</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>2D dynamics of the radiation zone of low mass stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures. To appear in the proceedings of &quot;The 19th
  Cambridge Workshop on Cool Stars, Stellar Systems, and the Sun&quot; (ed. G. A.
  Feiden), Uppsala, Sweden, 06-10 June 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The internal rotation of low mass stars all along their evolution is of
primary interest when studying their rotational dynamics, internal mixing and
magnetic fields generation. In this context, helio- and asteroseismology probe
angular velocity gradients deep within solar type stars. Still the rotation of
the close center of such stars on the main sequence is hardly detectable and
the dynamical interactions of the radiative core with the surface convective
envelope is not well understood. Among them, the influence of the differential
rotation profile sustained by convection and applied as a boundary condition to
the radiation zone may be very important leading to the formation of
tachoclines. In the solar convective region, the equator is rotating faster
than the pole while numerical simulations predict either a solar or an
anti-solar rotation in other low mass stars envelopes depending on their
convective Rossby number. In this work, we therefore build for the first time
2D steady hydrodynamical models of low mass stars radiation zone providing a
full 2D description of their dynamics and studying the influence of a general
shear boundary condition accounting for a solar or an anti-solar differential
rotation in the convective envelope. We compute coherently differential
rotation and the associated meridional circulation using the Boussinesq
approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00597</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>T&#xf3;th</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;ter</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xe9;gi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xe9;v&#xe9;sz</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oszetzky</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moln&#xe1;r</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakonyi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Cu deposition potential on the giant magnetoresistance and
  surface roughness of electrodeposited Ni-Co/Cu multilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Electrochimica Acta 91, 122-129 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.electacta.2012.12.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been shown previously for electrodeposited Co/Cu multilayers that the
single-bath electrodeposition process can be optimized from an electrochemical
point of view in order to avoid unwanted Co dissolution and incorporation of Co
in the non-magnetic layer during the Cu deposition pulse. In the present work,
electrodeposition of Ni-Co/Cu multilayers has been studied to clarify if the
same optimization method is appropriate when two magnetic elements are present
and if this potential results in the largest giant magnetoresistance (GMR) for
the particular alloy system studied. For this purpose, several Ni-Co/Cu
multilayers were prepared by varying the deposition potential of the Cu layer.
The composition analysis of the deposits showed that the Ni:Co ratio exhibits a
minimum as a function of the Cu deposition potential, which can be explained by
considering both the dissolution of Co and the mass transport of the reactants.
Both the saturation GMR value and the intensity of the satellite peaks in the
X-ray diffractograms were highly correlated with the resulting surface
roughness of the deposits which was strongly varying with the Cu deposition
potential. Higher GMR values, lower saturation fields and more perfect
multilayer structure were observed for sufficiently positive Cu deposition
potentials only which enabled a partial Co dissolution resulting in a reduced
surface roughness. The results draw attention to the complexity of the
optimization procedure of the deposition of multilayers with several alloying
components.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00609</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00609</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Xian-Qiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Parton distribution of nucleon and nuclear EMC effect in a statistical
  model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the parton distribution of nucleon and nuclear EMC effect in a
statistical model. We find when we choose the parameters appropriately, the
predictions given by pure statistical laws can fit the experimental data well
in most range of $x$, this reveal statistical law play an important role in the
parton distribution of nucleon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00611</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Ratnikov</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Dispersion Relation of Magnetoplasmons in a Planar Graphene-Based
  Superlattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, 2016, Vol. 103, No. 12, pp. 774-779</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0021364016120092</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dispersion relation for magnetoplasmons in a planar superlattice with
periodically alternating regions of gapless and gapped modications of graphene
has been derived within the frame of the random-phase approximation. The
contribution of virtual transitions between the lower electron miniband and the
upper hole miniband to the polarization operator has been taken into account in
addition to the contribution of virtual intra-miniband transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00618</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00618</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Franklin</keyname><forenames>Erick de Moraes</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Figueiredo</keyname><forenames>Fab&#xed;ola Tocchini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosa</keyname><forenames>Eug&#xea;nio Span&#xf3;</forenames></author></authors><title>The feedback effect caused by bed load on a turbulent liquid flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted Manuscript for the Journal of the Brazilian Society of
  Mechanical Sciences and Engineering, v. 36, p. 725-736, 2014. The final
  publication is available at Springer via
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40430-013-0122-y</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Brazilian Society of Mechanical Sciences and
  Engineering, v. 36, p. 725-736, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40430-013-0122-y</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Experiments on the effects due solely to a mobile granular layer on a liquid
flow are presented (feedback effect). Nonintrusive measurements were performed
in a closed conduit channel of rectangular cross section where grains were
transported as bed load by a turbulent water flow. The water velocity profiles
were measured over fixed and mobile granular beds of same granulometry by
Particle Image Velocimetry. The spatial resolution of the measurements allowed
the experimental quantification of the feedback effect. The present findings
are of importance for predicting the bed-load transport rate and the pressure
drop in activities related to the conveyance of grains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00638</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bachmann</keyname><forenames>Ivana</forenames><affiliation>ITMATI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reyes</keyname><forenames>Patricio</forenames><affiliation>ITMATI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Alonso</forenames><affiliation>LINCS</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bustos-Jim&#xe9;nez</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author></authors><title>Miuz: measuring the impact of disconnecting a node</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>in 34th International Conference of the Chilean Computer Science
  Society (SCCC), Nov 2015, Santiago, Chile. 2015. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1601.02465</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1109/SCCC.2015.7416586</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we present Miuz, a robustness index for complex networks.
Miuz measures the impact of disconnecting a node from the network while
comparing the sizes of the remaining connected components. Strictly speaking,
Miuz for a node is defined as the inverse of the size of the largest connected
component divided by the sum of the sizes of the remaining ones. We tested our
index in attack strategies where the nodes are disconnected in decreasing order
of a specified metric. We considered Miuz and other well-known centrality
measures such as betweenness, degree , and harmonic centrality. All of these
metrics were compared regarding the behavior of the robust-ness (R-index)
during the attacks. In an attempt to simulate the internet backbone, the
attacks were performed in complex networks with power-law degree distributions
(scale-free networks). Preliminary results show that attacks based on
disconnecting a few number of nodes Miuz are more dangerous (decreasing the
robustness) than the same attacks based on other centrality measures. We
believe that Miuz, as well as other measures based on the size of the largest
connected component, provides a good addition to other robustness metrics for
complex networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00648</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>Richard B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>Charles-Henri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorchon</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salahuddin</keyname><forenames>Sayeef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bokor</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron-phonon interaction during optically induced ultrafast
  magnetization dynamics of Au/GdFeCo bilayers</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>3 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The temperature evolution of GdFeCo electrons following optical heating plays
a key role in all optical switching of GdFeCo and is primarily governed by the
strength of coupling between electrons and phonons. Typically, the strength of
electron-phonon coupling in a metal is deduced by monitoring changes in
reflectance following optical heating and then analyzing the transient
reflectance with a simple two-temperature thermal model. In a magnetic metal,
the change in reflectance cannot be assumed to depend only the electron and
phonon temperatures because a metal's reflectance also depends on the
magnetization. To deduce the electron-phonon coupling constant in GdFeCo, we
analyze thermal transport in Au and GdFeCo bilayers following optical heating
of the GdFeCo electrons. We use the reflectance of the Au layer to monitor the
temperature evolution of the Au phonons. By interpreting the response of the
bilayer to heating with a thermal model, we determine the electron-phonon
coupling constant in GdFeCo to be 6 x 10^17 W/(m^3-K) corresponding to an
electron-phonon relaxation time in GdFeCo of ~150 fs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00662</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00662</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciamarra</keyname><forenames>Massimo Pica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piscitelli</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Escape rate and diffusion of a random walker</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the rate of escape from a potential well, and the diffusion
coefficient in a periodic potential, of a random walker that moves under the
influence of the potential in between successive collisions with the heat bath.
In the overdamped limit, both the escape rate and the diffusion coefficient
coincide with those of a Langevin particle. Conversely, in the underdamped
limit the two dynamics have a different temperature dependence. In particular,
at low temperature the random walk has a smaller escape rate, but a larger
diffusion coefficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00686</id><created>2016-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Naruse</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthel</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drezet</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huant</keyname><forenames>Serge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hori</keyname><forenames>Hirokazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Song-Ju</forenames></author></authors><title>Single photon in hierarchical architecture for physical reinforcement
  learning: Photon intelligence</title><categories>cs.LG physics.optics quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding and using natural processes for intelligent functionalities,
referred to as natural intelligence, has recently attracted interest from a
variety of fields, including post-silicon computing for artificial intelligence
and decision making in the behavioural sciences. In a past study, we
successfully used the wave-particle duality of single photons to solve the
two-armed bandit problem, which constitutes the foundation of reinforcement
learning and decision making. In this study, we propose and confirm a
hierarchical architecture for single-photon-based reinforcement learning and
decision making that verifies the scalability of the principle. Specifically,
the four-armed bandit problem is solved given zero prior knowledge in a
two-layer hierarchical architecture, where polarization is autonomously adapted
in order to effect adequate decision making using single-photon measurements.
In the hierarchical structure, the notion of layer-dependent decisions emerges.
The optimal solutions in the coarse layer and in the fine layer, however,
conflict with each other in some contradictive problems. We show that while
what we call a tournament strategy resolves such contradictions, the
probabilistic nature of single photons allows for the direct location of the
optimal solution even for contradictive problems, hence manifesting the
exploration ability of single photons. This study provides insights into photon
intelligence in hierarchical architectures for future artificial intelligence
as well as the potential of natural processes for intelligent functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00693</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Surajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Arijit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangadharaiah</keyname><forenames>Suhas</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunneling Conductance in Normal-Insulator-Superconductor junctions of
  Silicene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate the transport properties of a
normal-insulator-superconductor (NIS) junction of silicene in the thin barrier
limit. Similar to graphene the tunneling conductance in such NIS structure
exhibits an oscillatory behavior as a function of the strength of the barrier
in the insulating region. However, unlike in graphene, the tunneling
conductance in silicene can be controlled by an external electric field owing
to its buckled structure. We also demonstrate the change in behavior of the
tunneling conductance across the NIS junction as we change the chemical
potential in the normal silicene region. In addition, at high doping levels in
the normal region, the period of oscillation of the tunneling conductance as a
function of the barrier strength changes from $\pi/2$ to $\pi$ with the
variation of doping in the superconducting region of silicene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00697</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Hingant</keyname><forenames>Erwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yvinec</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author></authors><title>Deterministic and Stochastic Becker-D\&quot;oring equations: Past and Recent
  Mathematical Developments</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a survey on the results on a particular coagulation-fragmentation
model given by the Becker-D\&quot;oring equations. For both the deterministic and
stochastic versions, we include well-posedness, long-time behavior, convergence
rate towards equilibrium, coarsening and relation to transport equations,
time-dependent properties, metastability and classical nucleation theory. All
along this survey, we highlight recent results and open questions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00698</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Brachmann</keyname><forenames>Johannes F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaupp</keyname><forenames>Hanno</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe4;nsch</keyname><forenames>Theodor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hunger</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Photothermal effects in ultra-precisely stabilized tunable microcavities</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Optics Express Vol. 24, No. 18, 21205 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.021205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the mechanical stability of a tunable high-finesse microcavity under
ambient conditions and investigate light-induced effects that can both suppress
and excite mechanical fluctuations. As an enabling step, we demonstrate the
ultra-precise electronic stabilization of a microcavity. We then show that
photothermal mirror expansion can provide high-bandwidth feedback and improve
cavity stability by almost two orders of magnitude. At high intracavity power,
we observe self-oscillations of mechanical resonances of the cavity. We explain
the observations by a dynamic photothermal instability, leading to parametric
driving of mechanical motion. For an optimized combination of electronic and
photothermal stabilization, we achieve a feedback bandwidth of $500\,$kHz and a
noise level of $1.1 \times 10^{-13}\,$m rms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00701</id><created>2016-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Krasnozhon</keyname><forenames>Daria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Subhojit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nyffeler</keyname><forenames>Clemens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leblebici</keyname><forenames>Yusuf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kis</keyname><forenames>Andras</forenames></author></authors><title>High-frequency, scaled MoS2 transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>in Electron Devices Meeting (IEDM), 2015 IEEE International</comments><doi>10.1109/IEDM.2015.7409781</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interest in MoS2 for radio-frequency (RF) application has recently
increased. However, little is known on the scaling behavior of transistors made
from MoS2 for RF applications, which is important for establishing performance
limits for electronic circuits based on 2D semiconductors on flexible and rigid
substrates. Here, we present a systematic study of top-gated trilayer MoS2 RF
transistors with gate lengths scaled down to 70 and 40 nm. In addition, by
introducing edge-contacted injection of electrons in trilayer MoS2 devices, we
decrease the contact resistance and as a result obtain the highest cutoff
frequency of 6 GHz before the de-embedding procedure and 25 GHz after the
de-embedding procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-05</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00709</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Eubanks</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radley</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scientific Return of a Lunar Elevator</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>12 pages and 7 figures; Accepted for publication in Space Policy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of a space elevator dates back to Tsilokovsky, but they are not
commonly considered in near-term plans for space exploration, perhaps because a
terrestrial elevator would not be possible without considerable improvements in
tether material. A Lunar Space Elevator (LSE), however, can be built with
current technology using commercially available tether polymers. This paper
considers missions leading to infrastructure capable of shortening the time,
lowering the cost and enhancing the capabilities of robotic and human
explorers. These missions use planetary scale tethers, strings many thousands
of kilometers long stabilized either by rotation or by gravitational gradients.
These systems promise major reduction in transport costs versus chemical
rockets, in a rapid timeframe, for a modest investment. Science will thus
benefit as well as commercial activities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
