<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:12:47Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-09-16" from="2016-09-16" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.5027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.5027</id><created>2012-04-23</created><updated>2015-10-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Li-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yuan</forenames></author></authors><title>The tensor renormalization group study of the general spin-S Blume-Capel
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 104602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.104602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We focus on the special situation of $D=2J$ of the general spin-S Blume-Capel
model on the square lattice. Under the infinitesimal external magnetic field,
the phase transition behaviors due to the thermal fluctuations are discussed by
the newly developed tensor renormalization group method. For the case of the
integer spin-S, the system will undergo $S$ first-order phase transitions with
the successive symmetry breaking with the magnetization $M=S,S-1,...0$. For the
half-integer spin-S, there are similar $S-1/2$ first order phase transition
with $M=S,S-1,...1/2$ stepwise structure, in addition, there is a continuous
phase transition due to the spin-flip $Z_2$ symmetry breaking. In the low
temperature regions, all first-order phase transitions are accompanied by the
successive disappearance of the optional spin-component pairs($s,-s$),
furthermore, the critical temperature for the nth first-order phase transition
is the same, independent of the value of the spin-S. In the absence of the
magnetic field, the visualization parameter characterizing the intrinsic
degeneracy of the different phases clearly demonstrates the phase transition
process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.3537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.3537</id><created>2012-08-17</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiaolei</forenames></author></authors><title>N-Body Simulations of Collective Effects in Spiral and Barred Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>96 pages, 53 figures, part of the contents previously presented for
  an invited talk at the 2012 IAU SpS3</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy and Computing, Volume 17, p. 86-128, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2016.07.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present gravitational N-body simulations of the secular morphological
evolution of disk galaxies induced by density wave modes. In particular, we
address the demands collective effects place on the choice of simulation
parameters, and show that the common practice of the use of a large gravity
softening parameter was responsible for the failure of past simulations to
correctly model the secular evolution process in galaxies, even for those
simulations where the choice of basic state allows an unstable mode to emerge,
a prerequisite for obtaining the coordinated radial mass flow pattern needed
for secular evolution of galaxies along the Hubble sequence. We also
demonstrate that the secular evolution rates measured in our improved
simulations agree to an impressive degree with the corresponding rates
predicted by the recently-advanced theories of dynamically-driven secular
evolution of galaxies. The results of the current work, besides having direct
implications on the cosmological evolution of galaxies, also shed light on the
general question of how irreversibility emerges from a nominally reversible
physical system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.0950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.0950</id><created>2013-01-05</created><updated>2014-06-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arsie</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorenzoni</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moro</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable viscous conservation laws</title><categories>math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>47 pages, 3 figures; improved version with two new remarks, added
  references</comments><journal-ref>Nonlinearity 28 (2015), no. 6</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an extension of the Dubrovin-Zhang perturbative approach to the
study of normal forms for non-Hamiltonian integrable scalar conservation laws.
The explicit computation of the first few corrections leads to the conjecture
that such normal forms are parameterized by one single functional parameter,
named viscous central invariant. A constant valued viscous central invariant
corresponds to the well-known Burgers hierarchy. The case of a linear viscous
central invariant provides a viscous analog of the Camassa-Holm equation, that
formerly appeared as a reduction of a two-component Hamiltonian integrable
systems. We write explicitly the negative and positive hierarchy associated
with this equation and prove the integrability showing that they can be mapped
respectively into the heat hierarchy and its negative counterpart, named the
Klein-Gordon hierarchy. A local well-posedness theorem for periodic initial
data is also proven. We show how transport equations can be used to effectively
construct asymptotic solutions via an extension of the quasi-Miura map that
preserves the initial datum. The method is alternative to the method of the
string equation for Hamiltonian conservation laws and naturally extends to the
viscous case. Using these tools we derive the viscous analog of the Painlev\'e
I2 equation that describes the universal behaviour of the solution at the
critical point of gradient catastrophe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.7357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.7357</id><created>2013-03-29</created><updated>2014-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benchamekh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raouafi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Even</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larbi</keyname><forenames>F. Ben Cheikh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jancu</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic Electronic Wavefunction and interactions between quasi
  particles in Empirical Tight-Binding Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.045118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A procedure to obtain single-electron wavefunctions within the tight-binding
formalism is proposed. It is based on linear combinations of Slater-type
orbitals whose screening coefficients are extracted from the optical matrix
elements of the tight-binding Hamiltonian. Bloch functions obtained for
zinc-blende semiconductors in the extended-basis spds* tight-binding model
demonstrate very good agreement with first-principles wavefunctions. We apply
this method to the calculation of electron-hole exchange interaction, and
obtain the dispersion of excitonic fine structure of bulk GaAs. Beyond
semiconductor nanostructures, this work is a fundamental step toward modeling
many-body effects from post-processing single particle wavefunctions within the
tight-binding theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.5404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.5404</id><created>2013-11-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Benchamekh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gippius</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Even</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nestoklon</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jancu</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ithurria</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubertret</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efros</keyname><forenames>Al. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tight-binding calculations of image charge effects in colloidal
  nanoscale platelets of CdSe</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.035307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  CdSe nanoplatelets show perfectly quantized thicknesses of few monolayers.
They present a situation of extreme, yet well defined quantum confinement. Due
to large dielectric contrast between the semiconductor and its ligand
environment, interaction between carriers and their dielectric images strongly
renormalize bare single particle states. We discuss the electronic properties
of this original system in an advanced tight-binding model, and show that
Coulomb interactions, including self-energy corrections and enhanced
electron-hole interaction, lead to exciton binding energies up to several
hundred meVs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.7470</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.7470</id><created>2013-11-29</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sj&#xf6;qvist</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mousolou</keyname><forenames>Vahid Azimi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canali</keyname><forenames>Carlo M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conceptual aspects of geometric quantum computation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Revised version; journal reference added</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf. Process. 15, 3995 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1381-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geometric quantum computation is the idea that geometric phases can be used
to implement quantum gates, i.e., the basic elements of the Boolean network
that forms a quantum computer. Although originally thought to be limited to
adiabatic evolution, controlled by slowly changing parameters, this form of
quantum computation can as well be realized at high speed by using nonadiabatic
schemes. Recent advances in quantum gate technology have allowed for
experimental demonstrations of different types of geometric gates in adiabatic
and nonadiabatic evolution. Here, we address some conceptual issues that arise
in the realizations of geometric gates. We examine the appearance of dynamical
phases in quantum evolution and point out that not all dynamical phases need to
be compensated for in geometric quantum computation. We delineate the relation
between Abelian and non-Abelian geometric gates and find an explicit physical
example where the two types of gates coincide. We identify differences and
similarities between adiabatic and nonadiabatic realizations of quantum
computation based on non-Abelian geometric phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.5031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.5031</id><created>2013-12-17</created><updated>2015-01-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komori</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michimura</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayase</keyname><forenames>Gen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aso</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsubono</keyname><forenames>Kimio</forenames></author></authors><title>5-mg suspended mirror driven by measurement-induced back-action</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.033825</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum mechanics predicts superposition of position states even for
macroscopic objects. Recently, the use of a quasi-freely suspended mirror
combined with laser was proposed to prepare such states, by M\&quot;uller-Ebhardt et
al. [Phys.Rev.Lett.100, 013601 (2008)]. One of the key milestones towards this
goal is the preparation of the mechanical oscillator mainly driven by quantum
back-action, which identifies the connection between the object and quantumness
of the light. Here, we describe development of a suspended 5-mg mirror driven
by quantum back-action larger than thermal fluctuating force by a factor of
1.4$\pm$0.2 at 325 Hz,which is confirmed by using a triangular optical cavity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.6565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.6565</id><created>2014-11-24</created><updated>2015-04-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Raouafi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benchamekh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nestoklon</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jancu</keyname><forenames>J-M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic interface states in InAs-AlSb heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/4/045001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the possibility of intrinsic interface states bound to the plane
of In-Sb chemical bonds at InAs/AlSb interfaces. Careful parameterization of
the bulk materials in the frame of the extended basis spds^* tight-binding
model and recent progress in predictions of band offsets severely limit the
span of tight-binding parameters describing this system. We find that a
heavy-hole like interface state bound to the plane of In-Sb bonds exists for a
large range of values of the InSb/InAs band offset.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7673</id><created>2014-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sushch</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr</forenames></author></authors><title>On the chirality of a discrete Dirac-K\&quot;ahler equation</title><categories>math-ph math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1307.1220</comments><msc-class>39A12, 39A70, 35Q41</msc-class><journal-ref>Rept. Math.Phys, 76 (2015), 179-195</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0034-4877(15)30028-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a discrete analogue of the Dirac-K\&quot;{a}hler equation in which
chiral properties of the continual counterpart are captured. We pay special
attention to a discrete Hodge star operator. To build one a combinatorial
construction of double complex is used. We describe discrete exterior calculus
operations on a double comlex and obtain the discrete Dirac-K\&quot;{a}hler equation
using these tools. Self-dual and anti-self-dual discrete inhomogeneous forms
are presented. The chiral invariance of the massless discrete Dirac-K\&quot;{a}hler
equation is shown. Moreover, in the massive case we prove that a discrete
Dirac-K\&quot;{a}hler operator flips the chirality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.01058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.01058</id><created>2015-02-03</created><updated>2015-07-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buhrman</keyname><forenames>Harry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czekaj</keyname><forenames>Lukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grudka</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horodecki</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horodecki</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markiewicz</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Speelman</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strelchuk</keyname><forenames>Sergii</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum communication complexity advantage implies violation of a Bell
  inequality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>main text did not change. Modified the acknowledgements section</comments><journal-ref>PNAS March 22, 2016 vol. 113 no. 12 3191-3196</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1507647113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain a general connection between a quantum advantage in communication
complexity and non-locality. We show that given any protocol offering a
(sufficiently large) quantum advantage in communication complexity, there
exists a way of obtaining measurement statistics which violate some Bell
inequality. Our main tool is port-based teleportation. If the gap between
quantum and classical communication complexity can grow arbitrarily large, the
ratio of the quantum value to the classical value of the Bell quantity becomes
unbounded with the increase in the number of inputs and outputs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02952</id><created>2015-02-10</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Farshbaf-Shaker</keyname><forenames>M. Hassan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinemann</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>A phase field approach for optimal boundary control of damage processes
  in two-dimensional viscoelastic media</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.OC</categories><msc-class>35A01, 35A02, 35D35, 35M33, 35M87, 35Q74, 49J20, 74A45, 74D10,
  74F99, 74H20, 74H25, 74P99</msc-class><journal-ref>Math. Models Methods Appl. Sci., 25 (2015) pp. 2749--2793</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218202515500608</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we investigate a phase field model for damage processes in
two-dimensional viscoelastic media with nonhomogeneous Neumann data describing
external boundary forces. In the first part we establish global-in-time
existence, uniqueness, a priori estimates and continuous dependence of strong
solutions on the data. The main difficulty is caused by the irreversibility of
the phase field variable which results in a constrained PDE system. In the last
part we consider an optimal control problem where a cost functional penalizes
maximal deviations from prescribed damage profiles. The goal is to minimize the
cost functional with respect to exterior forces acting on the boundary which
play the role of the control variable in the considered model. To this end, we
prove existence of minimizers and study a family of &quot;local&quot; approximations via
adapted cost functionals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05051</id><created>2015-07-17</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pollock</keyname><forenames>Felix A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ch&#x119;ci&#x144;ska</keyname><forenames>Agata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascazio</keyname><forenames>Saverio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Modi</keyname><forenames>Kavan</forenames></author></authors><title>Using a biased qubit to probe complex systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8+8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex mesoscopic systems play increasingly important roles in modern
science -- from understanding biological functions at the molecular level, to
designing solid-state information processing devices. The operation of these
systems typically depends on their energetic structure, yet probing their
energy-landscape can be extremely challenging; they have many degrees of
freedom, which may be hard to isolate and measure independently. Here we show
that a qubit (a two-level quantum system) with a biased energy-splitting can
directly probe the spectral properties of a complex system, without knowledge
of how they couple. Our work is based on the completely-positive and
trace-preserving map formalism, which treats any unknown dynamics as a
`black-box' process. This black box contains information about the system with
which the probe interacts, which we access by measuring the survival
probability of the initial state of the probe as function of the
energy-splitting and the process time. Fourier transforming the results yields
the energy spectrum of the complex system. Without making assumptions about the
strength or form of its coupling, our probe could determine aspects of a
complex molecule's energy landscape as well as, in many cases, test for
coherent superposition of its energy eigenstates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02902</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>C. J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffiths</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrer</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>G. A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritchie</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsyplyatyev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schofield</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear spectra of spinons and holons in short GaAs quantum wires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures; definitive published version</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12784 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12784</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  One-dimensional electronic fluids are peculiar conducting systems, where the
fundamental role of interactions leads to exotic, emergent phenomena, such as
spin-charge (spinon-holon) separation. The distinct low-energy properties of
these 1D metals are successfully described within the theory of linear
Luttinger liquids, but the challenging task of describing their high-energy
nonlinear properties has long remained elusive. Recently, novel theoretical
approaches accounting for nonlinearity have been developed, yet the rich
phenomenology that they predict remains barely explored experimentally. Here,
we probe the nonlinear spectral characteristics of short GaAs quantum wires by
tunnelling spectroscopy, using an advanced device consisting of 6000 wires. We
find evidence for the existence of an inverted (spinon) shadow band in the main
region of the particle sector, one of the central predictions of the new
nonlinear theories. A (holon) band with reduced effective mass is clearly
visible in the particle sector at high energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03721</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Skinner</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathematical toy model inspired by the problem of the adaptive origins
  of the sexual orientation continuum</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.stat-mech physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Royal Society Open Science 3: 160403 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsos.160403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Same-sex sexual behavior is ubiquitous in the animal kingdom, but its
adaptive origins remain a prominent puzzle. Here I suggest the possibility that
same-sex sexual behavior arises as a consequence of the competition between an
evolutionary drive for a wide diversity in traits, which improves the
adaptability of a species, and a drive for sexual dichotomization of traits,
which promotes opposite-sex attraction and increases the rate of reproduction.
A simple analytical &quot;toy model&quot; is proposed for describing this tradeoff. The
model exhibits a number of interesting features, and suggests a simple
mathematical form for describing the sexual orientation continuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06373</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Braga</keyname><forenames>Nelson R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contreras</keyname><forenames>M. A. Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diles</keyname><forenames>Saulo</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic model for heavy vector meson masses</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>In V5 we just added some clarifying explanations about the model. 5
  tables, no figure. Version published in Europhysics Letters</comments><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/31002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The experimentally observed spectra of heavy vector meson radial excitations
show a dependence on two different energy parameters. One is associated with
the quark mass and the other with the binding energy levels of the quark
anti-quark pair. The first is present in the large mass of the first state
while the other corresponds to the small mass splittings between radial
excitations. In this article we show how to reproduce such a behavior with
reasonable precision using a holographic model. In the dual picture, the large
energy scale shows up from a bulk mass and the small scale comes from the
position of anti-de Sitter (AdS) space where field correlators are calculated.
The model determines the masses of four observed S-wave states of charmonium
and six S-wave states of bottomonium with , 6.1 % rms error. In consistency
with the physical picture, the large energy parameter is flavor dependent,
while the small parameter, associated with quark anti-quark interaction is the
same for charmonium and bottomonium states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05554</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarrataca</keyname><forenames>Lu&#xed;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nahimov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author></authors><title>Laplacian versus Adjacency Matrix in Quantum Walk Search</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf. Process. 15(10), 4029-4048 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1373-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum particle evolving by Schr\&quot;odinger's equation contains, from the
kinetic energy of the particle, a term in its Hamiltonian proportional to
Laplace's operator. In discrete space, this is replaced by the discrete or
graph Laplacian, which gives rise to a continuous-time quantum walk. Besides
this natural definition, some quantum walk algorithms instead use the adjacency
matrix to effect the walk. While this is equivalent to the Laplacian for
regular graphs, it is different for non-regular graphs, and is thus an
inequivalent quantum walk. We algorithmically explore this distinction by
analyzing search on the complete bipartite graph with multiple marked vertices,
using both the Laplacian and adjacency matrix. The two walks differ
qualitatively and quantitatively in their required jumping rate, runtime,
sampling of marked vertices, and in what constitutes a natural initial state.
Thus the choice of the Laplacian or adjacency matrix to effect the walk has
important algorithmic consequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08549</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08549</id><created>2015-12-28</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>M. C. David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sousa</keyname><forenames>Kepa</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Properties of Type IIB and F-theory Flux Compactifications at
  Large Complex Structure</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider flux compactifications of type IIB string theory and F-theory in
which the respective superpotentials at large complex structure are dominated
by cubic or quartic terms in the complex structure moduli. In this limit, the
low-energy effective theory for the complex structure and axio-dilaton sector
exhibits universal properties that are insensitive to the details of the
compactification manifold or the flux configuration. We show that there are no
vacua in this region and the spectrum of the Hessian matrix is highly peaked
and consists only of three distinct eigenvalues ($0$, $2m_{3/2}^2$ and
$8m_{3/2}^2$), independently of the number of moduli. We briefly comment on how
the inclusion of K\&quot;ahler moduli affect these findings. Our results generalise
those of Brodie &amp; Marsh [1], in which these universal properties were found in
a subspace of the large complex structure limit of type IIB compactifications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04508</id><created>2016-01-18</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>David G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sols</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guinea</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zapata</keyname><forenames>Ivar</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron-phonon vertex and its influence on the superconductivity of
  two-dimensional metals on a piezoelectric substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 085423 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the interaction between the electrons of a two-dimensional
metal and the acoustic phonons of an underlying piezoelectric substrate.
Fundamental inequalities can be obtained from general energy arguments. As a
result, phonon mediated attraction can be proven to never overcome electron
Coulomb repulsion, at least for long phonon wavelengths. We study the influence
of these phonons on the possible pairing instabilities of a two-dimensional
electron gas such as graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06983</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>Christof P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steude</keyname><forenames>Anja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tropf</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kronenberg</keyname><forenames>Nils M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostermann</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gather</keyname><forenames>Malte C.</forenames></author></authors><title>An exciton-polariton laser based on biologically produced fluorescent
  protein</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft physics.optics</categories><comments>13(+8) pages, 4(+7) figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Adv. 2, e1600666 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/sciadv.1600666</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under adequate conditions, cavity-polaritons form a macroscopic coherent
quantum state, known as Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC). Compared to
Wannier-Mott excitons in inorganic semiconductors, the localized Frenkel
excitons in organic emitter materials show weaker interaction but stronger
coupling, which recently enabled the first realization of BEC at room
temperature. However, this required ultrafast optical pumping which limits the
applications of organic BECs. Here, we demonstrate room-temperature BEC of
cavity-polaritons in simple laminated microcavities filled with the
biologically produced enhanced green fluorescent protein (eGFP). The unique
molecular structure of eGFP prevents exciton annihilation even at high
excitation densities, thus facilitating BEC under conventional nanosecond
pumping. BEC is clearly evidenced by a distinct threshold, an
interaction-induced blueshift of the condensate, long-range coherence and the
presence of a second threshold at higher excitation density which is associated
with the onset of photon lasing and results from thermalization of the exciton
reservoir.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07148</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barbosa</keyname><forenames>Fernando V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penna</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9; L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Rogelma M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novais</keyname><forenames>Keila L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Cunha</keyname><forenames>Jefferson A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Fernando A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pattern transitions in a nonlocal logistic map for populations</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the pattern solutions of doubly nonlocal logistic map
that include spatial kernels in both growth and competition terms. We show that
this map includes as a particular case the nonlocal Fisher-Kolmogorov equation,
and we demonstrate the existence of three kinds of stationary nonlinear
solutions: one uniform, one cosine type that we refer to as wavelike solution,
and another in the form of Gaussian. We also obtain analytical expressions that
describe the nonlinear pattern behavior in the system, and we establish the
stability criterion. We define thermodynamics grandeurs such as entropy and the
order parameter. Based on this, the pattern-no-pattern and pattern-pattern
transitions are properly analyzed. We show that these pattern solutions may be
related to the recently observed peak adding phenomenon in nonlinear optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03776</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03776</id><created>2016-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Dalmonte</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montangero</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lattice gauge theories simulations in the quantum information era</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech hep-lat quant-ph</categories><comments>Pedagogical review article. Originally submitted to Contemporary
  Physics, the final version will appear soon on the on-line version of the
  journal. 34 pages</comments><journal-ref>Contemporary Physics 57 388 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00107514.2016.1151199</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The many-body problem is ubiquitous in the theoretical description of
physical phenomena, ranging from the behavior of elementary particles to the
physics of electrons in solids. Most of our understanding of many-body systems
comes from analyzing the symmetry properties of Hamiltonian and states: the
most striking example are gauge theories such as quantum electrodynamics, where
a local symmetry strongly constrains the microscopic dynamics. The physics of
such gauge theories is relevant for the understanding of a diverse set of
systems, including frustrated quantum magnets and the collective dynamics of
elementary particles within the standard model. In the last few years, several
approaches have been put forward to tackle the complex dynamics of gauge
theories using quantum information concepts. In particular, quantum simulation
platforms have been put forward for the realization of synthetic gauge
theories, and novel classical simulation algorithms based on quantum
information concepts have been formulated. In this review we present an
introduction to these approaches, illustrating the basics concepts and
highlighting the connections between apparently very different fields, and
report the recent developments in this new thriving field of research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04164</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2016-04-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caprino</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavallaro</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchioro</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>A Vlasov-Poisson plasma with unbounded mass and velocities confined in a
  cylinder by a magnetic mirror</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>accepted on &quot;Kinetic and Related Models&quot;</comments><report-no>Roma01.Math.MP</report-no><journal-ref>Kinetic and Related Models 9, 657-686 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3934/krm.2016011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the time evolution of a single species positive plasma, confined in
a cylinder and having infinite charge. We extend the result of a previous work
by the same authors, for a plasma density having compact support in the
velocities, to the case of a density having unbounded support and gaussian
decay in the velocities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08121</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chudaykin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbunov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tkachev</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter component decaying after recombination: lensing constraints
  with Planck data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures; v2: journal version, pages++, figures++</comments><report-no>INR-TH/2016-006</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 023528 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.023528</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been recently suggested~\cite{Berezhiani:2015yta} that emerging
tension between cosmological parameter values derived in high-redshift (CMB
anisotropy) and low-redshift (cluster counts, Hubble constant) measurements can
be reconciled in a model which contains subdominant fraction of dark matter
decaying after recombination. We check the model against the CMB Planck data.
We find that lensing of the CMB anisotropies by the large-scale structure gives
strong extra constraints on this model, limiting the fraction as $F&lt;8\%$ at
2\,$\sigma$ confidence level. However, investigating the combined data set of
CMB and conflicting low-$z$ measurements, we obtain that the model with
$F\approx2\!-\!5$\% exhibits better fit (by 1.5-3\,$\sigma$ depending on the
lensing priors) compared to that of the concordance $\Lambda$CDM cosmological
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02190</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lamprea</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peinado</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>SeeSaw scale discrete dark matter and two-zero texture Majorana neutrino
  mass matrices</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 055007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.055007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a scenario where the stability of dark matter and
the phenomenology of neutrinos are related by the spontaneous breaking of a
non-Abelian flavor symmetry. In this scenario the breaking is done at the
seesaw scale, in such a way that what remains of the flavor symmetry is a Z2
symmetry, which stabilizes the dark matter. We have proposed two models based
on this idea, for which we have calculated their neutrino mass matrices
achieving two-zero texture in both cases. Accordingly, we have updated this
two-zero texture phenomenology finding an interesting correlation between the
reactor mixing angle and the sum of the light neutrino masses. We also have a
correlation between the lightest neutrino mass and the neutrinoless double beta
decay effective mass, obtaining a lower bound for the effective mass within the
region of the nearly future experimental sensitivities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02606</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Jerome</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ringeval</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vennin</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author></authors><title>Information Gain on Reheating: the One Bit Milestone</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, uses RevTeX. References added, matches published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 103532 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.103532</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the Planck 2015 and BICEP2/KECK measurements of the Cosmic
Microwave Background (CMB) anisotropies provide together an information gain of
0.82 +- 0.13 bits on the reheating history over all slow-roll single-field
models of inflation. This corresponds to a 40% improvement compared to the
Planck 2013 constraints on the reheating. Our method relies on an exhaustive
CMB data analysis performed over nearly 200 models of inflation to derive the
Kullback-Leibler entropy between the prior and the fully marginalized posterior
of the reheating parameter. This number is a weighted average by the Bayesian
evidence of each model to explain the data thereby ensuring its fairness and
robustness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04407</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04407</id><created>2016-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Raouafi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samti</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benchamekh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyd</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyer-Richard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voisin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jancu</keyname><forenames>J-M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical properties of potential-inserted quantum wells in the near
  infrared and Terahertz ranges</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2016.03.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an engineering of the optical properties of GaAs/AlGaAs quantum
wells using AlAs and InAs monolayer insertions. A quantitative study of the
effects of the monolayer position and the well thickness on the interband and
intersubband transitions, based on the extended-basis sp3d5s* tight-binding
model, is presented. The effect of insertion on the interband transitions is
compared with existing experimental data. As for intersubband transitions, we
show that in a GaAs/AlGaAs quantum well including two AlAs and one InAs
insertions, a three level {e1 , e2 , e3 } system where the transition energy
e3-e2 is lower and the transition energy e2-e1 larger than the longitudinal
optical phonon energy (36 meV) can be engineered together with a e3-e2
transition energy widely tunable through the TeraHertz range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05859</id><created>2016-03-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Onaga</keyname><forenames>Tomokatsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shinomoto</keyname><forenames>Shigeru</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of event cascades in inhomogeneous networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 33321 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep33321</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is a commonality among contagious diseases, tweets, urban crimes,
nuclear reactions, and neuronal firings that past events facilitate the future
occurrence of events. The spread of events has been extensively studied such
that the systems exhibit catastrophic chain reactions if the interaction
represented by the ratio of reproduction exceeds unity; however, their
subthreshold states for the case of the weaker interaction are not fully
understood. Here, we report that these systems are possessed by nonstationary
cascades of event-occurrences already in the subthreshold regime. Event
cascades can be harmful in some contexts, when the peak-demand causes vaccine
shortages, heavy traffic on communication lines, frequent crimes, or large
fluctuations in nuclear reactions, but may be beneficial in other contexts,
such that spontaneous activity in neural networks may be used to generate
motion or store memory. Thus it is important to comprehend the mechanism by
which such cascades appear, and consider controlling a system to tame or
facilitate fluctuations in the event-occurrences. The critical interaction for
the emergence of cascades depends greatly on the network structure in which
individuals are connected. We demonstrate that we can predict whether cascades
may emerge in a network, given information about the interactions between
individuals. Furthermore, we develop a method of reallocating connections among
individuals so that event cascades may be either impeded or impelled in a
network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07281</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tahamtan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svitek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of Robinson--Trautman solution with scalar hair</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>2 figures</comments><msc-class>83C15, 83C57, 83C75, 83C20</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064031 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064031</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  An explicit Robinson--Trautman solution with minimally coupled free scalar
field was derived and analyzed recently. It was shown that this solution
possesses a curvature singularity which is initially naked but later enveloped
by a horizon. However, this study concentrated on the general branch of the
solution where all free constants are nonzero. Interesting special cases arise
when some of the parameters are set to zero. In most of these cases the scalar
field is still present. One of the cases is a static solution which represents
a parametric limit of the Janis--Newman--Winicour scalar field spacetime.
Additionally, we provide a calculation of the Bondi mass which clarifies the
interpretation of the general solution. Finally, by a complex rotation of a
parameter describing the strength of the scalar field we obtain a dynamical
wormhole solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07334</id><created>2016-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Margalit</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>Brian D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time dependent models of accretion disks with nuclear burning following
  the tidal disruption of a white dwarf by a neutron star</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>25 pages, 19 figures, 2 tables; Submitted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 461, 1154-1176 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct time-dependent one-dimensional (vertically averaged) models of
accretion disks produced by the tidal disruption of a white dwarf (WD) by a
binary neutron star (NS) companion. Nuclear reactions in the disk midplane burn
the WD matter to increasingly heavier elements at sequentially smaller radii,
releasing substantial energy which can impact the disk dynamics. A model for
disk outflows is employed, by which cooling from the outflow balances other
sources of heating (viscous, nuclear) in regulating the Bernoulli parameter of
the midplane to a fixed value $\lesssim 0$. We perform a comprehensive
parameter study of the compositional yields and velocity distributions of the
disk outflows for WDs of different initial compositions. For C/O WDs, the
radial composition profile of the disk evolves self-similarly in a
quasi-steady-state manner, and is remarkably robust to model parameters. The
nucleosynthesis in helium WD disks does not exhibit this behavior, which
instead depends sensitively on factors controlling the disk midplane density
(e.g. the strength of the viscosity, $\alpha$). By the end of the simulation, a
substantial fraction of the WD mass is unbound in outflows at characteristic
velocities of $\sim 10^9~{\rm cm~s}^{-1}$. The outflows from WD-NS merger disks
contain $10^{-4}-3 \times 10^{-3} M_\odot$ of radioactive $^{56}$Ni, resulting
in fast ($\sim$ week long) dim ($\sim10^{40}~{\rm erg~s}^{-1}$) optical
transients; shock heating of the ejecta by late time outflows may increase the
peak luminosity to $\sim 10^{43}~{\rm erg~s}^{-1}$. The accreted mass onto the
neutron star is probably not sufficient to induce gravitational collapse, but
may be capable of spinning up the NS to periods of $\sim 10~{\rm ms}$. This is
a new possible channel for forming isolated recycled pulsars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08509</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sung-Sik</forenames></author></authors><title>Horizon as Critical Phenomenon</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>37 pages, 8 figures; v2) introduction expanded</comments><journal-ref>JHEP (2016) 2016: 44</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that renormalization group(RG) flow can be viewed as a gradual wave
function collapse, where a quantum state associated with the action of field
theory evolves toward a final state that describes an IR fixed point. The
process of collapse is described by the radial evolution in the dual
holographic theory. If the theory is in the same phase as the assumed IR fixed
point, the initial state is smoothly projected to the final state. If in a
different phase, the initial state undergoes a phase transition which in turn
gives rise to a horizon in the bulk geometry. We demonstrate the connection
between critical behavior and horizon in an example, by deriving the bulk
metrics that emerge in various phases of the U(N) vector model in the large N
limit based on the holographic dual constructed from quantum RG. The gapped
phase exhibits a geometry that smoothly ends at a finite proper distance in the
radial direction. The geometric distance in the radial direction measures a
complexity : the depth of RG transformation that is needed to project the
generally entangled UV state to a direct product state in the IR. For gapless
states, entanglement persistently spreads out to larger length scales, and the
initial state can not be projected to the direct product state. The obstruction
to smooth projection at charge neutral point manifests itself as the long
throat in the anti-de Sitter space. The Poincare horizon at infinity marks the
critical point which exhibits a divergent length scale in the spread of
entanglement. For the gapless states with non-zero chemical potential, the bulk
space becomes the Lifshitz geometry with the dynamical critical exponent two.
The identification of horizon as critical point may provide an explanation for
the universality of horizon. We also discuss the structure of the bulk tensor
network that emerges from the quantum RG.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00850</id><created>2016-04-04</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Str&#xe4;ter</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckardt</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Interband heating processes in a periodically driven optical lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1515/zna-2016-0129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate multi-&quot;photon&quot; interband excitation processes in an optical
lattice that is driven periodically in time by a modulation of the lattice
depth. Assuming the system to be prepared in the lowest band, we compute the
excitation spectrum numerically. Moreover, we estimate the effective coupling
parameters for resonant interband excitation processes analytically, employing
degenerate perturbation theory in Floquet space. We find that below a threshold
driving strength, interband excitations are suppressed exponentially with
respect to the inverse driving frequency. For sufficiently low frequencies,
this leads to a rather sudden onset of interband heating, once the driving
strength reaches the threshold. We argue that this behavior is rather generic
and should also be found in lattice systems that are driven by other forms of
periodic forcing. Our results are relevant for Floquet engineering, where a
lattice system is driven periodically in time in order to endow it with novel
properties like the emergence of a strong artificial magnetic field or a
topological band structure. In this context, interband excitation processes
correspond to detrimental heating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01499</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kharkov</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sushkov</keyname><forenames>Oleg P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The amplitudes and the structure of the charge density wave in YBCO</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Final version accepted to Scientific Reports</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find unknown $s$- and $d$-wave amplitudes of the recently discovered
charge density wave (CDW) in underdoped cuprates. To do so we perform a
combined analysis of experimental data for ortho-II YBa$_2$Cu$_3$O$_{y}$. The
analysis includes data on nuclear magnetic resonance, resonant inelastic X-ray
scattering, and hard X-ray diffraction. The amplitude of doping modulation
found in our analysis is $3.5\cdot 10^{-3}$ in a low magnetic field and
$T=60$K, the amplitude is $6.5\cdot 10^{-3}$ in a magnetic field of 30T and
$T=1.3$K. The values are in units of elementary charge per unit cell of a
CuO$_2$ plane. We show that the data rule out a checkerboard pattern, and we
also show that the data might rule out mechanisms of the CDW which do not
include phonons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01719</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01719</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Remko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roest</keyname><forenames>Diederik</forenames></author></authors><title>Exorcising the Ostrogradsky ghost in coupled systems</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages. v3: minor changes, matches version published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP07 (2016) 130</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Ostrogradsky theorem implies that higher-derivative terms of a single
mechanical variable are either trivial or lead to additional, ghost-like
degrees of freedom. In this letter we systematically investigate how the
introduction of additional variables can remedy this situation. Employing a
Lagrangian analysis, we identify conditions on the Lagrangian to ensure the
existence of primary and secondary constraints that together imply the absence
of Ostrogradsky ghosts. We also show the implications of these conditions for
the structure of the equations of motion as well as possible redefinitions of
the variables. We discuss applications to analogous higher-derivative field
theories such as multi-Galileons and beyond Horndeski.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05646</id><created>2016-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Barkley</keyname><forenames>Solomon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarfe</keyname><forenames>Samantha J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weeks</keyname><forenames>Eric R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalnoki-Veress</keyname><forenames>Kari</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting the size of droplets produced through Laplace pressure
  induced snap-off</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 7398 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM00853D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Laplace pressure driven snap-off is a technique that is used to produce
droplets for emulsions and microfluidics purposes. Previous predictions of
droplet size have assumed a quasi-equilibrium low flow limit. We present a
simple model to predict droplet sizes over a wide range of flow rates,
demonstrating a rich landscape of droplet stability depending on droplet size
and growth rate. The model accounts for the easily adjusted experimental
parameters of geometry, interfacial tension, and the viscosities of both
phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06093</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Jonathan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shappee</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holoien</keyname><forenames>T. W. -S</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanek</keyname><forenames>K. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kochanek</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prieto</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hello Darkness My Old Friend: The Fading of the Nearby TDE ASASSN-14ae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, published in MNRAS. For a brief video see
  https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lE_22inwynM</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1928</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present late-time optical spectroscopy taken with the Large Binocular
Telescope's Multi-Object Double Spectrograph, an improved ASAS-SN pre-discovery
non-detection, and late-time SWIFT observations of the nearby ($d=193$ Mpc,
$z=0.0436$) tidal disruption event (TDE) ASASSN-14ae. Our observations span
from $\sim$20 days before to $\sim$750 days after discovery. The proximity of
ASASSN-14ae allows us to study the optical evolution of the flare and the
transition to a host dominated state with exceptionally high precision. We
measure very weak H$\alpha$ emission 300 days after discovery ($L_{\rm H\alpha}
\simeq 4\times 10^{39}$ ergs s$^{-1}$) and the most stringent upper limit to
date on the H$\alpha$ luminosity $\sim$750 days after discovery ($L_{\rm
H\alpha} \lesssim 10^{39}$ ergs s$^{-1}$), suggesting that the optical emission
arising from a TDE can vanish on a timescale as short as 1 year. Our results
have important implications for both spectroscopic detection of TDE candidates
at late times, as well as the nature of TDE host galaxies themselves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07165</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gravert</keyname><forenames>Lars B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nase</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stolze</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uhrig</keyname><forenames>G&#xf6;tz S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Increased coherence time in narrowed bath states in quantum dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 094416 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the influence of narrowed distributions of the nuclear Overhauser
field on the decoherence of a central electron spin in quantum dots. We
describe the spin dynamics in quantum dots by the central spin model. We use
analytic solutions for uniform couplings and the time dependent density-matrix
renormalization group (tDMRG) for nonuniform couplings. With these tools we
calculate the dynamics of the central spin for large baths of nuclear spins
with or without external magnetic field applied to the central spin. The focus
of our study is the influence of initial mixtures with narrowed distributions
of the Overhauser field and of applied magnetic fields on the decoherence of
the central spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03743</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sohbi</keyname><forenames>Adel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaquine</keyname><forenames>Isabelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diamanti</keyname><forenames>Eleni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markham</keyname><forenames>Damian</forenames></author></authors><title>Logical and inequality based contextuality for qudits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present a generalization of the recently developed Hardy-like
logical proof of contextuality and of the so-called KCBS contextuality
inequality for any qudit of dimension greater than three. Our approach uses
compatibility graphs that can only be satisfied by qudits. We find a
construction for states and measurements that satisfy these graphs and
demonstrate both logical and inequality based contextuality for qudits.
Interestingly, the quantum violation of the inequality is constant as dimension
increases. We also discuss the issue of imprecision in experimental
implementations of contextuality tests and a way of addressing this problem
using the notion of ontological faithfulness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03990</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-08-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoang</keyname><forenames>Thai M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Jonghoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bang</keyname><forenames>Jaehoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robicheaux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Zhang-Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tongcang</forenames></author></authors><title>Torsional optomechanics of a levitated nonspherical nanoparticle</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 123604 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.123604</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An optically levitated nanoparticle in vacuum is a paradigm optomechanical
system for sensing and studying macroscopic quantum mechanics. While its
center-of-mass motion has been investigated intensively, its torsional
vibration has only been studied theoretically in limited cases. Here we report
the first experimental observation of the torsional vibration of an optically
levitated nonspherical nanoparticle in vacuum. We achieve this by utilizing the
coupling between the spin angular momentum of photons and the torsional
vibration of a nonspherical nanoparticle whose polarizability is a tensor. The
torsional vibration frequency can be one order of magnitude higher than its
center-of-mass motion frequency, which is promising for ground state cooling.
We propose a simple yet novel scheme to achieve ground state cooling of its
torsional vibration with a linearly-polarized Gaussian cavity mode. A levitated
nonspherical nanoparticle in vacuum will also be an ultrasensitive nanoscale
torsion balance with a torque detection sensitivity on the order of $10^{-29}
~\mathrm{N}\cdot \mathrm{m}/\sqrt{\mathrm{ Hz}}$ under realistic conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07539</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goyal</keyname><forenames>Sandeep K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanders</keyname><forenames>Barry C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Creating cat states in one-dimensional quantum walks using delocalized
  initial states</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 093025 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/9/093025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cat states are coherent quantum superpositions of macroscopically distinct
states and are useful for understanding the boundary between the classical and
the quantum world. Due to their macroscopic nature, cat states are difficult to
prepare in physical systems. We propose a method to create cat states in
one-dimensional quantum walks using delocalized initial states of the walker.
Since the quantum walks can be performed on any quantum system, our proposal
enables a platform-independent realization of the cat states. We further show
that the linear dispersion relation of the effective quantum walk Hamiltonian,
which governs the dynamics of the delocalized states, is responsible for the
formation of the cat states. We analyze the robustness of these states against
environmental interactions and present methods to control and manipulate the
cat states in the photonic implementation of quantum walks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00773</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lado</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melle-Franco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez-Rossier</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Engineering spin exchange in non-bipartite graphene zigzag edges</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 094414 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rules that govern spin exchange interaction in pristine graphene
nanostructures are constrained by the bipartite character of the lattice, so
that the sign of the exchange is determined by whether magnetic moments are on
the same sublattice or else. The synthesis of graphene ribbons with perfect
zigzag edges and a fluoranthene group with a pentagon ring, a defect that
breaks the bipartite nature of the honeycomb lattice, has been recently
demonstrated. Here we address how the electronic and spin properties of these
structures are modified by such defects, both for indirect exchange
interactions as well as the emergent edge magnetism, studied both with DFT and
mean field Hubbard model calculations. In all instances we find that the local
breakdown of the bipartite nature at the defect reverts the sign of the
otherwise ferromagnetic correlations along the edge, introducing a locally
antiferromagnetic intra-edge coupling and, for narrow ribbons, also revert the
antiferromagnetic inter-edge interactions that are normally found in pristine
ribbons. Our findings show that these pentagon defects are a resource that
permits to engineer the spin exchange interactions in graphene based
nano-structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02266</id><created>2016-06-07</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS</keyname></author><author><keyname>Collaborations</keyname><forenames>CMS</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements of the Higgs boson production and decay rates and
  constraints on its couplings from a combined ATLAS and CMS analysis of the
  LHC $pp$ collision data at $\sqrt{s}=$ 7 and 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>70 pages plus author lists + cover page (104 pages total), 32
  figures, 22 tables, submitted to JHEP. All figures including auxiliary
  figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/HIGG-2015-07/ and at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/HIG-15-002/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-100</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP08(2016)045</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combined ATLAS and CMS measurements of the Higgs boson production and decay
rates, as well as constraints on its couplings to vector bosons and fermions,
are presented. The combination is based on the analysis of five production
processes, namely gluon fusion, vector boson fusion, and associated production
with a $W$ or a $Z$ boson or a pair of top quarks, and of the six decay modes
$H \to ZZ, WW$, $\gamma\gamma, \tau\tau, bb$, and $\mu\mu$. All results are
reported assuming a value of 125.09 GeV for the Higgs boson mass, the result of
the combined measurement by the ATLAS and CMS experiments. The analysis uses
the CERN LHC proton--proton collision data recorded by the ATLAS and CMS
experiments in 2011 and 2012, corresponding to integrated luminosities per
experiment of approximately 5 fb$^{-1}$ at $\sqrt{s}=7$ TeV and 20 fb$^{-1}$ at
$\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV. The Higgs boson production and decay rates measured by the
two experiments are combined within the context of three generic
parameterisations: two based on cross sections and branching fractions, and one
on ratios of coupling modifiers. Several interpretations of the measurements
with more model-dependent parameterisations are also given. The combined signal
yield relative to the Standard Model prediction is measured to be 1.09 $\pm$
0.11. The combined measurements lead to observed significances for the vector
boson fusion production process and for the $H \to \tau\tau$ decay of $5.4$ and
$5.5$ standard deviations, respectively. The data are consistent with the
Standard Model predictions for all parameterisations considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03038</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lado</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez-Rossier</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau Levels in 2D materials using Wannier Hamiltonians obtained by
  first principles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials. 3 035023 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/3/3/035023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a method to calculate the Landau levels and the corresponding edge
states of two dimensional (2D) crystals using as a starting point their
electronic structure as obtained from standard density functional theory (DFT).
The DFT Hamiltonian is represented in the basis of maximally localized Wannier
functions. This defines a tight-binding Hamiltonian for the bulk that can be
used to describe other structures, such as ribbons, provided that atomic scale
details of the edges are ignored. The effect of the orbital magnetic field is
described using the Peierls substitution in the hopping matrix elements.
Implementing this approach in a ribbon geometry, we obtain both the Landau
levels and the dispersive edge states for a series of 2D crystals, including
graphene, Boron Nitride, MoS$_2$ , Black Phosphorous, Indium Selenide and
MoO$_3$ . Our procedure can readily be used in any other 2D crystal, and
provides an alternative to effective mass descriptions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03241</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2016-08-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monthus</keyname><forenames>Cecile</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization transition in random Levy matrices : multifractality of
  eigenvectors in the localized phase and at criticality</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>v2=revised version (15 pages)</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 093304</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/09/093304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For random L\'evy matrices of size $N \times N$, where matrix elements are
drawn with some heavy-tailed distribution $P(H_{ij}) \propto N^{-1} |H_{ij}
|^{-1-\mu}$ with $0&lt;\mu&lt;2$ (infinite variance), there exists an extensive
number of finite eigenvalues $E=O(1)$, while the maximal eigenvalue grows as
$E_{max} \sim N^{\frac{1}{\mu}}$. Here we study the localization properties of
the corresponding eigenvectors via some strong disorder perturbative expansion
that remains consistent within the localized phase and that yields their
Inverse Participation Ratios (I.P.R.) $Y_q$ as a function of the continuous
parameter $0&lt;q&lt;+\infty$. In the region $0&lt;\mu&lt;1$, we find that all eigenvectors
are localized but display some multifractality : the IPR are finite above some
threshold $q&gt;q_c$ but diverge in the region $0&lt;q&lt;q_c$ near the origin. In the
region $1&lt;\mu&lt;2$, only the sub-extensive fraction $N^{\frac{3}{2+\mu}}$ of the
biggest eigenvalues corresponding to the region $| E| \geq
N^{\frac{(\mu-1)}{\mu(2+\mu)}} $ remains localized, while the extensive number
of other states of smaller energy are delocalized. For the extensive number of
finite eigenvalues $E=O(1)$, the localization/delocalization transition thus
takes place at the critical value $\mu_c=1$ corresponding to Cauchy matrices :
the Inverse Participation Ratios $Y_q$ of the corresponding critical
eigenstates follow the Strong-Multifractality Spectrum characterized by the
generalized fractal dimensions $D^{criti}(q) = \frac{1-2q}{1-q} \theta (0 \leq
q \leq \frac{1}{2})$, which has been found previously in various other
Localization problems in spaces of effective infinite dimensionality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03980</id><created>2016-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Benchamekh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Reilly</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical analysis of influence of random alloy fluctuations on the
  opto-electronic properties of site-controlled (111)-oriented InGaAs/GaAs
  quantum dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use an $sp^3d^5s^* $ tight-binding model to investigate the electronic and
optical properties of realistic site-controlled (111)-oriented InGaAs/GaAs
quantum dots. Special attention is paid to the impact of random alloy
fluctuations on key factors that determine the fine-structure splitting in
these systems. Using a pure InAs/GaAs quantum dot as a reference system, we
show that the combination of spin-orbit coupling and biaxial strain effects can
lead to sizeable spin-splitting effects in these systems. Then, a realistic
alloyed InGaAs/GaAs quantum dot with 25\% InAs content is studied. Our analysis
reveals that the impact of random alloy fluctuations on the electronic and
optical properties of (111)-oriented InGaAs/GaAs quantum dots reduces strongly
as the lateral size of the dot increases and approaches realistic sizes. For
instance the optical matrix element shows an almost vanishing anisotropy in the
(111)-growth plane. Furthermore, conduction and valence band mixing effects in
the system under consideration are strongly reduced compared to standard
(100)-oriented InGaAs/GaAs systems. All these factors strongly indicate a
reduced fine structure splitting in site-controlled (111)-oriented InGaAs/GaAs
quantum dots. Thus, we conclude that quantum dots with realistic (50-80~nm)
base length represent promising candidates for polarization entangled photon
generation, consistent with recent experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07123</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smolyanitsky</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakobson</keyname><forenames>B. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wassenaar</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paulechka</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kroenlein</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A MoS2-based capacitive displacement sensor for DNA sequencing</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>28 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b05274</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an aqueous functionalized molybdenum disulfide nanoribbon
suspended over a solid electrode as the first capacitive displacement sensor
aimed at determining the DNA sequence. The detectable sequencing events arise
from the combination of Watson-Crick base-pairing, one of nature's most basic
lock-and-key-binding mechanisms, with the ability of appropriately sized
atomically thin membranes to flex substantially in response to sub-nanonewton
forces. We employ carefully designed numerical simulations and theoretical
estimates to demonstrate excellent (79 % to 86 %) raw target detection accuracy
at ~70 million bases per second and electrical measurability of the detected
events. In addition, we demonstrate reliable detection of repeated DNA motifs.
Finally, we argue that the use of a nanoscale opening (nanopore) is not
requisite for the operation of the proposed sensor and present a simplified
sensor geometry without the nanopore as part of the sensing element. Our
results therefore potentially suggest a realistic, inherently base-specific,
high-throughput electronic DNA sequencing device as a cost-effective de-novo
alternative to the existing methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08296</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nugier</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author></authors><title>From GLC to double-null coordinates and illustration with static black
  holes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>30 pages, 3 figures. Comments and references added. Paper published
  in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP09(2016)019</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/09/019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a system of coordinates deriving directly from the so-called
Geodesic Light-Cone (GLC) coordinates and made of two null scalars intersecting
on a 2-dimensional sphere parameterized by two constant angles along geodesics.
These coordinates are shown to be equivalent to the well-known double-null
coordinates. As GLC, they present interesting properties for cosmology and
astrophysics. We discuss this latter topic for static black holes, showing
simple descriptions for the metric or particles and photons trajectories. We
also briefly comment on the time of flight of ultra-relativistic particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09245</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kallosh</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vercnocke</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrase</keyname><forenames>Timm</forenames></author></authors><title>String Theory Origin of Constrained Multiplets</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages, v2: published version, 1 reference added</comments><report-no>TUW-16-11</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1609:063, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the non-linearly realized spontaneously broken supersymmetry of the
(anti-)D3-brane action in type IIB string theory. The worldvolume fields are
one vector $A_\mu$, three complex scalars $\phi^i$ and four 4d fermions
$\lambda^0$, $\lambda^i$. These transform, in addition to the more familiar N=4
linear supersymmetry, also under 16 spontaneously broken, non-linearly realized
supersymmetries. We argue that the worldvolume fields can be packaged into the
following constrained 4d non-linear N=1 multiplets: four chiral multiplets $S$,
$Y^i$ that satisfy $S^2=SY^i=0$ and contain the worldvolume fermions
$\lambda^0$ and $\lambda^i$; and four chiral multiplets $W_\alpha$, $H^i$ that
satisfy $S W_\alpha=0$ and $S \bar D_{\dot \alpha} \bar H^{\bar \imath}=0$ and
contain the vector $A_\mu$ and the scalars $\phi^i$. We also discuss how
placing an anti-D3-brane on top of intersecting O7-planes can lead to an
orthogonal multiplet $\Phi$ that satisfies $S(\Phi-\bar \Phi)=0$, which is
particularly interesting for inflationary cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01467</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miyaji</keyname><forenames>Masamichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Butterflies from Information Metric</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, reference added, minor modifications</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2016) 002</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study time evolution of distance between thermal states excited by local
operators, with different external couplings. We find that growth of the
distance implies growth of commutators of operators, signifying the local
excitations are scrambled. We confirm this growth of distance by holographic
computation, by evaluating volume of codimension 1 extremal volume surface. We
find that the distance increases exponentially as $e^{\frac{2\pi t}{\beta}}$.
Our result implies that, in chaotic system, trajectories of excited thermal
states exhibit high sensitivity to perturbation to the Hamiltonian, and the
distance between them will be significant at the scrambling time. We also
confirm the decay of two point function of holographic Wilson loops on
thermofield double state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02271</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Foyart</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ligoure</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>Serge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>Laurence</forenames></author></authors><title>Rearrangement zone around a crack tip in a double self-assembled
  transient network</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Macro Letters 2016, 5, 1080-1083</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsmacrolett.6b00516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nucleation and propagation of cracks in self-assembled
viscoelastic fluids, which are made of surfactant micelles reversibly linked by
telechelic polymers. The morphology of the micelles can be continuously tuned,
from spherical to rod-like to wormlike, thus producing transient double
networks when the micelles are sufficiently long and entangled, and transient
single networks otherwise. For a single network, we show that cracks nucleate
when the sample deformation rate involved is comparable to the relaxation time
scale of the network. For a double network, by contrast, significant
rearrangements of the micelles occur as a crack nucleates and propagates. We
show that birefringence develops at the crack tip over a finite length, $\xi$,
which corresponds to the length scale over which micelles alignment occur. We
find that $\xi$ is larger for slower cracks, suggesting an increase of
ductility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02626</id><created>2016-07-09</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Sun-Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>Rosa</forenames></author></authors><title>A hybrid superconducting quantum dot acting as an efficient charge and
  spin Seebeck diode</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 093024 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/9/093024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a highly efficient thermoelectric diode device built from the
coupling of a quantum dot with a normal or ferromagnetic electrode and a
superconducting reservoir. The current shows a strongly nonlinear behavior in
the forward direction (positive thermal gradients) while it almost vanishes in
the backward direction (negative thermal gradients). Our discussion is
supported by a gauge-invariant current-conserving transport theory accounting
for electron-electron interactions inside the dot. We find that the diode
behavior is greatly tuned with external gate potentials, Zeeman splittings or
lead magnetizations. Our results are thus relevant for the search of novel
thermoelectric devices with enhanced functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04838</id><created>2016-07-17</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komura</keyname><forenames>Shigeyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andelman</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Budding Transition of Asymmetric Two-component Lipid Domains</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032406 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a model that accounts for the budding transition of asymmetric
two-component lipid domains, where the two monolayers (leaflets) have different
average compositions controlled by independent chemical potentials. Assuming a
coupling between the local curvature and local lipid composition in each of the
leaflets, we discuss the morphology and thermodynamic behavior of asymmetric
lipid domains. The membrane free-energy contains three contributions: the
bending energy, the line tension, and a Landau free-energy for a lateral phase
separation. Within a mean-field treatment, we obtain various phase diagrams
containing fully budded, dimpled, and flat states as a function of the two
leaflet compositions. The global phase behavior is analyzed, and depending on
system parameters, the phase diagrams include one-phase, two-phase and
three-phase regions. In particular, we predict various phase coexistence
regions between different morphologies of domains, which may be observed in
multi-component membranes or vesicles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05118</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Limyansky</keyname><forenames>Brent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reese</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cressler</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otte</keyname><forenames>Adam Nepomuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taboada</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulusoy</keyname><forenames>Cagri</forenames></author></authors><title>FIPSER: Performance Study of a Readout Concept With Few Digitization
  Levels for Fast Signals</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>23 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Inst. and Methods in Physics Research, A (2016), pp.
  143-152</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.09.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the performance of a readout system, Fixed Pulse Shape Efficient
Readout (FIPSER), to digitize signals from detectors with a fixed pulse shape.
In this study we are mainly interested in the readout of fast photon detectors
like photomultipliers or Silicon photomultipliers. But the concept can be
equally applied to the digitization of other detector signals. FIPSER is based
on the flash analog to digital converter (FADC) concept, but has the potential
to lower costs and power consumption by using an order of magnitude fewer
discrete voltage levels. Performance is bolstered by combining the discretized
signal with the knowledge of the underlying pulse shape. Simulated FIPSER data
was reconstructed with two independent methods. One using a maximum likelihood
method and the other using a modified chisquared test. Both methods show that
utilizing 12 discrete voltage levels with a sampling rate of 4 samples per full
width half maximum (FWHM) of the pulse achieves an amplitude resolution that is
better than the Poisson limit for photon-counting experiments. The time
resolution achieved in this configuration ranges between 0.02 - 0.16 FWHM and
depends on the pulse amplitude. In a situation where the waveform is composed
of two consecutive pulses the pulses can be separated if they are at least 0.05
- 0.30 FWHM apart with an amplitude resolution that is better than 20%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06323</id><created>2016-08-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Cui-Zu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chaoxing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moodera</keyname><forenames>Jagadeesh. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Moses H. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of the quantum-anomalous-Hall insulator to Anderson
  insulator quantum phase transition and its scaling behavior</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures. Accepted by PRL. Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>PRL 117, 126802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.126802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fundamental insight into the nature of the quantum phase transition from a
superconductor to an insulator in two dimensions, or from one plateau to the
next or to an insulator in quantum Hall effect, has been revealed through the
study of its scaling behavior. Here, we report on the experimental observation
of a quantum phase transition from a quantum-anomalous-Hall (QAH) insulator to
an Anderson insulator in a magnetic topological insulator by tuning the
chemical potential. Our experiment demonstrates the existence of scaling
behavior from which we extract the critical exponent for this quantum phase
transition. We expect that our work will motivate much further investigation of
many properties of quantum phase transition in this new context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06430</id><created>2016-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruhl</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nther</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batke</keyname><forenames>Joerg-Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemme</keyname><forenames>Max C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-organized Growth of Graphene Nanomesh with Increased Gas
  Sensitivity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanoscale, 8: 15490, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6nr03954e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A bottom-up chemical vapor deposition (CVD) process for the growth of
graphene nanomesh films is demonstrated. The process relies on silicon
nanospheres to block nucleation sites for graphene CVD on copper substrates.
These spheres are formed in a self-organized way through silicon diffusion
through a 5 $\mu$m copper layer on a silicon wafer coated with 400 nm of
silicon nitride. The temperature during the growth process disintegrates the
$Si_3$$N_4$ layer and silicon atoms diffuse to the copper surface, where they
form the nanospheres. After graphene nanomesh growth, the Si nanospheres can be
removed by a simple hydrofluoric acid etch, leaving holes in the graphene film.
The nanomesh films have been successfully transferred to different substrates,
including gas sensor test structures, and verified and characterized by Auger,
TEM and SEM measurements. Electrical/gas-exposure measurements show a 2-fold
increase in ammonia sensitivity compared to plain graphene sensors. This
improvement can be explained by a higher adsorption site density (edge sites).
This new method for nanopatterned graphene is scalable, inexpensive and can be
carried out in standard semiconductor industry equipment. Furthermore, the
substrates are reusable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07151</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Lagomarsino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monticone</keyname><forenames>D. Gatto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciortino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sytchkova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sordini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex refractive index variation in proton-damaged diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1608.07122</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 20 (17), 19382-19394 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.20.019382</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An accurate control of the optical properties of single crystal diamond
during microfabrication processes such as ion implantation plays a crucial role
in the engineering of integrated photonic devices. In this work we present a
systematic study of the variation of both real and imaginary parts of the
refractive index of single crystal diamond, when damaged with 2 and 3 MeV
protons at low-medium fluences (range: 10^15 - 10^17 cm^-2). After implanting
in 125x125 um^2 areas with a scanning ion microbeam, the variation of optical
pathlength of the implanted regions was measured with laser interferometric
microscopy, while their optical transmission was studied using a spectrometric
set-up with micrometric spatial resolution. On the basis of a model taking into
account the strongly non-uniform damage profile in the bulk sample, the
variation of the complex refractive index as a function of damage density was
evaluated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07718</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07718</id><created>2016-08-27</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohya</keyname><forenames>Shinobu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muneta</keyname><forenames>Iriya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>Yukiharu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Yoshihisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krempasky</keyname><forenames>Juraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitt</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshima</keyname><forenames>Masaharu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strocov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Masaaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujimori</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author></authors><title>Alternative interpretation of the recent experimental results of
  angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy on GaMnAs [Sci. Rep. 6, 27266
  (2016)]</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Clarification of the position of the Fermi level ($E_\mathrm{F}$) is
important in understanding the origin of ferromagnetism in the prototypical
ferromagnetic semiconductor Ga$_{1-x}$Mn$_x$As (GaMnAs). In a recent
publication, Souma $et$ $al$. [Sci. Rep. $\mathbf{6}$, 27266 (2016)], have
investigated the band structure and the $E_\mathrm{F}$ position of GaMnAs using
angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES), and concluded that
$E_\mathrm{F}$ is located in the valence band (VB). However, this conclusion
contradicts a number of recent experimental results for GaMnAs, which showed
that $E_\mathrm{F}$ is located above the VB maximum in the impurity band (IB).
Here, we show an alternative interpretation of their ARPES experiments, which
is consistent with those recent experiments and supports the picture that
$E_\mathrm{F}$ is located above the VB maximum in the IB.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07928</id><created>2016-08-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Vinod</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhoraniya</keyname><forenames>Ramesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Global stability analysis of axisymmetric boundary layers</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1608.07695</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents the linear global stability analysis of the
incompressible axisymmetric boundary layer on a circular cylinder. The base
flow is parallel to the axis of the cylinder at inlet. The pressure gradient is
zero in the streamwise direction. The base flow velocity profile is fully
non-parallel and non-similar in nature. The boundary layer grows continuously
in the spatial directions. Linearized Navier-Stokes(LNS) equations are derived
for the disturbance flow quantities in the cylindrical polar coordinates. The
LNS equations along with homogeneous boundary conditions forms a generalized
eigenvalues problem. Since the base flow is axisymmetric, the disturbances are
periodic in azimuthal direction. Chebyshev spectral collocation method and
Arnoldi's iterative algorithm is used for the solution of the general
eigenvalues problem. The global temporal modes are computed for the range of
Reynolds numbers and different azimuthal wave numbers. The largest imaginary
part of the computed eigenmodes are negative and hence the flow is temporally
stable. The spatial structure of the eigenmodes shows that the flow is
convectively unstable because the disturbance amplitudes grow in size and
magnitude when moving towards downstream. The global modes of axisymmetric
boundary layer are more stable than that of 2D flat plate boundary layer at low
Reynolds number. However, at high Reynolds number they approaches to 2D flat
plate boundary layer. Thus, the damping effect of transverse curvature is
significant at low Reynolds number. The wave-like nature of the disturbances is
found for most unstable eigenmodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00508</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00508</id><created>2016-09-02</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vita-Finzi</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>The solar chromosphere as induction disk and the inverse Joule-Thomson
  effect</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages and 2 double figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The connection between nuclear fusion in the Sun's core and solar irradiance
is obscured among other things by uncertainty over the mechanism of coronal
heating. Data for solar wind density and velocity, sunspot number, and EUV flux
suggest that electromagnetic energy from the Sun's convection zone is converted
by induction through the chromosphere into thermal energy. The helium and
hydrogen mixture exhaled by the Sun is then heated by the inverse Joule-Thomson
effect when it expands via the corona into space. The almost complete shutdown
of the solar wind on 10-11 May 1999 demonstrated that its velocity is a more
faithful indicator of solar activity than are sunspots as it reflects
short-term variations in coronal heating rather than quasicyclical fluctuations
in the Sun's magnetism. Its reconstruction from the cosmic ray flux using
isotopes spanning over 800,000 yr should therefore benefit the analysis and
long-term forecasting of Earth and space weather.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00795</id><created>2016-09-03</created><updated>2016-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bardales</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Qinggele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Bingzhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tao</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinig</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubby</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author></authors><title>Creation of a tight PSF array for scanning structured illumination via
  phase retrieval</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.med-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we propose a structured illumination (SI) method based on a
two-photon excitation (TPE) scanning laser beam. Advantages of TPE methods
include optical sectioning, low photo-toxicity, and robustness in the face of
sample induced scattering. We designed a novel multi-spot point spread function
(PSF) for a fast, two-photon scanning SIM microscope. Our multi-spot PSF is
generated with a phase retrieval algorithm. We show how to obtain the phase
distribution and then simulate the effect of this distribution on a spatial
light modulator (SLM), which produces the multi-spot PSF in the object plane of
the microscope. We produce simulations that show the viability of this method.
The results are simulated and a multi-spot PSF scanning SIM microscope is
proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02190</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-09-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cummings</keyname><forenames>Evan M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the cryosphere with FEniCS</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>172 pages, 75 figures, 6 algorithms</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This manuscript is a collection of problems and solutions related to modeling
the cryosphere using the finite element software FEniCS. Included is an
introduction to the finite element method; solutions to a variety of problems
in one, two, and three dimensions; an overview of popular stabilization
techniques for numerically-unstable problems; and an introduction to the
governing equations of ice-sheet dynamics with associated FEniCS
implementations. The software developed for this project, Cryospheric Problem
Solver (CSLVR), is fully open-source and has been designed with the goal of
simplifying many common tasks associated with modeling the cryosphere. CSLVR
possesses the ability to download popular geological and geographical data,
easily convert between geographical projections, develop sophisticated two- or
three-dimensional finite-element meshes, convert data between many popular
formats, and produce production-quality images of data. Scripts are presented
which model the flow of ice using geometry defined by mathematical functions
and observed Antarctic and Greenland ice-sheets data. A new way of solving the
internal energy distribution of ice to match observed intra-ice water contents
within temperate regions is thoroughly explained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02604</id><created>2016-09-08</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fiziev</keyname><forenames>Plamen P</forenames></author></authors><title>On gravitational waves from classical three body problem</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Latex file, 12 figures, English corrected, short comments added in
  the text and in the abstract</comments><report-no>SU-08/09/2016</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using an effective one body approach we describe in detail gravitational
waves from classical three body problem on a non-rotating straight line and
derive their basic physical characteristics. Special attention is paid to the
irregular motions of such systems and to the significance of double and triple
collisions. The conclusive role of the collinear solutions is also discussed in
short. It is shown that the residuals may contain information about irregular
motion of the source of gravitational waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03120</id><created>2016-09-11</created><updated>2016-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burkhardt</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dewitt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hlavacek</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Steven J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sprunger</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vu</keyname><forenames>Yen Nhi Truong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Peski</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Matrix Ensembles with Split Limiting Behavior</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>Version 1.1, 31 pages, 3 figures, one appendix joint with Manuel
  Fernandez and Nicholas Sieger</comments><msc-class>15B52 (primary), 15B57, 15B33 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new family of $N\times N$ random real symmetric matrix
ensembles, the $k$-checkerboard matrices, whose limiting spectral measure has
two components which can be determined explicitly. All but $k$ eigenvalues are
in the bulk, and their behavior, appropriately normalized, converges to the
semi-circle as $N\to\infty$; the remaining $k$ are tightly constrained near
$N/k$ and their distribution converges to the $k \times k$ hollow GOE ensemble
(this is the density arising by modifying the GOE ensemble by forcing all
entries on the main diagonal to be zero). Similar results hold for complex and
quaternionic analogues. We isolate the two regimes by using matrix perturbation
results and a nonstandard weight function for the eigenvalues, then derive
their limiting distributions using a modification of the method of moments and
analysis of the resulting combinatorics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04059</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Buryak</keyname><forenames>Alexandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubrovin</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;r&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;my</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable systems of double ramification type</title><categories>math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>46 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study various aspects of the double ramification (DR)
hierarchy, introduced by the first author, and its quantization. We extend the
notion of tau-symmetry to quantum integrable hierarchies and prove that the
quantum DR hierarchy enjoys this property. We determine explicitly the genus
$1$ quantum correction and, as an application, compute completely the
quantization of the $3$- and $4$-KdV hierarchies (the DR hierarchies for
Witten's $3$- and $4$-spin theories). We then focus on the recursion relation
satisfied by the DR Hamiltonian densities and, abstracting from its geometric
origin, we use it to characterize and construct a new family of quantum and
classical integrable systems which we call of double ramification type, as they
satisfy all of the main properties of the DR hierarchy. In the second part, we
obtain new insight towards the Miura equivalence conjecture between the DR and
Dubrovin-Zhang hierarchies, via a geometric interpretation of the correlators
forming the double ramification tau-function. We then show that the candidate
Miura transformation between the DR and DZ hierarchies (which we uniquely
identified in our previous paper) indeed turns the Dubrovin-Zhang Poisson
structure into the standard form. Eventually, we focus on integrable
hierarchies associated with rank-$1$ cohomological field theories and their
deformations, and we prove the DR/DZ equivalence conjecture up to genus $5$ in
this context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04168</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghodrati</keyname><forenames>Mahdis</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond AdS Space-times, New Holographic Correspondences and Applications</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>143 pages; PhD thesis based on arXiv:1404.5399, arXiv:1506.08557,
  arXiv:1601.04403, arXiv:1606.04353; Defended on July. 6th, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To describe Lifshitz and hyperscaling violating (HSV) phenomena in CM one
uses gauge fields on the gravity side which naturally realize the breaking of
Lorentz invariance. These gravity constructions often contain naked
singularities. In this thesis, we construct a resolution of the infra-red (IR)
singularity of the HSV background. The idea is to add squared curvature terms
to the Einstein-Maxwell dilaton action to build a flow from $\text{AdS}_4$ in
the ultra violate (UV) to an intermediating HSV region and then to an
$\text{AdS}_2 \times {\text{R}}^2$ region in the IR. This general solution is
free from the naked singularities and would be more appropriate for
applications of HSV in physical systems.
  We also study the Schwinger effect by using the AdS/CFT duality. We present
the phase diagrams of the Schwinger effect and also the &quot;butterfly shaped-phase
diagrams&quot; of the entanglement entropy for four different confining supergravity
backgrounds. Comparing different features of all of these diagrams could point
out to a potential relation between the Schwinger effect and the entanglement
entropy which could lead to a method of measuring entanglement entropy in the
laboratory.
  Finally, we study the &quot;new massive gravity&quot; theory and the different black
hole solutions it admits. We first present three different methods of
calculating the conserved charges. Then, by calculating the on-shell Gibbs free
energy we construct the Hawking-Page phase diagrams for different solutions in
two thermodynamical ensembles. As the massive gravity models are dual to
dissipating systems, studying the Hawking-Page diagrams could point out to
interesting results for the confinement-deconfinement phase transitions of the
dual boundary theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04410</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bechter</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crass</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketterer</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crepp</keyname><forenames>Justin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Robert O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bechter</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinz</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedichini</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foley</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Runburg</keyname><forenames>Elliott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onuma</keyname><forenames>Eleanya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaudi</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micela</keyname><forenames>Giuseppina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>Isabella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodward</keyname><forenames>Charles E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On-sky single-mode fiber coupling measurements at the Large Binocular
  Telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9909, Adaptive Optics Systems V, 99092X (27 July 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2233153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The demonstration of efficient single-mode fiber (SMF) coupling is a key
requirement for the development of a compact, ultra-precise radial velocity
(RV) spectrograph. iLocater is a next generation instrument for the Large
Binocular Telescope (LBT) that uses adaptive optics (AO) to inject starlight
into a SMF. In preparation for commissioning iLocater, a prototype SMF
injection system was installed and tested at the LBT in the Y-band (0.970-1.065
$\mu$m). This system was designed to verify the capability of the LBT AO system
as well as characterize on-sky SMF coupling efficiencies. SMF coupling was
measured on stars with variable airmasses, apparent magnitudes, and seeing
conditions for six half-nights using the Large Binocular Telescope
Interferometer. We present the overall optical and mechanical performance of
the SMF injection system, including details of the installation and alignment
procedure. A particular emphasis is placed on analyzing the instrument's
performance as a function of telescope elevation to inform the final design of
the fiber injection system for iLocater.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04411</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04411</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Crass</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fantano</keyname><forenames>Louis G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hearty</keyname><forenames>Frederick R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crepp</keyname><forenames>Justin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wall</keyname><forenames>Sheila M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalieri</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koca</keyname><forenames>Corina</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>David L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Robert O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stapelfeldt</keyname><forenames>Karl R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The iLocater cryostat: design and thermal control strategy for precision
  radial velocity measurements</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9908, Ground-based and Airborne Instrumentation for
  Astronomy VI, 990873 (9 August 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2233617</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The current generation of precision radial velocity (RV) spectrographs are
seeing-limited instruments. In order to achieve high spectral resolution on 8m
class telescopes, these spectrographs require large optics and in turn, large
instrument volumes. Achieving milli-Kelvin thermal stability for these systems
is challenging but is vital in order to obtain a single measurement RV
precision of better than 1m/s. This precision is crucial to study Earth-like
exoplanets within the habitable zone. iLocater is a next generation RV
instrument being developed for the Large Binocular Telescope. Unlike
seeing-limited RV instruments, iLocater uses adaptive optics (AO) to inject a
diffraction-limited beam into single-mode fibers. These fibers illuminate the
instrument spectrograph, facilitating a diffraction-limited design and a small
instrument volume compared to present-day instruments. This enables intrinsic
instrument stability and facilitates precision thermal control. We present the
current design of the iLocater cryostat which houses the instrument
spectrograph and the strategy for its thermal control. The spectrograph is
situated within a pair of radiation shields mounted inside an MLI lined vacuum
chamber. The outer radiation shield is actively controlled to maintain
instrument stability at the sub-mK level and minimize effects of thermal
changes from the external environment. An inner shield passively dampens any
residual temperature fluctuations and is radiatively coupled to the optical
board. To provide intrinsic stability, the optical board and optic mounts will
be made from Invar and cooled to 58K to benefit from a zero coefficient of
thermal expansion (CTE) value at this temperature. Combined, the small
footprint of the instrument spectrograph, the use of Invar, and precision
thermal control will allow long-term sub-milliKelvin stability to facilitate
precision RV measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04412</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04412</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Crepp</keyname><forenames>Justin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crass</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bechter</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bechter</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketterer</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinz</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopon</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalieri</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fantano</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koca</keyname><forenames>Corina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onuma</keyname><forenames>Eleanya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stapelfeldt</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomes</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wall</keyname><forenames>Sheila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macenka</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korniski</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zugby</keyname><forenames>Leonard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisner</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaudi</keyname><forenames>B. Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hearty</keyname><forenames>Fred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kratter</keyname><forenames>Kaitlin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuchner</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micela</keyname><forenames>Giusi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>Isabella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quirrenbach</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skrutskie</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sozzetti</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodward</keyname><forenames>Charles E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>iLocater: A Diffraction-limited Doppler Spectrometer for the Large
  Binocular Telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9908, Ground-based and Airborne Instrumentation for
  Astronomy VI, 990819 (4 August 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2233135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are developing a stable and precise spectrograph for the Large Binocular
Telescope (LBT) named &quot;iLocater.&quot; The instrument comprises three principal
components: a cross-dispersed echelle spectrograph that operates in the
YJ-bands (0.97-1.30 microns), a fiber-injection acquisition camera system, and
a wavelength calibration unit. iLocater will deliver high spectral resolution
(R~150,000-240,000) measurements that permit novel studies of stellar and
substellar objects in the solar neighborhood including extrasolar planets.
Unlike previous planet-finding instruments, which are seeing-limited, iLocater
operates at the diffraction limit and uses single mode fibers to eliminate the
effects of modal noise entirely. By receiving starlight from two 8.4m diameter
telescopes that each use &quot;extreme&quot; adaptive optics (AO), iLocater shows promise
to overcome the limitations that prevent existing instruments from generating
sub-meter-per-second radial velocity (RV) precision. Although optimized for the
characterization of low-mass planets using the Doppler technique, iLocater will
also advance areas of research that involve crowded fields, line-blanketing,
and weak absorption lines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04418</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04418</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronous Lagrangian variational principles in General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal Plus 130, 123 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2015-15123-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of formulating synchronous variational principles in the context
of General Relativity is discussed. Based on the analogy with classical
relativistic particle dynamics, the existence of variational principles is
pointed out in relativistic classical field theory which are either
asynchronous or synchronous. The historical Einstein-Hilbert and Palatini
variational formulations are found to belong to the first category.
Nevertheless, it is shown that an alternative route exists which permits one to
cast these principles in terms of equivalent synchronous Lagrangian variational
formulations. The advantage is twofold. First, synchronous approaches allow one
to overcome the lack of gauge symmetry of the asynchronous principles. Second,
the property of manifest covariance of the theory is also restored at all
levels, including the symbolic Euler-Lagrange equations, with the variational
Lagrangian density being now identified with a $4-$scalar. As an application, a
joint synchronous variational principle holding both for the non-vacuum
Einstein and Maxwell equations is displayed, with the matter source being
described by means of a Vlasov kinetic treatment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04422</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Manifest Covariant Hamiltonian Theory of General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Applied Physics Research 8, 2 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.5539/apr.v8n2p60</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of formulating a manifest covariant Hamiltonian theory of General
Relativity in the presence of source fields is addressed, by extending the
so-called &quot;DeDonder-Weyl&quot; formalism to the treatment of classical fields in
curved space-time. The theory is based on a synchronous variational principle
for the Einstein equation, formulated in terms of superabundant variables. The
technique permits one to determine the continuum covariant Hamiltonian
structure associated with the Einstein equation. The corresponding continuum
Poisson bracket representation is also determined. The theory relies on
first-principles, in the sense that the conclusions are reached in the
framework of a non-perturbative covariant approach, which allows one to
preserve both the 4-scalar nature of Lagrangian and Hamiltonian densities as
well as the gauge invariance property of the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04423</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>McElroy</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Husemann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croom</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennert</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busch</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckart</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez-Torres</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Powell</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scharwachter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urrutia</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Close AGN Reference Survey (CARS) - Mrk 1018 returns to the shadows
  after 30 years as a Seyfert 1</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Published in A&amp;A</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the discovery that the known `changing look' AGN Mrk 1018 has
changed spectral type for a second time. New VLT-MUSE data taken in 2015 as
part of the Close AGN Reference Survey (CARS) shows that the AGN has returned
to its original Seyfert 1.9 classification. The CARS sample is selected to
contain only bright type 1 AGN, but Mrk 1018's broad emission lines and
continuum, typical of type 1 AGN, have almost entirely disappeared. We use
spectral fitting of the MUSE spectrum and previously available spectra to
determine the drop in broad line flux and the Balmer decrement. We find that
the broad line flux has decreased by a factor of 4.75+/- 0.5 in H{\alpha} since
an SDSS spectrum was taken in 2000. The Balmer decrement has not changed
significantly implying no enhanced reddening with time, but the remaining broad
lines are more asymmetric than those present in the type 1 phase. We posit that
the change is due to an intrinsic drop in flux from the accretion disk rather
than variable extinction or a tidal disruption event.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04425</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Husemann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urrutia</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tremblay</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krumpe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dexter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busch</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croom</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckart</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McElroy</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez-Torres</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Powell</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scharw&#xe4;chter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Close AGN Reference Survey (CARS) - What is causing Mrk1018's return
  to the shadows after 30 years?</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, Published in A&amp;A</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629245</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recently discovered that the active galactic nucleus (AGN) of Mrk 1018 has
changed optical type again after 30 years as a type 1 AGN. Here we combine
Chandra, NuStar, Swift, Hubble Space Telescope and ground-based observations to
explore the cause of this change. The 2-10keV flux declines by a factor of ~8
between 2010 and 2016. We show with our X-ray observation that this is not
caused by varying neutral hydrogen absorption along the line-of-sight up to the
Compton-thick level. The optical-UV spectral energy distributions are well fit
with a standard geometrically thin optically thick accretion disc model that
seems to obey the expected $L\sim T^4$ relation. It confirms that a decline in
accretion disc luminosity is the primary origin for the type change. We detect
a new narrow-line absorber in Lya blue-shifted by ~700km/s with respect to the
systemic velocity of the galaxy. This new Lya absorber could be evidence for
the onset of an outflow or a companion black hole with associated gas that
could be related to the accretion rate change. However, the low column density
of the absorber means that it is not the direct cause for Mrk 1018's
changing-look nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04429</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Shi</forenames></author></authors><title>Extended Harmonic Map Equations and the Chaotic Soliton Solutions</title><categories>nlin.CD nlin.PS</categories><comments>9 pages, no figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the theory of harmonic maps is extended. The soliton or
traveling wave solutions of Euler's equations of the extended harmonic maps are
studied. In certain cases, the chaotic behaviors of these partial equations can
be found for the particular case of the metrics and the potential functions of
the extended harmonic equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04445</id><created>2016-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>Graham P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradley</keyname><forenames>A. Louise</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature Dependent Luminescent Decay Properties of CdTe Quantum Dot
  Monolayers: Impact of Concentration on Carrier Trapping</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the temperature dependence of the photoluminescence
spectra and average photoluminescence decay rate of CdTe quantum dot monolayers
of different sizes as a function of concentration in the range 77 K to 296 K.
It is shown that a simple three level analytic model involving bright and dark
exciton states can only describe the lower temperature data but is unable to
satisfactorily fit the data over the full temperature range. An extended model
which includes external trap states is necessary to fit the data above
approximately 150 K. Parameters for the model are obtained using both temporal
and spectral data. The model indicates that the efficiency of interaction with
trap states increases as the QD monolayer concentration increases, which is
likely due to an increase in the density of available traps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04448</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>Alexey A</forenames></author></authors><title>New Physics from rare decays of charm</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 table, 1 figure. Invited talk at 16th International
  Conference on B-Physics at Frontier Machines (BEAUTY 2016), 2-6 May 2016,
  Marseille, France</comments><report-no>WSU-HEP-1604</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Abundance of charm data in the current and future low energy flavor
experiments makes it possible to study rare decays of D-mesons with ever
increased precision. I discuss theoretical implications of derived constraints
on New Physics models from these transitions. I argue that those constraints
could be competitive with results of direct searches for New Physics particles
(including Dark Matter) at the Large Hadron Collider.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04454</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sibasish</forenames></author></authors><title>Calabi-Yau compactification of type II string theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>PhD Thesis, defended on 29-09-2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superstring theories are the most promising theories for unified description
of all fundamental interactions including gravity. However, these theories are
formulated consistently only in 10 spacetime dimensions. Therefore, to connect
to the observable world, it is required to compactify 6 out of those 10
dimensions in a suitable fashion.
  In this thesis, we mainly consider compactifications of type II string
theories on Calabi-Yau threefolds. As a consequence, the resulting four
dimensional theories preserve $\mathcal{N}=2$ supersymmetry. In these cases the
metrics on the moduli spaces of the matter multiplets, vector and
hypermultiplets, completely determine the low energy theories. Whereas the
former are very well understood by now, the complete description of
hypermultiplets is more complicated. In fact, hypermultiplets receive both
perturbative and non-perturbative corrections. The thesis mainly pertains to
the understanding of the non-perturbative corrections. Our findings for the
hypermultiplets rely on the so called twistorial construction. We discuss this
technique in details and use it throughout the course of this thesis. In
particular, armed with this, and exploiting various symmetries, especially
S-duality and mirror symmetry, we discuss the procedure to derive the D-brane
and NS5-brane instanton corrections to the hypermultiplet moduli space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04455</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chekanov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Public repository with Monte Carlo simulations for high-energy particle
  collision experiments</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>5 pages. Contribution to the proceedings of the 38th International
  Conference of High Energy Physics (ICHEP), Chicago, Aug. 3-10, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Planning high-energy collision experiments for the next few decades requires
extensive Monte Carlo simulations in order to accomplish physics goals of these
experiments. Such simulations are essential for understanding fundamental
physics processes, as well as for setting up the detector parameters that help
establish R&amp;D projects required over the next few decades. This paper describes
a public repository with Monte Carlo event samples before and after
detector-response simulation. The goal of this repository is to facilitate the
accomplishment of many goals in planning a next generation of particle
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04456</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kelkar</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowakowski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extraction of the proton charge radius from experiments</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Mini review, 14 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Makara Journal of Science, 20/3 (2016), 119-126</journal-ref><doi>10.7454/mss.v20i3.6242</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Static properties of hadrons such as their radii and other moments of the
electric and magnetic distributions can only be extracted using theoretical
methods and not directly measured from experiments. As a result, discrepancies
between the extracted values from different precision measurements can exist.
The proton charge radius, $r_p$, which is either extracted from electron proton
elastic scattering data or from hydrogen atom spectroscopy seems to be no
exception. The value $r_p = 0.84087(39)$ fm extracted from muonic hydrogen
spectroscopy is about 4% smaller than that obtained from electron proton
scattering or standard hydrogen spectroscopy. The resolution of this so called
proton radius puzzle has been attempted in many different ways over the past
six years. The present article reviews these attempts with a focus on the
methods of extracting the radius.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04469</id><created>2016-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Mariana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasparotto</keyname><forenames>Piero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceriotti</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Anharmonic and Quantum Fluctuations in Molecular Crystals: A
  First-Principles Study of the Stability of Paracetamol</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117(11), 115702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.115702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular crystals often exist in multiple competing polymorphs, showing
significantly different physico-chemical properties. Computational crystal
structure prediction is key to interpret and guide the search for the most
stable or useful form: A real challenge due to the combinatorial search space,
and the complex interplay of subtle effects that work together to determine the
relative stability of different structures. Here we take a comprehensive
approach based on different flavors of thermodynamic integration in order to
estimate all contributions to the free energies of these systems with
density-functional theory, including the oft-neglected anharmonic contributions
and nuclear quantum effects. We take the two main stable forms of paracetamol
as a paradigmatic example. We find that anharmonic contributions, different
descriptions of van der Waals interactions, and nuclear quantum effects all
matter to quantitatively determine the stability of different phases. Our
analysis highlights the many challenges inherent in the development of a
quantitative and predictive framework to model molecular crystals. However, it
also indicates which of the components of the free energy can benefit from a
cancellation of errors that can redeem the predictive power of approximate
models, and suggests simple steps that could be taken to improve the
reliability of ab initio crystal structure prediction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04510</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokurin</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimko</keyname><forenames>G. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iv&#xe1;nov</keyname><forenames>Yu. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenraad</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silov</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Averkiev</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical spectroscopy of single beryllium acceptors in GaAs/AlGaAs
  quantum well</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 115307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.115307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We carry out microphotoluminescence measurements of an acceptor-bound exciton
(A^0X) recombination in the applied magnetic field with a single impurity
resolution. In order to describe the obtained spectra we develop a theoretical
model taking into account a quantum well (QW) confinement, an electron-hole and
hole-hole exchange interaction. By means of fitting the measured data with the
model we are able to study the fine structure of individual acceptors inside
the QW. The good agreement between our experiments and the model indicates that
we observe single acceptors in a pure two-dimensional environment whose states
are unstrained in the QW plain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04511</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Nhalil</keyname><forenames>Hariharan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Harikrishnan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>C. M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strydom</keyname><forenames>Andre M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elizabeth</keyname><forenames>Suja</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetism and the Effect of Free Charge Carriers on Electric
  Polarization in Y_2NiMnO_6 Double Perovskite</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Published in Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 92, 214426 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.214426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The double perovskite Y_2NiMnO_6 displays ferromagnetic transition at Tc = 81
K. The ferromagnetic order at low temperature is confirmed by the saturation
value of magnetization (M_s) and also, validated by the refined ordered
magnetic moment values extracted from neutron powder diffraction data at 10 K.
This way, the dominant Mn4+ and Ni2+ cationic ordering is confirmed. The
cation-ordered P 21/n nuclear structure is revealed by neutron powder
diffraction studies at 300 and 10 K. Analysis of frequency dependent dielectric
constant and equivalent circuit analysis of impedance data takes into account
the bulk contribution to total dielectric constant. This reveals an anomaly
which coincides with the ferromagnetic transition temperature (T_c).
Pyrocurrent measurements register a current flow with onset near Tc and a peak
at 57 K that shifts with temperature ramp rate. The extrinsic nature of the
observed pyrocurrent is established by employing a special protocol
measurement. It is realized that the origin is due to re-orientation of
electric dipoles created by the free charge carriers and not by spontaneous
electric polarization at variance with recently reported magnetism-driven
ferroelectricity in this material
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04515</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Raatz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weikl</keyname><forenames>Thomas R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Membrane tubulation by elongated and patchy nanoparticles</title><categories>q-bio.SC cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Mater. Interfaces 2016, 1600325</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/admi.201600325</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Advances in nanotechnology lead to an increasing interest in how
nanoparticles interact with biomembranes. Nanoparticles are wrapped
spontaneously by biomembranes if the adhesive interactions between the
particles and membranes compensate for the cost of membrane bending. In the
last years, the cooperative wrapping of spherical nanoparticles in membrane
tubules has been observed in experiments and simulations. For spherical
nanoparticles, the stability of the particle-filled membrane tubules strongly
depends on the range of the adhesive particle-membrane interactions. In this
article, we show via modeling and energy minimization that elongated and patchy
particles are wrapped cooperatively in membrane tubules that are highly stable
for all ranges of the particle-membrane interactions, compared to individual
wrapping of the particles. The cooperative wrapping of linear chains of
elongated or patchy particles in membrane tubules may thus provide an efficient
route to induce membrane tubulation, or to store such particles in membranes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04545</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Mauser</keyname><forenames>Nina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartmann</keyname><forenames>Nicolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Matthias S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janik</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;gele</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartschuh</keyname><forenames>Achim</forenames></author></authors><title>Antenna-enhanced Optoelectronic Probing of Carbon Nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Letters 2014, 14, 3773-3778</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/nl5006959</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the first antenna-enhanced optoelectronic microscopy studies on
nanoscale devices. By coupling the emission and excitation to a scanning
optical antenna, we are able to locally enhance the electroluminescence and
photocurrent along a carbon nanotube device. We show that the emission source
of the electroluminescence can be point-like with a spatial extension below 20
nm. Topographic and antenna-enhanced photocurrent measurements reveal that the
emission takes place at the location of highest local electric field indicating
that the mechanism behind the emission is the radiative decay of excitons
created via impact excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04555</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kanai</keyname><forenames>Tsuneto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malevich</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kangaparambil</keyname><forenames>Sarayoo Sasidharan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoogland</keyname><forenames>Heinar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holzwarth</keyname><forenames>Ronald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pug&#x17e;lys</keyname><forenames>Audrius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baltu&#x161;ka</keyname><forenames>Andrius</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub 100-fs, 5.2-$\mu$m ZGP Parametric Amplifier Driven by a ps Ho:YAG
  Chirped Pulse Amplifier and its application to high harmonic generation</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a 1 kHz repetition-rate mid-IR (MIR) optical parametric amplifier
(OPA) system operating at a central wavelength of 5.2 $\mu$m with the
tail-to-tail spectrum extending over 1.5 $\mu$m and delivering 40 $\mu$J pulses
that are compressed to 99 fs (5.6 optical cycles). Also we develop a novel
pulse compression scheme for further pulse compression and wavelength
tunability. As the first application of this laser system, we generated high
harmonics in bulk ZnSe above the bandgap, dense exciton generation after
10-photon absorption, high order sum- and difference-frequency generation,
ultrafast transition in the conduction band, which reflects the structure of
conduction bands.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04559</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Garra</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orsingher</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Random motions with space-varying velocities</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Chapter for the book: Modern Problems of Stochastic Analysis and
  Statistics - Festschrift in Honor of Valentin Konakov</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random motions on the line and on the plane with space-varying velocities are
considered and analyzed in this paper.
  On the line we investigate symmetric and asymmetric telegraph processes with
space-dependent velocities and we are able to present the explicit distribution
of the position $\mathcal{T}(t)$, $t&gt;0$, of the moving particle.
  Also the case of a non-homogeneous Poisson process (with rate $\lambda =
\lambda(t)$) governing the changes of direction is analyzed in three specific
cases. For the special case $\lambda(t)= \alpha/t$ we obtain a random motion
related to the Euler-Poisson-Darboux (EPD) equation which generalizes the
well-known case treated e.g. in Foong and Van Kolck (1992), Garra and Orsingher
(2016) and Rosencrans (1973).
  A EPD--type fractional equation is also considered and a parabolic solution
(which in dimension $d=1$ has the structure of a probability density) is
obtained.
  Planar random motions with space--varying velocities and infinite directions
are finally analyzed in Section 5. We are able to present their explicit
distributions and for polynomial-type velocity structures we obtain the hyper
and hypo-elliptic form of their support (of which we provide a picture).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04564</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dhakal</keyname><forenames>Ashim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peyskens</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clemmen</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raza</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wuytens</keyname><forenames>Pieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Haolan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Nicolas Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baets</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author></authors><title>Single mode waveguide platform for spontaneous and surface-enhanced
  on-chip Raman spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Interface Focus, 6(4), p.20160015 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsfs.2016.0015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review an on-chip approach for spontaneous Raman spectroscopy and Surface
Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy (SERS) based on evanescent excitation of the
analyte as well as evanescent collection of the Raman signal using
Complementary Metal Oxide Semiconductor (CMOS) compatible single mode
waveguides. The signal is either directly collected from the analyte molecules
or via plasmonic nanoantennas integrated on top of the waveguides. Flexibility
in the design of the geometry of the waveguide, and/or the geometry of the
antennas, enables optimization of the collection efficiency. Furthermore the
sensor can be integrated with additional functionality (sources, detectors,
spectrometers) on the same chip. In this paper, the basic theoretical concepts
are introduced to identify the key design parameters and some proof-of-concept
experimental results are reviewed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04583</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zacharias</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent injection as a model for rapid blazar flares</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, proceeding of the 'Blazars through sharp multi-wavelength
  eyes' conference, to appear in a special issue of 'Galaxies', edited by J. L.
  G\'omez, A. P. Marscher, and S. G. Jorstad</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time-dependent injection can cause non-linear cooling effects, which lead to
a faster energy loss of the electrons in jets. The most obvious result is the
appearance of unique breaks in the SED, which would normally be attributed to a
complicated electron distribution. The knowledge of the observation time and
duration is important to interpret the observed spectra, because of the
non-trivial evolution of the SED. Intrinsic gamma-gamma absorption processes in
the emission region are only of minor importance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04612</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zaninetti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>An analytical solution in the complex plane for the luminosity distance
  in flat cosmology</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of High Energy Physics, Gravitation and Cosmology, (2016),
  2, 581-586</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jhepgc.2016.24050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analytical solution for the luminosity distance in spatially
flat cosmology with pressureless matter and the cosmological constant. The
complex analytical solution is made of a real part and a negligible imaginary
part. The real part of the luminosity distance allows finding the two
parameters $H_0$ and $\om$. A simple expression for the distance modulus for
SNs of type Ia is reported in the framework of the minimax approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04613</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bar-David</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maayani</keyname><forenames>Shai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Leoplodo L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carmon</keyname><forenames>Tal</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluidic vortices generated from optical vortices in a microdroplet
  cavity</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages,6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We harness the momentum of light resonating inside a micro-droplet cavity, to
experimentally generate micro-flows within the envelope of the drop. We 3D map
these optically induced flows by using fluorescent nanoparticles; which reveals
circular micro-streams. The flows are parametrically studied and, as expected,
exhibit an increase of rotation speed with optical power. The flow is
non-circular only when we intentionally break the axial symmetry of the
droplet. Besides the fundamental interest in light-flow interactions including
in opto-fluidic cavities, the optically controlled flows can serve in bringing
analytes into the maximum-power region of the microcavity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04629</id><created>2016-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Sheen S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zajac</keyname><forenames>Edward J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Institutionalization in Efficient Markets: The Case of Price Bubbles</title><categories>q-fin.GN cs.SI nlin.AO</categories><comments>Academy of Management Best Paper Proceedings (2008)</comments><doi>10.5465/AMBPP.2008.33649949</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We seek to deepen understanding of the micro-foundations of
institutionalization while contributing to a sociological theory of markets by
investigating the puzzle of price bubbles in financial markets. We find that
such markets, despite textbook conditions of high efficiency -- perfect
information, atomistic agents, no uncertainty -- quickly develop patterns
consistent with institutionalization processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04630</id><created>2016-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Perrard</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labousse</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fort</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couder</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>Chaos driven by interfering memory</title><categories>cond-mat.soft nlin.CD physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 113 (10), 104101, (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.104101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transmission of information can couple two entities of very different
nature, one of them serving as a memory for the other. Here we study the
situation in which information is stored in a wave field and serves as a memory
that pilots the dynamics of a particle. Such a system can be implemented by a
bouncing drop generating surface waves sustained by a parametric forcing. The
motion of the resulting &quot;walker&quot; when confined in a harmonic potential well is
generally disordered. Here we show that these trajectories correspond to
chaotic regimes characterized by intermittent transitions between a discrete
set of states. At any given time, the system is in one of these states
characterized by a double quantization of size and angular momentum. A low
dimensional intermittency determines their respective probabilities. They thus
form an eigenstate basis of decomposition for what would be observed as a
superposition of states if all measurements were intrusive.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04631</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Briane</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames><affiliation>IRMAR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pallares-Mart&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames><affiliation>EDAN US</affiliation></author></authors><title>Homogenization of weakly coercive integral functionals in
  three-dimensional elasticity</title><categories>math.AP physics.class-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper deals with the homogenization through $\Gamma$-convergence of
weakly coercive integral energies with the oscillating density
$\mathbb{L}(x/\epsilon)\nabla v : \nabla v$ in three-dimensional elasticity.
The energies are weakly coercive in the sense where the classical functional
coercivity satisfied by the periodic tensor L (using smooth test functions v
with compact support in $\mathbb{R}^3$) which reads as $\Lambda(\mathbb{L})
&gt;0$, is replaced by the relaxed condition $\Lambda(\mathbb{L}) \ge 0$.
Surprisingly, we prove that contrary to the two-dimensional case of [2] which
seems a priori more constrained, the homogenized tensor $\mathbb{L}^0$ remains
strongly elliptic, or equivalently $\Lambda(\mathbb{L}^0) &gt;0$, for any tensor
$\mathbb{L} = \mathbb{L}(y_1)$ satisfying $\mathbb{L}(y)M : M + D : {\rm
Cof}(M) \ge 0$, a.e. $y \in \mathbb{R}^3$, $\forall M \in \mathbb{R}^{3\times
3}$, for some matrix $D \in \mathbb{R}^{3\times3}$ (which implies
$\Lambda(\mathbb{L}) \ge 0$), and the periodic functional coercivity (using
smooth test functions $v$ with periodic gradients) which reads as $\Lambda_{\rm
per}(\mathbb{L})&gt;0$. Moreover, we derive the loss of strong ellipticity for the
homogenized tensor using a rank-two lamination, which justifies by
$\Gamma$-convergence the formal procedure of [8].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04632</id><created>2016-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Barbagallo</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madeo</keyname><forenames>Angela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morestin</keyname><forenames>Fabrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boisse</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the deep drawing of a 3D woven fabric with a second gradient
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimental testing on dry woven fabrics exhibits a complex set of evidences
that are difficult to be completely described using classical continuum models.
The aim of this paper is to show how the introduction of energy terms related
to the micro-deformation mechanisms of the fabric, in particular to the bending
stiffness of the yarns, helps in the modeling of the mechanical behavior of
this kind of materials. To this aim, a second gradient, hyperelastic, initially
orthotropic continuum theory is proposed to model fibrous composite interlocks
at finite strains. In particular, the present work explores the relationship
between the onset of wrinkling appearing during the simulation of the deep
drawing of a woven fabric and the use of a second gradient model. It is shown
that the introduction of second gradient terms accounting for the description
of in-plane and out-of-plane bending rigidities, decreases the onset of
wrinkles during the simulation of deep-drawing.
  In this work, a quadratic energy, roughly proportional to the square of the
curvature of the fibers, is presented and implemented in the simulations. This
simple constitutive assumption allows to clearly show the effects of the second
gradient energy on both the wrinkling description and the numerical stability
of the model. The results obtained in second gradient simulations are
descriptive of the experimental evidence of deep drawing whose description is
targeted in this work. The present paper provides additional evidence of the
fact that first gradient continuum theories alone cannot be considered fully
descriptive of the behavior of dry woven composite reinforcements. On the other
hand, the proposed second gradient model for fibrous composite reinforcements
opens the way both to the more accurate simulation of complex forming processes
and to the possibility of controlling the onset of wrinkles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04635</id><created>2016-08-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Gertz</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>ET Probes: Looking Here as Well as There</title><categories>physics.pop-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>4 pages, no figures, JBIS Accepted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Almost all SETI searches to date have explicitly targeted stars in the hope
of detecting artificial radio or optical transmissions. It is argued that
extra-terrestrials (ET) might regard sending physical probes to our own Solar
System as a more efficient means for sending large amounts of information to
Earth. Probes are more efficient in terms of energy and time expenditures; may
solve for the vexing problem of Drake's L factor term, namely, that the
civilization wishing to send information may not coexist temporally with the
intended recipient; and they alleviate ET's reasonable fear that the intended
recipient might prove hostile. It is argued that probes may be numerous and
easier to find than interstellar beacons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04638</id><created>2016-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Buskes</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Will be Thrown: The Emerging Science of Cultural Evolution</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>International Journal of Humanities, Art and Social Studies,
  Volume 1, Nr. 1, August 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Culture evolves, not just in the trivial sense that cultures change over
time, but also in the strong sense that such change is governed by Darwinian
principles. Both biological and cultural evolution are essentially cumulative
selection processes in which information (whether genetic or cultural) is
sieved, retained and then transmitted to the next generation. In both domains
such a process will result in recognizable lineages and tree-like phylogenies
so characteristic of Darwinian evolution. Because a principle of inheritance
(i.e., faithful replication of information) holds in both domains, we may trace
back particular transmission histories and identify the forces that influenced
them. The idea that culture evolves is quite old, but only in recent years
there has been a serious effort to turn this idea into science. This article
offers a concise analysis of how a rudimentary idea gradually evolved into a
thriving research program.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04659</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04659</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Duradoni</keyname><forenames>Mirko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagnoli</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guazzini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-trivial reputation effects on social decision making in virtual
  environment</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>INSCI 2016, LNCS 9934, pp. 115-122, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-45982-0_11</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reputation systems are currently used, often with success, to ensure the
functioning of online services as well as of e-commerce sites. Despite the
relationship between reputation and material cooperative behaviours is quite
supported, less obvious appears the relationship with informative behaviours,
which are crucial for the transmission of reputational information and
therefore for the maintenance of cooperation among individuals. The purpose of
this study was to verify how reputation affects cooperation dynamics in virtual
environment, within a social dilemma situation (i.e., where there are
incentives to act selfishly). The results confirm that reputation can activate
prosocial conducts, however it highlights also the limitations and distortions
that reputation can create.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04669</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nerkararyan</keyname><forenames>Khachatur V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling in light scattering by sharp conical metal tips</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the electrostatic approximation, we analyze electromagnetic fields
scattered by sharp conical metal tips, which are illuminated with light
polarized along the tip axis. We establish scaling relations for the scattered
field amplitude and phase, whose validity is verified with numerical
simulations. Analytic expressions for the wavelength, at which the scattered
field near the tip changes its direction, and field decay near the tip
extremity are obtained, relating these characteristics to the cone angle and
metal permittivity. The results obtained have important implications to various
tip-enhanced phenomena, ranging from Raman and scattering near-field imaging to
photoemission spectroscopy and nano-optical trapping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04672</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Michael G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analog computing using reflective plasmonic metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the recent renewed interest in compact analog computing using
light and metasurfaces (Silva, A. et al., Science 2014, 343, 160-163), we
suggest a practical approach to its realization that involves reflective
metasurfaces consisting of arrayed gold nanobricks atop a subwavelength-thin
dielectric spacer and optically-thick gold film, a configuration that supports
gap-surface plasmon resonances. Using well established numerical routines, we
demonstrate that these metasurfaces enable independent control of the light
phase and amplitude, and design differentiator and integrator metasurfaces
featuring realistic system parameters. Proof-of-principle experiments are
reported along with the successful realization of a high-quality poor-man's
integrator metasurface operating at the wavelength of 800 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04678</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Tu</keyname><forenames>Renyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertoni</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lak</keyname><forenames>Aidin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaspari</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rapallo</keyname><forenames>Arnaldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Trizio</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manna</keyname><forenames>Liberato</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of the Ion Coordination Number on Cation Exchange Reactions
  with Copper Telluride Nanocrystals</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures in J. Am. Chem. Soc, 13 May 2016</comments><doi>10.1021/jacs.6b02830</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cu2-xTe nanocubes were used as starting seeds to access metal telluride
nanocrystals by cation exchanges at room temperature. The coordination number
of the entering cations was found to play an important role in dictating the
reaction pathways. The exchanges with tetrahedrally coordinated cations (i.e.
with coordination number 4), such as Cd2+ or Hg2+, yielded monocrystalline CdTe
or HgTe nanocrystals with Cu2-xTe/CdTe or Cu2-xTe/HgTe Janus-like
heterostructures as intermediates. The formation of Janus-like architectures
was attributed to the high diffusion rate of the relatively small tetrahedrally
coordinated cations, which could rapidly diffuse in the Cu2-xTe NCs and
nucleate the CdTe (or HgTe) phase in a preferred region of the host structure.
Also, with both Cd2+ and Hg2+ ions the exchange led to wurtzite CdTe and HgTe
phases rather than the more stable zinc-blende ones, indicating that the anion
framework of the starting Cu2- xTe particles could be more easily deformed to
match the anion framework of the metastable wurtzite structures. As hexagonal
HgTe had never been reported to date, this represents another case of
metastable new phases that can only be accessed by cation exchange. On the
other hand, the exchanges involving octahedrally coordinated ions (i.e. with
coordination number 6), such as Pb2+ or Sn2+, yielded rock-salt polycrystalline
PbTe or SnTe nanocrystals with Cu2-xTe@PbTe or Cu2-xTe@SnTe core@shell
architectures at the early stages of the exchange process. In this case, the
octahedrally coordinated ions are probably too large to diffuse easily through
the Cu2-xTe structure: their limited diffusion rate restricts their initial
reaction to the surface of the nanocrystals, where cation exchange is initiated
unselectively, leading to core@shell architectures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04681</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04681</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Emitters near Layered Plasmonic Nanostructures: Decay Rate
  Contributions</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a numerical framework for calculating decay rate contributions
when excited two-level quantum emitters are located near layered plasmonic
nanostructures, particularly emphasizing the case of plasmonic nanostructures
atop metal substrates where three decay channels exist: free space radiation,
Ohmic losses, and excitation of surface plasmon polaritons (SPPs). The
calculation of decay rate contributions is based on Huygen's equivalence
principle together with a near-field to far-field transformation of the local
electric field, thereby allowing us to discern the part of the electromagnetic
field associated with free propagating waves rather than SPPs. The methodology
is applied to the case of an emitter inside and near a gap-plasmon resonator,
emphasizing strong position and orientation dependencies of the total decay
rate, contributions of different decay channels, radiation patterns, and
directivity of SPP excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04684</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Rocha</keyname><forenames>W. R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pilling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Barros</keyname><forenames>A. L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>D. P. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rothard</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boduch</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Infrared complex refractive index of astrophysical ices exposed to
  cosmic rays simulated in the laboratory</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In dense and cold regions of the interstellar medium (ISM), molecules may be
adsorbed onto dust grains to form the ice mantles. Once formed, they can be
processed by ionizing radiation coming from stellar or interstellar medium
leading to formation of several new molecules in the ice. Among the different
kind of ionizing radiation, cosmic rays play an important role in the
solid-phase chemistry because of the large amount of energy deposited in the
ices. The physicochemical changes induced by the energetic processing of
astrophysical ices are recorded in a intrinsic parameter of the matter called
complex refractive index (CRI). In this paper, we present for the first time a
catalogue containing 39 complex refractive indices (n, k) in the infrared from
2.0 - 16.6 micrometer for 13 different water-containing ices processed in
laboratory by cosmic ray analogs. The calculation was done by using the NKABS
(acronym of determination of N and K from ABSorbance data) code, which employs
the Lambert-Beer and Kramers-Kronig equations to calculate the values of n and
k. The results are also available at the website:
http://www1.univap.br/gaa/nkabs-database/data.htm. As test case, a
H2O:NH3:CO2:CH4 ice was employed in a radiative transfer simulation of a
prototoplanetary disk to show that these data are indispensable to reproduce
the spectrum of YSOs containing ices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04691</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Pors</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Michael G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic metagratings for simultaneous determination of Stokes
  parameters</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measuring light's state of polarization is an inherently difficult problem,
since the phase information between orthogonal polarization states is typically
lost in the detection process. In this work, we bring to the fore the
equivalence between normalized Stokes parameters and diffraction contrasts in
appropriately designed phase-gradient birefringent metasurfaces and introduce a
concept of all-polarization birefringent metagratings. The metagrating, which
consists of three interweaved metasurfaces, allows one to easily analyze an
arbitrary state of light polarization by conducting simultaneous (i.e.,
parallel) measurements of the correspondent diffraction intensities that reveal
immediately the Stokes parameters of the polarization state under examination.
Based on plasmonic metasurfaces operating in reflection at the wavelength of
800 nm, we design and realize phase-gradient birefringent metasurfaces and the
correspondent metagrating, while experimental characterization of the
fabricated components convincingly demonstrates the expected functionalities.
We foresee the use of the metagrating in compact polarimetric setups at any
frequency regime of interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04695</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04695</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Shailesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lausen</keyname><forenames>Jens L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Cesar E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Sebastian K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Alexander S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radko</keyname><forenames>Ilya P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Cameron L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kristensen</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitation of surface plasmon polariton modes with multiple nitrogen
  vacancy centers in single nanodiamonds</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. 18 (2016) 024002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/2/024002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers in diamonds are interesting due to their
remarkable characteristics that are well suited to applications in
quantum-information processing and magnetic field sensing, as well as
representing stable fluorescent sources. Multiple NV centers in nanodiamonds
(NDs) are especially useful as biological fluorophores due to their chemical
neutrality, brightness and room-temperature photostability. Furthermore, NDs
containing multiple NV centers also have potential in high-precision magnetic
field and temperature sensing. Coupling NV centers to propagating surface
plasmon polariton (SPP) modes gives a base for lab-on-a-chip sensing devices,
allows enhanced fluorescence emission and collection which can further enhance
the precision of NV-based sensors. Here, we investigate coupling of multiple NV
centers in individual NDs to the SPP modes supported by silver surfaces
protected by thin dielectric layers and by gold V-grooves (VGs) produced via
the self-terminated silicon etching. In the first case, we concentrate on
monitoring differences in fluorescence spectra obtained from a source ND, which
is illuminated by a pump laser, and from a scattering ND illuminated only by
the fluorescence-excited SPP radiation. In the second case, we observe changes
in the average NV lifetime when the same ND is characterized outside and inside
a VG. Fluorescence emission from the VG terminations is also observed, which
confirms the NV coupling to the VG-supported SPP modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04701</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Obenberger</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holmes</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dowell</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schinzel</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stovall</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sutton</keyname><forenames>E. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Altitudinal dependence of meteor radio afterglows measured via optical
  counterparts</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1002/2016GL070059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Utilizing the all-sky imaging capabilities of the LWA1 radio telescope along
with a host of all-sky optical cameras, we have now observed 44 optical meteor
counterparts to radio afterglows. Combining these observations we have
determined the geographic positions of all 44 afterglows. Comparing the number
of radio detections as a function of altitude above sea level to the number of
expected bright meteors we find a strong altitudinal dependence characterized
by a cutoff below $\sim$ 90 km, below which no radio emission occurs, despite
the fact that many of the observed optical meteors penetrated well below this
altitude. This cutoff suggests that wave damping from electron collisions is an
important factor for the evolution of radio afterglows, which agrees with the
hypothesis that the emission is the result of electron plasma wave emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04703</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Cesar E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Shailesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Local excitation of surface plasmon polaritons using nitrogen-vacancy
  centers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 40, Issue 16, pp. 3830-3833 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.40.003830</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface plasmon polaritons (SPPs) are locally excited at silver surfaces
using (~100) nm-sized nanodiamonds (NDs) with multiple nitrogen-vacancy (NV)
centers (~400). The fluorescence from an externally illuminated (at 532 nm) ND
and from nearby NDs, which are not illuminated but produce out-of-plane
scattering of SPPs excited by the illuminated ND, exhibit distinctly different
wavelength spectra, showing short-wavelength filtering due to the SPP
propagation loss. The results indicate that NDs with multiple NV centers can be
used as efficient sub-wavelength SPP sources in planar integrated plasmonics
for various applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04709</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dittrich</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Dirichlet's Derivation of the Ellipsoid Potential</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Newton's potential of a massive homogeneous ellipsoid is derived via
Dirichlet's discontinuous factor. At first we review part of Dirichlet's work
in an English translation of the original German, and then continue with an
extension of his method into the complex plane. With this trick it becomes
possible to first calculate the potential and thereafter the force components
exerted on a test mass by the ellipsoid. This is remarkable in so far as all
other famous researchers prior to Dirichlet merely calculated the attraction
components. Unfortunately, Dirichlet's derivation is to a large extent
mathematically unacceptable which, however, can be corrected by treating the
problem in the complex plane.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04711</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04711</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kirstetter</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delestre</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darboux</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagr&#xe9;e</keyname><forenames>P. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popinet</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fullana</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Josserand</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling rain-driven overland flow: empirical versus analytical friction
  terms in the shallow water approximation</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>in Journal of Hydrology 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modeling and simulating overland flow fed by rainfall is a common issue in
watershed surface hydrology. Modelers have to choose among various friction
models when defining their simulation framework. The purpose of this work is to
compare the simulation quality for the Manning, Darcy-Weisbach, and Poiseuille
friction models on the simple case of a constant rain on a thin experimental
flume. Results show that the usual friction law of Manning is not suitable for
this type of flow. The Poiseuille friction model gave the best results both on
the flux at the outlet and the velocity and depth profile along the flume. The
Darcy-Weisbach model shows good results for laminar flow. Additional testing
should be carried out for turbulent cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04720</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Saunders</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Chance in the Everett interpretation</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 3 figures. This is a lightly edited reprint (with added
  footnotes and a new appendix) of `Chance in the Everett interpretaiton', in
  &quot;Many Worlds? Everett, quantum theory and reality&quot;, S. Saunders, J. Barrett,
  A. Kent, and D. Wallace (eds.), Oxford 2010</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The notion of objective probability or chance, as a physical trait of the
world, has proved elusive; the identification of chances with actual
frequencies does not succeed. An adequate theory of chance should explain not
only the connection of chance with statistics, but with degrees of belief, and
more broadly the entire phenomenology of (seemingly) chance events and their
measurement. Branching structure in the decoherence-based many worlds theory
provides an account of what chance is that satisfies all these desiderata,
including the requirement that chance involves uncertainty.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04732</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04732</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Nerkararyan</keyname><forenames>Khachatur V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement of two qubits mediated by a localized surface plasmon</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate relaxation dynamics in the system of two identical quantum
dipole emitters (QDEs) located near a metal nanoparticle (MNP) exhibiting a
dipolar localized surface plasmon (LSP) resonance at the frequency of the QDE
radiative transition. Considering one QDE to be brought into an optically
active excited state and weakly coupled to the resonant LSP, we show that a
stable superposition state of two QDEs is formed during the transition time,
which is much shorter than the QDE spontaneous decay time and determined by the
efficiency of resonant interaction between the QDEs and induced LSP. It is
elucidated that the superposition state is established as a result of
redistribution of the energy of the initially excited QDE so that the
corresponding steady-state QDE fields induced at the MNP site cancel each
other. The degree of steady-state entanglement characterized by the concurrence
is found dependent only on the ratio of distances between the QDEs and the MNP,
reaching its maximum value of ~ 0.65, when the separation between the MNP and
the initially excited QDE is larger by ~ 20% than the distance from the other
QDE to the MNP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04734</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04734</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ansell</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thackray</keyname><forenames>B. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aznakayeva</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Auton</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>O. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radko</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozhevolnyi</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigorenko</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hybrid graphene plasmonic waveguide modulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unique optical and electronic properties of graphene allow one to realize
active optical devices. While several types of graphene-based photonic
modulators have already been demonstrated, the potential of combining the
versatility of graphene with subwavelength field confinement of
plasmonic/metallic structures is not fully realized. Here we report fabrication
and study of hybrid graphene-plasmonic modulators. We consider several types of
modulators and identify the most promising one for light modulation at telecom
and near-infrared. Our proof-of-concept results pave the way towards on-chip
realization of efficient graphene-based active plasmonic waveguide devices for
optical communications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04742</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04742</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Helmbrecht</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kempf</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchis</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-term stability and temperature variability of Iris AO segmented
  MEMS deformable mirrors</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9909, Adaptive Optics Systems V, 990981, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2233923</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Long-term stability of deformable mirrors (DM) is a critical performance
requirement for instruments requiring open-loop corrections. The effects of
temperature changes in the DM performance are equally critical for such
instruments. This paper investigates the long-term stability of three different
Iris AO PTT111 DMs that were calibrated at different times ranging from 13
months to nearly 29 months prior to subsequent testing. Performance testing
showed that only a small increase in positioning errors occurred from the
initial calibration date to the test dates. The increases in errors ranged from
as little as 1.38 nm rms after 18 months to 5.68 nm rms after 29 months. The
paper also studies the effects of small temperature changes, up to 6.2{\deg}C
around room temperature. For three different arrays, the errors ranged from
0.62-1.42 nm rms/{\deg}C. Removing the effects of packaging shows that errors
are $\le$0.50 nm rms/{\deg}C. Finally, measured data showed that individual
segments deformed $\le$0.11 nm rms/{\deg}C when heated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04751</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04751</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Rubie</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laurenz</keyname><forenames>Vera</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobson</keyname><forenames>Seth A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morbidelli</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palme</keyname><forenames>Herbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>Antje K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly siderophile elements were stripped from Earth's mantle by iron
  sulfide segregation</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Science 353, 6304, 1141-1144 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aaf6919</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Highly siderophile elements (HSEs) are strongly depleted in the bulk silicate
Earth (BSE) but are present in near-chondritic relative abundances. The
conventional explanation is that the HSEs were stripped from the mantle by the
segregation of metal during core formation but were added back in
near-chondritic proportions by late accretion, after core formation had ceased.
Here we show that metal-silicate equilibration and segregation during Earth's
core formation actually increased HSE mantle concentrations because HSE
partition coefficients are relatively low at the high pressures of core
formation within Earth. The pervasive exsolution and segregation of iron
sulfide liquid from silicate liquid (the &quot;Hadean matte&quot;) stripped magma oceans
of HSEs during cooling and crystallization, before late accretion, and resulted
in slightly suprachondritic palladium/iridium and ruthenium/iridium ratios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04760</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wynn</keyname><forenames>Jamie M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Needs</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structures and finite-temperature abundances of defects in
  In$_2$O$_3$-II from first-principles calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied intrinsic defect complexes in In$_2$O$_3$ using ab initio
random structure searching (AIRSS). Our first-principles
density-functional-theory calculations predict the thermodynamic stability of
several novel defect structures. We combine the static lattice energy and
harmonic vibrational energy with the often-neglected configurational entropy to
construct the free energy, which is minimised to predict defect abundances at
finite temperatures. We predict that some of our new defect structures - in
particular our {In,2V$_\mathrm{O}$} and {2In,3V$_\mathrm{O}$} defects - can
exist in significant abundances at finite temperatures, and their densities of
electronic states indicate that they could play an important role in the
unexpectedly high density of n-type charge carriers observed in In$_2$O$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04762</id><created>2016-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Robert P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Interactions on Bose-Einstein Condensation</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>Unedited version of chapter to appear in &quot;Universal Themes of
  Bose-Einstein Condensation&quot;, edited by D. W. Snoke, N. P. Proukakis and P. B.
  Littlewood (Cambridge University Press)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bose-Einstein condensation is a unique phase transition in that it is not
driven by inter-particle interactions, but can theoretically occur in an ideal
gas, purely as a consequence of quantum statistics. This chapter addresses the
question \emph{`How is this ideal Bose gas condensation modified in the
presence of interactions between the particles?' } This seemingly simple
question turns out to be surprisingly difficult to answer. Here we outline the
theoretical background to this question and discuss some recent measurements on
ultracold atomic Bose gases that have sought to provide some answers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04768</id><created>2016-09-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sugakov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation of new phase inclusions in the system of quasi-equilibrium
  magnons of high density</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014407 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper studies the spatial variation of the magnetization in a
nonconducting magnetic sample with an excess number of magnons in comparison to
the equilibrium. The phenomenon is considered using the Landau-Lifshits
equation with additional terms describing the longitudinal relaxation of the
magnetization, the magnon diffusion and the magnon creation by external
pumping. The free energy of the system is presented in the mean field
approximation. It is shown that, if the pumping exceeds some critical value,
regions of the new phase arise where the magnetic moments are oriented opposite
to the magnetization of the magnetic sample. The phenomenon is similar to the
appearance of droplets of the condensed phase in the supersaturated vapor. The
appearance of the new phase either in the form of a single domain or a
periodical lattice is demonstrated. The studied process is a competitor to the
process of the Bose-Einstein condensation of magnons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:gr-qc/0610095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-09-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>gr-qc/0610095</id><created>2006-10-19</created><updated>2009-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malekolkalami</keyname><forenames>Behrooz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farhoudi</keyname><forenames>Mehrdad</forenames></author></authors><title>About Gravitomagnetism</title><categories>gr-qc physics.class-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, a few amendments have been performed and a new section has
  been added</comments><journal-ref>Mod.Phys.Lett.A24:601-613,2009</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732309028618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gravitomagnetic field is the force exerted by a moving body on the basis
of the intriguing interplay between geometry and dynamics which is the analog
to the magnetic field of a moving charged body in electromagnetism. The
existence of such a field has been demonstrated based on special relativity
approach and also by special relativity plus the gravitational time dilation
for two different cases, a moving infinite line and a uniformly moving point
mass, respectively. We treat these two approaches when the applied cases are
switched while appropriate key points are employed. Thus, we demonstrate that
the strength of the resulted gravitomagnetic field in the latter approach is
twice the former. Then, we also discuss the full linearized general relativity
and show that it should give the same strength for gravitomagnetic field as the
latter approach. Hence, through an exact analogy with the electrodynamic
equations, we present an argument in order to indicate the best definition
amongst those considered in this issue in the literature. Finally, we
investigate the gravitomagnetic effects and consequences of different
definitions on the geodesic equation including the second order approximation
terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
