<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:20:03Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-10-06" from="2016-10-06" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0709.3606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0709.3606</id><created>2007-09-22</created><updated>2007-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Assaf</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meerson</keyname><forenames>Baruch</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise enhanced persistence in a biochemical regulatory network with
  feedback control</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, submitted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 100, 058105 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.100.058105</doi><abstract>  We find that discrete noise of inhibiting (signal) molecules can greatly
delay the extinction of plasmids in a plasmid replication system: a
prototypical biochemical regulatory network. We calculate the probability
distribution of the metastable state of the plasmids and show on this example
that the reaction rate equations may fail in predicting the average number of
regulated molecules even when this number is large, and the time is much
shorter than the mean extinction time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0808.1676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0808.1676</id><created>2008-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sitenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vlasii</keyname><forenames>N. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vacuum polarization in graphene with a topological defect</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, submitted to J. Low Temp. Phys</comments><journal-ref>Low Temp. Phys. 34, 826 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.2981397</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of a topological defect in graphene on the ground state of
electronic quasiparticle excitations is studied in the framework of the
long-wavelength continuum model originating in the tight-binding approximation
for the nearest neighbour interaction in the graphitic lattice. A topological
defect that rolls up a graphitic sheet into a nanocone is represented by a
pointlike pseudomagnetic vortex with a flux which is related to the deficit
angle of the cone. The method of self-adjoint extensions is employed to define
the set of physically acceptable boundary conditions at the apex of the
nanocone. The electronic system on a graphitic nanocone is found to acquire the
ground state condensate and current of special type, and we determine the
dependence of these quantities on the deficit angle of the nanocone, continuous
parameter of the boundary condition at the apex, and the distance from the
apex.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1005.1444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1005.1444</id><created>2010-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient implementation of the pivot algorithm for self-avoiding walks</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 24 figures, 4 tables. Accepted for publication in the
  Journal of Statistical Physics.</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 140: 349-392 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-010-9994-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pivot algorithm for self-avoiding walks has been implemented in a manner
which is dramatically faster than previous implementations, enabling extremely
long walks to be efficiently simulated. We explicitly describe the data
structures and algorithms used, and provide a heuristic argument that the mean
time per attempted pivot for $N$-step self-avoiding walks is $O(1)$ for the
square and simple cubic lattices. Numerical experiments conducted for
self-avoiding walks with up to 268 million steps are consistent with $o(\log
N)$ behavior for the square lattice and $O(\log N)$ behavior for the simple
cubic lattice. Our method can be adapted to other models of polymers with
short-range interactions, on the lattice or in the continuum, and hence
promises to be widely useful.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.6931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.6931</id><created>2013-07-26</created><updated>2016-09-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Trambak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazumder</keyname><forenames>Surasree</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abir</keyname><forenames>Raktim</forenames></author></authors><title>Soft Gluon Radiation off Heavy Quarks beyond Eikonal Approximation</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures, Accepted for publication in Advances in High
  Energy Physics, article id 1298986</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  1298986</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the soft gluon radiation spectrum off heavy quarks (HQs)
interacting with light quarks (LQs) beyond small angle scattering (eikon-
ality) approximation and thus generalize the dead-cone formula of heavy quarks
extensively used in the literatures of Quark-Gluon Plasma (QGP) phenomenology
to the large scattering angle regime which may be im- portant in the energy
loss of energetic heavy quarks in the deconfined Quark-Gluon Plasma medium. In
the proper limits, we reproduce all the relevant existing formulae for the
gluon radiation distribution off energetic quarks, heavy or light used in the
QGP phenomenology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.6506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.6506</id><created>2013-11-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Men&#xe9;ndez-Proupin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palacios</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahn&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic and atomic structure of complex defects in highly n-type
  doped ZnO films</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures, UTF-8 encoding. To be published</comments><journal-ref>Mat. Chem. Phys.160, 420-428 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.matchemphys.2015.05.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Point defects in Ga- and Al-doped ZnO thin films are studied by means of
first principles electronic structure calculations. Candidate defects are
identified to explain recently observed differences in electrical and
spectroscopical behavior of both systems. Substitutional doping in Ga-ZnO
explain the metallic behavior of the electrical properties. Complexes of
interstitial oxygen with substitutional Ga can behave as acceptor and cause
partial compensation, as well as gap states below the conduction band minimum
as observed in photoemission experiments. Zn vacancies can also act as
compensating acceptors. On the other hand, the semiconducting behavior of
Al-ZnO and the small variation in the optical gap compared with pure ZnO, can
be explained by almost complete compensation between acceptor Zn vacancies and
substitutional Al donors. Interstitial Al can also be donor levels and can be
the origin of the small band observed in photoemission experiments below the
Fermi level. Combinations of substitutional Al with interstitial oxygen can act
simultaneously as compensating acceptor and generator o the mentioned
photoemission band. The theoretical calculations have been done using density
functional theory (DFT) within the generalized gradient approximation with
on-site Coulomb interaction. In selected cases, DFT calculations with
semilocal-exact exchange hybrid functionals have been performed. Results are
compared with photoelectron spectra for Ga-ZnO and Al-ZnO at the corresponding
doping levels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.3736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.3736</id><created>2013-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorkavenko</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sitenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>O. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Casimir energy and force induced by an impenetrable flux tube of finite
  radius</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1207.0224</comments><journal-ref>Intern. J. Mod. Phys. A 28, 1350161 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X13501613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A perfectly reflecting (Dirichlet) boundary condition at the edge of an
impenetrable magnetic-flux-carrying tube of nonzero transverse size is imposed
on the charged massive scalar matter field which is quantized outside the tube.
We show that the vacuum polarization effects outside the tube give rise to a
macroscopic force acting at the increase of the tube radius (if the magnetic
flux is held steady). The Casimir energy and force are periodic in the value of
the magnetic flux, being independent of the coupling to the space-time
curvature scalar. We conclude that a topological defect of the vortex type can
polarize the vacuum of only those quantum fields that have masses which are
much less than a scale of the spontaneous symmetry breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.6664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.6664</id><created>2013-12-23</created><updated>2014-02-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borot</keyname><forenames>Ga&#xeb;tan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guionnet</keyname><forenames>Alice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozlowski</keyname><forenames>Karol K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-N asymptotic expansion for mean field models with Coulomb gas
  interaction</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>52 pages ; v2 : change of title, references added + some more details
  in the proof of regularity (Section 7)</comments><msc-class>60Fxx, 82B05, 46-XX</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. Math. Res. Not. (2015) 2015 (20): 10451-10524</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the large-N, all order asymptotic expansion for a system of N
particles with mean-field interactions on top of a Coulomb repulsion at
temperature 1/\beta, under the assumptions that the interactions are analytic,
off-critical, and satisfy a local strict convexity assumption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2562</id><created>2014-06-10</created><updated>2015-06-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiuchi&#xfa;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diamantini</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gammaitoni</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conditional entropy and Landauer principle</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>EPL 111 4 (2015) 40004</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/111/40004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Landauer principle describes the minimum heat produced by an
information-processing device. Recently a new term has been included in the
minimum heat production: it's called conditional entropy and takes into account
the microstates content of a given logic state. Usually this term is assumed
zero in bistable symmetric systems thanks to the strong hypothesis used to
derive Landauer principle. In this paper we show that conditional entropy can
be nonzero even for bistable symmetric systems and that it can be expressed as
the sum of three different terms related to the probabilistic features of the
device. The contribution of the three terms to conditional entropy (and thus to
minimum heat production) is then discussed for the case of bit-reset.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.0298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.0298</id><created>2014-08-01</created><updated>2014-10-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kogan</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khasin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meerson</keyname><forenames>Baruch</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myers</keyname><forenames>Christopher R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-strain competition in quasi-neutral stochastic disease dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.PE</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 90, 042149 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.90.042149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a new perturbation method for studying quasi-neutral competition
in a broad class of stochastic competition models, and apply it to the analysis
of fixation of competing strains in two epidemic models. The first model is a
two-strain generalization of the stochastic Susceptible-Infected-Susceptible
(SIS) model. Here we extend previous results due to Parsons and Quince (2007),
Parsons et al (2008) and Lin, Kim and Doering (2012). The second model, a
two-strain generalization of the stochastic Susceptible-Infected-Recovered
(SIR) model with population turnover, has not been studied previously. In each
of the two models, when the basic reproduction numbers of the two strains are
identical, a system with an infinite population size approaches a point on the
deterministic coexistence line (CL): a straight line of fixed points in the
phase space of sub-population sizes. Shot noise drives one of the strain
populations to fixation, and the other to extinction, on a time scale
proportional to the total population size. Our perturbation method explicitly
tracks the dynamics of the probability distribution of the sub-populations in
the vicinity of the CL. We argue that, whereas the slow strain has a
competitive advantage for mathematically &quot;typical&quot; initial conditions, it is
the fast strain that is more likely to win in the important situation when a
few infectives of both strains are introduced into a susceptible population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.3231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.3231</id><created>2014-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Albeverio</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motovilov</keyname><forenames>Alexander K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounds on variation of the spectrum and spectral subspaces of a few-body
  Hamiltonian</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1311.6604</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of International Conference `Nuclear Theory in the
  Supercomputing Era - 2014'. Pacific National University, Khabarovsk, 2016,
  pp. 98-106 (http://ntse.khb.ru/files/uploads/2014/proceedings/Motovilov.pdf)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We overview the recent results on the shift of the spectrum and norm bounds
for variation of spectral subspaces of a Hermitian operator under an additive
Hermitian perturbation. Along with the known results, we present a new subspace
variation bound for the generic off-diagonal subspace perturbation problem. We
also demonstrate how some of the abstract results may work for few-body
Hamiltonians.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.06582</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.06582</id><created>2015-02-23</created><updated>2016-09-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kay</keyname><forenames>Bernard S.</forenames><affiliation>York</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lupo</keyname><forenames>Umberto</forenames><affiliation>York</affiliation></author></authors><title>Non-existence of isometry-invariant Hadamard states for a Kruskal black
  hole in a box and for massless fields on 1+1 Minkowski spacetime with a
  uniformly accelerating mirror</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages, 6 figures. Includes 9 page appendix which points out the
  existence of, and partially fills, a gap in the proofs of the theorems in
  B.S. Kay and R.M. Wald, Physics Reports 207, 49-136 (1991). Several small
  corrections and improvements in the exposition. Accepted for publication in
  Classical and Quantum Gravity</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 215001 (42pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/21/215001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We conjecture that (when the notion of Hadamard state is suitably adapted)
there is no isometry-invariant Hadamard state for the massive or massless
covariant Klein-Gordon equation defined on the region of the Kruskal spacetime
to the left of a surface of constant Schwarzschild radius in the right
Schwarzschild wedge when Dirichlet boundary conditions are put on that surface.
We also prove that, with a suitable definition for 'boost-invariant Hadamard
state' (which we call 'strongly boost-invariant globally-Hadamard') which takes
into account both the existence of the timelike boundary and the special
massless 1+1 infra-red pathology, there is no such state for the massless wave
equation on the region of 1+1 Minkowski space to the left of an eternally
uniformly accelerating mirror -- with Dirichlet boundary conditions. This
result is significant because such a state does exist if there is also a
symmetrically placed decelerating mirror in the left wedge (and the region to
the left of this mirror is excluded). We expect a similar existence result to
hold for Kruskal when there are symmetrically placed spherical boxes in both
right and left Schwarzschild wedges. Our Kruskal no-go conjecture raises basic
questions about the black holes in boxes considered in black hole
thermodynamics. If true, it would lend further support to the conclusion of
B.S. Kay 'Instability of enclosed horizons', Gen. Rel. Grav. 47, 1-27 (2015)
(arXiv: 1310.7395) that the nearest thing to a description of a black hole in
equilibrium in a box in terms of a classical spacetime with quantum fields
propagating on it has, for the classical spacetime, the exterior Schwarzschild
solution, with the classical spacetime picture breaking down near the horizon.
An appendix points out the existence of, and partially fills, a gap in the
proofs of the theorems in B.S. Kay and R.M. Wald Phys. Rep. 207, 49-136 (1991).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02085</id><created>2015-04-08</created><updated>2015-07-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conway</keyname><forenames>Andrew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guttmann</keyname><forenames>Anthony J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional terminally attached self-avoiding walks and bridges</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 015004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/1/015004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study terminally attached self-avoiding walks and bridges on the simple
cubic lattice, both by series analysis and Monte Carlo methods. We provide
strong numerical evidence supporting a scaling relation between self-avoiding
walks, bridges, and terminally attached self-avoiding walks, and posit that a
corresponding amplitude ratio is a universal quantity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04288</id><created>2015-04-16</created><updated>2016-01-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rauer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schweigler</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmiedmayer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Does an isolated quantum system relax?</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures, Proceedings of the International School of
  Physics 'Enrico Fermi' - Course 191 'Quantum Matter at Ultralow
  Temperatures', (removed typos, corrected bibliography)</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Internat. School Phys. Enrico Fermi 191, 485 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3254/978-1-61499-694-1-485</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Statistical mechanics is one of the most comprehensive theories in physics.
From a boiling pot of water to the complex dynamics of quantum many-body
systems it provides a successful connection between the microscopic dynamics of
atoms and molecules and the macroscopic properties of matter. However,
statistical mechanics only describes the thermal equilibrium situation of a
system, and there is no general framework to describe how equilibrium is
reached or under which circumstances it can be reached at all. This problem is
particularly challenging in quantum mechanics, where unitarity appears to
render the very concept of thermalization counterintuitive. With the rapid
experimental progress in the control and probing of ultracold quantum gases
this question has become within reach of detailed experimental investigations.
In these notes we present a series of experiments with ultracold
one-dimensional Bose gases, which provide novel insights into this fundamental
question.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06797</id><created>2015-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Men&#xe9;ndez-Proupin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orellana</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tellurium vacancy in cadmium telluride revisited: size effects in the
  electronic properties</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Status Solidi B 252, 2649-2656 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssb.201552357</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum states and thermodynamical properties of the Te vacancy in CdTe
are addressed by first principles calculations, including the supercell size
and quasiparticle corrections. It is shown that the 64-atoms supercell
calculation is not suitable to model the band structure of the isolated Te
vacancy. This problem can be solved with a larger 216-atoms supercell, where
the band structure of the defect seems to be a perturbation of that of the
perfect crystal. It is interesting to note that the Te-vacancy formation energy
calculated with both supercell sizes are close in energy, which is attributed
to error cancelation. We also show that the interplay between supercell size
effects and the band gap underestimation of the generalized gradient
approximation strongly influences the predicted symmetry of some charge states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02467</id><created>2015-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhedong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunjko</keyname><forenames>Vanja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olshanii</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author></authors><title>Atom transistor from the point of view of quantum nonequilibrium
  dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17, 125008 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the atom field-effect transistor scheme [J. A. Stickney, D. Z.
Anderson and A. A. Zozulya, Phys. Rev. A 75, 013608 (2007)] using the standard
tools of nonequlilibrium dynamics. In particular, we study the deviations from
the Eigenstate Thermalization Hypothesis, quantum fluctuations, and the density
of states, both ab initio and using their mean-field analogues. Having fully
established the quantum vs. mean-field correspondence for this system, we
attempt, using a mean-field model, to interpret the off-on threshold in our
transistor as the onset of ergodicity---a point where the system becomes able
to visit the thermal values of the former integrals of motion in principle,
albeit not being fully thermalized yet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05864</id><created>2015-06-18</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aubert</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>The BABAR Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>others</keyname><affiliation>The BABAR Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Collins asymmetries in inclusive charged $KK$ and $K\pi$ pairs produced
  in $e^+e^-$ annihilation</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 postscript figures, 5 pages of Supplemental Material</comments><report-no>SLAC-PUB-16311</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 111101 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.111101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of Collins asymmetries in the inclusive process
$e^+e^- \rightarrow h_1 h_2 X$, $h_1h_2=KK,\, K\pi,\, \pi\pi$, at the
center-of-mass energy of 10.6 GeV, using a data sample of 468 fb$^{-1}$
collected by the BaBar experiment at the PEP-II $B$ factory at SLAC National
Accelerator Center. Considering hadrons in opposite thrust hemispheres of
hadronic events, we observe clear azimuthal asymmetries in the ratio of unlike-
to like-sign, and unlike- to all charged $h_1 h_2$ pairs, which increase with
hadron energies. The $K\pi$ asymmetries are similar to those measured for the
$\pi\pi$ pairs, whereas those measured for high-energy $KK$ pairs are, in
general, larger.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00404</id><created>2015-07-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Men&#xe9;ndez-Proupin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xed;os</keyname><forenames>Carlos L. Beltr&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wahn&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-hydrogenic excitons in perovskite CH$_3$NH$_3$PbI$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Status Solidi RRL 9, 559-563 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssr.201510265</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The excitons in the orthorhombic phase of the perovskite CH$_3$NH$_3$PbI$_3$
are studied using the effective mass approximation. The electron-hole
interaction is screened by a distance-dependent dielectric function, as
described by the Haken potential or the Pollmann-B\&quot;uttner potential. The
energy spectrum and the eigenfunctions are calculated for both cases. The
effective masses, the low and high frequency dielectric constants, and the
interband absorption matrix elements, are obtained from generalized density
functional theory calculations. The results show that the Pollmann-B\&quot;uttner
model provides better agreement with the experimental results. The discrete
part of the exciton spectrum is composed of a fundamental state with a binding
energy of 24 meV, and higher states that are within 2 meV from the onset the
unbound exciton continuum. Light absorption is dominated by the fundamental
line with an oscillator strength of 0.013, followed by the exciton continuum.
The calculations have been performed without fitting any parameter from
experiments and are in close agreement with recent experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01669</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Linch</keyname><forenames>William D</forenames><suffix>III</suffix></author><author><keyname>Siegel</keyname><forenames>Warren</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical Super F-theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Notation improved and minor errors corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present F-theories that reduce to 10D Type II Green-Schwarz superstrings.
They vary in manifest U-duality according to division between spacetime and
&quot;internal&quot; coordinates. They are defined by selfdual current superalgebras in
higher worldvolume dimensions with manifest $\mathrm G\times \mathrm G'$
symmetry where the spacetime symmetry $\mathrm G=\mathrm E_{n(n)}$ ranges over
the (split form of the) exceptional groups with ranks $n=\mathrm D+1 \leq 7$
and the internal symmetry $\mathrm {G'= GL(10-D)}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02975</id><created>2015-07-10</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Amiri</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wallden</keyname><forenames>Petros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kent</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersson</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author></authors><title>Secure Quantum Signatures Using Insecure Quantum Channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages including supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 032325 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.032325</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Digital signatures are widely used in modern communication to guarantee
authenticity and transferability of messages, The security of currently used
classical schemes relies on computational assumptions. We present a quantum
signature scheme that does not require trusted quantum channels. We prove that
it is unconditionally secure against the most general coherent attacks, and
show that it requires the transmission of significantly fewer quantum states
than previous schemes. We also show that the quantum channel noise threshold
for our scheme is less strict than for distilling a secure key using quantum
key distribution. This shows that direct quantum signature schemes can be
preferable to signature schemes relying on secret shared keys generated using
quantum key distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05954</id><created>2015-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Olshanii</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames><affiliation>University of Massachusetts Boston</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Steven G.</forenames><affiliation>University of Massachusetts Boston</affiliation></author></authors><title>An exactly solvable quantum four-body problem associated with the
  symmetries of an octacube</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys., 17, 105005 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we show that eigenenergies and eigenstates of a system
consisting of four one-dimensional hard-core particles with masses $6m$, $2m$,
$m$, and $3m$ in a hard-wall box can be found exactly using Bethe Ansatz. The
Ansatz is based on the exceptional affine reflection group $\tilde{F}_{4}$
associated with the symmetries and tiling properties of an octacube---a
Platonic solid unique to four dimensions, with no three-dimensional analogues.
We also uncover the Liouville integrability structure of our problem: the four
integrals of motion in involution are identified as invariant polynomials of
the finite reflection group $F_{4}$, taken as functions of the components of
momenta.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02065</id><created>2015-09-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Olshanii</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunjko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feiguin</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrin</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruhl</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aveline</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-dimensional Gross-Pitaevskii solitary waves in optical lattices:
  stabilization using the artificial quartic kinetic energy induced by lattice
  shaking</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 figure, accepted in Phys. Lett. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. A 380, 177 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Letter, we show that a three-dimensional Bose-Einstein solitary wave
can become stable if the dispersion law is changed from quadratic to quartic.
We suggest a way to realize the quartic dispersion, using shaken optical
lattices. Estimates show that the resulting solitary waves can occupy as little
as $\sim 1/20$-th of the Brillouin zone in each of the three directions and
contain as many as $N = 10^{3}$ atoms, thus representing a \textit{fully
mobile} macroscopic three-dimensional object.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06240</id><created>2015-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Nozari</keyname><forenames>Kourosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashidi</keyname><forenames>Narges</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing an Inflation Model with Nonminimal Derivative Coupling in the
  Light of PLANCK 2015 Data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  1252689</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of a generalized inflationary model in which both the
scalar field and its derivatives are coupled to the gravity. We consider a
general form of the nonminimal derivative coupling in order to have a complete
treatment of the model. By expanding the action up to the second order in
perturbation, we study the spectrum of the primordial modes of the
perturbations. Also, by expanding the action up to the third order and
considering the three point correlation functions, the amplitude of the
non-Gaussianity of the primordial perturbations is studied both in equilateral
and orthogonal configurations. Finally, by adopting some sort of potentials, we
compare the model at hand with the Planck 2015 released observational data and
obtain some constraints on the model's parameters space. As an important
result, we show that the nonminimal couplings help to make models of chaotic
inflation, that would otherwise be in tension with Planck data, in better
agreement with the data. This model is consistent with observation at weak
coupling limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08064</id><created>2015-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Peropadre</keyname><forenames>Borja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerreschi</keyname><forenames>Gian Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huh</keyname><forenames>Joonsuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Al&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Microwave Boson Sampling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 140505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.140505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first post-classical computation will most probably be performed not on a
universal quantum computer, but rather on a dedicated quantum hardware. A
strong candidate for achieving this is represented by the task of sampling from
the output distribution of linear quantum optical networks. This problem, known
as boson sampling, has recently been shown to be intractable for any classical
computer, but it is naturally carried out by running the corresponding
experiment. However, only small scale realizations of boson sampling
experiments have been demonstrated to date. Their main limitation is related to
the non-deterministic state preparation and inefficient measurement step. Here,
we propose an alternative setup to implement boson sampling that is based on
microwave photons and not on optical photons. The certified scalability of
superconducting devices indicates that this direction is promising for a
large-scale implementation of boson sampling and allows for more flexible
features like arbitrary state preparation and efficient photon-number
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04572</id><created>2015-11-14</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banda</keyname><forenames>Mapundi K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uoane</keyname><forenames>Tumelo R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Stability notion for the viscous Shallow Water Discrete-Velocity
  Boltzmann Equations</title><categories>math.NA physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>30 pages, Keywords: viscous shallow water equations, lattice
  Boltzmann equations, reduced gravity, computational method and stability</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stability of Lattice Boltzmann Equations modelling Shallow Water
Equations in the special case of reduced gravity is investigated theoretically.
A stability notion is defined as applied in incompressible Navier-Stokes
equations in Banda, M. K., Yong, W.- A. and Klar, A: A stability notion for
lattice Boltzmann equations. SIAM J. Sci. Comput. {\bf 27(6)}, 2098-2111
(2006). It is found that to maintain stability a careful choice of the value of
the reduced gravity must be made. The stability notion is employed to
investigate different shallow water lattice Boltzmann Equations. Results are
tested using the Lattice Boltzmann Method for various values of the governing
parameters of the flow. It is observed that even for the discrete model the
reduced gravity has a significant effect on the stability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00143</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Alternative Approach to Noncommutative Quantum Mechanics on a Curved
  Space</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, some changes; in sect.3, sect.4, sect.5</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting with the first-order singular Lagrangian containing the redundant
variables, the noncommutative quantum mechanics on a curved space is
investigated by the constraint star-product quantization formalism of the
projection operator method. Imposing the additional constraints to eliminate
the reduntant degrees of freedom, the noncommutative quantum system with
noncommutativity among the coordinates on the curved space is exactly
constructed. Then, it is shown that the resultant Hamiltonian contains the
quantum corrections in the exact form. We further discuss the additional
constraints to realize the noncommutativities both of coordinates and momenta
on the curved space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01093</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fonda</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canessa</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Making Ideas at Scientific Fabrication Laboratories</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.CY</categories><comments>12 pages, PDF, to Appear</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Education 51 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-9120/51/6/065016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Creativity, together with the making of ideas into fruition, is essential for
progress. Today the evolution from an idea to its application can be
facilitated by the implementation of Fabrication Laboratories, or FabLabs,
having affordable digital tools for prototyping. FabLabs aiming at scientific
research and invention are now starting to be established inside Universities,
Research Centers and Schools. We review the setting up of the ICTP Scientific
FabLab in Trieste, Italy, give concrete examples on the use in physics, and
propose to replicate world-wide this class of multi-purpose workplaces within
academia as a support for physics and math education and for community
development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03264</id><created>2015-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Renyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>I-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapman</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khestanova</keyname><forenames>Ekaterina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigorieva</keyname><forenames>Irina V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity in potassium-doped metallic polymorphs of MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures plus 7 supplementary figures in Nano Letters,
  November 27, 2015</comments><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 16, 629-636 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b04361</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconducting layered transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs) stand out
among other superconductors due to the tunable nature of the superconducting
transition, coexistence with other collective electronic excitations (charge
density waves) and strong intrinsic spin-orbit coupling. Molybdenum disulphide
(MoS2) is the most studied representative of this family of materials,
especially since the recent demonstration of the possibility to tune its
critical temperature, Tc, by electric-field doping. However, just one of its
polymorphs, band-insulator 2H-MoS2, has so far been explored for its potential
to host superconductivity. We have investigated the possibility to induce
superconductivity in metallic polytypes, 1T- and 1T'-MoS2, by potassium (K)
intercalation. We demonstrate that at doping levels significantly higher than
that required to induce superconductivity in 2H-MoS2, both 1T and 1T' phases
become superconducting, with Tc = 2.8 and 4.6K, respectively. Unusually, K
intercalation in this case is responsible both for the structural and
superconducting phase transitions. By adding new members to the family of
superconducting TMDs our findings open the way to further manipulate and
enhance the electronic properties of these technologically important materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05831</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Molina</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doring</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The pole structure of the Lambda(1405) in a recent QCD simulation</title><categories>hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 056010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.056010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $\Lambda(1405)$ baryon is difficult to detect in experiment, absent in
many quark model calculations, and supposedly manifested through a two-pole
structure. Its uncommon properties made it subject to numerous experimental and
theoretical studies in recent years. Lattice-QCD eigenvalues for different
quark masses were recently reported by the Adelaide group. We compare these
eigenvalues to predictions of a model based on Unitary Chiral Perturbation
Theory. The UCHPT calculation predicts the quark mass dependence remarkably
well. It also explains the overlap pattern with different meson-baryon
components, mainly $\pi\Sigma$ and $\bar KN$, at different quark masses. More
accurate lattice QCD data are required to draw definite conclusions on the
nature of the $\Lambda(1405)$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08767</id><created>2015-12-29</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caudrelier</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doyon</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>The Quench Map in an Integrable Classical Field Theory: Nonlinear
  Schr\&quot;odinger Equation</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math.AP math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>35 pages. Matches published version. Added Appendix to clarify
  analytic structure of the quench map. Corrected some typos. Updated
  references</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A49 (2016) 445201</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the non-equilibrium dynamics obtained by an abrupt change (a {\em
quench}) in the parameters of an integrable classical field theory, the
nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation. We first consider explicit one-soliton
examples, which we fully describe by solving the direct part of the inverse
scattering problem. We then develop some aspects of the general theory using
elements of the inverse scattering method. For this purpose, we introduce the
{\em quench map} which acts on the space of scattering data and represents the
change of parameter with fixed field configuration (initial condition). We
describe some of its analytic properties by implementing a higher level version
of the inverse scattering method, and we discuss the applications of
Darboux-B\&quot;acklund transformations, Gelfand-Levitan-Marchenko equations and the
Rosales series solution to a related, dual quench problem. Finally, we comment
on the interplay between quantum and classical tools around the theme of
quenches and on the usefulness of the quantization of our classical approach to
the quantum quench problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09215</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2016-03-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Xiaofeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the QCD Phase Structure with Beam Energy Scan in Heavy-ion
  Collisions</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 14 figures. Proceedings of the Quark Matter 2015 conference,
  Kobe, Japan</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics A 956 (2016) 75-82</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.03.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Beam energy scan programs in heavy-ion collisions aim to explore the QCD
phase structure at high baryon density. Sensitive observables are applied to
probe the signatures of the QCD phase transition and critical point in
heavy-ion collisions at RHIC and SPS. Intriguing structures, such as dip, peak
and oscillation, have been observed in the energy dependence of various
observables. In this paper, an overview is given and corresponding physics
implications will be discussed for the experimental highlights from the beam
energy scan programs at the STAR, PHENIX and NA61/SHINE experiments.
Furthermore, the beam energy scan phase II at RHIC (2019-2020) and other future
experimental facilities for studying the physics at low energies will be also
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06716</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Poulikakos</keyname><forenames>Lisa V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutsche</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>McPeak</keyname><forenames>Kevin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niegemann</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafner</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norris</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Optical Chirality Flux as a Useful Far-Field Probe of Chiral Near
  Fields</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 3, 1619 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.6b00201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To optimize the interaction between chiral matter and highly twisted light,
quantities that can help characterize chiral electromagnetic fields near
nanostructures are needed. Here, by analogy with Poynting's theorem, we
formulate the time-averaged conservation law of optical chirality in lossy
dispersive media and identify the optical chirality flux as an ideal far-field
observable for characterizing chiral optical near fields. Bounded by the
conservation law, we show that it provides precise information, unavailable
from circular dichroism spectroscopy, on the magnitude and handedness of highly
twisted fields near nanostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00295</id><created>2016-01-31</created><updated>2016-03-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boyer</keyname><forenames>Timothy H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Understanding the Planck Blackbody Spectrum and Landau Diamagnetism
  within Classical Electromagnetism</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. J. Phys. 37, 065102(17) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0143-0807/37/6/065102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetism is a \textit{relativistic} theory and one must exercise care
in coupling this theory with \textit{nonrelativistic} classical mechanics and
with \textit{nonrelativistic} classical statistical mechanics. Indeed
historically, both the blackbody radiation spectrum and diamagnetism within
classical theory have been misunderstood because of two crucial failures: 1)the
neglect of classical electromagnetic zero-point radiation, and 2) the use of
erroneous combinations of nonrelativistic mechanics with relativistic
electrodynamics. Here we review the treatment of classical blackbody radiation,
and show that use of Lorentz-invariant classical electromagnetic zero-point
radiation can be used to explain both the Planck blackbody spectrum and Landau
diamagnetism at thermal equilibrium within classical electromagnetic theory.
The analysis requires that relativistic electromagnetism is joined
appropriately with simple nonrelativistic mechanical systems which can be
regarded as the zero-velocity limits of relativistic systems, and that
nonrelativistic classical statistical mechanics is applied only in the
low-frequency limit when zero-point energy makes no contribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00697</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Christian</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Newton's Theorem of Revolving Orbits in Curved Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Newton's theorem of revolving orbits states that one can multiply the angular
speed of a Keplerian orbit by a factor $k$ by applying a radial inverse cubed
force proportional to $(1-k^2)$. In this paper we derive an extension of this
theorem in general relativity, valid for the motion of massive particles in any
static, spherically symmetric metrics. We verify the Newtonian limit of this
extension and demonstrate that there is no such generalization for rotating
metrics. Further we also extend the theory to the case of charged particles in
the Einstein-Maxwell and Kaluza-Klein theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02212</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>STAR Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Adamczyk</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adkins</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agakishiev</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aggarwal</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahammed</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alekseev</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aparin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arkhipkin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aschenauer</keyname><forenames>E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashraf</keyname><forenames>M. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Attri</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Averichev</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bairathi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellwied</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhasin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhati</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattarai</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bielcik</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bielcikova</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordyuzhin</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchet</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandenburg</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunzarov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butterworth</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caines</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>M. Calder&#xf3;n de la Barca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cebra</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakaberia</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaloupka</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chattopadhyay</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherney</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christie</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contin</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Silva</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debbe</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedovich</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derevschikov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>di Ruzza</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Didenko</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dilks</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drachenberg</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draper</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunkelberger</keyname><forenames>L. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlop</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efimov</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engelage</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eppley</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esha</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evdokimov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyser</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fatemi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Federic</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorisin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filip</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisyak</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flores</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulek</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gagliardi</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garand</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geurts</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Girard</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosnick</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunarathne</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guryn</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamad</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamed</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haque</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heppelmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heppelmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirsch</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>G. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horvat</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>H. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huck</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Humanic</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Igo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobs</keyname><forenames>W. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jentsch</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Judd</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabana</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalinkin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kauder</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keane</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kechechyan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiko&#x142;a</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisel</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisiel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kochenda</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koetke</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosarzewski</keyname><forenames>L. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraishan</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kravtsov</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krueger</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamont</keyname><forenames>M. A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landgraf</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landry</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauret</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebedev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lednicky</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisa</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ljubicic</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llope</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lomnitz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longacre</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magdy</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majka</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manion</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margetis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markert</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matis</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDonald</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKinzie</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meehan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minaev</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mioduszewski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondal</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mustafa</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasim</keyname><forenames>Md.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nigmatkulov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niida</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogach</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noh</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nurushev</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Odyniec</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okorokov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olvitt</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Page</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pak</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Y. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandit</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panebratsev</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pawlik</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pei</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkins</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pile</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pluta</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poniatowska</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poskanzer</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Powell</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pruthi</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putschke</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quintero</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramachandran</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reed</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritter</keyname><forenames>H. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rogachevskiy</keyname><forenames>O. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusnak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusnakova</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>N. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakrejda</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salur</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandweiss</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schambach</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scharenberg</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmah</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidke</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmitz</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seger</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seyboth</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shahaliev</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shanmuganathan</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>W. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shou</keyname><forenames>Q. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sichtermann</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikora</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singha</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skoby</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solyst</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorensen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spinka</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanislaus</keyname><forenames>T. D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stock</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strikhanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stringfellow</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumbera</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Summa</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>X. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surrow</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svirida</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarnowsky</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tawfik</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Th&#xe4;der</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Timmins</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tlusty</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todoroki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokarev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trentalange</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tribble</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tribedy</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tripathy</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>O. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ullrich</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Underwood</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upsal</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Buren</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Nieuwenhuizen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandenbroucke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varma</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vertesi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Videb&#xe6;k</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vokal</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voloshin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vossen</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westfall</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieman</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wissink</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yip</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>I. -K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zbroszczyk</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zha</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>X. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoulkarneeva</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zyzak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\rm{J}/\psi$ production at low transverse momentum in p+p and d+Au
  collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$ = 200 GeV</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 064904 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.064904</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the measurement of $\rm{J}/\psi$ production in the dielectron
channel at mid-rapidity (|y|&lt;1) in p+p and d+Au collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$ =
200 GeV from the STAR experiment at the Relativistic Heavy Ion Collider. The
transverse momentum $p_{T}$ spectra in p+p for $p_{T}$ &lt; 4 GeV/c and d+Au
collisions for $p_{T}$ &lt; 3 GeV/c are presented. These measurements extend the
STAR coverage for $\rm{J}/\psi$ production in p+p collisions to low $p_{T}$.
The $&lt;p_{T}^{2}&gt;$ from the measured $\rm{J}/\psi$ invariant cross section in
p+p and d+Au collisions are evaluated and compared to similar measurements at
other collision energies. The nuclear modification factor for $\rm{J}/\psi$ is
extracted as a function of $p_{T}$ and collision centrality in d+Au and
compared to model calculations using the modified nuclear Parton Distribution
Function and a final-state $\rm{J}/\psi$ nuclear absorption cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02653</id><created>2016-02-08</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kehagias</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riotto</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>BMS in Cosmology</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/05/059</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Symmetries play an interesting role in cosmology. They are useful in
characterizing the cosmological perturbations generated during inflation and
lead to consistency relations involving the soft limit of the statistical
correlators of large-scale structure dark matter and galaxies overdensities. On
the other hand, in observational cosmology the carriers of the information
about these large-scale statistical distributions are light rays traveling on
null geodesics. Motivated by this simple consideration, we study the structure
of null infinity and the associated BMS symmetry in a cosmological setting. For
decelerating Friedmann-Robertson-Walker backgrounds, for which future null
infinity exists, we find that the BMS transformations which leaves the
asymptotic metric invariant to leading order. Contrary to the asymptotic flat
case, the BMS transformations in cosmology generate Goldstone modes
corresponding to both scalar and tensor degrees of freedom which may exist at
null infinity and perturb the asymptotic data. Therefore, BMS transformations
generate physically inequivalent vacua as they populate the universe at null
infinity with these physical degrees of freedom. We also discuss the
gravitational memory effect when cosmological expansion is taken into account.
In this case, there are extra contribution to the gravitational memory due to
the tail of the retarded Green functions which are supported not only on the
light-cone, but also in its interior. The gravitational memory effect can be
understood also from an asymptotic point of view as a transition among
cosmological BMS-related vacua.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08187</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takada</keyname><forenames>Kabuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimori</keyname><forenames>Hidetoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical properties of dissipative quantum spin systems in finite
  dimensions</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure. v2: a reference added, minor revision, and change
  to 1 column layout</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 435001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/43/435001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the critical properties of finite-dimensional dissipative quantum
spin systems with uniform ferromagnetic interactions. Starting from the
transverse-field Ising model coupled to a bath of harmonic oscillators with
Ohmic spectral density, we generalize its classical representation to classical
spin systems with $O(n)$ symmetry and then take the large-$n$ limit to reduce
the system to the spherical model. The exact solution to the resulting
spherical model with long-range interactions along the imaginary-time axis
shows a phase transition with static critical exponents coinciding with those
of the conventional short-range spherical model in $d+2$ dimensions, where $d$
is the spatial dimensionality of the original quantum system. This implies the
dynamical exponent to be $z=2$. These conclusions are consistent with the
results of Monte Carlo simulations and renormalization group calculations for
dissipative transverse-field Ising and $O(n)$ models in one and two dimensions.
The present approach therefore serves as a useful tool to analytically
investigate the properties of quantum phase transitions of the dissipative
transverse-field Ising and related models. Our method may also offer a platform
to study more complex phase transitions in dissipative finite-dimensional
quantum spin systems, which recently receive renewed interest under the context
of quantum annealing in a noisy environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03037</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chevallard</keyname><forenames>Jacopo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charlot</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling and interpreting spectral energy distributions of galaxies
  with BEAGLE</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>added missing term in equation 4.1 (Erratum submitted to MNRAS)</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1756</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new-generation tool to model and interpret spectral energy
distributions (SEDs) of galaxies, which incorporates in a consistent way the
production of radiation and its transfer through the interstellar and
intergalactic media. This flexible tool, named BEAGLE (for BayEsian Analysis of
GaLaxy sEds), allows one to build mock galaxy catalogues as well as to
interpret any combination of photometric and spectroscopic galaxy observations
in terms of physical parameters. The current version of the tool includes
versatile modeling of the emission from stars and photoionized gas, attenuation
by dust and accounting for different instrumental effects, such as
spectroscopic flux calibration and line spread function. We show a first
application of the BEAGLE tool to the interpretation of broadband SEDs of a
published sample of ${\sim}10^4$ galaxies at redshifts $0.1 \lesssim
z\lesssim8$. We find that the constraints derived on photometric redshifts
using this multi-purpose tool are comparable to those obtained using public,
dedicated photometric-redshift codes and quantify this result in a rigorous
statistical way. We also show how the post-processing of BEAGLE output data
with the Python extension PYP-BEAGLE allows the characterization of systematic
deviations between models and observations, in particular through posterior
predictive checks. The modular design of the BEAGLE tool allows easy extensions
to incorporate, for example, the absorption by neutral galactic and
circumgalactic gas, and the emission from an active galactic nucleus, dust and
shock-ionized gas. Information about public releases of the BEAGLE tool will be
maintained on http://www.jacopochevallard.org/beagle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03578</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-04-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhan</keyname><forenames>Q. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuo</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>L. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Run-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of anomalous-Hall and spin-Hall effects of
  antiferromagnetic IrMn sandwiched by Pt and YIG layers</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 120.133901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an investigation of temperature and IrMn layered thickness
dependence of anomalous-Hall resistance (AHR), anisotropic magnetoresistance
(AMR), and magnetization on Pt/Ir20Mn80/Y3Fe5O12 (Pt/IrMn/YIG)
heterostructures. The magnitude of AHR is dramatically enhanced compared with
Pt/YIG bilayers. The enhancement is much more profound at higher temperatures
and peaks at the IrMn thickness of 3 nm. The observed spin-Hall
magnetoresistance (SMR) in the temperature range of 10-300 K indicates that the
spin current generated in the Pt layer can penetrate the entire thickness of
the IrMn layer to interact with the YIG layer. The lack of conventional
anisotropic magnetoresistance (CAMR) implies that the insertion of the IrMn
layer between Pt and YIG efficiently suppresses the magnetic proximity effect
(MPE) on induced Pt moments by YIG. Our results suggest that the dual roles of
the InMn insertion in Pt/IrMn/YIG heterostructures are to block the MPE and to
transport the spin current between Pt and YIG layers. We discuss possible
mechanisms for the enhanced AHR.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03686</id><created>2016-03-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Reinholz</keyname><forenames>Daniel L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dounas-Frazer</keyname><forenames>Dimitri R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using Peer Feedback to Promote Reflection on Open-Ended Problems</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>14 pages (preprint format), 2 figures; accepted for publication in
  The Physics Teacher</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Teach. 54, 364 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4961181</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper describes a new approach for learning from homework, called
Peer-Assisted Reflection (PAR). PAR involves students using peer feedback to
improve their work on open-ended homework problems. Collaborating with peers
and revising one's work based on the feedback of others are important aspects
of doing and learning physics. While notable exceptions exist, homework and
exams are generally individual activities that do not support collaboration and
refinement, which misses important opportunities to use assessment for
learning. In contrast, PAR provides students with a structure to iteratively
engage with challenging, open-ended problems and solicit the input of their
peers to improve their work.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05012</id><created>2016-03-16</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Albi</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pareschi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Selective model-predictive control for flocking systems</title><categories>math.OC math.NA nlin.AO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the optimal control of alignment models composed by a large
number of agents is investigated in presence of a selective action of a
controller, acting in order to enhance consensus. Two types of selective
controls have been presented: an homogeneous control filtered by a selective
function and a distributed control active only on a selective set. As a first
step toward a reduction of computational cost, we introduce a model predictive
control (MPC) approximation by deriving a numerical scheme with a feedback
selective constrained dynamics. Next, in order to cope with the numerical
solution of a large number of interacting agents, we derive the mean-field
limit of the feedback selective constrained dynamics, which eventually will be
solved numerically by means of a stochastic algorithm, able to simulate
efficiently the selective constrained dynamics. Finally, several numerical
simulations are reported to show the efficiency of the proposed techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00086</id><created>2016-03-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Khestanova</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guinea</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fumagalli</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geim</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigorieva</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Graphene bubbles on a substrate : Universal shape and van der Waals
  pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures, supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12587 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12587</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Trapped substances between a 2D crystal, such as graphene, and an atomically
flat substrate, for example, hexagonal boron nitride, give rise to the
formation of bubbles. We show that the size, shape and internal pressure inside
these bubbles are determined by the competition between van der Waals
attraction of a 2D crystal to the substrate and the elastic energy needed to
deform the atomically thin layer. This presents opportunities to use bubbles to
study the elasticity of 2D materials as well as the conditions of confinement,
yet none of these have been explored so far, either theoretically or
experimentally. We have created a variety of bubbles formed by monolayers of
graphene, hBN and MoS2 mechanically exfoliated onto hBN, graphite and MoS2
substrates. Their shapes, analyzed using atomic force microscopy, are found to
exhibit universal scaling with well-defined aspect ratios, in agreement with
theoretical analysis based on general properties of membranes. We also measured
the pressure induced by the confinement, which increased with decreasing
bubble's size and reached tens on MPa inside submicron bubbles. This agrees
with our theory estimates and suggests that for bubbles with radii &lt; 10 nm
hydrostatic pressures can reach close to 1 GPa, which may modify the properties
of a trapped material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01240</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawabe</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Causal dynamical triangulation of a 3D tensor model</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>17pages,12figures, typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Prog.Theor.Exp.Phys.(2016)073B04</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw085</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the string field theory of 2D generalized causal dynamical
triangulation (GCDT) with the Ishibashi-Kawai type (IK-type) interaction
formulated by the matrix model to the 3D model of the surface field theory.
Based on the loop gas model, we construct a tensor model for the discretized
surface field and then apply it the stochastic quantization method. In the
double-scaling limit, the model is characterized by two scaling dimensions $D$
and $D_N$, the power indices of the minimal length as the scaling parameter.
The continuum GCDT model with the IK-type interaction is realized with a
similar restriction in the $D_N$-$D$ space to the 2D model. The distinct
property in the 3D model is that the quantum effect contains the IK-type
interaction only, while the ordinary splitting interaction is excluded.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04033</id><created>2016-04-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Meisel</keyname><forenames>Zach</forenames></author></authors><title>From dripline to dripline: Nuclear astrophysics in the laboratory</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings for invited review to GSI FAIRNESS 2016</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 742 012019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/742/1/012019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the better part of a century the field of nuclear astrophysics has aimed
to answer fundamental questions about nature, such as the origin of the
elements and the behavior of high-density, low-temperature matter. Sustained
and concerted efforts in nuclear experiment have been key to achieving progress
in these areas and will continue to be so. Here I will briefly review recent
accomplishments and open questions in experimental nuclear astrophysics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04239</id><created>2016-04-14</created><updated>2016-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gallavotti</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author></authors><title>Ergodicity: a historical perspective. Equilibrium and Nonequilibrium</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>92 pages; 4 figures v2 changed figure in app D, typos corrected, some
  characters colors changed, and some rm character changed to slanted. arXiv
  admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1311.6448</comments><report-no>FM 2-16</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. H 41, 181-259 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjh/e2016-70030-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A view on the physical meaning of the so called ergodic hypothesis: its role
on the foundations of equilibrium statistical mechanics in mid '800, its
interpretations and hints at its relevance for modern nonequilibrium
statistical mechanics. Followed by appendices with detailed comments on the
original papers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05244</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>W. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>D. -M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrimination of nuclear and electronic recoil events using plasma
  effect in germanium detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>16 Pages, 12 figures in JINST 2016</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation, Volume 11, P07008, July 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/07/P07008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new method of using the plasma time difference, which results
from the plasma effect, between the nuclear and electronic recoil events in
high-purity germanium detectors to distinguish these two types of events in the
search for rare physics processes. The physics mechanism of the plasma effect
is discussed in detail. A numerical model is developed to calculate the plasma
time for nuclear and electronic recoils at various energies in germanium
detectors. It can be shown that under certain conditions the plasma time
difference is large enough to be observable. The experimental aspects in
realizing such a discrimination in germanium detectors is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06130</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-09-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kamenev</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meerson</keyname><forenames>Baruch</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasorov</keyname><forenames>Pavel V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Short-time height distribution in 1d KPZ equation: starting from a
  parabola</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 032108 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.032108</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the probability distribution $\mathcal{P}(H,t,L)$ of the surface
height $h(x=0,t)=H$ in the Kardar-Parisi-Zhang (KPZ) equation in $1+1$
dimension when starting from a parabolic interface, $h(x,t=0)=x^2/L$. The
limits of $L\to\infty$ and $L\to 0$ have been recently solved exactly for any
$t&gt;0$. Here we address the early-time behavior of $\mathcal{P}(H,t,L)$ for
general $L$. We employ the weak-noise theory - a variant of WKB approximation
-- which yields the optimal history of the interface, conditioned on reaching
the given height $H$ at the origin at time $t$. We find that at small $H$
$\mathcal{P}(H,t,L)$ is Gaussian, but its tails are non-Gaussian and highly
asymmetric. In the leading order and in a proper moving frame, the tails behave
as $-\ln \mathcal{P}= f_{+}|H|^{5/2}/t^{1/2}$ and $f_{-}|H|^{3/2}/t^{1/2}$. The
factor $f_{+}(L,t)$ monotonically increases as a function of $L$, interpolating
between time-independent values at $L=0$ and $L=\infty$ that were previously
known. The factor $f_{-}$ is independent of $L$ and $t$, signalling
universality of this tail for a whole class of deterministic initial
conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07472</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zenitani</keyname><forenames>Seiji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagai</keyname><forenames>Tsugunobu</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle dynamics in the electron current layer in collisionless
  magnetic reconnection</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph physics.space-ph</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physics of Plasmas, 23, 102102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4963008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Particle dynamics in the electron current layer in collisionless magnetic
reconnection is investigated by using a particle-in-cell simulation. Electron
motion and velocity distribution functions are studied by tracking
self-consistent trajectories. New classes of electron orbits are discovered:
figure-eight-shaped regular orbits inside the electron jet, noncrossing regular
orbits on the jet flanks, noncrossing Speiser orbits, and nongyrotropic
electrons in the downstream of the jet termination region. Properties of a
super-Alfv\'{e}nic outflow jet are attributed to an ensemble of electrons
traveling through Speiser orbits. Noncrossing orbits are mediated by the
polarization electric field near the electron current layer. The noncrossing
electrons are found to be non-negligible in number density. The impact of these
new orbits to electron mixing, spatial distribution of energetic electrons, and
observational signatures, is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09247</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lahiri</keyname><forenames>Sayantani</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic inflation in Gauss-Bonnet gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures, typos corrected, published in JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/09/025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study anisotropic inflation with Gauss-Bonnet correction in presence of a
massless vector field. In this scenario, exact anisotropic power-law inflation
is realized when the inflaton potential, gauge coupling function and the
Gauss-Bonnet coupling are exponential functions. We show that anisotropy
becomes proportional to two slow-roll parameters of the theory and hence gets
enhanced in presence of quadratic curvature corrections. The stability analysis
reveals that anisotropic power-law solutions remain stable over a substantially
large parameter region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00442</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boley</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaherty</keyname><forenames>K. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ford</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilner</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corder</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>ALMA Observations of HD141569's Circumstellar Disk</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>35 pages, 7 figures, submitted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 829:6 (11pp), 2016 September 20</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present ALMA band 7 (345 GHz) continuum and $^{12}$CO(J = 3-2)
observations of the circumstellar disk surrounding HD141569. At an age of about
5 Myr, the disk has a complex morphology that may be best interpreted as a
nascent debris system with gas. Our $870\rm~\mu m$ ALMA continuum observations
resolve a dust disk out to approximately $ 56 ~\rm au$ from the star (assuming
a distance of 116 pc) with $0.&quot;38$ resolution and $0.07 ~ \rm mJy~beam^{-1}$
sensitivity. We measure a continuum flux density for this inner material of
$3.8 \pm 0.4 ~ \rm mJy$ (including calibration uncertainties). The
$^{12}$CO(3-2) gas is resolved kinematically and spatially from about 30 to 210
au. The integrated $^{12}$CO(3-2) line flux density is $15.7 \pm 1.6~\rm
Jy~km~s^{-1}$. We estimate the mass of the millimeter debris and $^{12}$CO(3-2)
gas to be $\gtrsim0.04~\rm M_{\oplus}$ and $\sim2\times 10^{-3}~\rm
M_{\oplus}$, respectively. If the millimeter grains are part of a collisional
cascade, then we infer that the inner disk ($&lt;50$ au) has $\sim 160~\rm
M_{\oplus}$ contained within objects less than 50 km in radius, depending on
the planetesimal size distribution and density assumptions. MCMC modeling of
the system reveals a disk morphology with an inclination of $53.4^{\circ}$
centered around a $\rm M=2.39~ M_{\odot}$ host star ($\rm Msin(i)=1.92~
M_{\odot}$). We discuss whether the gas in HD141569's disk may be second
generation. If it is, the system can be used to study the clearing stages of
planet formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01622</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yaqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hwang</keyname><forenames>Harold Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ofori-Okai</keyname><forenames>Benjamin K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleischer</keyname><forenames>Sharly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear two-dimensional terahertz photon echo and rotational
  spectroscopy in the gas phase</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>31 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1073/pnas.1609558113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrafast two-dimensional spectroscopy utilizes correlated multiple
light-matter interactions for retrieving dynamic features that may otherwise be
hidden under the linear spectrum. Its extension to the terahertz regime of the
electromagnetic spectrum, where a rich variety of material degrees of freedom
reside, remains an experimental challenge. Here we report ultrafast
two-dimensional terahertz spectroscopy of gas-phase molecular rotors at room
temperature. Using time-delayed terahertz pulse pairs, we observe photon echoes
and other nonlinear signals resulting from molecular dipole orientation induced
by three terahertz field-dipole interactions. The nonlinear time-domain
orientation signals are mapped into the frequency domain in two-dimensional
rotational spectra which reveal J-state-resolved nonlinear rotational dynamics.
The approach enables direct observation of correlated rotational transitions
and may reveal rotational coupling and relaxation pathways in the ground
electronic and vibrational state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01900</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kelley</keyname><forenames>Luke Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blecha</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernquist</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive Black Hole Binary Mergers in Dynamical Galactic Environments</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>28 pages, 28 figures, 3 tables, Monthly Notices of the Royal
  Astronomical Society 2016</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2452</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitational Waves (GW) have now been detected from stellar-mass black hole
binaries, and the first observations of GW from Massive Black Hole (MBH)
Binaries are expected within the next decade. Pulsar Timing Arrays (PTA), which
can measure the years long periods of GW from MBHB, have excluded many standard
predictions for the amplitude of a stochastic GW Background (GWB). We use
coevolved populations of MBH and galaxies from hydrodynamic, cosmological
simulations ('Illustris') to calculate a predicted GWB. The most advanced
predictions so far have included binary hardening mechanisms from individual
environmental processes. We present the first calculation including all of the
environmental mechanisms expected to be involved: dynamical friction, stellar
'loss-cone' scattering, and viscous drag from a circumbinary disk. We find that
MBH binary lifetimes are generally multiple gigayears, and only a fraction
coalesce by redshift zero. For a variety of parameters, we find all GWB
amplitudes to be below the most stringent PTA upper limit of
$A_{\textrm{yr}^{-1}} \approx 10^{-15}$. Our fairly conservative fiducial model
predicts an amplitude of $A_{\textrm{yr}^{-1}} \approx 0.4\times
10^{-15}$---less than a factor of three below the current limit. At lower
frequencies, we find $A_{0.1\,\textrm{yr}^{-1}} \approx 1.5\times 10^{-15}$
with spectral indices between $-0.4$ and $-0.6$---significantly flatter than
the canonical value of $-2/3$ due to purely GW-driven evolution. Typical MBHB
driving the GWB signal come from redshifts around $0.3$, with total masses of a
few times $10^9\,M_\odot$, and in host galaxies with very large stellar masses.
Even without GWB detections, our results can be connected to observations of
dual AGN to constrain binary evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01920</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Basanisi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabortty</keyname><forenames>Shankhadeep</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Entanglement Entropy in NMG</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 1 figure. v3: published version</comments><report-no>UG-16-73</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1609 (2016) 144</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we show that a higher derivative theory, such as New Massive
Gravity, allows the existence of new entangling surfaces with non-zero
extrinsic curvature. We perform the analysis for Lifshitz and Warped $AdS$
space times, revealing the role of the higher derivative contributions in the
calculation of the holographic entanglement entropy. Finally, as an outcome of
our holographic analysis we briefly comment on the dual boundary theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02606</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bellorin</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Restuccia</keyname><forenames>Alvaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantization of the Horava theory at the kinetic-conformal point</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>36 pages, 1 figure. Version 2: changes in presentation, some
  explanations have been expanded</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 064041 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.064041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Horava theory depends on several coupling constants. The kinetic term of
its Lagrangian depends on one dimensionless coupling constant lambda. For the
particular value lambda = 1/3 the kinetic term becomes conformal invariant,
although the full Lagrangian does not have this symmetry. For any value of
lambda the nonprojectable version of the theory has second-class constraints
which play a central role in the process of quantization. Here we study the
complete nonprojectable theory, including the Blas-Pujolas-Sibiryakov
interacting terms, at the kinetic-conformal point lambda = 1/3. The generic
counting of degrees of freedom indicates that this theory propagates the same
physical degrees of freedom of General Relativity. We analyze this point
rigorously taking into account all the z=1,2,3 terms that contribute to the
action describing quadratic perturbations around the Minkowski spacetime. We
show that the constraints of the theory and equations determining the Lagrange
multipliers are strongly elliptic partial differential equations, an essential
condition for a constrained phase-space structure in field theory. We show how
their solutions lead to the two independent tensorial physical modes propagated
by the theory. We also obtain the reduced Hamiltonian. These arguments
strengthen the consistency of the theory. We find the restrictions on the space
of coupling constants to ensure the positiveness of the reduced Hamiltonian. We
obtain the propagator of the physical modes, showing that there are not ghosts
and that the propagator effectively acquires the z=3 scaling for all physical
degrees of freedom at the high energy regime. By evaluating the superficial
degree of divergence, taking into account the second-class constraints, we show
that the theory is power-counting renormalizable. ...
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03260</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aneva</keyname><forenames>Boyka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brankov</keyname><forenames>Jordan</forenames></author></authors><title>MPA for TASEP with a generalized update on a ring</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Version 2, updated and corrected, 38 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the Matrix Product Ansatz to study the Totally Asymmetric Simple
Exclusion Process on a ring with a generalized discrete-time dynamics depending
on two hopping probabilities, $p$ and $\tilde{p}$. The model contains as
special cases the TASEP with parallel update, when $\tilde{p} =0$, and with
sequential backward-ordered update, when $\tilde{p} =p$.
  We construct a two-dimensional matrix-product representation and use it to
obtain exact finite-size expressions for the partition function, the current of
particles and the two-point correlation function. Our main new result is the
derivation of the finite-size pair correlation function. Its behavior is
analyzed in different regimes of effective attraction and repulsion between the
particles, depending on whether $\tilde{p} &gt;p$ or $\tilde{p} &lt; p$. In
particular, we explicitly obtain an analytic expression for the pair
correlation function in the limit of irreversible aggregation
$\tilde{p}\rightarrow 1$, when the stationary configurations contain just one
cluster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03492</id><created>2016-06-10</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Camargo-Molina</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; Eliel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morais</keyname><forenames>Ant&#xf3;nio P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasechnik</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wess&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author></authors><title>On a radiative origin of the Standard Model from Trinification</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>39 pages, 6 figures. Added a discussion (Sect. 7.2) on 1-loop
  contributions to the masses of light scalars. Published version</comments><report-no>LU TP 16-32</report-no><journal-ref>J. High Energ. Phys. (2016) 2016: 129</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)129</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present a trinification-based grand unified theory
incorporating a global $\mathrm{SU}(3)$ family symmetry that after a
spontaneous breaking leads to a left-right symmetric model. Already at the
classical level, this model can accommodate the matter content and the quark
Cabbibo mixing in the Standard Model (SM) with only one Yukawa coupling at the
unification scale. Considering the minimal low-energy scenario with the least
amount of light states, we show that the resulting effective theory enables
dynamical breaking of its gauge group down to that of the SM by means of
radiative corrections accounted for by the renormalisation group evolution at
one loop. This result paves the way for a consistent explanation of the SM
breaking scale and fermion mass hierarchies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03905</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dekel</keyname><forenames>Avishai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishai</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutton</keyname><forenames>Aaron A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maccio</keyname><forenames>Andrea V.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Dark-Matter Halo Profile allowing a Variable Cusp-Core with Analytic
  Velocity and Potential</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author because it became
  obsolete</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a useful function for describing the profiles of dark-matter
haloes with a varying asymptotic inner slope -\alpha, ranging from a cusp to a
core, where the profiles of density, mass-velocity and potential are simple
analytic expressions for any \alpha. The idea is to express the mean-density
profile as a simple functional form, and obtain the local density by
derivative. The model involves a concentration parameter c analogous to the NFW
profile. More flexibility is provided by a sum of two such functions, with
concentrations c_1 and c_2. An optional additional parameter is the asymptotic
outer slope -\gamma, which allows more flexibility in the outskirts of haloes.
For \gamma different than 3, there are analytic expressions for the profiles of
density and mass-velocity but not for the potential. We match the proposed
function, in different variants, to the dark-matter profiles of haloes in
cosmological simulations, with and without baryons, spanning inner profiles
that range from steep cusps to flat cores, and find excellent fits. The
analytic potential profile is useful in modeling the evolution of the inner
halo due to episodes of gas inflow and outflow. The analytic profile,
especially with a free \gamma, is useful for a study of environmental effects
in the outer halo. In general, these analytic profiles can serve for
straightforwardly quantifying the shapes of simulated and observed rotation
curves, without the need for numerical integrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05747</id><created>2016-06-18</created><updated>2016-09-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>Debottam</forenames><affiliation>IISER-TVM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shankaranarayanan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>IISER-TVM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Complete Hamiltonian analysis of cosmological perturbations at all
  orders II: Non-canonical scalar field</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>20 pages, no figures, Accepted in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP10(2016)008</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present a consistent Hamiltonian analysis of cosmological
perturbations for generalized non-canonical scalar fields. In order to do so,
we introduce a new phase-space variable that is uniquely defined for different
non-canonical scalar fields. We also show that this is the simplest and
efficient way of expressing the Hamiltonian. We extend the Hamiltonian approach
of [arXiv:1512.02539] to non-canonical scalar field and obtain a new definition
of speed of sound in phase-space. In order to invert generalized phase-space
Hamilton's equations to Euler-Lagrange equations of motion, we prescribe a
general inversion formulae and show that our approach for non-canonical scalar
field is consistent. We also obtain the third and fourth order interaction
Hamiltonian for generalized non-canonical scalar fields and briefly discuss the
extension of our method to generalized Galilean scalar fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07475</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Golovanov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostyukov</keyname><forenames>I. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pukhov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beam loading in the bubble regime in plasmas with hollow channels</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Plasmas 23, 093114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962565</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the already existing analytical theory of the strongly-nonlinear
wakefield (which is called &quot;bubble&quot;) in transversely inhomogeneous plasmas, we
study particular behavior of non-loaded (empty) bubbles and bubbles with
accelerated bunches. We obtain an analytical expression for the shape of a
non-loaded bubble in a general case and verify it with particle-in-cell (PIC)
simulations. We derive a method of calculation of the acceleration efficiency
for arbitrary accelerated bunches. The influence of flat-top electron bunches
on the shape of a bubble is studied. It is also shown that it is possible to
achieve acceleration in a homogeneous longitudinal electric field by the
adjustment of the longitudinal density profile of the accelerated electron
bunch. The predictions of the model are verified by 3D PIC simulations and are
in a good agreement with them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07647</id><created>2016-06-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Baake</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames><affiliation>Bielefeld</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ecija</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>Madrid</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grimm</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames><affiliation>Milton Keynes</affiliation></author></authors><title>A guide to lifting aperiodic structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.MG</categories><comments>8 pages, many figures</comments><msc-class>53C23</msc-class><journal-ref>Z. Kristallogr. 231 (2016) 507-515</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/zkri-2016-1982</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The embedding of a given point set with non-crystallographic symmetry into
higher-dimensional space is reviewed, with special emphasis on the Minkowski
embedding known from number theory. This is a natural choice that does not
require an a priori construction of a lattice in relation to a given symmetry
group. Instead, some elementary properties of the point set in physical space
are used, and explicit methods are described. This approach works particularly
well for the standard symmetries encountered in the practical study of
quasicrystalline phases. We also demonstrate this with a recent experimental
example, taken from a sample with square-triangle tiling structure and
(approximate) twelvefold symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07851</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Slovick</keyname><forenames>Brian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krishnamurthy</keyname><forenames>Srini</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal insulator transition induced by interface scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 141905 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop an effective medium model of thermal conductivity that accounts
for both percolation and interface scattering. This model accurately explains
the measured increase and decrease of thermal conductivity with loading in
composites dominated by percolation and interface scattering, respectively. Our
model further predicts that strong interface scattering leads to a sharp
decrease in thermal conductivity, or an insulator transition, at high loadings
when conduction through the matrix is restricted and heat is forced to diffuse
through particles with large interface resistance. The accuracy of our model
and its ability to predict transitions between insulating and conducting states
suggest it can be a useful tool for designing materials with low or high
thermal conductivity for a variety of applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08579</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2016-09-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xuekai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Driben</keyname><forenames>Rodislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>Boris A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meier</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumacher</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional symbiotic solitons and vortices in binary condensates
  with attractive cross-species interaction</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Scientific Reports, in press</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 34847, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep34847</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a two-dimensional (2D) two-component spinor system with cubic
attraction between the components and intra-species self-repulsion, which may
be realized in atomic Bose-Einstein condensates, as well as in a
quasi-equilibrium condensate of microcavity polaritons. Including a 2D
spatially periodic potential, which is necessary for the stabilization of the
system against the critical collapse, we use detailed numerical calculations
and an analytical variational approximation (VA) to predict the existence and
stability of several types of 2D symbiotic solitons in the spinor system.
Stability ranges are found for symmetric and asymmetric symbiotic fundamental
solitons and vortices, including hidden-vorticity (HV) modes, with opposite
vorticities in the two components. The VA produces exceptionally accurate
predictions for the fundamental solitons and vortices. The fundamental
solitons, both symmetric and asymmetric ones, are completely stable, in either
case when they exist as gap solitons or regular ones. The symmetric and
asymmetric vortices are stable if the inter-component attraction is stronger
than the intra-species repulsion, while the HV modes have their stability
region in the opposite case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03268</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03268</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yin-Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author></authors><title>Tailoring the topological details of the magnetic skyrmion by the spin
  configuration at the edges</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 380, 3756 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.09.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetic skyrmion structure can be formed in the chiral magnets (CMs)
with strong Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interactions. In this work, we propose a way
of artificially tailoring the topological details of the skyrmion such as its
radial and whirling symmetric patterns by external magnetic fields besieging
the CM slab. As long as the boundary magnetic fields are strong enough to fix
the boundary ferromagnetism, the attained skyrmion profile is stable over time.
The dynamics of spins is considered by numerically solving the non-equilibrium
Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05663</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fertig</keyname><forenames>Angelika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lehners</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mallwitz</keyname><forenames>Enno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson-Ewing</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Converting entropy to curvature perturbations after a cosmic bounce</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>minor corrections, version published in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP10(2016)005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study two-field bouncing cosmologies in which primordial perturbations are
created in either an ekpyrotic or a matter-dominated contraction phase. We use
a non-singular ghost condensate bounce model to follow the perturbations
through the bounce into the expanding phase of the universe. In contrast to the
adiabatic perturbations, which on large scales are conserved across the bounce,
entropy perturbations can grow significantly during the bounce phase. If they
are converted into adiabatic/curvature perturbations after the bounce, they
typically form the dominant contribution to the observed temperature
fluctuations in the microwave background, which can have several beneficial
implications. For ekpyrotic models, this mechanism loosens the constraints on
the amplitude of the ekpyrotic potential while naturally suppressing the
intrinsic amount of non-Gaussianity. For matter bounce models, the mechanism
amplifies the scalar perturbations compared to the associated primordial
gravitational waves.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00368</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shiraishi</keyname><forenames>Maresuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Parity violation in the CMB trispectrum from the scalar sector</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures; version matching publication in PRD</comments><report-no>IPMU16-0111</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 083503 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.083503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under the existence of chiral non-Gaussian sources during inflation, the
trispectrum of primordial curvature perturbations can break parity. We examine
signatures of the induced trispectrum of the cosmic microwave background (CMB)
anisotropies. It is confirmed via a harmonic-space analysis that, as a
consequence of parity violation, such a CMB trispectrum has nonvanishing signal
in the $\ell_1 + \ell_2 + \ell_3 + \ell_4 = \text{odd}$ domain, which is
prohibited in the concordance cosmology. When the curvature trispectrum is
parametrized with Legendre polynomials, the CMB signal due to the Legendre
dipolar term is enhanced at the squeezed configurations in $\ell$ space,
yielding a high signal-to-noise ratio. A Fisher matrix computation results in a
minimum detectable size of the dipolar coefficient in a
cosmic-variance-limited-level temperature survey as $d_1^{\rm odd} = 640$. In
an inflationary model where the inflaton field couples to the gauge field via
an $f(\phi)(F^2 + F\tilde{F})$ interaction, the curvature trispectrum contains
such a parity-odd dipolar term. We find that, in this model, the CMB
trispectrum yields a high signal-to-noise ratio compared with the CMB power
spectrum or bispectrum. Therefore, the $\ell_1 + \ell_2 + \ell_3 + \ell_4 =
\text{odd}$ signal could be a promising observable of cosmological parity
violation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00594</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2016-09-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernandez-Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mong</keyname><forenames>Roger S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landon-Cardinal</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez-Garcia</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuch</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Constructing topological models by symmetrization: A PEPS study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages. v2: accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 155106 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.155106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Symmetrization of topologically ordered wavefunctions is a powerful method
for constructing new topological models. Here, we study wavefunctions obtained
by symmetrizing quantum double models of a group $G$ in the Projected Entangled
Pair States (PEPS) formalism. We show that symmetrization naturally gives rise
to a larger symmetry group $\tilde G$ which is always non-abelian. We prove
that by symmetrizing on sufficiently large blocks, one can always construct
wavefunctions in the same phase as the double model of $\tilde G$. In order to
understand the effect of symmetrization on smaller patches, we carry out
numerical studies for the toric code model, where we find strong evidence that
symmetrizing on individual spins gives rise to a critical model which is at the
phase transitions of two inequivalent toric codes, obtained by anyon
condensation from the double model of $\tilde G$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01528</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abbott</keyname><forenames>Alastair A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giarmatzi</keyname><forenames>Christina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Branciard</keyname><forenames>Cyril</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipartite Causal Correlations: Polytopes and Inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages and 1 supplementary CDF file</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 032131 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.032131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the most general correlations that can be obtained by a group of
parties whose causal relations are well-defined, although possibly
probabilistic and dependent on past parties' operations. We show that, for any
fixed number of parties and inputs and outputs for each party, the set of such
correlations forms a convex polytope, whose vertices correspond to
deterministic strategies, and whose (nontrivial) facets define so-called causal
inequalities. We completely characterize the simplest tripartite polytope in
terms of its facet inequalities, propose generalizations of some inequalities
to scenarios with more parties, and show that our tripartite inequalities can
be violated within the process matrix formalism, where quantum mechanics is
locally valid but no global causal structure is assumed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03288</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Durieux</keyname><forenames>Gauthier</forenames></author></authors><title>CP violation in multibody decays of beauty baryons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>2 figures, 16 tables, minor comments and references added in v2
  (published version)</comments><report-no>DESY 16-153</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 10 (2016) 005</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2016)005</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Beauty baryons are being observed in large numbers in the LHCb detector. The
rich kinematic distributions of their multibody decays are therefore becoming
accessible and provide us with new opportunities to search for CP violation. We
analyse the angular distributions of some three- and four-body decays of
spin-$1/2$ baryons using the Jacob-Wick helicity formalism. The asymmetries
that provide access to small differences of CP-odd phases between decay
amplitudes of identical CP-even phases are notably discussed. The understanding
gained on processes featuring specific resonant intermediate states allows us
to establish which asymmetries are relevant for what purpose. It is for
instance shown that some CP-odd angular asymmetries measured by the LHCb
collaboration in the $\Lambda_b \to \Lambda\,\varphi \to p\,\pi\, K^+ K^-$
decay are expected to vanish identically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06278</id><created>2016-08-20</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soma</keyname><forenames>Arun Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Light yield of an undoped CsI crystal coupled directly to a
  photomultiplier tube at 77 Kelvin</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures, published in JINST</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation, Volume 11, P10003, October 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/10/P10003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A light yield of 20.4 $\pm$ 0.8 photoelectrons/keV was achieved with an
undoped CsI crystal coupled directly to a photomultiplier tube at 77 Kelvin.
This is by far the largest yield in the world achieved with CsI crystals. An
energy threshold that is several times lower than the current dark matter
experiments utilizing CsI(Tl) crystals may be achievable using this technique.
Together with novel CsI crystal purification methods, the technique may be used
to improve the sensitivities of dark matter and coherent elastic
neutrino-nucleus scattering experiments. Also measured were the scintillation
light decay constants of the undoped CsI crystal at both room temperature and
77 Kelvin. The results are consistent with those in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01716</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sokolovsky</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gavras</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karampelas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antipin</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellas-Velidis</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benni</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonanos</keyname><forenames>A. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burdanov</keyname><forenames>A. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Derlopa</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatzidimitriou</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khokhryakova</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolesnikova</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkiy</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lapukhin</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pouliasis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samus</keyname><forenames>N. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spetsieri</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veselkov</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zubareva</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparative performance of selected variability detection techniques in
  photometric time series</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>29 pages, 8 figures, 7 tables; accepted to MNRAS; for additional
  plots, see http://scan.sai.msu.ru/~kirx/var_idx_paper/</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2262</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photometric measurements are prone to systematic errors presenting a
challenge to low-amplitude variability detection. In search for a
general-purpose variability detection technique able to recover a broad range
of variability types including currently unknown ones, we test 18 statistical
characteristics quantifying scatter and/or correlation between brightness
measurements. We compare their performance in identifying variable objects in
seven time series data sets obtained with telescopes ranging in size from a
telephoto lens to 1m-class and probing variability on time-scales from minutes
to decades. The test data sets together include lightcurves of 127539 objects,
among them 1251 variable stars of various types and represent a range of
observing conditions often found in ground-based variability surveys. The real
data are complemented by simulations. We propose a combination of two indices
that together recover a broad range of variability types from photometric data
characterized by a wide variety of sampling patterns, photometric accuracies,
and percentages of outlier measurements. The first index is the interquartile
range (IQR) of magnitude measurements, sensitive to variability irrespective of
a time-scale and resistant to outliers. It can be complemented by the ratio of
the lightcurve variance to the mean square successive difference, 1/h, which is
efficient in detecting variability on time-scales longer than the typical time
interval between observations. Variable objects have larger 1/h and/or IQR
values than non-variable objects of similar brightness. Another approach to
variability detection is to combine many variability indices using principal
component analysis. We present 124 previously unknown variable stars found in
the test data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01721</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Henshaw</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longmore</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruijssen</keyname><forenames>J. M. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Seeding the Galactic Centre gas stream: gravitational instabilities set
  the initial conditions for the formation of protocluster clouds</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. Accepted for publication in MNRAS
  Letters. Table values updated, conclusions unaffected</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw168</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Star formation within the Central Molecular Zone (CMZ) may be intimately
linked to the orbital dynamics of the gas. Recent models suggest that star
formation within the dust ridge molecular clouds (from G0.253+0.016 to Sgr B2)
follows an evolutionary time sequence, triggered by tidal compression during
their preceding pericentre passage. Given that these clouds are the most likely
precursors to a generation of massive stars and extreme star clusters, this
scenario would have profound implications for constraining the time-evolution
of star formation. In this Letter, we search for the initial conditions of the
protocluster clouds, focusing on the kinematics of gas situated upstream from
pericentre. We observe a highly-regular corrugated velocity field in
$\{l,\,v_{\rm LSR}\}$ space, with amplitude and wavelength $A=3.7\,\pm\,0.1$
kms$^{-1}$ and $\lambda_{\rm vel, i}=22.5\,\pm\,0.1$ pc, respectively. The
extremes in velocity correlate with a series of massive
($\sim10^{4}$M$_{\odot}$) and compact ($R_{\rm eq}\sim2$ pc), quasi-regularly
spaced ($\sim8$ pc), molecular clouds. The corrugation wavelength and cloud
separation closely agree with the predicted Toomre ($\sim17$ pc) and Jeans
($\sim6$ pc) lengths, respectively. We conclude that gravitational
instabilities are driving the condensation of molecular clouds within the
Galactic Centre gas stream. Furthermore, we speculate these seeds are the
historical analogue of the dust-ridge molecular clouds, representing the
initial conditions of star and cluster formation in the CMZ.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03156</id><created>2016-09-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Oikonomou</keyname><forenames>V. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Aspects of Late-time Evolution in Mimetic $F(R)$ Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>MPLA accepted</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501911</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate how to describe in an unified way early and late-time
acceleration in the context of mimetic $F(R)$ gravity. As we show, an
exponential $F(R)$ gravity model has appealing features, with regard to
unification, and we perform an analysis of the late-time evolution. The
resulting picture is interesting since in the mimetic case, certain pathologies
of some ordinary $F(R)$ models are remedied in a consistent way, owing to the
presence of the mimetic potential and the Lagrange multiplier. We quantify the
late-time evolution analysis by studying the scaled dark energy density, the
dark energy equation of state and the total effective equation of state, and as
we show the late-time evolution is crucially affected by the functional form of
the $F(R)$ gravity. It is intriguing that the most appealing case corresponds
to the exponential $F(R)$ gravity which unifies late and early-time
acceleration. Finally, we study the behavior of the effective gravitational
constant and the growth factor, and as we show, significant differences between
the mimetic and ordinary $F(R)$ exponential model are spotted in the growth
factor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04957</id><created>2016-09-16</created><updated>2016-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawaguchi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujiwara</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iimura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuishi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosono</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental evidence of $T_c$ enhancement without the influence of spin
  fluctuations: NMR study on LaFeAsO_{1-x}H_x under a pressure of 3.0 GPa</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Correponding Author: Naoki Fujiwara</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94 161104(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.161104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electron-doped high-transition-temperature (T_c) iron-based pnictide
superconductor LaFeAsO_{1-x}H_x has a unique phase diagram: superconducting
(SC) double domes are sandwiched by antiferromagnetic phases at ambient
pressure and they turn to a single dome with a maximum T_c that exceeds 45K at
a pressure of 3.0 GPa. We studied whether spin fluctuations are involved in
increasing T_c under a pressure of 3.0 GPa by using ^{75}As nuclear magnetic
resonance (NMR) technique. The ^{75}As-NMR results for the powder samples show
that T_c increases up to 48 K without the influence of spin fluctuations. The
fact indicates that spin fluctuations are not involved in raising T_c, which
implies that other factors, such as orbital degrees of freedom, may be
important for achieving a high T_c of almost 50 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00468</id><created>2016-10-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Modeling of Musical Solos as Complex Networks</title><categories>cs.SD cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>to appear in Information Science, Elsevier. Please cite the paper
  including such information. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1603.04979</comments><doi>10.1016/j.ins.2016.10.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Notes in a musical piece are building blocks employed in non-random ways to
create melodies. It is the &quot;interaction&quot; among a limited amount of notes that
allows constructing the variety of musical compositions that have been written
in centuries and within different cultures. Networks are a modeling tool that
is commonly employed to represent a set of entities interacting in some way.
Thus, notes composing a melody can be seen as nodes of a network that are
connected whenever these are played in sequence. The outcome of such a process
results in a directed graph. By using complex network theory, some main metrics
of musical graphs can be measured, which characterize the related musical
pieces. In this paper, we define a framework to represent melodies as networks.
Then, we provide an analysis on a set of guitar solos performed by main
musicians. Results of this study indicate that the presented model can have an
impact on audio and multimedia applications such as music classification,
identification, e-learning, automatic music generation, multimedia
entertainment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01147</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhanabaev</keyname><forenames>Z. Zh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grevtseva</keyname><forenames>T. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozhagulov</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Characteristics of Neural Signals</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO</categories><comments>Our work is dedicated to the research of nonlinear characteristics of
  neural signals. 6 pages, 2 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1610.00446</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study is devoted to definition of generalized metrical and topological
(informational entropy) characteristics of neural signals via their well-known
theoretical models. We have shown that time dependence of action potential of
neurons is scale invariant. Information and entropy of neural signals have
constant values in case of self-similarity and self-affinity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01151</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>Rafael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moradpour</keyname><forenames>Hooman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barboza</keyname><forenames>Ed&#xe9;sio M.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Abreu</keyname><forenames>Everton M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>Jorge Ananias</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic gravity from noncommutative black holes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, two column format, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we will investigate the effects of a noncommutative (NC)
space-time on the dynamics of the universe. We will generalize the black hole
entropy formula for a NC black hole. Then, using the entropic gravity
formalism, we will show that the noncommutativity changes the strength of the
gravitational field. By applying this result to a homogeneous and isotropic
universe containing nonrelativistic matter and a cosmological constant, we will
show that the model modified by the noncommutativity of the space-time is a
better fit to the obtained data than the standard one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01152</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Choudhary</keyname><forenames>Sujit K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Pankaj</forenames></author></authors><title>The Hardy's nonlocality argument</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1408.0526 by other authors</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Quantum Information, Vol. 14, No. 6
  (2016) 1640035</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749916400359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Certain predictions of quantum theory are not compatible with the notion of
local-realism. This was the content of Bell's famous theorem of the year 1964.
Bell proved this with the help of an inequality, famously known as Bell's
inequality. The alternative proofs of Bell's theorem without using Bell's
inequality are known as `nonlocality without inequality (NLWI)' proofs. We,
review one such proof, namely the Hardy's proof which due to its simplicity and
generality has been considered the best version of Bell's theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01163</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Hagen</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bond</keyname><forenames>Nicholas A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciardullo</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gronwall</keyname><forenames>Caryl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gawiser</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowman</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bridge</keyname><forenames>Joanna S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gebhardt</keyname><forenames>Henry S. Grasshorn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Donald P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Rest-Frame Optical Morphology of Emission Line Galaxies at 2 &lt; z &lt;
  3: Evidence for Inside-Out Formation in Low-Mass Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, and 2 tables. Submitted to ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compare the rest-frame ultraviolet and rest-frame optical morphologies of
2 &lt; z &lt; 3 star-forming galaxies in the GOODS-S field using Hubble Space
Telescope WFC3 and ACS images from the CANDELS, GOODS, and ERS programs. We
show that the distribution of sizes and concentrations for 1.90 &lt; z &lt; 2.35
galaxies selected via their rest-frame optical emission-lines are statistically
indistinguishable from those of Lyman-alpha emitting systems found at z ~ 2.1
and z ~ 3.1. We also show that the z &gt; 2 star-forming systems of all sizes and
masses become smaller and more compact as one shifts the observing window from
the UV to the optical. We argue that this offset is due to inside-out galaxy
formation over the first ~ 2 Gyr of cosmic time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01169</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Nesvadba</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kneissl</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canameras</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boone</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falgarone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frye</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenig</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagache</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Floc'h</keyname><forenames>E. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Planck's Dusty GEMS. II. Extended [CII] emission and absorption in the
  Garnet at z=3.4 seen with ALMA</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>A&amp;A 593, L2</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present spatially resolved ALMA [CII] observations of the bright (flux
density S=400 mJy at 350 microns), gravitationally lensed, starburst galaxy
PLCK G045.1+61.1 at z=3.427, the &quot;Garnet&quot;. This source is part of our set of
&quot;Planck's Dusty GEMS&quot;, discovered with the Planck's all-sky survey. Two
emission-line clouds with a relative velocity offset of ~600 km/s extend
towards north-east and south-west, respectively, of a small, intensely
star-forming clump with a star-formation intensity of 220 Msun/yr/kpc^2, akin
to maximal starbursts. [CII] is also seen in absorption, with a redshift of
+350 km/s relative to the brightest CO component. [CII] absorption has
previously only been found in the Milky Way along sightlines toward bright
high-mass star-forming regions, and this is the first detection in another
galaxy. Similar to Galactic environments, the [CII] absorption feature is
associated with [CI] emission, implying that this is diffuse gas shielded from
the UV radiation of the clump, and likely at large distances from the clump.
Since absorption can only be seen in front of a continuum source, the gas in
this structure can definitely be attributed to gas flowing towards the clump.
The absorber could be part of a cosmic filament or merger debris being accreted
onto the galaxy. We discuss our results also in light of the on-going debate of
the origin of the [CII] deficit in dusty star-forming galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01172</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Brunelli</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paternostro</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Irreversibility and correlations in coupled quantum oscillators</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12+4 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the link between the irreversibility generated by a stationary
dissipative process and the correlations established within a composite quantum
system. We provide two equivalent expressions for the entropy generated in the
non-equilibrium steady state of coupled quantum harmonic oscillators that allow
for a simple interpretation of the onset of irreversibility. We then unveil a
quantitative relation between the entropy production rate and correlations,
both total and quantum, built between the two oscillators. In the
small-coupling limit, the entropy production rate is shown to be proportional
to both the mutual information and the quantum correlations. We apply our
results to the analysis of the optomechanical interaction between a
nano-mechanical resonator and a cavity field, and show that the behavior of the
entropy production captures the peculiar features of the model, such as
sideband cooling and amplification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01174</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>T. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>R. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>IFU spectroscopy of 10 early-type galactic nuclei - IV. Properties of
  the circumnuclear stellar kinematics</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2318</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of stellar kinematic properties may provide hints on the formation
and evolution of elliptical and lenticular galaxies. Although most previous
studies have focused on the large scale of these galaxies, their central
regions (scales of $\sim$ 100 pc) may contain important clues about their
structure, such as kinematically decoupled cores. This is the fourth paper on a
sample of 10 massive ($\sigma$ $&gt;$ 200 km s$^{-1}$) and nearby ($d$ $&lt;$ 31 Mpc)
early-type galaxies, observed with the integral field unit of the Gemini South
Multi Object Spectrograph. Here, we analyse the properties of the stellar
kinematics in the circumnuclear region. We fitted the line-of-sight velocity
distribution with a Gauss-Hermite function. In seven galaxies of the sample, we
detected a rotation pattern in their radial velocity maps that are
anti-correlated with $h_3$. We interpret this as stellar structures in rotation
embedded in the bulges of the objects. Comparing the stellar kinematic results
with the PCA Tomography results and also with the gas kinematic results of IC
5181, it seems that this object may have a non-axisymmetric potential at its
centre. The velocity dispersion maps of four objects have a nuclear peak, which
must correspond, in part, to unresolved stellar rotation. In NGC 1404, we
detected a kinematic decoupled core with an extension of $\sim$ 200 pc. This
galaxy also has a $\sigma$-drop in the centre, which may be related to both
stellar components in counterrotation or with a kinematically cold star-forming
region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01190</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Ware</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bucksbaum</keyname><forenames>Philip H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cryan</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haxton</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The attosecond regime of impulsive stimulated electronic Raman
  excitation</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated the resonant and nonresonant contributions to attosecond
impulsive stimulated electronic Raman scattering (SERS) in regions of
autoionizing transitions. Comparison with Multiconfiguration Time-Dependent
Hartree-Fock (MCTDHF) calculations find that attosecond SERS is dominated by
continuum transitions and not autoionizing resonances. These results agree
quantitatively with a rate equation that includes second-order Raman and
first-and second-order photoionization rates. Such rate models can be extended
to larger molecular systems. Our results indicate that attosecond SERS
transition probabilities may be understood in terms of two-photon generalized
cross sections even in the high-intensity limit for extreme ultraviolet
wavelengths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01202</id><created>2016-10-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Deng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xin-He</forenames></author></authors><title>Model-independent determination on $H_0$ using the latest $H(z)$ data</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform the improved constraints on the Hubble constant $H_0$ by using the
model-independent method, Gaussian Processes. Utilizing the latest 36 $H(z)$
measurements, we obtain $H_0=69.21\pm3.72$ km s$^{-1}$ Mpc$^{-1}$, which is
consistent with the Planck 2015 and Riess et al. 2016 analysis at $1\sigma$
confidence level, and reduces the uncertainty from $6.5\%$ (Busti et al. 2014)
to $5.4\%$. Different from the results of Busti et al. 2014 by only using 19
$H(z)$ measurements, our reconstruction results of $H(z)$ and the derived
values of $H_0$ are independent of the choice of covariance functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01204</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Maxwell</keyname><forenames>Brian McN.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharjee</keyname><forenames>Rohit R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lau-Chapdelaine</keyname><forenames>Sebastien S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falle</keyname><forenames>Sam A. E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>Gary J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radulescu</keyname><forenames>Matei I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Turbulent Fluctuations on Detonation Propagation</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>50 pages, 35 figures, journal article submitted to JFM 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present study addresses the reaction zone structure and burning mechanism
of unstable detonations. Experiments investigated mainly two-dimensional
methane-oxygen cellular detonations in a thin channel geometry. The
sufficiently high temporal resolution permitted to determine the PDF of the
shock distribution, a power-law with an exponent of -3, and the burning rate of
unreacted pockets from their edges - through surface turbulent flames with a
speed approximately 3-7 times larger than the laminar one at the local
conditions. Numerical simulations were performed using a novel Large Eddy
Simulation method where the reactions due to both auto-ignition and turbulent
transport and treated exactly at the sub-grid scale in a reaction-diffusion
formulation. The model is an extension of Kerstein &amp; Menon's Linear Eddy Model
for Large Eddy Simulation to treat flows with shock waves and rapid gasdynamic
transients. The two-dimensional simulations recovered well the amplification of
the laminar flame speed owing to the turbulence generated mainly by the shear
layers originating from the triple points and subsequent Richtmyer-Meshkov
instability associated with the internal pressure waves. The simulations
clarified how the level of turbulence generated controlled the burning rate of
the pockets, the hydrodynamic thickness of the wave, the cellular structure and
its distribution. Three-dimensional simulations were found in general good
agreement with the two-dimensional ones, in that the sub-grid scale model
captured the ensuing turbulent burning once the scales associated with the
cellular dynamics, where turbulent kinetic energy is injected, are well
resolved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01207</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Platonova</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kukulin</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Manifestation of the $P$-wave diproton resonance in single-pion
  production in $pp$ collisions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>Version accepted for publication in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 054039 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.054039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is demonstrated that many important features of single-pion production in
$pp$ collisions at intermediate energies ($T_p \simeq 400$-$800$ MeV) can
naturally be explained by supposing excitation of intermediate diproton
resonances in $pp$ channels ${}^1D_2$, ${}^3F_3$ and ${}^3P_2$, in addition to
conventional mechanisms involving an intermediate $\Delta$-isobar. We predict
for the first time the crucial role of the ${}^3P_2$ diproton resonance, found
in recent experiments on the single-pion production reaction $pp \to
pp({}^1S_0) \pi^0$, in reproducing the proper behavior of spin-correlation
parameters in the reaction $pp \to d \pi^+$ which were poorly described by
conventional meson-exchange models to date. The possible quark structure of the
$P$-wave diproton resonances is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01224</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Heitmann</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamsal</keyname><forenames>Jagat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>Shannon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erwin</keyname><forenames>Ross</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wangchun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montfrooij</keyname><forenames>Wouter</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification of the low-energy excitations in a quantum critical
  system</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, contributed conference proceeding for MMM16</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have identified low-energy magnetic excitations in a doped quantum
critical system by means of polarized neutron scattering experiments. The
presence of these excitations could explain why
Ce(Fe$_{0.76}$Ru$_{0.24}$)$_2$Ge$_2$ displays dynamical scaling in the absence
of local critical behavior or long-range spin-density wave criticality. The
low-energy excitations are associated with the reorientations of the superspins
of fully ordered, isolated magnetic clusters that form spontaneously upon
lowering the temperature. The system houses both frozen clusters and dynamic
clusters, as predicted by Hoyos and Vojta [Phys. Rev. B 74, 140401 (R) (2006)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01235</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Pimentel</keyname><forenames>Luis O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabarrete</keyname><forenames>Carlos E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Some exact solutions in K-essence theory isotropic cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a simple form of the K-essence theory and apply it to the classic
isotropic cosmological model and seek exact solutions. The particular form of
the kinetic term that we choose is $K \left(\phi, X \right)= K_0(\phi)X^m
+K_1$. The resulting field equations in the homogeneous and isotropic cosmology
(FRW)is considered. Several exact solutions are obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01248</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Harder</keyname><forenames>T. Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>How Particles can Emerge in a Relativistic Version of Bohmian Quantum
  Field Theory: Part 2 - Fermions</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown how Fermionic material particles can emerge from a covariant
formulation of the de Broglie-Bohm theory. Material particles are continuous
fields, formed as the eigenvalue of the Schrodinger field operator, evaluated
along a Bohmian trajectory. The motivation for this work is due to a theorem
proved by Malament that states there cannot be a relativistic quantum mechanics
of localizable particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01262</id><created>2016-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Wilde</keyname><forenames>Mark M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Monotonicity of $p$-norms of multiple operators via unitary swivels</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following the various statements of [DW16] to their logical conclusion, this
note explicitly argues the following statement, implicit in [DW16]: for
positive semi-definite operators $C_{1},\ldots,\,C_{L} $, a unitary $V_{C_{i}}$
commuting with $C_{i}$, and $p\geq1$, the quantity $$
\max_{V_{C_{1}},\ldots,V_{C_{L}}}\left\Vert C_{1}^{1/p}V_{C_{1}}\cdots
C_{L}^{1/p}V_{C_{L}}\right\Vert _{p}^{p} $$ is monotone non-increasing with
respect to $p$. The idea from [DW16] is that by allowing unitary swivels
connecting a long chain of positive semi-definite operators together, we can
establish such a statement, which might not hold generally without the presence
of the unitary swivels. Other related statements follow directly from [DW16] as
well, being implicit there, and are given explicitly in this note.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01272</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Marcondes</keyname><forenames>Rafael J. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting dark energy models in Cosmology and large-scale structure
  observational tests</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>PhD thesis. 108 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern Cosmology offers us a great understanding of the universe with
striking precision, made possible by the modern technologies of the newest
generations of telescopes. The standard cosmological model, however, is not
absent of theoretical problems and open questions. One possibility that has
been put forward is the existence of a coupling between dark sectors. The idea
of an interaction between the dark components could help physicists understand
why we live in an epoch of the universe where dark matter and dark energy are
comparable in terms of energy density, which can be regarded as a coincidence
given that their time evolutions are completely different.
  We introduce the interaction phenomenologically and proceed to test models of
interaction with observations of redshift-space distortions. In a flat universe
composed only of those two fluids, we consider separately two forms of
interaction, through terms proportional to the densities of both dark energy
and dark matter. An analytic expression for the growth rate approximated as $f
= \Omega_{\mathrm{DM}}^{\gamma}$, where $\Omega_{\mathrm{DM}}$ is the
percentage contribution from the dark matter to the content of the universe and
$\gamma$ is the growth index, is derived in terms of the interaction strength
and of other parameters of the model in the first case, while for the second
model we show that a non-zero interaction cannot be accommodated by the index
growth approximation. The successful expressions obtained are then used to
compare the predictions with growth of structure observational data in a MCMC
code.
  We also employ observations of galaxy clusters to assess their virial state
via the modified Layzer-Irvine equation in order to detect signs of an
interaction, obtaining measurements of observed virial ratios, interaction
strength, rest virial ratio and departure from equilibrium for a set of
clusters. [abridged]
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01285</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xing-yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yu-dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Cheng-fa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Total Ionizing Dose and Synergistic Effect of Magnetoresistive Random
  Access Memory</title><categories>physics.space-ph physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magetoresistive Random Access Memory (MRAM) was irradiated by 60Co
{\gamma}-rays and electron beam. The test of synergistic effect was performed
under additional magnetic field when irradiation. We analyzed Total Ionizing
Dose (TID) and synergistic damage mechanism of MRAM. DC, AC and function
parameters of the memory were tested in radiation and annealing by Very Large
Scale Integrated circuit (VLSI) test system. The radiation sensitive parameters
were obtained through analyzing the data. Because magnetic field imposed on
MRAM when the test of synergistic effect, Shallow Trench Isolation (STI)
leakage or Frenkel-Poole emission of synergistic effect was smaller than that
of TID, and radiation damage of synergistic effect was lower than that of TID.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01304</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Fletcher</keyname><forenames>Leigh N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Pater</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reach</keyname><forenames>W. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orton</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>P. G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehrz</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Jupiter's Para-H$_2$ Distribution from SOFIA/FORCAST and Voyager/IRIS
  17-37 $\mu$m Spectroscopy</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>23 pages, 14 figures, accepted for publication in Icarus</comments><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.10.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spatially resolved maps of Jupiter's far-infrared 17-37 $\mu$m
hydrogen-helium collision-induced spectrum were acquired by the FORCAST
instrument on the Stratospheric Observatory for Infrared Astronomy (SOFIA) in
May 2014. Spectral scans in two grisms covered the broad S(0) and S(1)
absorption lines, in addition to contextual imaging in eight broad-band filters
(5-37 $\mu$m) with spatial resolutions of 2-4&quot;. The spectra were inverted to
map the zonal-mean temperature and para-H$_2$ distribution ($f_p$, the fraction
of the para spin isomer with respect to the ortho spin isomer) in Jupiter's
upper troposphere (the 100-700 mbar range). We compared these to a reanalysis
of Voyager-1 and -2 IRIS spectra covering the same spectral range. Para-H$_2$
increases from equator to pole, with low-$f_p$ air at the equator representing
sub-equilibrium conditions (i.e., less para-H$_2$ than expected from thermal
equilibration), and high-$f_p$ air and possible super-equilibrium at higher
latitudes. In particular, we confirm the continued presence of a region of
high-$f_p$ air at high northern latitudes discovered by Voyager/IRIS, and an
asymmetry with generally higher $f_p$ in the north than in the south. We note
that existing collision-induced absorption databases lack opacity from
(H$_2$)$_2$ dimers, leading to under-prediction of the absorption near the S(0)
and S(1) peaks. There appears to be no spatial correlation between para-H$_2$
and tropospheric ammonia, phosphine and cloud opacity derived from Voyager/IRIS
at mid-infrared wavelengths (7-15 $\mu$m). We note, however, that para-H$_2$
tracks the similar latitudinal distribution of aerosols within Jupiter's upper
tropospheric and stratospheric hazes observed in reflected sunlight, suggesting
that catalysis of hydrogen equilibration within the hazes (and not the main
clouds) may govern the equator-to-pole gradient. [Abridged]
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01306</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Latour</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chayer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontaine</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral analysis of the sdO standard star Feige 34</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>to be published by Astronomical Society of the Pacific Conference
  Series in the proceedings of the &quot;20th European Workshop on White Dwarfs&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our current work on the spectral analysis of the hot sdO star
Feige 34. We combine high S/N optical spectra and fully-blanketed non-LTE model
atmospheres to derive its fundamental parameters (Teff, log g) and helium
abundance. Our best fits indicate Teff =63 000 K, log g=6.0 and log
N(He)/N(H)=-1.8. We also use available ultraviolet spectra (IUE and FUSE) to
measure metal abundances. We find the star to be enriched in iron and nickel by
a factor of ten with respect to the solar values, while lighter elements have
subsolar abundances. The FUSE spectrum suggests that the spectral lines could
be broadened by rotation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01313</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Bartolomei</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giorgi</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author></authors><title>A Novel Nanoporous Graphite Based on Graphynes: First Principles
  Structure and Carbon Dioxide Preferential Physisorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/acsami.6b08743</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ubiquitous graphene is a stricly 2D material representing an ideal adsorbing
platform due to its large specific surface area as well as its mechanical
strength and resistance to both thermal and chemical stresses. However,
graphene as a bulk material has the tendency to form irreversible agglomerates
leading to 3D graphitic structures with a significant decrease of the area
available for adsorption and no room for gas intercalation. In this paper a
novel nanoporous graphite formed by graphtriyne sheets is introduced: its 3D
structure is theoretically assessed by means of electronic structure and
molecular dynamics computations within the DFT level of theory. It is found
that the novel layered carbon allotrope is almost as compact as pristine
graphite but the inherent porosity of the 2D graphyne sheets and its relative
stacking leads to nanochannels that cross the material and whose sub-nanometer
size could allow the diffusion and storage of gas species. A molecular
prototype of the nanochannel is used to accurately determine first principles
adsorption energies and enthalpies for CO2, N2, H2O and H2 within the pores.
The proposed porous graphite presents no significant barrier for gas diffusion
and it shows a high propensity for CO2 physisorption with respect to the other
relevant components in both pre- and post-combustion gas streams.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01334</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Chachamis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vera</keyname><forenames>A. Sabio</forenames></author></authors><title>The High Energy Radiation Pattern from BFKLex</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, presented by G. Chachamis at the XXIV International Workshop
  on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 11-15 April 2016, DESY
  Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a recent study on high-energy jet production in the multi-Regge
limit done with the use of the Monte Carlo event generator BFKLex which
includes collinear improvements in the form of double-log contributions. We
will show results for the average transverse momentum and azimuthal angle of
the final state jets when at least one of them is very forward in rapidity and
another one is very backward. We also discuss the introduction of a new
observable which accounts for the average rapidity ratio among subsequent
emissions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01340</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01340</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Belov</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikora</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weis</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yerokhin</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sturm</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaum</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keitel</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harman</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Muonic vacuum polarization correction to the bound-electron $g$-factor</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The muonic vacuum polarization contribution to the $g$-factor of the electron
bound in a nuclear potential is investigated theoretically. The electric as
well as the magnetic loop contributions are evaluated. We found these muonic
effects to be observable in planned trapped-ion experiments with light and
medium-heavy highly charged ions. The enhancement due to the strong Coulomb
field boosts these contributions much above the corresponding terms in the
free-electron $g$-factor. Due to their magnitude, muonic vacuum polarization
terms are also significant in planned determinations of the fine-structure
constant from the bound-electron $g$-factor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01342</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Chachamis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caporale</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Celiberto</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>D. Gordo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vera</keyname><forenames>A. Sabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Inclusive three jet production at the LHC at 7 and 13 TeV collision
  energies</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, presented by G. Chachamis at the XXIV International Workshop
  on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects, 11-15 April 2016, DESY
  Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss briefly a recent study of new observables in LHC inclusive events
with three tagged jets. One jet is in the forward direction, the second is in
the backward direction and well-separated in rapidity from the first, whereas,
the third tagged jet is to be found in more central regions of the detector.
Taking into consideration that non-tagged mini-jet emissions are allowed and
that they may be accounted for by the BFKL gluon Green function, we project the
cross sections on azimuthal-angle components and define suitable ratios based
on these projections which can provide several distinct tests of the BFKL
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01345</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Leyva</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla-Escoboza</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sendi&#xf1;a-Nadal</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buld&#xfa;</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boccaletti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inter-layer synchronization in non-identical multi-layer networks</title><categories>nlin.AO nlin.CD</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inter-layer synchronization is a dynamical state occurring in multi-layer
networks composed of identical nodes. The state corresponds to have all layers
synchronized, with nodes in each layer which do not necessarily evolve in
unison. So far, the study of such a solution has been restricted to the case in
which all layers had an identical connectivity structure. When layers are not
identical, the inter-layer synchronous state is no longer a stable solution of
the system. Nevertheless, when layers differ in just a few links, an
approximate treatment is still feasible, and allows one to gather information
on whether and how the system may wander around an inter-layer synchronous
configuration. We report the details of an approximate analytical treatment for
a two-layer multiplex, which results in the introduction of an extra inertial
term accounting for structural differences. Numerical validation of the
predictions highlights the usefulness of our approach, especially for small or
moderate topological differences in the intra-layer coupling. Moreover, we
identify a non-trivial relationship between the betweenness centrality of the
missing links and the intra-layer coupling strength. Finally, by the use of two
multiplexed identical layers of electronic circuits in a chaotic regime, we
study the loss of inter-layer synchronization as a function of the betweenness
centrality of the removed links.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01364</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Alok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Meghraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sonawane</keyname><forenames>A. U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rawat</keyname><forenames>Prashant S.</forenames></author></authors><title>FMEA Based Risk Assessment of Component Failure Modes in Industrial
  Radiography</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-th physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Industrial radiography has its inimitable role in non-destructive
examinations. Industrial radiography devices, consisting of significantly high
activity of the radioisotopes, are operated manually by remotely held control
unit. Malfunctioning of these devices may cause potential exposure to the
operator and nearby public, and thus should be practiced under a systematic
risk control. To ensure the radiation safety, proactive risk assessment should
be implemented. Risk assessment in industrial radiography using the Failure
Modes &amp; Effect Analysis (FMEA) for the design and operation of industrial
radiography exposure devices has been carried out in this study. Total 56
component failure modes were identified and Risk Priority Numbers (RPNs) were
assigned by the FMEA expert team, based on the field experience and reported
failure data of various components. Results shows all the identified failure
modes have RPN in the range of 04 to 216 and most of the higher RPN are due to
low detectability and high severity levels. Assessment reveals that increasing
failure detectability is a practical and feasible approach to reduce the risk
in most of the failure modes of industrial radiography devices. Actions for
reducing RPN for each failure mode have been suggested. Feasibility of FMEA for
risk assessment in industrial radiography has been established by this study
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01385</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Jenab</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spanier</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of trapping effect on ion-acoustic solitary waves based on a fully
  kinetic simulation approach</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, accepted for publication in Physics of Plasmas</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fully kinetic simulation approach, treating each plasma component based on
the Vlasov equation, is adopted to study the disintegration of an initial
density perturbation (IDP) into a number of ion-acoustic solitary waves (IASWs)
in the presence of the trapping effect of electrons. The non-linear fluid
theory developed by Schamel has identified three separate regimes of
ion-acoustic solitary waves based on the trapping parameter. Here, the
disintegration process and the resulting self-consistent IASWs are studied in a
wide range of trapping parameters covering all the three regimes continuously.
The dependency of features such as the time of disintegration, the number,
speed and size of IASWs on the trapping parameter are focused upon. It is shown
that an increase in this parameter slows down the propagation of IASWs while
decreases their sizes in the phase space. These features of IASWs tend to
saturate for large value of trapping parameters. The disintegration time shows
a more complicated behavior than what was predicted by the theoretical
approach. Also for the case of trapping parameters bigger than one, propagation
of IASWs is observed in contrast with the theoretical predictions. The kinetic
simulation results unveil a smooth and well-defined dependency of solitary
waves' features on the trapping parameter, showing the possibility of bridging
all the three regimes. Finally, it is shown that for beta around zero, the
electron phase space structure of the accompanying vortex stays symmetric. The
effect of the electron-to-ion temperature ratio on the disintegration and the
propagation of IASWs are considered as a benchmarking test of the simulation
code (in the nonlinear regime).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01387</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mathew</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Raj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borah</keyname><forenames>Abhinandan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maliakkal</keyname><forenames>Carina B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abhilash</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deshmukh</keyname><forenames>Mandar M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanoscale electromechanics to measure thermal conductivity, expansion
  and interfacial losses</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 15 (2015) 7621-7626</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b03451</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of localized Joule heating on the mechanical properties
of doubly clamped nanowires under tensile stress. Local heating results in
systematic variation of the resonant frequency; these frequency changes result
from thermal stresses that depend on temperature dependent thermal conductivity
and expansion coefficient. The change in sign of the linear expansion
coefficient of InAs is reflected in the resonant response of the system near a
bath temperature of 20 K. Using finite element simulations to model the
experimentally observed frequency shifts, we show that the thermal conductivity
of a nanowire can be approximated in the 10-60 K temperature range by the
empirical form $\kappa=b$T W/mK, where the value of $b$ for a nanowire was
found to be $b=0.035$ W/mK$^2$, significantly lower than bulk values. Also,
local heating allows us to independently vary the temperature of the nanowire
relative to the clamping points pinned to the bath temperature. We suggest a
loss mechanism (dissipation $\sim10^{-4}-10^{-5}$) originating from the
interfacial clamping losses between the metal and the semiconductor
nanostructure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01388</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Regulski</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leonardi</keyname><forenames>Christoper Ross</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szumbarski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author></authors><title>On the spatial convergence and transient behaviour of lattice Boltzmann
  methods for modelling fluids with yield stress</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CG</categories><comments>45 pages (after compilation), 12 figures (with multifigures in those
  entries). Paper under revision in Journal of Computational Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the performance of two lattice Boltzmann method formulations
for yield-stress (i.e. viscoplastic) fluids has been investigated. The first
approach is based on the popular Papanastasiou regularisation of the fluid
rheology in conjunction with explicit modification of the lattice Boltzmann
relaxation rate. The second approach uses a locally-implicit formulation to
simultaneously solve for the fluid stress and the underlying particle
distribution functions. After investigating issues related to the lattice
symmetry and non-hydrodynamic Burnett stresses, the two models were compared in
terms of spatial convergence and their behaviour in transient and inertial
flows. The choice of lattice and the presence of Burnett stresses was found to
influence the results of both models, however the latter did not significantly
degrade the velocity field. Using Bingham flows in ducts and synthetic porous
media, it was found that the implicitly-regularised model was superior in
capturing transient and inertial fluid behaviour. This result presents
potential implications for the application of the Papanastasiou-regularised
model in such scenarios. In creeping flows the performance of both models was
found to be both similar and satisfactory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01390</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Desseroit</keyname><forenames>Marie-Charlotte</forenames><affiliation>CHU Poitiers - D&#xe9;partement de m&#xe9;decine nucl&#xe9;aire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tixier</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames><affiliation>CHU Poitiers - D&#xe9;partement de m&#xe9;decine nucl&#xe9;aire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames><affiliation>CHU Poitiers - D&#xe9;partement de m&#xe9;decine nucl&#xe9;aire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Siegel</keyname><forenames>Barry A</forenames><affiliation>CHU Poitiers - D&#xe9;partement de m&#xe9;decine nucl&#xe9;aire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rest</keyname><forenames>Catherine Cheze Le</forenames><affiliation>CHU Poitiers - D&#xe9;partement de m&#xe9;decine nucl&#xe9;aire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Visvikis</keyname><forenames>Dimitris</forenames><affiliation>LaTIM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hatt</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames><affiliation>LaTIM</affiliation></author></authors><title>Reliability of PET/CT shape and heterogeneity features in functional and
  morphological components of Non-Small Cell Lung Cancer tumors: a
  repeatability analysis in a prospective multi-center cohort</title><categories>cs.CV physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Journal of Nuclear Medicine, Society of Nuclear Medicine, 2016</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: The main purpose of this study was to assess the reliability of
shape and heterogeneity features in both Positron Emission Tomography (PET) and
low-dose Computed Tomography (CT) components of PET/CT. A secondary objective
was to investigate the impact of image quantization.Material and methods: A
Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act -compliant secondary
analysis of deidentified prospectively acquired PET/CT test-retest datasets of
74 patients from multi-center Merck and ACRIN trials was performed.
Metabolically active volumes were automatically delineated on PET with Fuzzy
Locally Adaptive Bayesian algorithm. 3DSlicerTM was used to semi-automatically
delineate the anatomical volumes on low-dose CT components. Two quantization
methods were considered: a quantization into a set number of bins
(quantizationB) and an alternative quantization with bins of fixed width
(quantizationW). Four shape descriptors, ten first-order metrics and 26
textural features were computed. Bland-Altman analysis was used to quantify
repeatability. Features were subsequently categorized as very reliable,
reliable, moderately reliable and poorly reliable with respect to the
corresponding volume variability. Results: Repeatability was highly variable
amongst features. Numerous metrics were identified as poorly or moderately
reliable. Others were (very) reliable in both modalities, and in all categories
(shape, 1st-, 2nd- and 3rd-order metrics). Image quantization played a major
role in the features repeatability. Features were more reliable in PET with
quantizationB, whereas quantizationW showed better results in CT.Conclusion:
The test-retest repeatability of shape and heterogeneity features in PET and
low-dose CT varied greatly amongst metrics. The level of repeatability also
depended strongly on the quantization step, with different optimal choices for
each modality. The repeatability of PET and low-dose CT features should be
carefully taken into account when selecting metrics to build multiparametric
models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01413</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Niemann</keyname><forenames>Anna Corinna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gooth</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Shu-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;&#xdf;ler</keyname><forenames>Svenja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sergelius</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xfc;hne</keyname><forenames>Ruben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rellinghaus</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shekhar</keyname><forenames>Chandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xfc;&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>Vicky</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Binghai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsch</keyname><forenames>Kornelius</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral magnetoresistance in the Weyl semimetal NbP</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NbP is a recently realized Weyl semimetal (WSM), hosting Weyl points through
which conduction and valence bands cross linearly in the bulk and exotic Fermi
arcs appear. However, the most intriguing transport phenomenon of a WSM, the
chiral anomaly-induced negative magnetoresistance (NMR) in parallel electric
and magnetic fields, has yet to be observed in NbP. In intrinsic NbP the Weyl
points lie far from the Fermi energy, making chiral magneto-transport elusive.
Here, we use Ga-doping to relocate the Fermi energy in NbP sufficiently close
to the Weyl points, for which the different Fermi surfaces are verified by
resultant quantum oscillations. Consequently, we observe a NMR for parallel
electric and magnetic fields, which is considered as a signature of the chiral
anomaly in condensed-matter physics. The NMR survives up to room temperature,
making NbP a versatile material platform for the development of Weyltronic
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01415</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiaojie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szolnoki</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author></authors><title>Individual wealth-based selection supports cooperation in spatial public
  goods games</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>19 pages; 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 32802 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a social dilemma game group members are allowed to decide if they
contribute to the joint venture or not. As a consequence, defectors, who do not
invest but only enjoy the mutual benefit, prevail and the system evolves onto
the tragedy of the common state. This unfortunate scenario can be avoided if
participation is not obligatory but only happens with a given probability. But
what if we also consider a player's individual wealth when to decide about
participation? To address this issue we propose a model in which the
probabilistic participation in the public goods game is combined with a
conditional investment mode that is based on individual wealth: if a player's
wealth exceeds a threshold value then it is qualified and can participate in
the joint venture. Otherwise, the participation is forbidden in the investment
interactions. We show that if only probabilistic participation is considered,
spatially structured populations cannot support cooperation better than
well-mixed populations where full defection state can also be avoided for small
participation probabilities. By adding the wealth-based criterion of
participation, however, structured populations are capable to augment network
reciprocity relevantly and allow cooperator strategy to dominate in a broader
parameter interval.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01431</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kharchenko</keyname><forenames>V. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial-wave Coulomb transition matrices for attractive interaction by
  Fock's method</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Leaning upon the Fock method of the stereographic projection of the
three-dimensional momentum space onto the four-dimensional unit sphere the
possibility of the analytical solving of the Lippmann-Schwinger integral
equation for the partial wave two-body Coulomb transition matrix at the ground
bound state energy has been studied. In this case new expressions for the
partial p-, d- and f-wave two-body Coulomb transition matrices have been
obtained in the simple analytical form. The developed approach can also be
extended to determine analytically the partial wave Coulomb transition matrices
at the energies of excited bound states. Keywords: Partial wave Coulomb
transition matrix; Lippmann-Schwinger equation; Fock method; Analytical
solution PACS Nos. 03.65.-w; 03.65.Nk; 34.20.Cf
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01436</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Boldrin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wills</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbital frustration in the S = 1/2 kagome magnet vesignieite,
  BaCu3V2O8(OD)2</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we report crystallographic and magnetic studies on high quality samples
of the magnetically frustrated S = 1/2 kagome antiferromagnet vesignieite,
BaCu3V2O8(OD)2. Powder neutron diffraction data collected from samples obtained
by a new hydrothermal synthetic route reveal a previously unobserved trigonal
P3121 structure, similar to the isoelectronic mineral SrCu3V2O8(OH)2. The
refined structure is consistent with orbital frustration of the eg d-orbitals
in a sublattice of the Cu2+ kagome network due to a dynamic Jahn-Teller effect,
which persists below the magnetic transition at TN = 9K and makes the material
an interesting candidate for exploring concomitant spin and orbital
frustration. A combination of crystallographic strain analysis and
magnetisation measurements indicate strong magnetostructural coupling which may
explain the varied magnetic behaviour between samples of vesignieite in the
literature. The revised orbital structure is similar to that found in
volborthite, rather than the quantum spin liquid herbertsmithite, and provides
a convincing argument for the differing magnetic properties found in these
frustrated magnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01463</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Davidge</keyname><forenames>H. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serjeant</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pearson</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Initial analysis of extragalactic fields using a new AKARI/IRC analysis
  pipeline</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Publications of the Korean
  Astronomical Society. Based on review at The Universe in the Light of AKARI
  and Synergy with future Large Space Telescopes, Oxford, 2014</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first results of a new data analysis pipeline for processing
extragalactic AKARI/IRC images. The main improvements of the pipeline over the
standard analysis are the removal of Earth shine and image distortion
correction. We present the differential number counts of the AKARI/IRC S11
filter IRAC validation field. The differential number counts are consistent
with S11 AKARI NEP deep and 12 microns WISE NEP number counts, and with a
phenomenological backward evolution galaxy model, at brighter fluxes densities.
There is a detection of deeper galaxies in the IRAC validation field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01483</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Aleksandrova</keyname><forenames>Nadezhda</forenames></author></authors><title>Seismic waves in a three-dimensional block medium</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 11 figures, 1 table and an electronic supplementary
  material which consists of 11 pages, 13 figures</comments><msc-class>74J15</msc-class><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Royal Society of London. A. Mathematical,
  Physical and Engineering Sciences 472, no. 2192, Article ID 20160111, 16 p.
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rspa.2016.0111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically the propagation of seismic waves in a three-dimensional
block medium. The medium is modeled by a spatial lattice of masses connected by
elastic springs and viscous dampers. We study Lamb's problem under a surface
point vertical load. The cases of both step and pulse load are considered. The
displacements and velocities are calculated for surface masses. The influence
of the viscosity of the dampers on the attenuation of perturbations is studied.
We compare our numerical results for the block medium with known analytical
solutions for the elastic medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01491</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Garrappa</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mainardi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>On Volterra functions and Ramanujan integrals</title><categories>math.CV math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, 11 figures</comments><msc-class>33E20, 33E50, 33F05, 45D05, 65D20</msc-class><journal-ref>Analysis 36 No 2 (2016), 89-105</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/anly-2015-5009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Volterra functions were introduced at the beginning of the twentieth century
as solutions of some integral equations of convolution type with logarithmic
kernel. Since then, few authors have studied this family of functions and faced
with the problem of providing a clear understanding of their asymptotic
behaviour for small and large arguments. This paper reviews some of the most
important results on Volterra functions and in particular collects, into a
quite general framework, several results on their asymptotic expansions, these
results turn out to be useful not only for the full understanding of the
behaviour of the Volterra functions but also for their numerical computation.
The connections with integrals of Ramanujan type, which have several important
applications, are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01493</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salinas</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Construction of hazard maps of Hantavirus contagion using Remote
  Sensing, logistic regression and Artificial Neural Networks: case Araucan\'ia
  Region, Chile</title><categories>q-bio.PE physics.bio-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this research, methods and computational results based on statistical
analysis and mathematical modelling, data collection in situ in order to make a
hazard map of Hanta Virus infection in the region of Araucania, Chile are
presented. The development of this work involves several elements such as
Landsat satellite images, biological information regarding seropositivity of
Hanta Virus and information concerning positive cases of infection detected in
the region. All this information has been processed to find a function that
models the danger of contagion in the region, through logistic regression
analysis and Artificial Neural Networks
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01501</id><created>2016-09-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Mersini-Houghton</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morse</keyname><forenames>Dillon N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking radiation conference, book of proceedings</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Proceedings of the 'Hawking Radiation' conference in Stockholm, Sweden 2015.
It includes a link to the video recording of the conference and all the talks,
discussions, and communications, that took place during the week of the
conference . We hope the recorded discussions will be helpful, especially to
the current and future young researchers and students.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01513</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Debord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amsanpally</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chafer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maurel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blondy</keyname><forenames>J. M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugonnot</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scol</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vincetti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerome</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benabid</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-low transmission loss (7.7 dB/km at 750 nm) inhibited-coupling
  guiding hollow-core photonic crystal fibers with a single ring of tubular
  lattice cladding</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The advent of photonic bandgap (PBG) guiding hollow- core photonic crystal
fiber (HC-PCF) sparked the hope of guiding light with attenuation below the
fundamental silica Rayleigh scattering limit (SRSL) of conventional step-index
fibers. Unfortunately, the combination of the strong core-cladding
optical-overlap, the surface roughness at the silica cladding struts and the
presence of interface-modes limited the lowest reported transmission-loss to
1.2 dB/km at 1550 nm. This hope is recently revived by the introduction of
hypocycloid core- contour (i.e. negative curvature) in inhibited-coupling (IC)
guiding HC-PCF, and the reduction of their confinement loss to a level that
makes them serious contenders for light transmission below the SRSL in UV-
VIS-NIR spectral range. Here, we report on several IC guiding HC-PCFs with a
hypocycloid core-contour and a cladding structure made of a single ring from a
tubular lattice. The fibers guide in the UV-VIS and NIR, and among which we
list one with a record transmission loss of 7.7 dB/km at ~750 nm (only a factor
~2 above the SRSL), and a second with an ultra-broad fundamental-band with loss
in the range of 10-20 dB/km spanning from 600 to 1200 nm. Both fibers present
near-single mode guidance and very low bend loss sensitivity. The results show
that the limit in the transmission is set by confinement loss for wavelengths
longer than ~1 {\mu}m and by surface- roughness for shorter wavelengths, thus
indicating that transmission loss well below the SRSL in the visible is
possible with a surface roughness reduction and would open the possibility of
the first UV low-loss light- guidance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01517</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Hua-Shu</forenames></author></authors><title>A universal equation for calculating the energy gradient function in the
  energy gradient theory</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math.AP</categories><comments>7 pages; 23 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relationship for the energy variation, work done, and energy dissipation
in unit volumetric fluid of incompressible flow is derived. A universal
equation for calculating the energy gradient function is presented for
situations where both pressure driven flow and shear driven flow are present
simultaneously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01522</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jordan</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic White Dwarfs with Heavy Elements</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the 20th European
  Workshop on White Dwarfs held July 25-29th, 2016 at the University of
  Warwick, United Kingdom</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using our newly developed model atmosphere code appropriate for magnetic
white dwarfs with metal lines in the Paschen-Back regime, we study various
magnetic white dwarfs and explore the effects of various parameters such as the
field geometry and the convective efficiency
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01538</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Abufouda</keyname><forenames>Mohammed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zweig</keyname><forenames>Katharina A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Theoretical Model for Understanding the Dynamics of Online Social
  Networks Decay</title><categories>cs.SI cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Online social networks represent a main source of communication and
information exchange in today's life. They facilitate exquisitely news sharing,
knowledge elicitation, and forming groups of same interests. Researchers in the
last two decades studied the growth dynamics of the online social networks
extensively questing a clear understanding of the behavior of humans in online
social networks that helps in many directions, like engineering better
recommendation systems and attracting new members. However, not all of social
networks achieved the desired growth, for example, online social networks like
MySpace, Orkut, and Friendster are out of service today. In this work, we
present a probabilistic theoretical model that captures the dynamics of the
social decay due to the inactivity of the members of a social network. The
model is proved to have some interesting mathematical properties, namely
\textit{submodularity}, which imply achieving the model optimization in a
reasonable performance. That means the maximization problem can be approximated
within a factor of $(1-1/e)$ and the minimization problem can be achieved in
polynomial time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01550</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Romero-Mu&#xf1;iz</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamura</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Victorino</forenames></author></authors><title>Applicability of scaling behavior and power laws in the analysis of the
  magnetocaloric effect in second-order phase transition materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 134401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.134401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, universal scaling has gained renewed attention in the study
of magnetocaloric materials. It has been applied to a wide variety of pure
elements and compounds, ranging from rare earth-based materials to transition
metal alloys, from bulk crystalline samples to nanoparticles. It is therefore
necessary to quantify the limits within which the scaling laws would remain
applicable for magnetocaloric research. For this purpose, a threefold approach
has been followed: a) the magnetocaloric responses of a set of materials with
Curie temperatures ranging from 46 to 336 K have been modeled with a mean-field
Brillouin model, b) experimental data for Gd has been analyzed, and c) a
3D-Ising model ---which is beyond the mean-field approximation--- has been
studied. In this way we can demonstrate that the conclusions extracted in this
work are model-independent. It is found that universal scaling remains
applicable up to applied fields which provide a magnetic energy to the system
up to 8\% of the thermal energy at the Curie temperature. In this range, the
predicted deviations from scaling laws remain below the experimental error
margin of carefully performed experiments. Therefore, for materials whose Curie
temperature is close to room temperature, scaling laws at the Curie temperature
would be applicable for the magnetic field range available at conventional
magnetism laboratories ($\sim 10$ T), well above the fields which are usually
available for magnetocaloric devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01551</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Cortes</keyname><forenames>Emiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huidobro</keyname><forenames>Paloma A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>Hugo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guldbrand</keyname><forenames>Stina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peveler</keyname><forenames>William J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parrinello</keyname><forenames>Simona</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;rlitz</keyname><forenames>Frederik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunsby</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neil</keyname><forenames>Mark A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sivan</keyname><forenames>Yonatan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkin</keyname><forenames>Ivan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>French</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>Stefan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic nanoprobes for stimulated emission depletion microscopy</title><categories>physics.optics physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>30 pages, 15 figures, main text and supplementary information</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Plasmonic nanoparticles influence the absorption and emission processes of
nearby emitters due to local enhancements of the illuminating radiation and the
photonic density of states. Here, we use the plasmon resonance of metal
nanoparticles in order to enhance the stimulated depletion of excited molecules
for super-resolved microscopy. We demonstrate stimulated emission depletion
(STED) microscopy with gold nanorods with a long axis of only 26 nm and a width
of 8 nm that provide an enhancement of the resolution compared to
fluorescent-only probes without plasmonic components irradiated with the same
depletion power. These novel nanoparticle-assisted STED probes represent a
~2x10^3 reduction in probe volume compared to previously used nanoparticles and
we demonstrate their application to the first plasmon-assisted STED cellular
imaging. We also discuss their current limitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01557</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Spiridonov</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Elliptic hypergeometric functions</title><categories>math.CA hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>218 pp, Habilitation Thesis, in Russian, JINR, Dubna, 2004</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is author's Habilitation Thesis (Dr. Sci. dissertation) submitted at the
beginning of September 2004. It is written in Russian and is posted due to the
continuing requests for the manuscript.
  The content: 1. Introduction, 2. Nonlinear chains with the discrete time and
their self-similar solutions, 3. General theory of theta hypergeometric series,
4. Theta hypergeometric integrals, 5. Biorthogonal functions, 6. Elliptic
hypergeometric functions with |q|=1, 7. Conclusion, 8. References.
  It contains an outline of a general heuristic scheme for building univariate
special functions through self-similar reductions of spectral transformation
chains, which allowed construction of the differential-difference q-Painleve
equations, as well as of the most general known set of elliptic biorthogonal
functions comprising all classical orthogonal polynomials and biorthogonal
rational functions. One of the key results of the thesis consists in the
discovery of genuinely transcendental elliptic hypergeometric functions
determined by the elliptic hypergeometric integrals. The whole theory of such
integrals can be built from the univariate elliptic beta integral -- the most
complicated known definite integral with exact evaluation, which generalizes
the ordinary binomial theorem and its q-extension, Euler's beta integral, the
measure for Askey-Wilson polynomials, and many other previously established
results on ordinary and q-hypergeometric functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01559</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Reeves</keyname><forenames>Kyle G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanai</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion Quantum Monte Carlo Study of Martensitic Phase Transition: The
  Case of Phosphorene</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 124705 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4962759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent technical advances in dealing with finite-size errors make quantum
Monte Carlo methods quite appealing for treating extended systems in electronic
structure calculations, especially when commonly-used density functional theory
(DFT) methods might not be satisfactory. We present a theoretical study of
martensitic phase transition of a two-dimensional phosphorene by employing
diffusion Monte Carlo (DMC) approach to investigate the energetics of this
phase transition. The DMC calculation supports DFT prediction of having a
rather diffusive barrier that is characterized by having two transition states,
in addition to confirming that the so-called black and blue phases of
phosphorene are essentially degenerate. At the same time, the calculation shows
the importance of treating correlation energy accurately for describing the
energy changes in the martensitic phase transition, as is already widely
appreciated for chemical bond formation/dissociation. Building on the atomistic
characterization of the phase transition process, we also discuss how
mechanical strain influences the stabilities of the two phases of phosphorene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01566</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Tolstoy</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Super-de Sitter and alternative super-Poincar\'e symmetries</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, X. International Workshop LIE THEORY AND ITS APPLICATIONS
  IN PHYSICS, (Varna, Bulgaria, 2013)</comments><journal-ref>Lie Theory and Its Application in Physics (Ed. V. Dobrev),
  Springer Proceedings in Mathematics, v. 111, (2014), 357--367</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-4-431-55285-7_26</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well-known that de Sitter Lie algebra $\mathfrak{o}(1,4)$ contrary to
anti-de Sitter one $\mathfrak{o}(2,3)$ does not have a standard
$\mathbb{Z}_2$-graded superextension. We show here that the Lie algebra
$\mathfrak{o}(1,4)$ has a superextension based on the
$\mathbb{Z}_2\times\mathbb{Z}_2$-grading. Using the standard contraction
procedure for this superextension we obtain an {\it alternative}
super-Poincar\'e algebra with the $\mathbb{Z}_2\times\mathbb{Z}_2$-grading.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01575</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macchiavelli</keyname><forenames>A. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bader</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cromaz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dilling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gade</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallant</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holt</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssens</keyname><forenames>R. V. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;cken</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauritsen</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>I. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Men&#xe9;ndez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noji</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paschalis</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Recchia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rissanen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwenk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonis</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stroberg</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tostevin</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walz</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weisshaar</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiens</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wimmer</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unexpected distribution of $\nu1f_{7/2}$ strength in the calcium
  isotopes at $N$=30</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The calcium isotopes have emerged as an important testing ground for new
microscopically derived shell-model interactions, and a great deal of focus has
been directed toward this region. We investigate the relative spectroscopic
strengths associated with $1f_{7/2}$ neutron hole states in $^{47, 49}$Ca
following one-neutron knockout reactions from $^{48,50}$Ca. The observed
reduction of strength populating the lowest 7/2$^{-}_{1}$ state in $^{49}$Ca,
as compared to $^{47}$Ca, is consistent with the description given by
shell-model calculations based on two- and three-nucleon forces in the neutron
$pf$ model space, implying a fragmentation of the $l$=3 strength to
higher-lying states. The experimental result is inconsistent with both the
GXPF1 interaction routinely used in this region of the nuclear chart and with
microscopic calculations in an extended model space including the $\nu1g_{9/2}$
orbital.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01579</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Mili&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Carles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marest</keyname><forenames>Tomy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudlinski</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skryabin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supercontinuum generation with bright and dark solitons in optical
  fibers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically and experimentally supercontinuum generation in optical
fibers with dark and bright solitons simultaneously contributing into the
spectral broadening and dispersive wave generation. We report a novel type of
weak trapped radiation arising due to interaction of bright solitons with the
dark soliton background. This radiation expresses itself as two pulses with the
continuously shifting spectra constituting the short and long wavelength limits
of the continuum. Our theoretical and experimental results are in good
agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01589</id><created>2016-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Hadjighasem</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haller</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Level set formulation of two-dimensional Lagrangian vortex detection
  methods</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Chaos. 2016;26(10):103102</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose here the use of the variational level set methodology to capture
Lagrangian vortex boundaries in 2D unsteady velocity fields. This method
reformulates earlier approaches that seek material vortex boundaries as
extremum solutions of variational problems. We demonstrate the performance of
this technique for two different variational formulations built upon different
notions of coherence. The first formulation uses an energy functional that
penalizes the deviation of a closed material line from piecewise uniform
stretching [Haller and Beron-Vera, J. Fluid Mech. 731, R4 (2013)]. The second
energy function is derived for a graph-based approach to vortex boundary
detection [Hadjighasem et al., Phys. Rev. E 93, 063107 (2016)]. Our level-set
formulation captures an a priori unknown number of vortices simultaneously at
relatively low computational cost. We illustrate the approach by identifying
vortices from different coherence principles in several examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0303098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0303098</id><created>2003-03-06</created><updated>2003-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCoy</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic calculation of B4 for hard spheres in even dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures. Some typos corrected. Final version, to appear
  in the Journal of Statistical Physics</comments><report-no>YITP-SB-03-09</report-no><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 114: 1343-1360 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1023/B:JOSS.0000013959.30878.d2</doi><abstract>  We exactly calculate the fourth virial coefficient for hard spheres in even
dimensions for D=4,6,8,10, and 12.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0303100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0303100</id><created>2003-03-06</created><updated>2003-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCoy</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative virial coefficients and the dominance of loose packed diagrams
  for D-dimensional hard spheres</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>26 pages, 69 figures. Some typos corrected. Final version, to appear
  in the Journal of Statistical Physics</comments><report-no>YITP-SB-03-10</report-no><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 114: 1361-1392 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1023/B:JOSS.0000013960.83555.7d</doi><abstract>  We study the virial coefficients B_k of hard spheres in D dimensions by means
of Monte-Carlo integration. We find that B_5 is positive in all dimensions but
that B_6 is negative for all D &gt;= 6. For 7&lt;=k&lt;=17 we compute sets of Ree-Hoover
diagrams and find that either for large D or large k the dominant diagrams are
&quot;loose packed&quot;. We use these results to study the radius of convergence and the
validity of the many approximations used for the equations of state for hard
spheres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0410511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0410511</id><created>2004-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCoy</keyname><forenames>Barry M.</forenames></author></authors><title>New results for virial coefficients of hard spheres in D dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, to appear in conference proceedings of STATPHYS
  2004 in Pramana - Journal of Physics</comments><report-no>YITP-SB-04-57</report-no><journal-ref>Pramana -- J. Phys. 64: 775-783 (2005)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/BF02704582</doi><abstract>  We present new results for the virial coefficients B_k with k &lt;= 10 for hard
spheres in dimensions D=2,...,8.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0503525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-10-06</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0503525</id><created>2005-03-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Clisby</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCoy</keyname><forenames>B. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ninth and Tenth Order Virial Coefficients for Hard Spheres in D
  Dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>33 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 122: 15-57 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-005-8080-0</doi><abstract>  We evaluate the virial coefficients B_k for k&lt;=10 for hard spheres in
dimensions D=2,...,8. Virial coefficients with k even are found to be negative
when D&gt;=5. This provides strong evidence that the leading singularity for the
virial series lies away from the positive real axis when D&gt;=5. Further analysis
provides evidence that negative virial coefficients will be seen for some k&gt;10
for D=4, and there is a distinct possibility that negative virial coefficients
will also eventually occur for D=3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
