<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T12:11:11Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-11-20" from="2017-11-20" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.2150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.2150</id><created>2011-10-10</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Strohmaier</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uski</keyname><forenames>Ville</forenames></author></authors><title>An Algorithm for the Computation of Eigenvalues, Spectral Zeta Functions
  and Zeta-Determinants on Hyperbolic Surfaces</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP math.NA</categories><comments>48 pages, 8 figures, LaTeX, some more typos corrected, more Figures
  added, some explanations are more detailed now, Fenchel-Nielsen coordinates
  and numbers for the surface with symmetry group of order 10 corrected,
  datafiles are now available as ancillary files</comments><msc-class>11F72, 11M36, 35P15, 58J52</msc-class><journal-ref>Communications in Mathematical Physics February 2013, Volume 317,
  Issue 3, pp 827-869</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-012-1557-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a rigorous scheme that makes it possible to compute eigenvalues of
the Laplace operator on hyperbolic surfaces within a given precision. The
method is based on an adaptation of the method of particular solutions to the
case of locally symmetric spaces and on explicit estimates for the
approximation of eigenfunctions on hyperbolic surfaces by certain basis
functions. It can be applied to check whether or not there is an eigenvalue in
an \epsilon-neighborhood of a given number \lambda&gt;0. This makes it possible to
find all the eigenvalues in a specified interval, up to a given precision with
rigorous error estimates. The method converges exponentially fast with the
number of basis functions used. Combining the knowledge of the eigenvalues with
the Selberg trace formula we are able to compute values and derivatives of the
spectral zeta function again with error bounds. As an example we calculate the
spectral determinant and the Casimir energy of the Bolza surface and other
surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.6795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.6795</id><created>2012-05-30</created><updated>2012-09-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kalam</keyname><forenames>Mehedi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usmani</keyname><forenames>Anisul Ain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Farook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossein</keyname><forenames>Sk. Monowar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karar</keyname><forenames>Indrani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author></authors><title>A relativistic model for Strange Quark Star</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures. Major revision has been done</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Theor. Phys. (2013) 52:3319</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-013-1629-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a spherically symmetric and anisotropic model for strange quark
stars within the framework of MIT Bag model. Though the model is found to
comply with all the physical requirements of a realistic star satisfying a
strange matter equation of state (EOS), the estimated values the Bag constant
for different strange star candidates like Her X-1, SAX J 1808.4-3658 and 4U
1820-30, clearly indicate that the Bag constant need not necessarily lie within
the range of 60-80 MeV fm$^{-3}$ as claimed in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.2906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.2906</id><created>2013-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Govender</keyname><forenames>Megan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogadi</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Shyam</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational collapse in spatially isotropic coordinates</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Submitted for publication</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Relativ. Gravit (2015) 47:25</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dynamical nature of the collapse process of a spherically
symmetric star in quasi-static hydrodynamical equilibrium. The star collapses
from an initial static configuration by dissipating energy in the form of a
radial heat flux. The dissipation ensures that the singularity is never formed
and the stellar mass completely evaporates over a finite time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.6435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.6435</id><created>2014-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Eser</keyname><forenames>E. Kilerci</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultraluminous Infrared Galaxies in the AKARI All Sky Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>31 pages, 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>2014ApJ...797...54K</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/797/1/54</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new catalog of 118 Ultraluminous Infrared Galaxies (ULIRGs) and
one Hyperluminous Infrared Galaxy (HLIRG) by crossmatching AKARI all-sky survey
with the Sloan Digital Sky Survey Data Release 10 (SDSS DR10) and the Final
Data Release of the Two-Degree Field Galaxy Redshift Survey (2dFGRS). 40 of the
ULIRGs and one HLIRG are new identifications. We find that ULIRGs are
interacting pair galaxies or ongoing/post mergers. This is consistent with the
widely accepted view: ULIRGs are major mergers of disk galaxies. We confirm the
previously known positive trend between the AGN fraction and IR luminosity. We
show that ULIRGs have a large off-set from the 'main sequence' up to z~1; their
off-set from the z~2 'main sequence' is relatively smaller. We find a
consistent result with the previous studies showing that compared to local star
forming SDSS galaxies of similar mass, local ULIRGs have lower oxygen
abundances. We for the first time demonstrate that ULIRGs follow the
fundamental metallicity relation (FMR). The scatter of ULIRGs around the FMR
(0.09 dex - 0.5 dex) is comparable with the scatter of z~2-3 galaxies. Their
optical colors show that ULIRGs are mostly blue galaxies and this agrees with
previous findings. We provide the largest local (0.050 &lt; z &lt; 0.487) ULIRG
catalog with stellar masses, SFRs, gas metallicities and optical colors. Our
catalog provides us active galaxies analogous to high-z galaxies in the local
Universe where they can be rigorously scrutinized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00866</id><created>2015-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex Korteweg-de Vries equation and Nonlinear dust-acoustic waves in
  a magnetoplasma with a pair of trapped ions</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures; To appear in Appl. Math. Comput. (2015)</comments><journal-ref>Applied Mathematics and Computation 256 (2015) 368-374</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.amc.2015.01.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonlinear propagation of dust-acoustic (DA) waves in a magnetized dusty
plasma with a pair of trapped ions is investigated. Starting from a set of
hydrodynamic equations for massive dust fluids as well as kinetic Vlasov
equations for ions, and applying the reductive perturbation technique, a
Korteweg-de Vries (KdV)-like equation with a complex coefficient of
nonlinearity is derived, which governs the evolution of small-amplitude DA
waves in plasmas. The complex coefficient arises due to vortex-like
distributions of both positive and negative ions. An analytical as well as
numerical solution of the KdV equation are obtained and analyzed with the
effects of external magnetic field, the dust pressure as well as different mass
and temperatures of positive and negative ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02988</id><created>2015-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Ranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Shyam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tikekar</keyname><forenames>Ramesh</forenames></author></authors><title>A class of conformally flat solutions for systems undergoing radiative
  gravitational collapse</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>To appear in Gen. Relativ. Grav</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Relativ. Gravit (2015) 47:25</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-015-1869-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a class of conformally flat solutions of the Einstein's field
equations for spherical systems undergoing gravitational collapse accompanied
with radial heat flux. The interior space-time of the collapsing matter is
chosen to be conformal to the Robertson-Walker space-time so that its Weyl
tensor vanishes identically. The conditions which ensure smooth matching of the
interior space-time of the collapsing system, across its boundary, with the
exterior space-time of a radiating star which is described by Vaidya metric
lead to an equation governing its overall subsequent evolution. New solutions
of this equation have been shown to provide physically viable models of
collapsing stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07891</id><created>2015-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>Tuan</forenames><affiliation>Dunlap Institute, University of Toronto</affiliation><affiliation>Physics and Astronomy Department, UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kerzendorf</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames><affiliation>Department of Astronomy, University of Toronto</affiliation><affiliation>ESO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Winsor</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames><affiliation>Dunlap Institute, University of Toronto</affiliation><affiliation>Grenfell Campus, Memorial University of Newfoundland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>St&#xf8;stad</keyname><forenames>Morten</forenames><affiliation>Department of Astronomy, University of Toronto</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>Mark R.</forenames><affiliation>Physics and Astronomy Department, UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Jessica R.</forenames><affiliation>IfA, University of Hawaii</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ghez</keyname><forenames>Andrea M.</forenames><affiliation>Physics and Astronomy Department, UCLA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Discovery of low-metallicity stars in the central parsec of the Milky
  Way</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures, ApJ Accepted</comments><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/809/2/143</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a metallicity analysis of 83 late-type giants within the central 1
pc of the Milky Way. K-band spectroscopy of these stars were obtained with the
medium-spectral resolution integral-field spectrograph NIFS on Gemini North
using laser-guide star adaptive optics. Using spectral template fitting with
the MARCS synthetic spectral grid, we find that there is large variation in
metallicity, with stars ranging from [M/H] $&lt;$ -1.0 to above solar metallicity.
About 6\% of the stars have [M/H] $&lt;$ -0.5. This result is in contrast to
previous observations, with smaller samples, that show stars at the Galactic
center have approximately solar metallicity with only small variations. Our
current measurement uncertainties are dominated by systematics in the model,
especially at [M/H] $&gt;$ 0, where there are stellar lines not represented in the
model. However, the conclusion that there are low metallicity stars, as well as
large variations in metallicity is robust. The metallicity may be an indicator
of the origin of these stars. The low-metallicity population is consistent with
that of globular clusters in the Milky Way, but their small fraction likely
means that globular cluster infall is not the dominant mechanism for forming
the Milky Way nuclear star cluster. The majority of stars are at or above solar
metallicity, which suggests they were formed closer to the Galactic center or
from the disk. In addition, our results indicate that it will be important for
star formation history analyses using red giants at the Galactic center to
consider the effect of varying metallicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04538</id><created>2015-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Fusy</keyname><forenames>&#xc9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing two statistical ensembles of quadrangulations: a continued
  fraction approach</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 17 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t15/133</report-no><journal-ref>Ann. Inst. Henri Poincar\'e Comb. Phys. Interact. 4 (2017),
  125-176</journal-ref><doi>10.4171/AIHPD/37</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a continued fraction approach to compare two statistical ensembles of
quadrangulations with a boundary, both controlled by two parameters. In the
first ensemble, the quadrangulations are bicolored and the parameters control
their numbers of vertices of both colors. In the second ensemble, the
parameters control instead the number of vertices which are local maxima for
the distance to a given vertex, and the number of those which are not. Both
ensembles may be described either by their (bivariate) generating functions at
fixed boundary length or, after some standard slice decomposition, by their
(bivariate) slice generating functions. We first show that the fixed boundary
length generating functions are in fact equal for the two ensembles. We then
show that the slice generating functions, although different for the two
ensembles, simply correspond to two different ways of encoding the same
quantity as a continued fraction. This property is used to obtain explicit
expressions for the slice generating functions in a constructive way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06467</id><created>2015-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Scholtes</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wider</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garas</keyname><forenames>Antonios</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-Order Aggregate Networks in the Analysis of Temporal Networks:
  Path structures and centralities</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>27 pages, 13 figures, 3 tables</comments><msc-class>05C82</msc-class><acm-class>C.2.1; G.2.2; H.1.2; H.2.8; H.3.3</acm-class><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal B, 89:61, March 2 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-60663-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent research on temporal networks has highlighted the limitations of a
static network perspective for our understanding of complex systems with
dynamic topologies. In particular, recent works have shown that i) the specific
order in which links occur in real-world temporal networks affects causality
structures and thus the evolution of dynamical processes, and ii) higher-order
aggregate representations of temporal networks can be used to analytically
study the effect of these order correlations on dynamical processes. In this
article we analyze the effect of order correlations on path-based centrality
measures in real-world temporal networks. Analyzing temporal equivalents of
betweenness, closeness and reach centrality in six empirical temporal networks,
we first show that an analysis of the commonly used static, time-aggregated
representation can give misleading results about the actual importance of
nodes. We further study higher-order time-aggregated networks, a recently
proposed generalization of the commonly applied static, time-aggregated
representation of temporal networks. Here, we particularly define path-based
centrality measures based on second-order aggregate networks, empirically
validating that node centralities calculated in this way better capture the
true temporal centralities of nodes than node centralities calculated based on
the commonly used static (first-order) representation. Apart from providing a
simple and practical method for the approximation of path-based centralities in
temporal networks, our results highlight interesting perspectives for the use
of higher-order aggregate networks in the analysis of time-stamped network
data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01773</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01773</id><created>2015-11-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>The distance-dependent two-point function of triangulations: a new
  derivation from old results</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>22 pages, 13 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t15/187</report-no><journal-ref>Inst. Henri Poincar\'e Comb. Phys. Interact. 4 (2017), 177-211</journal-ref><doi>10.4171/AIHPD/38</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new derivation of the distance-dependent two-point function of
random planar triangulations. As it is well-known, this function is intimately
related to the generating functions of so-called slices, which are pieces of
triangulation having boundaries made of shortest paths of prescribed length. We
show that the slice generating functions are fully determined by a direct
recursive relation on their boundary length. Remarkably, the kernel of this
recursion is some quantity introduced and computed by Tutte a long time ago in
the context of a global enumeration of planar triangulations. We may thus rely
on these old results to solve our new recursion relation explicitly in a
constructive way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08998</id><created>2015-11-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaeta</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>On the isotropic-biaxial phase transition in nematic liquid crystals</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.soft math.MP physics.class-ph</categories><comments>To appear in EuroPhys. Lett</comments><journal-ref>EuroPhys. Lett. 112 (2015), 46002</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/112/46002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply a recently developed technique to determine adapted coordinates for
the sixth degree Landau-deGennes potential, in which the potential is specially
simple, to analyze the possibility of a direct transition between the fully
symmetric state and a biaxial phase in nematic liquid crystals. {Our results
confirm, with simpler computations, results by Allender and Longa.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00179</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The distance-dependent two-point function of quadrangulations: a new
  derivation by direct recursion</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>22 pages, 14 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t15/211</report-no><journal-ref>Ann. Inst. Henri Poincar\'e Comb. Phys. Interact. 4 (2017),
  213-244</journal-ref><doi>10.4171/AIHPD/39</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a new derivation of the distance-dependent two-point function of
planar quadrangulations by solving a new direct recursion relation for the
associated slice generating functions. Our approach for both the derivation and
the solution of this new recursion is in all points similar to that used
recently by the author in the context of planar triangulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07433</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07433</id><created>2016-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Some results on the statistics of hull perimeters in large planar
  triangulations and quadrangulations</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>32 pages, 16 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t16/015</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, Volume 49,
  Number 44, 445203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/44/445203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The hull perimeter at distance d in a planar map with two marked vertices at
distance k from each other is the length of the closed curve separating these
two vertices and lying at distance d from the first one (d&lt;k). We study the
statistics of hull perimeters in large random planar triangulations and
quadrangulations as a function of both k and d. Explicit expressions for the
probability density of the hull perimeter at distance d, as well as for the
joint probability density of hull perimeters at distances d1 and d2, are
obtained in the limit of infinitely large k. We also consider the situation
where the distance d at which the hull perimeter is measured corresponds to a
finite fraction of k. The various laws that we obtain are identical for
triangulations and for quadrangulations, up to a global rescaling. Our approach
is based on recursion relations recently introduced by the author which
determine the generating functions of so-called slices, i.e. pieces of maps
with appropriate distance constraints. It is indeed shown that the map
decompositions underlying these recursion relations are intimately linked to
the notion of hull perimeters and provide a simple way to fully control them.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05862</id><created>2016-03-18</created><updated>2016-08-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jhih-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Hao-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Convertino</keyname><forenames>Domenica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coletti</keyname><forenames>Camilla</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Lo-Yueh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiu</keyname><forenames>Hung-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Maw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Min-Fa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heun</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chien</keyname><forenames>Forest Shih-Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yi-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Chia-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chung-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient n-type Doping in Epitaxial Graphene through Strong Lateral
  Orbital Hybridization of Ti Adsorbate</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 109 (2016) 300-305</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2016.08.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, various doping methods for epitaxial graphene have been
demonstrated through atom substitution and adsorption. Here we observe by
angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES) a coupling-induced Dirac cone
renormalization when depositing small amounts of Ti onto epitaxial graphene on
SiC. We obtain a remarkably high doping efficiency and a readily tunable
carrier velocity simply by changing the amount of deposited Ti.
First-principles theoretical calculations show that a strong lateral
(non-vertical) orbital coupling leads to an efficient doping of graphene by
hybridizing the 2pz orbital of graphene and the 3d orbitals of the Ti
adsorbate, which attached on graphene without creating any trap/scattering
states. This Ti-induced hybridization is adsorbate-specific and has major
consequences for efficient doping as well as applications towards
adsorbate-induced modification of carrier transport in graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08925</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2017-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shalini</keyname></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saini</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Amplitude modulation of three-dimensional low frequency solitary waves
  in a magnetized dusty superthermal plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, The revised version in which the title is
  changed, typos are corrected and few references are added, to appear in J
  Theo Appl Phys (2017)</comments><journal-ref>J Theor Appl Phys (2017) 11:217-224</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s40094-017-0255-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The amplitude modulation of three dimensional (3D) dust ion-acoustic wave
(DIAW) packets is studied in a collisionless magnetized plasma with inertial
positive ions, superthermal electrons and negatively charged immobile dust
grains. By using the reductive perturbation technique, a 3D-nonlinear
Schr\&quot;odinger (NLS) equation is derived, which governs the slow modulation of
DIAW packets. The latter are found to be stable in the low-frequency
$(\omega&lt;\omega_c)$ regime, whereas they are unstable for $\omega&gt;\omega_c$,
and the modulational instability (MI) is related to the modulational
obliqueness $(\theta)$. Here, $\omega~(\omega_c)$ is the nondimensional wave
(ion-cyclotron) frequency. It is shown that the superthermal parameter
$\kappa$, the frequency $\omega_c$ as well as the charged dust impurity
$(0&lt;\mu&lt;1)$ shift the MI domains around the $\omega-\theta$ plane, where $\mu$
is the ratio of electron to ion number densities. Furthermore, it is found that
the decay rate of instability is quenched by the superthermal parameter
$\kappa$ with cut-offs at lower wave number of modulation ($K$), however, it
can be higher (lower) with increasing values of $\mu$ ($\omega_c$) having
cut-offs at higher values of $K$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04828</id><created>2016-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Davydychev</keyname><forenames>Andrei I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical splitting and reduction of Feynman diagrams</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures, contribution for proceedings of ACAT 2016
  (Valparaiso, Chile, January 18-22, 2016)</comments><report-no>MSU-SINP 2016-2/890</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 762 (2016) 012068</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/762/1/012068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A geometrical approach to the calculation of N-point Feynman diagrams is
reviewed. It is shown that the geometrical splitting yields useful connections
between Feynman integrals with different momenta and masses. It is demonstrated
how these results can be used to reduce the number of variables in the
occurring functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06814</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shirakawa</keyname><forenames>Tomonori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tohyama</keyname><forenames>Takami</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kokalj</keyname><forenames>Jure</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sota</keyname><forenames>Shigetoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunoki</keyname><forenames>Seiji</forenames></author></authors><title>Ground state phase diagram of the triangular lattice Hubbard model by
  density matrix renormalization group method</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 205130 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.205130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional density-matrix renormalization group method is employed to
examine the ground state phase diagram of the Hubbard model on the triangular
lattice at half filling. The calculation reveals two discontinuities in the
double occupancy with increasing the repulsive Hubbard interaction U at Uc1 =
7.55 t and Uc2 = 9.65 t (t being the hopping integral), indicating that there
are three phases separated by first order transitions. The absence of any
singularity in physical quantities for 0 &lt; U &lt; Uc1 implies that this phase
corresponds to a metallic phase. The local spin density induced by an applied
pinning magnetic field for U &gt; Uc2 exhibits a three sublattice feature, which
is compatible with the Neel ordered state realized in the strong coupling
limit. For Uc1 &lt; U &lt; Uc2, a response to the applied pinning magnetic field is
comparable to that in the metallic phase but a relatively large spin
correlation length is found with neither valence bond nor chiral magnetic
order, suggesting a paramagnetic nature which resembles gapless spin liquid.
The calculation also finds that the pair- ing correlation function
monotonically decreases with increasing U and thus the superconductivity is
unlikely in the intermediate phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01334</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Luigi Amedeo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morandin</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure function and fractal dissipation for an intermittent inviscid
  dyadic model</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>33 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 356 (2017), no. 1, 231--260</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2974-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a generalization of the original tree-indexed dyadic model by Katz
and Pavlovi\'c for the turbulent energy cascade of three-dimensional Euler
equation. We allow the coefficients to vary with some restrictions, thus giving
the model a realistic spatial intermittency. By introducing a forcing term on
the first component, the fixed point of the dynamics is well defined and some
explicit computations allow to prove the rich multifractal structure of the
solution. In particular the exponent of the structure function is concave in
accordance with other theoretical and experimental models. Moreover anomalous
energy dissipation happens in a fractal set of dimension strictly less than 3.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02925</id><created>2016-08-09</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>Piers</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory Perspective: SCES 2016</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures. Theory Perspective Talk from SCES 2016,
  Hangzhou, China. Additional references on spin exciton in SmB6, Majorana time
  reversal symmetry and discussion about quantum spin ice added to v3</comments><journal-ref>Philosophical Magazine, 97, 3257-3543 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/14786435.2016.1232866</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New discoveries and developments in almost every area of correlated electron
physics were presented at SCES 2016. Here, I provide a personal perspective on
some of these developments, highlighting some new ideas in computational
physics, discussing the &quot;hidden order&quot; challenges of cuprate and heavy electron
superconductors, the mysterious bulk excitations of the topological Kondo
insulator SmB$_{6}$ and new progress in research on quantum spin ice, iron
based superconductors and quantum criticality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04073</id><created>2016-08-14</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Mandip</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Stern-Gerlach experiment and path entanglement of Bose-Einstein
  condensate</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 043620 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.043620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, a quantum Stern-Gerlach thought experiment is introduced
where, in addition to the intrinsic angular momentum of an atom, the magnetic
field is also treated quantum mechanically. A freely falling spin polarised
Bose-Einstein condensate passes close to a flux-qubit and interacts with the
quantum superimposed magnetic field of the flux-qubit. Such an interaction
results a macroscopic quantum entanglement of the path of a Bose-Einstein
condensate with the magnetic flux quantum state of the flux-qubit. In this
paper, three regimes of coupling between the flux-qubit and a freely falling
Bose-Einstein condensate are discussed. The decoherence time limit required to
achieve a strong coupling regime is also estimated. This paper also explores,
how to produce a path entangled Bose-Einstein condensate where, the condensate
can be located at physically distinct locations simultaneously. Paper provides
new fundamental insights about the foundations of the quantum Stern-Gerlach
experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01907</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pirker</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunjko</keyname><forenames>Vedran</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briegel</keyname><forenames>Hans J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement generation secure against general attacks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages + 31 pages supplementary material, 1 + 13 figures, V2:
  replaced with accepted version, improved presentation and results,</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 113012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa8086</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a security proof for establishing private entanglement by means of
recurrence-type entanglement distillation protocols over noisy quantum
channels. We consider protocols where the local devices are imperfect, and show
that nonetheless a confidential quantum channel can be established, and used to
e.g. perform distributed quantum computation in a secure manner. While our
results are not fully device independent (which we argue to be unachievable in
settings with quantum outputs), our proof holds for arbitrary channel noise and
noisy local operations, and even in the case where the eavesdropper learns the
noise. Our approach relies on non-trivial properties of distillation protocols
which are used in conjunction with de-Finetti and post-selection-type
techniques to reduce a general quantum attack in a non-asymptotic scenario to
an i.i.d. setting. As a side result, we also provide entanglement distillation
protocols for non-i.i.d. input states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02400</id><created>2016-10-07</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pratley</keyname><forenames>Luke</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEwen</keyname><forenames>Jason D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>d'Avezac</keyname><forenames>Mayeul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carrillo</keyname><forenames>Rafael E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onose</keyname><forenames>Alexandru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiaux</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust sparse image reconstruction of radio interferometric observations
  with purify</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>22 pages, 10 figures, PURIFY code available at
  http://basp-group.github.io/purify</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 473,
  Issue 1, 1 January 2018, Pages 1038--1058</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2237</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next-generation radio interferometers, such as the Square Kilometre Array
(SKA), will revolutionise our understanding of the universe through their
unprecedented sensitivity and resolution. However, to realise these goals
significant challenges in image and data processing need to be overcome. The
standard methods in radio interferometry for reconstructing images, such as
CLEAN, have served the community well over the last few decades and have
survived largely because they are pragmatic. However, they produce
reconstructed inter\-ferometric images that are limited in quality and
scalability for big data. In this work we apply and evaluate alternative
interferometric reconstruction methods that make use of state-of-the-art sparse
image reconstruction algorithms motivated by compressive sensing, which have
been implemented in the PURIFY software package. In particular, we implement
and apply the proximal alternating direction method of multipliers (P-ADMM)
algorithm presented in a recent article. First, we assess the impact of the
interpolation kernel used to perform gridding and degridding on sparse image
reconstruction. We find that the Kaiser-Bessel interpolation kernel performs as
well as prolate spheroidal wave functions, while providing a computational
saving and an analytic form. Second, we apply PURIFY to real interferometric
observations from the Very Large Array (VLA) and the Australia Telescope
Compact Array (ATCA) and find images recovered by PURIFY are higher quality
than those recovered by CLEAN. Third, we discuss how PURIFY reconstructions
exhibit additional advantages over those recovered by CLEAN. The latest version
of PURIFY, with developments presented in this work, is made publicly
available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05886</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Er-dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Shu</forenames></author></authors><title>Quark Mass Correction to Chiral Separation Effect and Pseudoscalar
  Condensate</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures. additional normalizable modes included,
  published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derived an analytic structure of the quark mass correction to chiral
separation effect (CSE) in small mass regime. We confirmed this structure by a
D3/D7 holographic model study in a finite density, finite magnetic field
background. The quark mass correction to CSE can be related to correlators of
pseudo-scalar condensate, quark number density and quark condensate in static
limit. We found scaling relations of these correlators with spatial momentum in
the small momentum regime. They characterize medium responses to electric
field, inhomogeneous quark mass and chiral shift. Beyond the small momentum
regime, we found existence of normalizable mode, which possibly leads to
formation of spiral phase. The normalizable mode exists beyond a critical
magnetic field, whose magnitude decreases with quark chemical potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02871</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Refined universal laws for hull volumes and perimeters in large planar
  maps</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>28 pages, 14 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t16/149</report-no><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical, Volume 50,
  Number 27, 275203, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7088</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider ensembles of planar maps with two marked vertices at distance k
from each other and look at the closed line separating these vertices and lying
at distance d from the first one (d&lt;k). This line divides the map into two
components, the hull at distance d which corresponds to the part of the map
lying on the same side as the first vertex and its complementary. The number of
faces within the hull is called the hull volume and the length of the
separating line the hull perimeter. We study the statistics of the hull volume
and perimeter for arbitrary d and k in the limit of infinitely large planar
quadrangulations, triangulations and Eulerian triangulations. We consider more
precisely situations where both d and k become large with the ratio d/k
remaining finite. For infinitely large maps, two regimes may be encountered:
either the hull has a finite volume and its complementary is infinitely large,
or the hull itself has an infinite volume and its complementary is of finite
size. We compute the probability for the map to be in either regime as a
function of d/k as well as a number of universal statistical laws for the hull
perimeter and volume when maps are conditioned to be in one regime or the
other.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05286</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05286</id><created>2016-11-16</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Loiseau</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory overview on amplitude analyses with charm decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 table, 2 figures, Contribution to the VIII International
  Workshop On Charm Physics, 5-9 September, 2016, Bologna, Italy. A related
  work, Ref. [18], has been added in section 2.1 and commented</comments><journal-ref>PoS CHARM2016 (2016) 033, conference: C16-09-05.2 proceedings</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This contribution about amplitude analyses in multibody hadronic charm decays
deals with some attempts to introduce theoretical constraints. Different
effective hadronic formalism approaches are mentioned. A recent work, based on
a basic weak interaction process and a Chiral unitary model to account for the
final state interaction, is described in details for the $f_0(980)$ production
in $D_s^+ \to \pi^+ \pi^+ \pi^-$ and $D_s^+ \to \pi^+ K^+ K^- $ decays. Within
the framework of the diagrammatic approach and flavor symmetry, a global
analysis of two-body $D$ decays into a vector meson and a pseudoscalar meson is
presented. A quasi-two-body QCD factorization model for $D$ decays into three
mesons and its recent application to $D^0 \to K_S^0 \pi^+ \pi^-$ is outlined.
For processes with final-state pions and kaons and as an alternative to the sum
of Breit-Wigner amplitudes, often used in experimental Dalitz-plot analyses,
amplitude parametrizations, in term of unitary $\pi \pi$, $\pi K$ and $K \bar
K$ form factors, are proposed. These parametrizations are derived from
quasi-two-body factorization models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06804</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bouchard</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de la Hoz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bjork</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>R. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hradil</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karimi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimov</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rehacek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Soto</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum metrology at the limit with extremal Majorana constellations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Comments welcome!</comments><journal-ref>Optica, vol. 4, no. 11, pp. 1429-1432 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.001429</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum metrology allows for a tremendous boost in the accuracy of
measurement of diverse physical parameters. The estimation of a rotation
constitutes a remarkable example of this quantum-enhanced precision. The
recently introduced Kings of Quantumness are especially germane for this task
when the rotation axis is unknown, as they have a sensitivity independent of
that axis and they achieve a Heisenberg-limit scaling. Here, we report the
experimental realization of these states by generating up to 21-dimensional
orbital angular momentum states of single photons, and confirm their high
metrological abilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02335</id><created>2017-01-09</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marks</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jochym-O'Connor</keyname><forenames>Tomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gheorghiu</keyname><forenames>Vlad</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparison of memory thresholds for planar qudit geometries</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version, small typos corrected, any
  comments are welcome! QTop software available at
  https://github.com/jacobmarks/QTop</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 113022 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa939a</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce and analyze a new type of decoding algorithm called General
Color Clustering (GCC), based on renormalization group methods, to be used in
qudit color codes. The performance of this decoder is analyzed under code
capacity depolarizing noise, and is used to obtain the first fault-tolerant
threshold estimates for qudit 6-6-6 color codes. The proposed decoder is
compared with similar decoding schemes for qudit surface codes as well as the
current leading qubit decoders for both sets of codes. We find that, as with
surface codes, clustering performs sub-optimally for qubit color codes, giving
a threshold of $9.75\%$ compared to the $11.4\%$ obtained through surface
projection decoding methods. However, the threshold rate increases by up to
$75\%$ for large qudit dimensions, plateauing around $17.1\%$. All the analysis
is performed using QTop, a new open-source software for simulating and
visualizing topological quantum error correcting codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04961</id><created>2017-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetohydrodynamic shocks in a dissipative quantum plasma with
  exchange-correlation effects</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132: 316</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11630-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the nonlinear propagation of multidimensional magnetosonic
shock waves (MSWs) in a dissipative quantum magnetoplasma. A macroscopic
quantum magnetohydrodynamic (QMHD) model is used to include the quantum force
associated with the Bohm potential, the pressure-like spin force, the exchange
and correlation force of electrons, as well as the dissipative force due to the
kinematic viscosity of ions and the magnetic diffusivity. The effects of these
forces on the properties of arbitrary amplitude MSWs are examined numerically.
It is found that the contribution from the exchange-correlation force appears
to be dominant over those from the pressure gradient and the other similar
quantum forces, and it results into a transition from monotonic to oscillatory
shocks in presence of either the ion kinematic viscosity or the magnetic
diffusivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05499</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-03-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scholtes</keyname><forenames>Ingo</forenames></author></authors><title>When is a Network a Network? Multi-Order Graphical Model Selection in
  Pathways and Temporal Networks</title><categories>cs.SI cond-mat.dis-nn physics.data-an physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, 1 table, companion python package pathpy
  available on gitHub</comments><acm-class>H.2.8; G.3</acm-class><journal-ref>In KDD'17 - Proceedings of the 23rd ACM SIGKDD International
  Conference on Knowledge Discovery and Data Mining, Halifax, Nova Scotia,
  Canada, August 13-17, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1145/3097983.3098145</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a framework for the modeling of sequential data capturing
pathways of varying lengths observed in a network. Such data are important,
e.g., when studying click streams in information networks, travel patterns in
transportation systems, information cascades in social networks, biological
pathways or time-stamped social interactions. While it is common to apply graph
analytics and network analysis to such data, recent works have shown that
temporal correlations can invalidate the results of such methods. This raises a
fundamental question: when is a network abstraction of sequential data
justified? Addressing this open question, we propose a framework which combines
Markov chains of multiple, higher orders into a multi-layer graphical model
that captures temporal correlations in pathways at multiple length scales
simultaneously. We develop a model selection technique to infer the optimal
number of layers of such a model and show that it outperforms previously used
Markov order detection techniques. An application to eight real-world data sets
on pathways and temporal networks shows that it allows to infer graphical
models which capture both topological and temporal characteristics of such
data. Our work highlights fallacies of network abstractions and provides a
principled answer to the open question when they are justified. Generalizing
network representations to multi-order graphical models, it opens perspectives
for new data mining and knowledge discovery algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08586</id><created>2017-02-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>Can Boltzmann Machines Discover Cluster Updates ?</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.LG stat.ML</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, and half page appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 051301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.051301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boltzmann machines are physics informed generative models with wide
applications in machine learning. They can learn the probability distribution
from an input dataset and generate new samples accordingly. Applying them back
to physics, the Boltzmann machines are ideal recommender systems to accelerate
Monte Carlo simulation of physical systems due to their flexibility and
effectiveness. More intriguingly, we show that the generative sampling of the
Boltzmann Machines can even discover unknown cluster Monte Carlo algorithms.
The creative power comes from the latent representation of the Boltzmann
machines, which learn to mediate complex interactions and identify clusters of
the physical system. We demonstrate these findings with concrete examples of
the classical Ising model with and without four spin plaquette interactions.
Our results endorse a fresh research paradigm where intelligent machines are
designed to create or inspire human discovery of innovative algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00045</id><created>2017-02-28</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Navajas</keyname><forenames>Joaquin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niella</keyname><forenames>Tamara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garbulsky</keyname><forenames>Gerry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bahrami</keyname><forenames>Bahador</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigman</keyname><forenames>Mariano</forenames></author></authors><title>Aggregated knowledge from a small number of debates outperforms the
  wisdom of large crowds</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aggregation of many independent estimates can outperform the most
accurate individual judgment. This centenarian finding, popularly known as the
wisdom of crowds, has been applied to problems ranging from the diagnosis of
cancer to financial forecasting. It is widely believed that social influence
undermines collective wisdom by reducing the diversity of opinions within the
crowd. Here, we show that if a large crowd is structured in small independent
groups, deliberation and social influence within groups improve the crowd's
collective accuracy. We asked a live crowd (N=5180) to respond to
general-knowledge questions (e.g., what is the height of the Eiffel Tower?).
Participants first answered individually, then deliberated and made consensus
decisions in groups of five, and finally provided revised individual estimates.
We found that averaging consensus decisions was substantially more accurate
than aggregating the initial independent opinions. Remarkably, combining as few
as four consensus choices outperformed the wisdom of thousands of individuals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02781</id><created>2017-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Guitter</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>On a conjecture by Chapuy about Voronoi cells in large maps</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages, 8 figures</comments><report-no>IPhT t17/031</report-no><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 103401</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa8c25</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper, Chapuy conjectured that, for any positive integer k, the
law for the fractions of total area covered by the k Voronoi cells defined by k
points picked uniformly at random in the Brownian map of any fixed genus is the
same law as that of a uniform k-division of the unit interval. For k=2, i.e.
with two points chosen uniformly at random, it means that the law for the ratio
of the area of one of the two Voronoi cells by the total area of the map is
uniform between 0 and 1. Here, by a direct computation of the desired law, we
show that this latter conjecture for k=2 actually holds in the case of large
planar (genus 0) quadrangulations as well as for large general planar maps
(i.e. maps whose faces have arbitrary degrees). This corroborates Chapuy's
conjecture in its simplest realizations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03183</id><created>2017-04-11</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keck</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montangero</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoro</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>Rosario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossini</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipation in adiabatic quantum computers: Lessons from an exactly
  solvable model</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19 113029 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa8cef</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce and study the adiabatic dynamics of free-fermion models subject
to a local Lindblad bath and in the presence of a time-dependent Hamiltonian.
The merit of these models is that they can be solved exactly, and will help us
to study the interplay between non-adiabatic transitions and dissipation in
many-body quantum systems. After the adiabatic evolution, we evaluate the
excess energy (average value of the Hamiltonian) as a measure of the deviation
from reaching the target final ground state. We compute the excess energy in a
variety of different situations, where the nature of the bath and the
Hamiltonian is modified. We find a robust evidence of the fact that an optimal
working time for the quantum annealing protocol emerges as a result of the
competition between the non-adiabatic effects and the dissipative processes. We
compare these results with matrix-product-operator simulations of an Ising
system and show that the phenomenology we found applies also for this more
realistic case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03209</id><created>2017-05-09</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sbrizzi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Heide</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cloos</keyname><forenames>Martijn</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Toorn</keyname><forenames>Annette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoogduin</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luijten</keyname><forenames>Peter R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Cornelis A. T. van den</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast quantitative MRI as a nonlinear tomography problem</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.med-ph</categories><journal-ref>Magnetic Resonance Imaging, Volume 46 (2018), pag. 56-63</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mri.2017.10.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantitative Magnetic Resonance Imaging (MRI) is based on a two-steps
approach: estimation of the magnetic moments distribution inside the body,
followed by a voxel-by-voxel quantification of the human tissue properties.
This splitting simplifies the computations but poses several constraints on the
measurement process, limiting its efficiency. Here, we perform quantitative MRI
as a one step process; signal localization and parameter quantification are
simultaneously obtained by the solution of a large scale nonlinear inversion
problem based on first-principles. As a consequence, the constraints on the
measurement process can be relaxed and acquisition schemes that are time
efficient and widely available in clinical MRI scanners can be employed. We
show that the nonlinear tomography approach is applicable to MRI and returns
human tissue maps from very short experiments. Keywords: MR-STAT, quantitative
MRI, nonlinear tomography, MR Fingerprinting, large scale inversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03665</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matsunaga</keyname><forenames>Daiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Fanlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoettl</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golestanian</keyname><forenames>Ramin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeomans</keyname><forenames>Julia M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Focusing and sorting of ellipsoidal magnetic particles in microchannels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 198002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.198002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple method to control the position of ellipsoidal magnetic
particles in microchannel Poiseuille flow using a static uniform magnetic
field. The magnetic field is utilized to pin the particle orientation, and the
hydrodynamic interactions between ellipsoids and channel walls allow control of
the transverse position of the particles. We employ a far-field hydrodynamic
theory and simulations using the boundary element method and Brownian dynamics
to show how magnetic particles can be focussed and segregated by size and
shape. This is of importance for particle manipulation in lab-on-a-chip
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03858</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cox</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chengcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagida</keyname><forenames>Tsutomu T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Flavoured $B-L$ Local Symmetry and Anomalous Rare $B$ Decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures; v2: version published in PLB</comments><report-no>IPMU17-0075, CERN-TH-2017-106</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B774 (2017) 643-648</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a flavoured $B-L$ gauge symmetry under which only the third
generation fermions are charged. Such a symmetry can survive at low energies
(~TeV) while still allowing for two superheavy right-handed neutrinos,
consistent with neutrino masses via see-saw and leptogenesis. We describe a
mechanism for generating Yukawa couplings in this model and also discuss the
low-energy phenomenology. Interestingly, the new gauge boson could explain the
recent hints of lepton universality violation at LHCb, with a gauge coupling
that remains perturbative up to the Planck scale. Finally, we discuss more
general $U(1)$ symmetries and show that there exist only two classes of
vectorial $U(1)$ that are both consistent with leptogenesis and remain
phenomenologically viable at low-energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04186</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cort&#xe9;s</keyname><forenames>Vicente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Arpan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quarter-pinched Einstein metrics interpolating between real and complex
  hyperbolic metrics</title><categories>math.DG hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages, accepted for publication in Mathematische Zeitschrift</comments><msc-class>53C26</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the one-loop quantum deformation of the universal hypermultiplet
provides a family of complete $1/4$-pinched negatively curved quaternionic
K\&quot;ahler (i.e. half conformally flat Einstein) metrics $g^c$, $c\ge 0$, on
$\mathbb R^4$. The metric $g^0$ is the complex hyperbolic metric whereas the
family $(g^c)_{c&gt;0}$ is equivalent to a family of metrics $(h^b)_{b&gt;0}$
depending on $b=1/c$ and smoothly extending to $b=0$ for which $h^0$ is the
real hyperbolic metric. In this sense the one-loop deformation interpolates
between the real and the complex hyperbolic metrics. We also determine the
(singular) conformal structure at infinity for the above families.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05282</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-10-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Funatsu</keyname><forenames>Shuichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatanaka</keyname><forenames>Hisaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosotani</keyname><forenames>Yutaka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orikasa</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author></authors><title>Distinct signals of the gauge-Higgs unification in $e^+e^-$ collider
  experiments</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, 7 tables (v3) numerical evaluations renewed,
  comments and references added, 4 tables added</comments><report-no>KEK-TH-1978, OU-HET 934</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 775 (2017) 297-302</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effects of Kaluza-Klein excited neutral vector bosons ($Z'$ bosons) in the
gauge-Higgs unification on $e^+e^- \to \bar{q}q, \ell^+\ell^-$ cross sections
are studied, particularly in future $e^+ e^-$ collider experiments with
polarized beams. Significant deviations in the energy and polarization
dependence in $\sigma(\mu^+\mu^-)$, the lepton forward-backward asymmetry,
$R_b(\mu) \equiv \sigma(\bar{b}b)/\sigma(\mu^+\mu^-)$ and the left-right
asymmetry from the standard model are predicted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08208</id><created>2017-05-23</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beuria</keyname><forenames>Jyotiranjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>AseshKrishna</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous breakdown of charge in the MSSM and in the NMSSM:
  Possibilities and Implications</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 8 figures, 1 table; matches with published version</comments><report-no>HRI-P-17-05-002, RECAPP-HRI-2017-006</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP11(2017)042</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2017)042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the possibilities and the implications of a spontaneous breakdown of
charge in the MSSM and in the $Z_3$-symmetric NMSSM. The breakdown is triggered
by the charged states of the Higgs doublets acquiring vacuum expectation
values. In the MSSM, it is known that the presence of a charge conserving
minimum for the tree-level Higgs potential precludes a deeper (global)
charge-breaking minimum. We find that the inclusion of radiative correction to
the potential does not alter the situation while a deeper charge-conserving
minimum could arise, albeit with no major practical consequences. In the NMSSM
scenario, a charge-breaking global minimum, with or without an accompanying
charge-conserving deeper minimum, could appear even with the tree-level Higgs
potential thanks to the presence of a charge-neutral scalar state which
transforms as a singlet under the Standard Model gauge group. Use of the NMSSM
Higgs potential that includes both quantum and thermal corrections and the
requirement of a viable (stable or long-lived) vacuum that breaks the
electroweak symmetry, along with its compatibility with the latest Higgs data,
lead to nontrivial constraints on the NMSSM parameter space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09292</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garny</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heisig</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;lf</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogl</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Coannihilation without chemical equilibrium</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages + references, 10 figures; v2: Discussion of kinetic
  equilibrium extended, matches published version</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP 1085/17, TTK-17-18</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 103521 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.103521</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chemical equilibrium is a commonly made assumption in the freeze-out
calculation of coannihilating dark matter. We explore the possible failure of
this assumption and find a new conversion-driven freeze-out mechanism.
Considering a representative simplified model inspired by supersymmetry with a
neutralino- and sbottom-like particle we find regions in parameter space with
very small couplings accommodating the measured relic density. In this region
freeze-out takes place out of chemical equilibrium and dark matter
self-annihilation is thoroughly inefficient. The relic density is governed
primarily by the size of the conversion terms in the Boltzmann equations. Due
to the small dark matter coupling the parameter region is immune to direct
detection but predicts an interesting signature of disappearing tracks or
displaced vertices at the LHC. Unlike freeze-in or superWIMP scenarios,
conversion-driven freeze-out is not sensitive to the initial conditions at the
end of reheating.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09953</id><created>2017-05-28</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Haipeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dual meson condensates in the Polyakov-loop extended linear sigma model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages,7 figures, discussions added, references added, typos
  corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dual meson condensates as possible order parameters for deconfinement are
investigated in a Polyakov-loop enhanced linear sigma model of QCD at both zero
and finite isospin chemical potential $\mu_I$. We find that the rapid rise of
the dual sigma condensate (corresponding to the dressed Polyakov-loop) with $T$
is driven by the chiral transition, no matter whether the Polyakov-loop
dynamics is included or not. For $\mu_I&gt;m_\pi/2$, the dual sigma condensate
shows abnormal thermal behavior which even decreases with $T$ below the melting
temperature $T_c^{I_3}$ of pion superfluidity; On the other hand, even the dual
pion condensate always increases with $T$, its maximum slope locates exactly at
$T_c^{I_3}$ rather than the deconfinement temperature $T_c^{P}$ determined by
the Polyakov-loop. All these are qualitatively consistent with the previous
results obtained in the Nambu-Jona-Lasinio type models. The dual vector meson
condensate for $\mu_I&gt;m_\pi/2$ is also calculated. This quantity is more
sensitive to the chiral transition when taking into account the Dirac-sea
contribution. Our study further suggests that it should be cautious to use dual
observables to indicate the deconfinement transition, especially in QCD models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01204</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Aydemir</keyname><forenames>A. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>B. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>In</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of an $n=1$ explosive instability and its role in high-$\beta$
  disruptions</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to Nucl. Fusion, April 17, 2017. 19 pages, 9 figures,
  expanded version of work presented at the FEC2016 Conference, October 2016,
  Kyoto, Japan</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Fusion 58 (2018) 016026</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1741-4326/aa95c9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some low-$n$ kink-ballooning modes not far from marginal stability are shown
to exhibit a bifurcation between two very distinct nonlinear paths that depends
sensitively on the background transport levels and linear perturbation
amplitudes. The particular instability studied in this work is an $n=1$ mode
dominated by an $m/n=2/1$ component. It is driven by a large pressure gradient
in weak magnetic shear and can appear in various high-$\beta,$ hybrid/advanced
scenarios. Here it is investigated in reversed shear equilibria where the
region around the safety-factor minimum provides favorable conditions. For a
certain range of parameters, a relatively benign path results in a saturated
&quot;long-lived mode&quot; (LLM) that causes little confinement degradation. At the
other extreme, the quadrupole geometry of the $2/1$ perturbed pressure field
evolves into a ballooning finger that subsequently transitions from exponential
to explosive growth. The finger eventually leads to a fast disruption with
precursors too short for any mitigation effort. Interestingly, the saturated
LLM state is found to be metastable, it also can be driven explosively unstable
by finite-amplitude perturbations. Similarities to some high-$\beta$
disruptions in reversed-shear discharges are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03817</id><created>2017-06-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Peizhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple types of topological fermions in transition metal silicides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 206402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.206402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Exotic massless fermionic excitations with non-zero Berry flux, other than
Dirac and Weyl fermions, could exist in condensed matter systems under the
protection of crystalline symmetries, such as spin-1 excitations with 3-fold
degeneracy and spin-3/2 Rarita-Schwinger-Weyl fermions. Herein, by using ab
initio density functional theory, we show that these unconventional
quasiparticles coexist with type-I and type-II Weyl fermions in a family of
transition metal silicides, including CoSi, RhSi, RhGe and CoGe, when the
spin-orbit coupling (SOC) is considered. Their non-trivial topology results in
a series of extensive Fermi arcs connecting projections of these bulk
excitations on side surface, which is confirmed by (010) surface electronic
spectra of CoSi. In addition, these stable arc states exist within a wide
energy window around the Fermi level, which makes them readily accessible in
angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04031</id><created>2017-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>Tomin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subramanian</keyname><forenames>Prasad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kontar</keyname><forenames>Eduard P</forenames></author></authors><title>Small electron acceleration episodes in the solar corona</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE physics.space-ph</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1460</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the energetics of nonthermal electrons produced in small
acceleration episodes in the solar corona. We carried out an extensive survey
spanning 2004--2015 and shortlisted 6 impulsive electron events detected at 1
AU that was not associated with large solar flares(GOES soft X-ray class $&gt;$
C1) or with coronal mass ejections. Each of these events had weak, but
detectable hard Xray (HXR) emission near the west limb, and were associated
with interplanetary type III bursts. In some respects, these events seem like
weak counterparts of &quot;cold/tenuous&quot; flares. The energy carried by the HXR
producing electron population was $\approx 10^{23}$ -- $10^{25}$ erg, while
that in the corresponding population detected at 1 AU was $\approx
10^{24}$--$10^{25}$ erg. The number of electrons that escape the coronal
acceleration site and reach 1 AU constitute 6 % to 148 % of those that
precipitate downwards to produce thick target HXR emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04514</id><created>2017-06-14</created><updated>2017-11-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brauner</keyname><forenames>Tomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadam</keyname><forenames>Saurabh</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous low-temperature thermodynamics of QCD in strong magnetic
  fields</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>1+19 pages, v2: matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP11(2017)103</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2017)103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermodynamics of quantum chromodynamics at low temperatures and in
sufficiently strong magnetic fields is governed by neutral pions. We analyze
the interacting system of neutral pions and photons at zero baryon chemical
potential using effective field theory. As a consequence of the axial anomaly
and the external magnetic field, the pions and photons mix with one another.
The resulting spectrum contains one usual, relativistic photon state, and two
nonrelativistic modes, one of which is gapless and the other gapped.
Furthermore, we calculate the leading, one-loop contribution to the pressure of
the system. In the chiral limit, a closed analytic expression for the pressure
exists, which features an unusual scaling with temperature and magnetic field,
$T^3B/f_\pi$, at low temperatures, $T\ll B/f_\pi$. Finally, we determine the
pion decay rate as a function of the magnetic field at the tree level. The
result is affected by a competition of the anisotropic kinematics and the
enlarged phase space due to the anomalous mass of the neutral pion. In the
chiral limit, the decay rate scales as $B^3/f_\pi^5$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04587</id><created>2017-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Losano</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menezes</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized scalar field models with the same energy density and linear
  stability</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 775 (2017) 178</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study how the properties of a Lagrangian density for a single real scalar
field in flat spacetime change with inclusion of an overall factor depending
only on the field. The focus of the paper is to obtain analytical results. So,
we show that even though it is possible to perform a field redefinition to get
an equivalent canonical model, it is not always feasible to write the canonical
model in terms of elementary functions. Also, we investigate the behavior of
the energy density and the linear stability of the solutions. Finally, we show
that one can find a class of models that present the same energy density and
the same stability potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05608</id><created>2017-06-18</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Toprasertpong</keyname><forenames>Kasidit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodnick</keyname><forenames>Stephen M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugiyama</keyname><forenames>Masakazu</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective mobility for sequential carrier transport in multiple quantum
  well structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 075441 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.075441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate a theoretical model for effective carrier mobility to
comprehensively describe the behavior of the perpendicular carrier transport
across multiple quantum well (MQW) structures under applied electric field. The
analytical expressions of effective mobilities for thermionic emission, direct
tunneling, and thermally-assisted tunneling are derived based on the
quasi-thermal equilibrium approximation and the semi-classical approach.
Effective electron and hole mobilities in InGaAs/GaAsP MQWs predicted from our
model are in good agreement with the experimental results obtained from the
carrier time-of-flight measurement near room temperature. With this concept,
the complicated carrier dynamics inside MQWs can be simplified to an effective
mobility, an equivalent parameter which is more straightforward to handle and
can be easily incorporated in the conventional drift-diffusion model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03130</id><created>2017-07-11</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deb</keyname><forenames>Sukanta</forenames></author></authors><title>Distance, reddening and three dimensional structure of the SMC - I:
  Using RRab stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 15 figures, Revised version resubmitted to MNRAS Main
  Journal on October 22, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a study of simultaneous determination of mean distance and
reddening to the Small Magellanic Cloud (SMC) using the two photometric band RR
Lyrae data. Currently available largest number of highly accurate and precise
light curve data of the fundamental mode RR Lyrae stars (RRab) with better
areal coverage released by the Optical Gravitational Lensing Experiment
(OGLE)-IV project observed in the two photometric bands $(V,I)$ were utilised
simultaneously in order to determine true distance and reddening independently
for each of the individual RRab stars. Different empirical and theoretical
calibrations leading to the determination of absolute magnitudes of RRab stars
in the two bands, $V$ and $I$ along with their mean magnitudes were utilised to
calculate the apparent distance moduli of each of these RRab stars in these two
bands. Decomposing the apparent distance moduli into true distance modulus and
reddening in each of these two bands, individual RRab distance and reddening
were estimated solving the two apparent distance moduli equations. Modeling the
observed distributions of the true distance moduli and reddenings of the SMC
RRab stars as Gaussian, the true mean distance modulus and mean reddening value
to the SMC were found to be {\bf $\mu_{0}=18.909\pm0.148$ mag and
$E(B-V)=0.066\pm0.036$ mag, respectively. This corresponds to a distance of $D
= 60.506\pm 4.126$~kpc to the SMC. The three dimensional distribution of the
SMC RRab stars was approximated as ellipsoid. Then using the principal axes
transformation method \citep{deb14} we find the axes ratios of the SMC:
$1.000\pm0.001,1.113\pm 0.002, 2.986\pm0.023$ with
$i=3^{\circ}.156\pm0^{\circ}.188$ and
$\theta_{\text{lon}}=38^{\circ}.027\pm0.577$.} These results are in agreement
with other recent independent previous studies using different tracers and
methodologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03949</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gou</keyname><forenames>Xing-rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Feng-lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Zuo-Tang</forenames></author></authors><title>Quark number scaling of hadronic $p_T$ spectra and constituent quark
  degree of freedom in $p$-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}=5.02$ TeV</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B774 (2017) 516-521</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the experimental data of $p_T$ spectra of identified hadrons
released recently by ALICE collaboration for $p$-Pb collisions at
$\sqrt{s_{NN}}=5.02$ TeV exhibit a distinct universal behavior --- the quark
number scaling. We further show that the scaling is a direct consequence of
quark (re-)combination mechanism of hadronization and can be regarded as a
strong indication of the existence of the underlying source with constituent
quark degree of freedom for the production of hadrons in $p$-Pb collisions at
such high energies. We make also predictions for production of other hadrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04206</id><created>2017-07-13</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poulin</keyname><forenames>Vivian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serpico</keyname><forenames>Pasquale D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calore</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clesse</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohri</keyname><forenames>Kazunori</forenames></author></authors><title>CMB bounds on disk-accreting massive Primordial Black Holes</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><report-no>LAPTH-022/17, TTK-17-22</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 083524 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.083524</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stellar-mass Primordial Black Holes (PBH) have been recently reconsidered as
a Dark Matter (DM) candidate, after the aLIGO discovery of several binary BH
mergers with masses of tens of $M_\odot$. Matter accretion on such massive
objects leads to the emission of high-energy photons, capable of altering the
ionization and thermal history of the universe. This in turn affects the
statistical properties of the cosmic microwave background (CMB) anisotropies.
Previous analyses have assumed spherical accretion. We argue that this
approximation likely breaks down and that an accretion disk should form in the
dark ages. Using the most up-to-date tools to compute the energy deposition in
the medium, we derive constraints on the fraction of DM in PBH. Provided that
disks form early on, even under conservative assumptions for accretion, these
constraints exclude a monochromatic distribution of PBH with masses above $\sim
2\, M_\odot$ as the dominant form of DM. The bound on the median PBH mass gets
more stringent if a broad, log-normal mass function is considered. A deepened
understanding of non-linear clustering properties and BH accretion disk physics
would permit an improved treatment and possibly lead to more stringent
constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05131</id><created>2017-07-17</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>G. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Mo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interpreting quantum coherence through a quantum measurement process</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 052322 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.052322</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, there has been a renewed interest in the quantification of
coherence or other coherence-like concepts within the framework of quantum
resource theory. However, rigorously defined or not, the notion of coherence or
decoherence has already been used by the community for decades since the advent
of quantum theory. Intuitively, the definitions of coherence and decoherence
should be the two sides of the same coin. Therefore, a natural question is
raised: how can the conventional decoherence processes, such as the von
Neumann-L\&quot;{u}ders (projective) measurement postulation or partially dephasing
channels, fit into the bigger picture of the recently established theoretic
framework? Here we show that the state collapse rules of the von Neumann or
L\&quot;{u}ders-type measurements, as special cases of genuinely incoherent
operations (GIO), are consistent with the resource theories of quantum
coherence. New hierarchical measures of coherence are proposed for the
L\&quot;{u}ders-type measurement and their relationship with measurement-dependent
discord is addressed. Moreover, utilizing the fixed point theory for
$C^\ast$-algebra, we prove that GIO indeed represent a particular type of
partially dephasing (phase-damping) channels which have a matrix representation
based on the Schur product. By virtue of the Stinespring's dilation theorem,
the physical realizations of incoherent operations are investigated in detail
and we find that GIO in fact constitute the core of strictly incoherent
operations (SIO) and generally incoherent operations (IO) and the unspeakable
notion of coherence induced by GIO can be transferred to the theories of
speakable coherence by the corresponding permutation or relabeling operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08179</id><created>2017-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Giovannini</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Squeezed relic photons beyond the horizon</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1608.05843</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 103513 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.103513</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Owing to the analogy with the ordinary photons in the visible range of the
electromagnetic spectrum, the Glauber theory is generalized to address the
quantum coherence of the gauge field fluctuations parametrically amplified
during an inflationary stage of expansion. The first and second degrees of
quantum coherence of relic photons are then computed beyond the effective
horizon defined by the evolution of the susceptibility. In the zero-delay limit
the Hanbury Brown-Twiss correlations exhibit a super-Poissonian statistics
which is however different from the conventional results of the single-mode
approximation customarily employed, in quantum optics, to classify the
coherence properties of visible light. While in the case of large-scale
curvature perturbations the degrees of quantum coherence coincide with the
naive expectation of the single-mode approximation, the net degree of
second-order coherence computed for the relic photons diminishes thanks to the
effect of the polarizations. We suggest that the Hanbury Brown-twiss
correlations are probably the only tool to assess the quantum or classical
origin of the large-scale magnetic fluctuations and of the corresponding
curvature perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09439</id><created>2017-07-28</created><updated>2017-09-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blunt</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neuscamman</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge-transfer excited states: Seeking a balanced and efficient wave
  function ansatz in variational Monte Carlo</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4998197</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a simple and efficient wave function ansatz for the treatment of
excited charge-transfer states in real-space quantum Monte Carlo methods. Using
the recently-introduced variation-after-response method [J. Chem. Phys. 145,
081103 (2016)], this ansatz allows a crucial orbital optimization step to be
performed beyond a configuration interaction singles expansion, while only
requiring calculation of two Slater determinant objects. We demonstrate this
ansatz for the illustrative example of the stretched LiF molecule, for a range
of excited states of formaldehyde, and finally for the more challenging
ethylene-tetrafluoroethylene molecule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01627</id><created>2017-08-04</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abbate</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastrobuono-Battisti</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colpi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Possenti</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sippel</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dotti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the formation history of the nuclear star cluster at the
  Galactic Centre with millisecond pulsars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2364</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the Nuclear Star Cluster in the centre of our Galaxy is still
unknown. One possibility is that it formed after the disruption of stellar
clusters that spiralled into the Galactic Centre due to dynamical friction. We
trace the formation of the Nuclear Star Cluster around the central black hole,
using state-of-the-art N-body simulations, and follow the dynamics of the
neutron stars born in the clusters. We then estimate the number of Millisecond
Pulsars (MSPs) that are released in the Nuclear Star Cluster, during its
formation. The assembly and tidal dismemberment of globular clusters lead to a
population of MSPs distributed over a radius of about 20 pc, with a peak near 3
pc. No clustering is found on the sub-parsec scale. We simulate the
detectability of this population with future radio telescopes like the MeerKAT
radio telescope and SKA1, and find that about of order ten MSPs can be observed
over this large volume, with a paucity of MSPs within the central parsec. This
helps discriminating this scenario from the in-situ formation model for the
Nuclear Star Cluster that would predict an over abundance of MSPs closer to the
black hole. We then discuss the potential contribution of our MSP population to
the gamma-ray excess at the Galactic Centre.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01740</id><created>2017-08-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Dutreix</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delplace</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical phase shift in Friedel oscillations</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 195207 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.195207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work addresses the problem of elastic scattering through a localized
impurity in a one-dimensional crystal with sublattice freedom degrees. The
impurity yields long-range interferences in the local density of states known
as Friedel oscillations. Here, we show that the internal degrees of freedom of
Bloch waves are responsible for a geometrical phase shift in Friedel
oscillations. The Fourier transform of the energy-resolved interference pattern
reveals a topological property of this phase shift, which is intrinsically
related to the Bloch band structure topology in the absence of impurity.
Therefore, Friedel oscillations in the local density of states can be regarded
as a probe of wave topological properties in a broad class of classical and
quantum systems, such as acoustic and photonic crystals, ultracold atomic gases
in optical lattices, and electronic compounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.07477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.07477</id><created>2017-08-24</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fantoni</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s</forenames></author></authors><title>One-dimensional fluids with second nearest-neighbor interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 12 figures; v2: more references added</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 169, 1171-1201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-017-1908-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As is well known, one-dimensional systems with interactions restricted to
first nearest neighbors admit a full analytically exact statistical-mechanical
solution. This is essentially due to the fact that the knowledge of the first
nearest-neighbor probability distribution function, $p_1(r)$, is enough to
determine the structural and thermodynamic properties of the system. On the
other hand, if the interaction between second nearest-neighbor particles is
turned on, the analytically exact solution is lost. Not only the knowledge of
$p_1(r)$ is not sufficient anymore, but even its determination becomes a
complex many-body problem. In this work we systematically explore different
approximate solutions for one-dimensional second nearest-neighbor fluid models.
We apply those approximations to the square-well and the attractive two-step
pair potentials and compare them with Monte Carlo simulations, finding an
excellent agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.09166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.09166</id><created>2017-08-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Knispel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jolie</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgwardt</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lux</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosch</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michely</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xfc;ninger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge puddles in the bulk and on the surface of the topological
  insulator BiSbTeSe$_2$ studied by scanning tunneling microscopy and optical
  spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 195135 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.195135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topological insulator BiSbTeSe$_2$ corresponds to a compensated
semiconductor in which strong Coulomb disorder gives rise to the formation of
charge puddles, i.e., local accumulations of charge carriers, both in the bulk
and on the surface. Bulk puddles are formed if the fluctuations of the Coulomb
potential are as large as half of the band gap. The gapless surface, in
contrast, is sensitive to small fluctuations but the potential is strongly
suppressed due to the additional screening channel provided by metallic surface
carriers. To study the quantitative relationship between the properties of bulk
puddles and surface puddles, we performed infrared transmittance measurements
as well as scanning tunneling microscopy measurements on the same sample of
BiSbTeSe$_2$, which is close to perfect compensation. At 5.5 K, we find surface
potential fluctuations occurring on a length scale $r_s = 40-50$ nm with
amplitude $\Gamma = 8-14$ meV which is much smaller than in the bulk, where
optical measurements detect the formation of bulk puddles. In this nominally
undoped compound, the value of $\Gamma$ is smaller than expected for pure
screening by surface carriers, and we argue that this arises most likely from a
cooperative effect of bulk screening and surface screening.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.06064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.06064</id><created>2017-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Fantoni</keyname><forenames>Riccardo</forenames></author></authors><title>White-dwarfs equation of state and structure: The effect of temperature</title><categories>astro-ph.SR cond-mat.quant-gas gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. P113101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa9339</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of having a finite temperature on the equation of state
and structure of a white dwarf. In order to keep the treatment as general as
possible we carry on our discussion for ideal quantum gases obeying to both the
Fermi-Dirac and the Bose-Einstein statistics even if we will only use the
results for the free electron gas inside a white dwarf. We discuss the effect
of temperature on the stability of the star and on the Fermi hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08602</id><created>2017-09-25</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bravina</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lokhtin</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malinina</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrushanko</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snigirev</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabrodin</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical vs geometric anisotropy in relativistic heavy-ion collisions:
  which one prevails?</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>minor corrections, published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2017) 53: 219</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12420-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the influence of geometric and dynamical anisotropies on the
development of flow harmonics and, simultaneously, on the second- and
third-order oscillations of femtoscopy radii. The analysis is done within the
Monte Carlo event generator HYDJET++, which was extended to dynamical
triangular deformations. It is shown that the merely geometric anisotropy
provides the results which anticorrelate with the experimental observations of
either $v_2$ (or $v_3$) or second-order (or third-order) oscillations of the
femtoscopy radii. Decays of resonances significantly increase the emitting
areas but do not change the phases of the radii oscillations. In contrast to
the spatial deformations, the dynamical anisotropy alone provides the correct
qualitative description of the flow and the femtoscopy observables
simultaneously. However, one needs both types of the anisotropy to match
quantitatively the experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.09101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.09101</id><created>2017-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Albaladejo</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Feng-Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanhart</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei&#xdf;ner</keyname><forenames>Ulf-G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nieves</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogga</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Zhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on X(3872) production at hadron colliders and its molecular
  structure</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C 41 (2017): 121001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/12/121001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of the X(3872) as a hadronic molecule in hadron colliders is
clarified. We show that the conclusion of Bignamini et al., Phys. Rev. Lett.
103 (2009) 162001, that the production of the X(3872) at high $p_T$ implies a
non-molecular structure, does not hold. In particular, using the well
understood properties of the deuteron wave function as an example, we identify
the relevant scales in the production process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.09178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.09178</id><created>2017-09-26</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author></authors><title>Overdamped modes in Schwarzschild-de Sitter and a Mathematica package
  for the numerical computation of quasinormal modes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Typos fixed, citations added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a package for Mathematica that facilitates the numerical
computation of the quasinormal mode (QNM) spectrum of a black hole/black brane.
Requiring as input only the QNM equation(s), the application of a single
Mathematica function will compute the spectrum efficiently, by discretizing the
equation(s) and solving the resulting generalized eigenvalue equation. It is
applicable to a large variety of black holes, independent of their asymptotics.
The package comes fully documented and with several tutorials. Here we present
a self-contained review of the method and consider several applications. We
illustrate the method in the simplest case of scalar QNMs of a Schwarzschild
black brane in anti-de Sitter. Then we go on to look at the scalar QNMs of the
Schwarzschild black hole in de Sitter, in anti-de Sitter and in asymptotically
flat spacetimes, finding a novel infinite set of purely imaginary modes in the
first case. We also derive the QNM equations for a generic
Einstein-Maxwell-scalar background and use these to compute the QNMs of the
asymptotically anti-de Sitter Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m black brane, as a further
illustration and check of the method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03350</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03350</id><created>2017-10-09</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Dae Jung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Doorsselaere</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goossens</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant absorption of surface sausage and surface kink modes under
  photospheric conditions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 13 figures, published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Vol. 850, 44 (17pp); 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa9223</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of resonant absorption of surface sausage and surface
kink modes under photospheric conditions where the slow surface sausage modes
undergo resonant damping in the slow continuum and the surface kink modes in
the slow and Alfv\'{e}n continua at the transitional layers. We use recently
derived analytical formulas to obtain the damping rate (time). By considering
linear density and linear pressure profiles for the transitional layers, we
show that resonant absorption in the slow continuum could be an efficient
mechanism for the wave damping of the slow surface sausage and slow surface
kink modes whilst the damping rate of the slow surface kink mode in the
Alfv\'{e}n continuum is weak. It is also found that the resonant damping of the
fast surface kink mode is much stronger than that of the slow surface kink
mode, showing a similar efficiency as under coronal conditions. It is worth to
notice that the slow body sausage and kink modes can also resonantly damp in
the slow continuum for those linear profiles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03802</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03802</id><created>2017-10-10</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deffner</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Kibble-Zurek scaling of the irreversible entropy production</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 052125 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.052125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If a system is driven at finite-rate through a phase transition by varying an
intensive parameter, the order parameter shatters into finite domains. The
Kibble-Zurek mechanism predicts the typical size of these domains, which are
governed only by the rate of driving and the spatial and dynamical critical
exponents. We show that also the irreversible entropy production fulfills a
universal behavior, which however is determined by an additional critical
exponent corresponding to the intensive control parameter. Our universal
prediction is numerically tested in two systems exhibiting noise-induced phase
transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.06197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.06197</id><created>2017-10-17</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andronov</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames><affiliation>for the NA61/SHINE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Transverse Momentum and Multiplicity Fluctuations in Ar+Sc Collisions at
  the CERN SPS from NA61/SHINE</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>This submission has been withdrawn by arXiv administrators because it
  is a duplicate of arXiv:1610.05569</comments><journal-ref>Acta Physica Polonica B Proceedings Supplement, Vol. 10, No. 3
  (2017) 449-453</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolBSupp.10.449</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The NA61/SHINE experiment aims to discover the critical point of strongly
interacting matter and study the properties of the onset of deconfinement. For
these goals a scan of the two dimensional phase diagram ($T$-$\mu_{B}$) is
being performed at the SPS by measurements of hadron production in
proton-proton, proton-nucleus and nucleus-nucleus interactions as a function of
collision energy and system size. In this contribution preliminary results on
transverse momentum and multiplicity fluctuations expressed in terms of
strongly intensive quantities from the Ar+Sc energy scan will be presented.
These fluctuations are expected to be sensitive to the existence of a critical
point. The results are compared with results from the p+p and Be+Be energy scan
as well as with NA49 measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.07514</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.07514</id><created>2017-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Fengxia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brivio</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Shijing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bristowe</keyname><forenames>Paul D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheetham</keyname><forenames>Anthony K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthesis, Crystal Structure, Magnetic and Electronic Properties of the
  Caesium-based Transition Metal Halide Cs3Fe2Br9</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1039/C7TC04798C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The diversity of halide materials related to important solar energy systems
such as CsPbX3 (X = Cl, Br, I) is explored by introducing the transition metal
element Fe. In particular a new compound, Cs3Fe2Br9 (space group P6_3/mmc with
a = 7.5427(8) and c = 18.5849(13) {\AA}), has been synthesized and found to
contain 0D face-sharing Fe2Br9 octahedral dimers. Unlike its isomorph,
Cs3Bi2I9, it is black in color, has a low optical bandgap of 1.65 eV and
exhibits antiferromagnetic behavior below TN = 13 K. Density functional theory
calculations shed further light on these properties and also predict that the
material should have anisotropic transport characteristics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.10622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.10622</id><created>2017-10-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Malek</keyname><forenames>Shahrazad M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowles</keyname><forenames>Richard K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saika-Voivod</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciortino</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>Peter H.</forenames></author></authors><title>&quot;Swarm relaxation&quot;: Equilibrating a large ensemble of computer
  simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages. To appear in Eur. Phy. J. E, 2017</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. E 40, 98 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epje/i2017-11588-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is common practice in molecular dynamics and Monte Carlo computer
simulations to run multiple, separately-initialized simulations in order to
improve the sampling of independent microstates. Here we examine the utility of
an extreme case of this strategy, in which we run a large ensemble of $M$
independent simulations (a &quot;swarm&quot;), each of which is relaxed to equilibrium.
We show that if $M$ is of order $10^3$, we can monitor the swarm's relaxation
to equilibrium, and confirm its attainment, within $\sim 10\bar\tau$, where
$\bar\tau$ is the equilibrium relaxation time. As soon as a swarm of this size
attains equilibrium, the ensemble of $M$ final microstates from each run is
sufficient for the evaluation of most equilibrium properties without further
sampling. This approach dramatically reduces the wall-clock time required,
compared to a single long simulation, by a factor of several hundred, at the
cost of an increase in the total computational effort by a small factor. It is
also well-suited to modern computing systems having thousands of processors,
and is a viable strategy for simulation studies that need to produce
high-precision results in a minimum of wall-clock time. We present results
obtained by applying this approach to several test cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00467</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>MacDonald</keyname><forenames>Ryan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madhusudhan</keyname><forenames>Nikku</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures of Nitrogen Chemistry in Hot Jupiter Atmospheres</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJL</comments><journal-ref>ApJL (2017): 850, L15</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa97d4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inferences of molecular compositions of exoplanetary atmospheres have
generally focused on C, H, and O-bearing molecules. Recently, additional
absorption in HST WFC3 transmission spectra around 1.55$\mu$m has been
attributed to nitrogen-bearing chemical species: NH$_3$ or HCN. These species,
if present in significant abundance, would be strong indicators of
disequilibrium chemical processes -- e.g. vertical mixing and photochemistry.
The derived N abundance, in turn, could also place important constraints on
planetary formation mechanisms. Here, we examine the detectability of nitrogen
chemistry in exoplanetary atmospheres. In addition to the WFC3 bandpass
(1.1-1.7$\mu$m), we find that observations in K-band at $\sim$2.2$\mu$m,
achievable with present ground-based telescopes, sample a strong NH$_3$
feature, whilst observations at $\sim$3.1$\mu$m and $\sim$4.0$\mu$m sample
strong HCN features. In anticipation of such observations, we predict
absorption feature amplitudes due to nitrogen chemistry in the 1-5$\mu$m
spectral range possible for a typical hot Jupiter. Finally, we conduct
atmospheric retrievals of 9 hot Jupiter transmission spectra in search of
near-infrared absorption features suggestive of nitrogen chemistry. We report
weak detections of NH$_3$ in WASP-31b (2.2$\sigma$), HCN in WASP-63b
(2.3$\sigma$), and excess absorption that could be attributed to NH$_3$ in HD
209458b. High-precision observations from 1-5$\mu$m (e.g., with the James Webb
Space Telescope), will enable definitive detections of nitrogen chemistry, in
turn serving as powerful diagnostics of disequilibrium atmospheric chemistry
and planetary formation processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00666</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00666</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Yuk Tai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alireza</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yip</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goh</keyname><forenames>Swee K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nearly isotropic superconductivity in layered Weyl semimetal WTe$_2$ at
  98.5 kbar</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures. Accepted for publication in Phys. Rev. B (Rapid
  Comm.)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 180504(R) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.180504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Layered transition metal dichalcogenide WTe$_2$ has recently attracted
significant attention due to the discovery of an extremely large
magnetoresistance, a predicted type-II Weyl semimetallic state, and the
pressure-induced superconducting state. By a careful measurement of the
superconducting upper critical fields as a function of the magnetic field angle
at a pressure as high as 98.5 kbar, we provide the first detailed examination
of the dimensionality of the superconducting condensate in WTe$_2$. Despite the
layered crystal structure, the upper critical field exhibits a negligible field
anisotropy. The angular dependence of the upper critical field can be
satisfactorily described by the anisotropic mass model from 2.2 K
($T/T_c\sim0.67$) to 0.03 K ($T/T_c\sim0.01$), with a practically identical
anisotropy factor $\gamma\sim1.7$. The temperature dependence of the upper
critical field, determined for both $H\perp ab$ and $H\parallel ab$, can be
understood by a conventional orbital depairing mechanism. Comparison of the
upper critical fields along the two orthogonal field directions results in the
same value of $\gamma\sim1.7$, leading to a temperature independent anisotropy
factor from near $T_c$ to $&lt;0.01T_c$. Our findings thus identify WTe$_2$ as a
nearly isotropic superconductor, with an anisotropy factor among one of the
lowest known in superconducting transition metal dichalcogenides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.01671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.01671</id><created>2017-11-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abrams</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alsalmi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ankowski</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bane</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benhar</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Day</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higinbotham</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mariani</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing electron-argon scattering for liquid-argon based
  neutrino-oscillation program</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex nucl-th physics.ins-det</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. Contribution to the International
  Workshop on (e,e'p) Processes, July 2-6, 2017, Bled, Slovenia</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electron scattering has been a vital tool to study the properties of the
target nucleus for over five decades. Though, the particular interest on
$^{40}$Ar nucleus stemmed from the progress in the accelerator-based
neutrino-oscillation experiments. The complexity of nuclei comprising the
detectors and their weak response turned out to be one of the major hurdles in
the quest of achieving unprecedented precision in these experiments. The
challenges are further magnified by the use of Liquid Argon Time Projection
Chambers (LArTPCs) in the short- (SBN) and long-baseline (DUNE) neutrino
program, with almost non-existence electron-argon scattering data and hence
with no empirical basis to test and develop nuclear models for $^{40}$Ar. In
light of these challenges, an electron-argon experiment, E12-14-012, was
proposed at Jefferson Lab. The experiment has recently successfully completed
collecting data for $(e,e'p)$ and $(e,e')$ processes, not just on $^{40}$Ar but
also on $^{48}$Ti, and $^{12}$C targets. While the analysis is running with
full steam, in this contribution, we present a brief overview of the
experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.02041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.02041</id><created>2017-11-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xian</keyname><forenames>Jiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Huai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhigang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yigang</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-phase Thermodynamic Model for Computing Entropies of Liquids
  Reanalyzed</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 147, 194505 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.5001798</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The two-phase thermodynamic (2PT) model {[}J. Chem. Phys., \textbf{119},
11792 (2003){]} provides a promising paradigm to efficiently determine the
ionic entropies of liquids from molecular dynamics (MD). In this model, the
vibrational density of states (VDoS) of a liquid is decomposed into a diffusive
gas-like component and a vibrational solid-like component. By treating the
diffusive component as hard sphere (HS) gas and the vibrational component as
harmonic oscillators, the ionic entropy of the liquid is determined. Here we
examine three issues crucial for practical implementations of the 2PT model:
(i) the mismatch between the VDoS of the liquid system and that of the HS gas;
(ii) the excess entropy of the HS gas; (iii) the partition of the gas-like and
solid-like components. Some of these issues have not been addressed before, yet
they profoundly change the entropy predicted from the model. Based on these
findings, a revised 2PT formalism is proposed and successfully tested in
systems with Lennard-Jones potentials as well as many-atom potentials of liquid
metals. Aside from being capable of performing quick entropy estimations for a
wide range of systems, the formalism also supports fine-tuning to accurately
determine entropies at specific thermal states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.04403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.04403</id><created>2017-11-12</created><updated>2017-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wen-Biao</forenames></author></authors><title>Coexistence curve and molecule number density of AdS topological charged
  black hole in massive gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1604.07931, arXiv:1506.03578 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The coexistence curve and molecule number density of a 4-dimensional AdS
topological charged black hole in massive gravity is investigated. We find that
the analytic expression of the coexistence curve in the reduced parameter space
is dependent on theory parameters. This is very different from the previous
results obtained in other modified gravity such as $f(R)$ gravity and
Gauss-Bonnet gravity. Besides, we derive the explicit expression of the
physical quantity which describes the difference of the number densities of AdS
topological charged black hole molecules between the small and large black
hole. It is observed that the difference of the molecule number densities is
also dependent on theory parameters. Both the expressions of the coexistence
curve and the difference of the molecule number densities can be reduced into a
form which is similar to a RN-AdS black hole if the mass of graviton $m$ is
zero. Moreover, we find the shifted temperature under massive gravity. This can
highlight the important role played by the mass of graviton and other
parameters in the phase transitions of AdS black holes in massive gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.05182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.05182</id><created>2017-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Ruiz</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendoza-Arenas</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Acevedo</keyname><forenames>O. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quiroga</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>N. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of Entanglement and the Schmidt Gap in a Driven Light-Matter
  System</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures, Accepted for publication in Journal of Physics
  B, special issue Correlations in light-matter interactions</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6455/aa9a92</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to modify light-matter coupling in time (e.g. using external
pulses) opens up the exciting possibility of generating and probing new aspects
of quantum correlations in many-body light-matter systems. Here we study the
impact of such a pulsed coupling on the light-matter entanglement in the Dicke
model as well as the respective subsystem quantum dynamics. Our dynamical
many-body analysis exploits the natural partition between the radiation and
matter degrees of freedom, allowing us to explore time-dependent
intra-subsystem quantum correlations by means of squeezing parameters, and the
inter-subsystem Schmidt gap for different pulse duration (i.e. ramping
velocity) regimes -- from the near adiabatic to the sudden quench limits. Our
results reveal that both types of quantities indicate the emergence of the
superradiant phase when crossing the quantum critical point. In addition, at
the end of the pulse light and matter remain entangled even though they become
uncoupled, which could be exploited to generate entangled states in
non-interacting systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.05784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.05784</id><created>2017-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Torreggiani</keyname><forenames>Sofia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mangioni</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puma</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fagiolo</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying the community structure of the international food-trade
  multi network</title><categories>q-fin.GN physics.soc-ph q-fin.EC</categories><comments>47 pages, 19 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Achieving international food security requires improved understanding of how
international trade networks connect countries around the world through the
import-export flows of food commodities. The properties of food trade networks
are still poorly documented, especially from a multi-network perspective. In
particular, nothing is known about the community structure of food networks,
which is key to understanding how major disruptions or 'shocks' would impact
the global food system. Here we find that the individual layers of this network
have densely connected trading groups, a consistent characteristic over the
period 2001 to 2011. We also fit econometric models to identify social,
economic and geographic factors explaining the probability that any two
countries are co-present in the same community. Our estimates indicate that the
probability of country pairs belonging to the same food trade community depends
more on geopolitical and economic factors -- such as geographical proximity and
trade agreements co-membership -- than on country economic size and/or income.
This is in sharp contrast with what we know about bilateral-trade determinants
and suggests that food country communities behave in ways that can be very
different from their non-food counterparts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.05915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.05915</id><created>2017-11-15</created><updated>2017-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maayani</keyname><forenames>Shai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carmon</keyname><forenames>Tal</forenames></author></authors><title>Cavity Optofluidics: Raman Laser Made of a Fiber Coupled nano-Liter
  Droplet</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We fabricate a fiber coupled ultrahigh-Q resonator from a {\mu}droplet per
se; and experimentally measure stimulated Raman emission showing itself at a
160{\mu}W threshold. We observe Raman-laser lines that agree with their related
calculated molecular-vibrations, as well as with a control-group experiment
that uses a Raman-spectrometer. Yet, unlike spectrometers where emission is
spontaneous and less directional, our droplet emitter is stimulated,
single-mode-fiber coupled, resonantly enhanced with Q of 250 million, confined
to a 23 um3 mode volume and has 7 orders of magnitude higher power.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06247</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghadimi</keyname><forenames>Amir H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engelsen</keyname><forenames>Nils J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bereyhi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schilling</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>Dalziel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kippenberg</keyname><forenames>Tobias J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain engineering for ultra-coherent nanomechanical oscillators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Elastic strain engineering utilizes stress to realize unusual material
properties. For instance, strain can be used to enhance the electron mobility
of a semiconductor, enabling more efficient solar cells and smaller, faster
transistors. In the context of nanomechanics, the pursuit of resonators with
ultra-high coherence has led to intense study of a complementary strain
engineering technique, &quot;dissipation dilution&quot;, whereby the stiffness of a
material is effectively increased without added loss. Dissipation dilution is
known to underlie the anomalously high Q factor of Si$_3$N$_4$ nanomechanical
resonators, including recently-developed &quot;soft-clamped&quot; resonators; however,
the paradigm has to date relied on weak strain produced during material
synthesis. By contrast, the use of geometric strain engineering techniques --
capable of producing local stresses near the material yield strength -- remains
largely unexplored. Here we show that geometric strain combined with
soft-clamping can produce unprecedentedly high Q nanomechanical resonators.
Specifically, using a spatially non-uniform phononic crystal pattern, we
colocalize the strain and flexural motion of a Si$_3$N$_4$ nanobeam, while
increasing the former to near the yield strength. This combined strategy
produces string-like modes with room-temperature Q$\times$frequency products
approaching $10^{15}$ Hz, an unprecedented value for a mechanical oscillator of
any size. The devices we study can have force sensitivities of aN/rtHz, perform
hundreds of quantum coherent oscillations at room temperature, and attain Q &gt;
400 million at radio frequencies. These results signal a paradigm shift in the
control of nanomechanical dissipation, with impact ranging from precision force
microscopy to tests of quantum gravity. Combining the reported approach with
crystalline or 2D materials may lead to further improvement, of as yet unknown
limitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06274</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Monserrat</keyname><forenames>Bartomeu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanderbilt</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon-assisted spin splitting in centrosymmetric crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For static crystals it is well known that electronic states are doubly
degenerate in their spin degree of freedom in the presence of time reversal and
inversion symmetries. This degeneracy can only be lifted by either (i) breaking
time reversal symmetry, for example in a ferromagnet, or (ii) breaking
inversion symmetry and having spin orbit coupling, for example in the Rashba
effect. We propose that spin degeneracy can be lifted in time reversal and
inversion symmetric crystals with a combination of lattice vibrations and
spin-orbit coupling. We demonstrate this effect in the cubic perovskite
CsPbCl$_3$ by performing first principles calculations of the finite
temperature band structure, which, in accordance with our prediction, undergoes
spin splitting. We also suggest optical and photoemission experiments to
examine our predictions. This new understanding dramatically expands the range
of materials that can exhibit spin splitting, with potential applications in a
variety of technologies such as spintronics and photovoltaics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06291</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Coldwell</keyname><forenames>Georgina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereyra</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Sol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donoso</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duplancic</keyname><forenames>Fernanda</forenames></author></authors><title>Occurrence of LINER galaxies within the galaxy group environment</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS, 10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>2017MNRAS.467.3338C</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx294</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the properties of a sample of 3967 LINER galaxies selected from
SDSS-DR7, respect to their proximity to galaxy groups. The host galaxies of
LINER have been analysed and compared with a well defined control sample of
3841 non-LINER galaxies matched in redshift, luminosity, colour, morphology,
age and stellar mass content. We find no difference between LINER and control
galaxies in terms of colour and age of stellar population as function of the
virial mass and distance to the geometric centre of the group. However, we find
that LINER are more likely to populate low density environments in spite of
their morphology, which is typical of high density regions such as rich galaxy
clusters. For rich (poor) galaxy groups, the occurrence of LINER is $\sim$2
times lower (higher) than the occurrence of matched, non-LINER galaxies.
Moreover, LINER hosts do not seem to follow the expected morphology-density
relation in groups of high virial mass. The high frequency of LINERS in low
density regions could be due to the combination of a sufficiently ample gas
reservoir to power the low ionization emission and/or enhanced galaxy
interaction rates benefiting the gas flow toward their central regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06304</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Fadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Junsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Jinwu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Youjin</forenames></author></authors><title>Abelian flux induced magnetic frustrations of spinor boson superfluids
  on a square lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, REVTEX-4, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by recent experimental advances to generate Abelian flux for neutral
cold atoms and photons moving in a lattice, we investigate the possible effects
of the $ \pi $ flux through a unit cell in the pseudo-spin 1/2 spinor boson
Hubbard model in a square lattice.
  We find that the $ \pi $ flux induces a dramatic interplay between the charge
and the spin which leads to a frustrated superfluid.
  We develop a new and systematic &quot;order from quantum disorder&quot; analysis to
determine not only the true quantum ground state, but also the excitation
spectrum.
  The superfluid ground state has a 4 sublattice $ 90^{\circ} $ coplanar spin
structure which supports 4 linear gapless modes with 3 different velocities.
  We speculate the transition from the weak coupling frustrated SF to the
strong coupling Ferromagnetic Mott state to be in a new universality class of
non-Ginsburg Landau type.
  These novel phenomena may be observed in these recent cold atom and photonic
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06308</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06308</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kvit</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chenyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffman</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Anand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Dane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voyles</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging of Single La Vacancies in LaMnO$_{3}$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an approach for three-dimensional imaging of single vacancies using
high precision quantitative high-angle annular dark-field Z-contrast scanning
transmission electron microscopy (STEM). Vacancies are identified by both the
reduction in scattered intensity created by the missing atom and the distortion
of the surrounding atom positions. Vacancy positions are determined laterally
to a unique lattice site in the image and in depth to within one of two lattice
sites by dynamical diffraction effects. 35 single La vacancies are identified
in images of a LaMnO3 thin film sample. The vacancies are randomly distributed
in depth and correspond to a La vacancy concentration of 0.79%, which is
consistent with the level of control of cation stoichiometry within our
synthesis process (~1%) and with the equilibrium concentration of La vacancies
under the film growth conditions. This work demonstrates an approach to
characterizing low concentrations of vacancies with high spatial resolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06324</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Araujo</keyname><forenames>R. A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>R. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prado</keyname><forenames>A. F. B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>O. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mapping stable direct and retrograde orbits around the triple system of
  asteroids (45) Eugenia</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>MNRAS, Vol 472, Issue 4, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2230</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well accepted that knowing the composition and the orbital evolution of
asteroids may help us to understand the process of formation of the Solar
System. It is also known that asteroids can represent a threat to our planet.
Such important role made space missions to asteroids a very popular topic in
the current astrodynamics and astronomy studies. By taking into account the
increasingly interest in space missions to asteroids, especially to multiple
systems, we present a study aimed to characterize the stable and unstable
regions around the triple system of asteroids (45) Eugenia. The goal is to
characterize unstable and stable regions of this system and compare with the
system 2001 SN263 - the target of the ASTER mission. Besides, Prado (2014) used
a new concept for mapping orbits considering the disturbance received by the
spacecraft from all the perturbing forces individually. This method was also
applied to (45) Eugenia. We present the stable and unstable regions for
particles with relative inclination between 0 and 180 degrees. We found that
(45) Eugenia presents larger stable regions for both, prograde and retrograde
cases. This is mainly because the satellites of this system are small when
compared to the primary body, and because they are not so close to each other.
We also present a comparison between those two triple systems, and a discussion
on how these results may guide us in the planning of future missions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06329</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06329</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Muslimov</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dohlen</keyname><forenames>Kjetil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neichel</keyname><forenames>Benoit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugot</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Design of pre-optics for laser guide star wavefront sensor for the ELT</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</comments><doi>10.1515/aot-2017-0056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper, we consider the optical design of a zoom system for the
active refocusing in laser guide star wavefront sensors. The system is designed
according to the specifications coming from the Extremely Large Telescope
(ELT)-HARMONI instrument, the first-light, integral field spectrograph for the
European (E)-ELT. The system must provide a refocusing of the laser guide as a
function of telescope pointing and large decentring of the incoming beam. The
system considers four moving lens groups, each of them being a doublet with one
aspherical surface. The advantages and shortcomings of such a solution in terms
of the component displacements and complexity of the surfaces are described in
detail. It is shown that the system can provide the median value of the
residual wavefront error of 13.8-94.3 nm and the maximum value &lt;206 nm, while
the exit pupil distortion is 0.26-0.36% for each of the telescope pointing
directions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06358</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Cobos-Mart&#xed;nez</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsushima</keyname><forenames>K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krein</keyname><forenames>G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>A W</forenames></author></authors><title>Partial restoration of chiral symmetry in cold nuclear matter: the
  $\phi$-meson case</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings of the XXXI Annual Meeting of the Division of Particles
  and Fields of the Mexican Physical Society</comments><journal-ref>J J Cobos-Martinez et al 2017 J. Phys.: Conf.Ser, 912 012009</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The work presented at this workshop is divided into two parts. In the first
part, the mass and decay width of the $\phi$-meson in cold nuclear matter are
computed in an effective Lagrangian approach. The medium dependence of these
properties are obtained by evaluating kaon-antikaon loop contributions to the
$\phi$-meson self-energy, employing medium-modified kaon masses calculated
using the quark-meson coupling model. The loop integral is regularized with a
dipole form factor, and the sensitivity of the results to the choice of cutoff
mass in the form factor is investigated. At normal nuclear matter density, we
find a downward shift of the $\phi$ mass by a few percent, while the decay
width is enhanced by an order of magnitude.
  Our results support the literature which suggest that one should observe a
small downward mass shift and a large broadening of the decay width. In the
second part, we present $\phi$-meson--nucleus bound state energies and
absorption widths for four selected nuclei, calculated by solving the
Klein-Gordon equation with complex optical potentials. The attractive potential
for the $\phi$-meson in the nuclear medium originates from the in-medium
enhanced KK loop in the $\phi$-meson selfenergy. The results suggest that the
$\phi$-meson should form bound states with all the nuclei considered. However,
the identification of the signal for these predicted bound states will need
careful investigation because of their sizable absorption widths.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06359</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Minkyoung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jurdak</keyname><forenames>Raja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paini</keyname><forenames>Dean</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling Reflexivity of Social Systems in Disease Spread</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diffusion processes in a social system are governed by external triggers and
internal excitations via interactions between individuals over social networks.
Underlying mechanisms are crucial to understand emergent phenomena in the real
world and accordingly establish effective strategies. However, it is
challenging to reveal the dynamics of a target diffusion process due to
invisible causality between events and their time-evolving intensity. In this
study, we propose the Latent Influence Point Process model (LIPP) by
incorporating external heterogeneity and internal dynamics of meta-populations
based on human mobility. Our proposed model quantifies the reflexivity of a
social system, which is the level of feedback on event occurrences by its
internal dynamics. As an exemplary case study, we investigate dengue outbreaks
in Queensland, Australia during the last 15 years. We find that abrupt and
steady growth of disease outbreaks relate to exogenous and endogenous
influences respectively. Similar diffusion trends between regions reflect
synchronous reflexivity of a regional social system, likely driven by human
mobility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06364</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Baik</keyname><forenames>Jinho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ji Oon</forenames></author></authors><title>Free energy of bipartite spherical Sherrington--Kirkpatrick model</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>43 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the free energy of the bipartite spherical
Sherrington--Kirkpatrick model. We find the critical temperature and prove the
limiting free energy for all non-critical temperature. We also show that the
law of the fluctuation of the free energy converges to the Gaussian
distribution when the temperature is above the critical temperature, and to the
GOE Tracy--Widom distribution when the temperature is below the critical
temperature. The result is universal, and the analysis is applicable to a more
general setting including the case where the disorders are non-identically
distributed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06372</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Adrian J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bapst</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byrne</keyname><forenames>Shane</forenames></author></authors><title>Observations of a new stabilizing effect for polar water ice on Mars</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>26 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars (CRISM), we
map the temporal variability of water ice absorption bands over the near-polar
ice mound in Louth crater, Mars. The absorption band depth of water ice at 1.5
microns can be used as a proxy for ice grain size and so sudden reductions can
time any switches from ablation to condensation. A short period of deposition
on the outer edge of the ice mound during late spring coincides with the
disappearance of seasonal water frost from the surrounding regolith suggesting
that this deposition is locally sourced. The outer unit at Louth ice mound
differs from its central regions by being rough, finely layered, and lacking
wind-blown sastrugi. This suggests we are observing a new stabilizing effect
wherein the outer unit is being seasonally replenished with water ice from the
surrounding regolith during spring. We observe the transport distance for water
migration at Louth crater to be ~4km, and we use this new finding to address
why no water ice mounds are observed in craters &lt;9km in diameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06380</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bence</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenkovszky</keyname><forenames>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szanyi</keyname><forenames>Istv&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Approaching the asymptotics at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures; submitted to Physical Review D</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent results on the slope of the $pp$ diffraction cone measured by TOTEM at
$7$ and $8$ GeV show an unexpected rapid rise in $s$, close to $B(s)\sim
\ln^2$, rather than $\ln s$, typical of the Regge-pole predictions. We show
that the new phenomenon can be accommodated by the inclusion of unitarity
corrections to a simple Regge (pomeron) pole exchange. Interestingly, the
odderon may also promote the acceleration of $B(s)$. The onset of the new
regime may be indicative of the approach to the asymptotic dynamics of strong
interactions. We analyse the new data together with other available forward
measurable in a unitarized Regge dipole. Unitarization proves crucial in
fitting the data, especially those on the slope $B(s)$ showing a change from
the $\ln (s)$ to $\ln^2 (s)$ behavior. Having fitted the free parameters of the
unitarized model to the data, we predict the behavior of the cross sections and
the slope at still higher energies, including those asymptotic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06381</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Priya</keyname><forenames>T G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiangtao</keyname><forenames>Su</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuanyong</keyname><forenames>Deng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choudhury</keyname><forenames>Debi Prasad</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical analysis on Dynamic Fibrils observed from NST/BBSO
  observations</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in RAA</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results obtained from the analysis of dynamic fibrils in NOAA
active region (AR) 12132, using high resolution H$\alpha$ observations from New
Solar Telescope operating at BBSO. The dynamic fibrils are seen to be moving up
and down, and most of these dynamic fibrils are periodic and have jet like
appearance. We found from our observations that the fibrils follows perfect
parabolic paths at the most in many cases. A statistical measure on the
properties of the parabolic paths showing an analysis on deceleration, maximum
velocity, duration and kinetic energy of these fibrils is presented here. We
found the average maximum velocity to be around 15 km s$^{-1}$ and mean
deceleration to be around 100 m s$^{-2}$. The deceleration observed appears to
be a fraction of gravity of sun and is not compatible with the path of
ballistic at the gravity of sun. We found positive correlation between the
deceleration and the maximum velocity. This correlation is consistent with the
simulations done earlier on magnetoacoustic shock waves propagating upward.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06389</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>Tuan</forenames><affiliation>UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hees</keyname><forenames>Aurelien</forenames><affiliation>UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dehghanfar</keyname><forenames>Arezu</forenames><affiliation>UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ghez</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames><affiliation>UCLA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Shelley</forenames><affiliation>UC San Diego</affiliation></author></authors><title>Measuring the effects of General Relativity at the Galactic Center with
  Future Extremely Large Telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Galactic center offers us a unique opportunity to test General Relativity
(GR) with the orbits of stars around a supermassive black hole. Observations of
these stars have been one of the great successes of adaptive optics on 8-10 m
telescopes, driving the need for the highest angular resolution and astrometric
precision. New tests of gravitational physics in the strong gravity regime with
stellar orbits will be made possible through the leap in angular resolution and
sensitivity from the next generation of extremely large ground-based
telescopes. We present new simulations of specific science cases such as the
detection of the GR precession of stars, the measurement of extended dark mass,
and the distance to the Galactic center. We use realistic models of the
adaptive optics system for TMT and the IRIS instrument to simulate these
science cases. In additions, the simulations include observational issues such
as the impact of source confusion on astrometry and radial velocities in the
dense environment of the Galactic center. We qualitatively show how
improvements in sensitivity, astrometric and spectroscopic precision, and
increasing the number of stars affect the science with orbits at the Galactic
center. We developed a tool to determine the constraints on physical models
using a joint fit of over 100 stars that are expected to be observable with
TMT. These science cases require very high astrometric precision and stability,
thus they provide some of the most stringent constraints on the planned
instruments and adaptive optics systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06404</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Benusiglio</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cira</keyname><forenames>Nate</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lai</keyname><forenames>Anna Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>Manu</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-component self-contracted droplets: long-range attraction and
  confinement effects</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Marangoni self-contracted droplets are formed by a mixture of two liquids,
one of larger surface tension and larger evaporation rate than the other. Due
to evaporation, the droplets contract to a stable contact angle instead of
spreading on a wetting substrate. This gives them unique properties, including
absence of pinning force and ability to move under vapor gradients, self- and
externally imposed. We first model the dynamics of attraction in an unconfined
geometry and then study the effects of confinement on the attraction range and
dynamics, going from minimal confinement (vertical boundary), to medium
confinement (2-D vapor diffusion) and eventually strong confinement (1-D).
&quot;Self-induced&quot; motion is observed when single droplets are placed close to a
vapor boundary toward which they are attracted, the boundary acting as an image
droplet with respect to itself. When two droplets are confined between two
horizontal plates, they interact at a longer distance with modified dynamics.
Finally, confining the droplet in a tunnel, the range of attraction is greatly
enhanced, as the droplet moves all the way up the tunnel when an external
humidity gradient is imposed. &quot;Self-induced&quot; motion is also observed, as the
droplet can move by itself towards the center of the tunnel. Confinement
greatly increase the range at which droplets interact as well as their lifetime
and thus greatly expands the control and design possibilities for applications
offered by self-contracted droplets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06416</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Ai-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Qing-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Ginzburg-Landau-type theory of non-polarized spin superconductivity</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 014501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.014501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the concept of spin superconductor was proposed, all the related
studies concentrate on spin-polarized case. Here, we generalize the study to
spin-non-polarized case. The free energy of non-polarized spin superconductor
is obtained, and the Ginzburg-Landau-type equations are derived by using the
variational method. These Ginzburg-Landau-type equations can be reduced to the
spin-polarized case when the spin direction is fixed. Moreover, the expressions
of super linear and angular spin currents inside the superconductor are
derived. We demonstrate that the electric field induced by super spin current
is equal to the one induced by equivalent charge obtained from the second
Ginzburg-Landau-type equation, which shows self-consistency of our theory. By
applying these Ginzburg-Landau-type equations, the effect of electric field on
the superconductor is also studied. These results will help us get a better
understanding of the spin superconductor and the related topics such as
Bose-Einstein condensate of magnons and spin superfluidity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06419</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06419</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Ai-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Huaiyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chunxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Qing-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-flip reflection at the normal metal-spin superconductor interface</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 104516 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.104516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study spin transport through a normal metal-spin superconductor junction.
A spin-flip reflection is demonstrated at the interface, where a spin-up
electron incident from the normal metal can be reflected as a spin-down
electron and the spin $2\times \hbar/2$ will be injected into the spin
superconductor. When the (spin) voltage is smaller than the gap of the spin
superconductor, the spin-flip reflection determines the transport properties of
the junction. We consider both graphene-based (linear-dispersion-relation) and
quadratic-dispersion-relation normal metal-spin superconductor junctions in
detail. For the two-dimensional graphene-based junction, the spin-flip
reflected electron can be along the specular direction (retro-direction) when
the incident and reflected electron locates in the same band (different bands).
A perfect spin-flip reflection can occur when the incident electron is normal
to the interface, and the reflection coefficient is slightly suppressed for the
oblique incident case. As a comparison, for the one-dimensional
quadratic-dispersion-relation junction, the spin-flip reflection coefficient
can reach 1 at certain incident energies. In addition, both the charge current
and the spin current under a charge (spin) voltage are studied. The spin
conductance is proportional to the spin-flip reflection coefficient when the
spin voltage is less than the gap of the spin superconductor. These results
will help us get a better understanding of spin transport through the normal
metal-spin superconductor junction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06426</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06426</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Darr</keyname><forenames>Yasir R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niazi</keyname><forenames>Muaz A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Self-organized Large-Scale Shape Formation: A Cognitive
  Agent-Based Computing Approach</title><categories>cs.RO cs.MA nlin.AO nlin.CG nlin.PS</categories><comments>40 pages</comments><acm-class>I.2.11; I.2.9; I.6; I.6.7; B.4.3; F.1.1</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Swarm robotic systems are currently being used to address many real-world
problems. One interesting application of swarm robotics is the self-organized
formation of structures and shapes. Some of the key challenges in the swarm
robotic systems include swarm size constraint, random motion, coordination
among robots, localization, and adaptability in a decentralized environment.
Rubenstein et al. presented a system (&quot;Programmable self-assembly in a
thousand-robot swarm&quot;, Science, 2014) for thousand-robot swarm able to form
only solid shapes with the robots in aggregated form by applying the collective
behavior algorithm. Even though agent-based approaches have been presented in
various studies for self-organized formation, however these studies lack
agent-based modeling (ABM) approach along with the constraints in term of
structure complexity and heterogeneity in large swarms with dynamic
localization. The cognitive agent-based computing (CABC) approach is capable of
modeling such self-organization based multi-agents systems (MAS). In this
paper, we develop a simulation model using ABM under CABC approach for
self-organized shape formation in swarm robots. We propose a shape formation
algorithm for validating our model and perform simulation-based experiments for
six different shapes including hole-based shapes. We also demonstrate the
formal specification for our model. The simulation result shows the robustness
of the proposed approach having the emergent behavior of robots for the
self-organized shape formation. The performance of the proposed approach is
evaluated by robots convergence rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06437</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhaoyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Liu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Jingliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Jiteng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yiqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yanpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author></authors><title>Parity-time-symmetric optical lattice with alternating gain and loss
  atomic configurations</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the spatially extended periodic parity-time (PT) symmetric potential
can possess certain unique properties compared to a single PT cell (with only a
pair of coupled gain-loss components), various schemes have been proposed to
realize periodic PT-symmetric potentials based on optical lattices. Here, we
experimentally construct a spatially periodic PT-symmetric optical potential
based on gain-loss arrays induced in a coherently-prepared atomic medium. The
gain and loss arrays are generated in alternating four-level N-type and
three-level $\Lambda$-type configurations in the same atomic medium,
respectively, which do not require discrete diffractions as demonstrated in the
previous work [Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 123601(2016)] and can be easier to realize
with more relaxed operating conditions. The dynamical behaviors of the system
are investigated by measuring the phase difference between two adjacent gain
and loss channels. The demonstrated PT-symmetric optical lattice with easy
accessibility and better tunability sets a new stage for further exploiting the
peculiar physical properties in periodic non-Hermitian systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06438</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Faxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Huan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Hua-Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface Probing by Dielectric Frequency Dispersion in Carbon
  Nanocomposites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interfaces remain one of the major issues in limiting the understanding and
designing polymer nanocomposites due to their complexity and pivotal role in
determining the ultimate composites properties. In this study, we take
multi-walled carbon nanotubes/silicone rubber nanocomposites as a
representative example, and have for the first time studied the correlation
between high-frequency dielectric dispersion and static/dynamic interfacial
characteristics. We have found that the interface together with other
meso-structural parameters (volume fraction, dispersion, agglomeration) play
decisive role in formulating the dielectric patterns. The calculation of the
relaxation times affords the relative importance of interfacial polarization to
dipolar polarization in resultant dielectric relaxation. Dielectric
measurements coupled with cyclic loading further reveals the remarkable
capability of dielectric frequency dispersion in capturing the evolution of
interfacial properties, such as a particular interface reconstruction process
occurred to the surfactant-modified samples. All these results demonstrate that
high-frequency dielectric spectroscopy is instrumental to probing both static
and dynamic meso-structural characteristics, especially effective for the
composites with relative weak interfaces which remains a mission impossible for
many other techniques. The insights provided here based on the analyses of
dielectric frequency dispersion will pave the way for optimized design and
precise engineering of meso-structure in polymer nanocomposites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06440</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06440</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Patoary</keyname><forenames>Abu Saleh Musa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oreshkina</keyname><forenames>Natalia S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite Nuclear Size Effect to the Fine Structure of Heavy Muonic Atoms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The finite-nuclear size correction to the fine structure of muonic atoms are
considered. The procedure for the analytical calculation of the energies and
wave functions has been derived in a homogeneously charged sphere nuclear
charge distribution approximation. The finite-nuclear size effect was
calculated in a first few orders of the perturbation energy, with the accurate
estimations of the convergence. Finally, we present energies of the low-lying
electronic and muonic states with the finite-nuclear size correction,
calculated analytically, for ${}^{185}_{75}\text{Re}$ ion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06457</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Arimoto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harita</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugita</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yatsu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawai</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomida</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isobe</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueno</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihara</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohmura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsunemi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatori</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kume</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of a 32-channel ASIC for an X-ray APD Detector onboard the
  ISS</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in NIMA</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2017.09.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the design and performance of a mixed-signal application
specific integrated circuit (ASIC) dedicated to avalanche photodiodes (APDs) in
order to detect hard X-ray emissions in a wide energy band onboard the
International Space Station. To realize wide-band detection from 20 keV to 1
MeV, we use Ce:GAGG scintillators, each coupled to an APD, with low-noise
front-end electronics capable of achieving a minimum energy detection threshold
of 20 keV. The developed ASIC has the ability to read out 32-channel APD
signals using 0.35 $\mu$m CMOS technology, and an analog amplifier at the input
stage is designed to suppress the capacitive noise primarily arising from the
large detector capacitance of the APDs. The ASIC achieves a performance of 2099
e$^{-}$ + 1.5 e$^{-}$/pF at root mean square (RMS) with a wide 300 fC dynamic
range. Coupling a reverse-type APD with a Ce:GAGG scintillator, we obtain an
energy resolution of 6.7% (FWHM) at 662 keV and a minimum detectable energy of
20 keV at room temperature (20 $^{\circ}$C). Furthermore, we examine the
radiation tolerance for space applications by using a 90 MeV proton beam,
confirming that the ASIC is free of single-event effects and can operate
properly without serious degradation in analog and digital processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06492</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Dabrowski</keyname><forenames>Ludwik</forenames></author></authors><title>On noncommutative geometry of the Standard Model: fermion multiplet as
  internal forms</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.DG math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>Talk at the XXXVI Workshop on Geometric Methods in Physics,
  Bialowieza 5.07.2017</comments><msc-class>Primary 58B34, Secondary 46L87, 81T13</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We unveil the geometric nature of the multiplet of fundamental fermions in
the Standard Model of fundamental particles as a noncommutative analogue of de
Rham forms on the internal finite quantum space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06512</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Senichev</keyname><forenames>Yury</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aksentev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Andrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valetov</keyname><forenames>Eremey</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency domain method of the search for the deuteron electric dipole
  moment in a storage ring with imperfections</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The method is based on four fundamental features. The total spin precession
frequency in the vertical plane due to the electric and magnetic dipole moments
in an imperfect ring in a vertical plane is measured. The position of the ring
elements is unchanged from clockwise to counter-clockwise operation. The
calibration of the effective Lorentz factor using the polarization precession
frequency measurement in the horizontal plane is carried out alternately in
each CW and CCW operation. And the approximate relationship between the
frequencies of the polarization precession in different planes is set to
exclude them from mixing to the vertical frequency of the expected EDM signal
at a sensitivity level approaching $10^{-29}$ $e\cdot cm$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06525</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Cesar R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romano</keyname><forenames>Renan G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Results on the Aharonov-Bohm effect without contact with the solenoid</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>It is a report of results. Proofs appear elsewhere</comments><journal-ref>JOURNAL OF MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS 58, 102102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4992123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We add a confining potential to the Aharonov-Bohm model resulting in no
contact of the particle with the solenoid (border); this is characterized by a
unique self-adjoint extension of the initial Hamiltonian operator. It is shown
that the spectrum of such extension is discrete and the first eigenvalue is
found to be a nonconstant 1-periodic function of the magnetic flux circulation
with a minimum at integers and maximum at half-integer circulations. This is a
rigorous verification of the effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06531</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Belhaj</keyname><forenames>Adil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ennadifi</keyname><forenames>Salah Eddine</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Information and Elementary Particles</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, latex file</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by string theory and standard model physics, we discuss the
possibility of other particles-based quantum information. A special attention
is put on the consideration of the graviton in light of the gravitational wave
detection. This may offer a new take in approaching quantum information using
messenger particles. The construction is readily extended to higher dimensional
qubits where we speculate on possible connections with open and closed string
sectors in terms of quiver and graph theories, respectively. In particular, we
reveal that the vectorial qubits could be associated with skeleton diagrams
considered as extended quivers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06561</id><created>2017-11-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Taiwo</keyname><forenames>Tunde Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Meixner- Pollaczek Quantum System</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  In an effort to achieve our aims (getting larger quantum system) in the
recent reformulation of quantum mechanics without potential function [1-5], we
obtained a new quantum system associated with Meixner Pollaczek Orthogonal
polynomial class (hereby called Meixner - Pollaczek Quantum system). The energy
spectrum and wave function of the quantum system were given. To the best of our
knowledge, this quantum system is not found in physics literatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06563</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Bougoffa</keyname><forenames>Lazhar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Awfi</keyname><forenames>Saud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bougouffa</keyname><forenames>Smail</forenames></author></authors><title>A complete and partial integrability technique of the Lorenz system</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we deal with the well-known nonlinear Lorenz system that
describes the deterministic chaos phenomenon. We consider an interesting
problem with time-varying phenomena in quantum optics. Then we establish from
the motion equations the passage to the Lorenz system. Furthermore, we show
that the reduction to the third order non linear equation can be performed.
Therefore, the obtained differential equation can be analytically solved in
some special cases and transformed to Abel, Dufing, Painlev\'{e} and
generalized Emden-Fowler equations. So, a motivating technique that permitted a
complete and partial integrability of the Lorenz system is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06567</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Songhu</forenames></author></authors><title>RV-detected Kepler-multi Analogs Exhibit Intra-system Mass Uniformity</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Submitted to Research Notes of the AAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent work has shown that the planets in the $Kepler$ Mission's population
of multi-transiting systems show surprising uniformity in both mass and radius.
In this brief note, I show that this intra-system mass uniformity extends to
multiple-planet systems detected with the Doppler velocity technique, thereby
avoiding possible biases associated with masses determined by transit timing. I
also show that intra-system mass uniformity breaks down when a system contains
one or more giant planets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06568</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Stokes</keyname><forenames>Finn M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamleh</keyname><forenames>Waseem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leinweber</keyname><forenames>Derek B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic Form Factors of Nucleon Excitations in Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>proceedings for INPC2016, 5 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: text
  overlap with arXiv:1701.07177</comments><journal-ref>PoS INPC2016 (2017) 263</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Variational analysis techniques in lattice QCD are powerful tools that give
access to the full spectrum of QCD. At zero momentum, these techniques are well
established and can cleanly isolate energy eigenstates of either positive or
negative parity. In order to compute the form factors of a single energy
eigenstate, we must perform a variational analysis at non-zero momentum. When
we do this with baryons, we run into issues with parity mixing in the Dirac
spinors, as boosted baryons are not eigenstates of parity. Due to this parity
mixing, care must be taken to ensure that the projected correlation functions
provided by the variational analysis correspond to the same states at zero
momentum. This can be achieved through the parity-expanded variational analysis
(PEVA) technique, a novel method developed at the University of Adelaide for
ensuring the successful and consistent isolation of boosted baryons. Utilising
this technique, we are able to compute the form factors of baryon excitations
without contamination from other states. We present world-first calculations of
excited state nucleon form factors using this new technique.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06572</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Opa&#x10d;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarevi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaskovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radonji&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milosavljevi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yongchang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrovic</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Z. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Small influence of magnetic ordering on lattice dynamics in
  TaFe$_{1.25}$Te$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 174303, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.174303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Raman scattering spectra of zigzag spin chain TaFe$_{1.25}$Te$_3$ single
crystal are presented in a temperature range from 80 to 300 K. Nine Raman
active modes of $A_g$ and $B_g$ symmetry are clearly observed and assigned by
probing different scattering channels, which is confirmed by lattice dynamics
calculations. Temperature dependence of the Raman modes linewidth is mainly
governed by the lattice anharmonicity. The only deviation from the conventional
behavior is observed for $A_g$ symmetry modes in a vicinity of the magnetic
phase transition at $T_N \approx 200$ K. This implies that the electron-phonon
interaction weakly changes with temperature and magnetic ordering, whereas
small changes in the spectra near the critical temperature can be ascribed to
spin fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06573</id><created>2017-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Vafaee</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khorramian</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Beauty and Charm H1-ZEUS Combined Measurements on PDFs and
  Determination of the Strong Coupling</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1709.08402</comments><journal-ref>Published in Eur. Phys. J. A (2017) 53: 220</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12405-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this QCD analysis, we investigate the impact of recent measurements of
heavy-flavor charm and beauty cross sections data sets on the simultaneous
determination of Parton Distribution Functions (PDFs) and the strong coupling,
$\alpha_s(M^2_Z)$. We perform three different fits based on Variable-Flavour
Number Scheme (VFNS) at the Leading Order (LO) and Next-to-Leading Order (NLO)
and choose the full HERA run I and II combined data as a new measurement of
inclusive Deep Inelastic Scattering (DIS) cross sections for our base data set.
We show that including charm and beauty cross sections data reduces the
uncertainty of gluon distribution and improves the fit quality up to 4.1\% from
leading order to next-to-leading order and up to 1.7\% for only NLO without and
with beauty and charm data contributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06587</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Nissen</keyname><forenames>Jayson M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jariwala</keyname><forenames>Manher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>Xochith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Close</keyname><forenames>Eleanor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dusen</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance differences for in-class and online administration of
  low-stakes research-based assessments</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Research-based assessments (RBAs), such as the Force Concept Inventory, have
played central roles in many course transformations from traditional
lecture-based instruction to research-based teaching methods. In order to
support instructors in assessing their courses, the online Learning About STEM
Student Outcomes (LASSO) platform simplifies administering, scoring, and
interpreting RBAs. Reducing the barriers to using RBAs will support more
instructors in objectively assessing the efficacy of their courses and,
subsequently, transforming their courses to improve student outcomes. The
purpose of this study was to investigate the extent to which RBAs administered
online and outside of class with the LASSO platform provided equivalent data to
traditional paper and pencil tests administered in class. Research indicates
that these two modes of administering assessments provide equivalent data for
graded exams that are administered in class. However, little research has
focused on ungraded (low-stakes) exams that are administered outside of class.
We used an experimental design to investigate the differences between these two
test modes. Results indicated that the LASSO platform provided equivalent data
to paper and pencil tests.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06595</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Nissen</keyname><forenames>Jayson M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jariwala</keyname><forenames>Manher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Close</keyname><forenames>Eleanor W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dusen</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>Participation and Performance on Paper- and Computer-Based Low-Stakes
  Assessments</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-stakes assessments, such the Graduate Records Examination, have
transitioned from paper to computer administration. Low-stakes Research-Based
Assessments (RBAs), such as the Force Concept Inventory, have only recently
begun this transition to computer administration with online services. These
online services can simplify administering, scoring, and interpreting
assessments, thereby reducing barriers to instructors' use of RBAs. By
supporting instructors' objective assessment of the efficacy of their courses,
these services can stimulate instructors to transform their courses to improve
student outcomes. We investigate the extent to which RBAs administered outside
of class with the online Learning About STEM Student Outcomes (LASSO) platform
provide equivalent data to tests administered on paper in class, in terms of
both student participation and performance. We use an experimental design to
investigate the differences between these two assessment conditions with 1,310
students in 25 sections of 3 college physics courses spanning 2 semesters.
Analysis conducted using Hierarchical Linear Models indicates that student
performance on low-stakes RBAs is equivalent for online (out-of-class) and
paper-and-pencil (in-class) administrations. The models also show differences
in participation rates across assessment conditions and student grades, but
that instructors can achieve participation rates with online assessments
equivalent to paper assessments by offering students credit for participating
and by providing multiple reminders to complete the assessment. We conclude
that online out-of-class administration of RBAs can save class and instructor
time while providing participation rates and performance results equivalent to
in-class paper-and-pencil tests.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06596</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Alonso</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gamba</keyname><forenames>Irene M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taskovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Maja</forenames></author></authors><title>Exponentially-tailed regularity and time asymptotic for the homogeneous
  Boltzmann equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>46 pages</comments><msc-class>82B40, 45Gxx</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present in this document the Lebesgue and Sobolev propagation of
exponential tails for solutions of the homogeneous Boltzmann equation for hard
and Maxwell interactions. In addition, we show the $L^{p}$-integrability
creation of such tails in the case of hard interactions. The document also
presents a result on exponentially-fast convergence to thermodynamical
equilibrium and propagation of singularities and regularization of such
solutions. All these results are valid under the mere Grad's cut-off condition
for the angular scattering kernel. Highlights of this contribution include: (1)
full range of $L^{p}$-norms with $p\in[1,\infty]$, (2) analysis for the
critical case of Maxwell interactions, (3) propagation of fractional Sobolev
exponential tails using pointwise conmutators, and (4) time asymptotic and
propagation of regularity and singularities under general physical data. In
many ways, this work is an improvement and an extension of several classical
works in the area; we use known techniques and introduce new and flexible ideas
that achieve the proofs in an elementary manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06617</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Regmi</keyname><forenames>Raju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winkler</keyname><forenames>Pamina M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flauraud</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgman</keyname><forenames>Kyra J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manzo</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brugger</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigneault</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wenger</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Parajo</keyname><forenames>Mar&#xed;a F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Planar Optical Nanoantennas Resolve Cholesterol-Dependent Nanoscale
  Heterogeneities in the Plasma Membrane of Living Cells</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2017, 17 (10), pp 6295-6302</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b02973</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical nanoantennas can efficiently confine light into nanoscopic hotspots,
enabling single-molecule detection sensitivity at biological relevant
conditions. This innovative approach to breach the diffraction limit offers a
versatile platform to investigate the dynamics of individual biomolecules in
living cell membranes and their partitioning into cholesterol-dependent lipid
nanodomains. Here, we present optical nanoantenna arrays with accessible
surface hotspots to study the characteristic diffusion dynamics of
phosphoethanolamine (PE) and sphingomyelin (SM) in the plasma membrane of
living cells at the nanoscale. Fluorescence burst analysis and fluorescence
correlation spectroscopy performed on nanoantennas of different gap sizes show
that, unlike PE, SM is transiently trapped in cholesterol-enriched nanodomains
of 10 nm diameter with short characteristic times around 100 {\mu}s. The
removal of cholesterol led to the free diffusion of SM, consistent with the
dispersion of nanodomains. Our results are consistent with the existence of
highly transient and fluctuating nanoscale assemblies enriched by cholesterol
and sphingolipids in living cell membranes, also known as lipid rafts.
Quantitative data on sphingolipids partitioning into lipid rafts is crucial to
understand the spatiotemporal heterogeneous organization of transient molecular
complexes on the membrane of living cells at the nanoscale. The proposed
technique is fully biocompatible and thus provides various opportunities for
biophysics and live cell research to reveal details that remain hidden in
confocal diffraction-limited measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06622</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Xing-Can</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang-Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Qiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Xuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hao-Ze</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly Interacting Bose Gases near a $d$-wave Shape Resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many unconventional quantum matters, such as fractional quantum Hall effect
and $d$-wave high-Tc superconductor, are discovered in strongly interacting
systems. Understanding quantum many-body systems with strong interaction and
the unconventional phases therein is one of the most challenging problems in
physics nowadays. Cold atom systems possess a natural way to create strong
interaction by bringing the system to the vicinity of a scattering resonance.
Although this has been a focused topic in cold atom physics for more than a
decade, these studies have so far mostly been limited for $s$-wave resonance.
Here we report the experimental observation of a broad $d$-wave shape resonance
in degenerate ${}^{41}$K gas. We further measure the molecular binding energy
that splits into three branches as a hallmark of $d$-wave molecules, and find
that the lifetime of this many-body system is reasonably long at strongly
interacting regime. From analyzing the breathing mode excited by ramping
through this resonance, it suggests that a quite stable low-temperature atom
and molecule mixture is produced. Putting all the evidence together, our system
offers great promise to reach a $d$-wave molecular superfluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06629</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bokas</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perepezko</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nucleation Kinetics in Al-Sm Metallic Glasses</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Zhao, L., Bokas, G. B., Perepezko, J.H., Szlufarska, I. (2017).
  Nucleation kinetics in Al-Sm metallic glasses. Acta Materialia, 142, 1-7</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.09.050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The isothermal nucleation kinetics in Al-Sm metallic glasses with low Sm
concentrations (xSm) was studied using molecular dynamics simulations in order
to calculate time-temperature-transformation curves. The average delay time of
Al nanocrystal nucleation was found to increase exponentially with xSm, whereas
the estimated critical cooling rate necessary to avoid crystallization
decreases exponentially with xSm. Sm solutes were found to suppress Al
nucleation by increasing the attachment barrier and therefore by reducing the
attachment frequency. The analysis shows that the attachment of Al to the
evolving nucleus has the same characteristics as Al diffusion within the
amorphous matrix and they both take place heterogeneously via collective
movement of a group of Al atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06645</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallahi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gardner</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfra</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible nematic to smectic phase transition in a two-dimensional
  electron gas at half-filling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 1536 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-01810-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Liquid crystalline phases of matter permeate nature and technology, with
examples ranging from cell membranes to liquid-crystal displays. Remarkably,
electronic liquid crystal phases can exist in two-dimensional electron systems
(2DES) at half Landau level filling in the quantum Hall regime. Theory has
predicted the existence of a liquid crystal smectic phase that breaks both
rotational and translational symmetries. However, previous experiments in 2DES
are most consistent with an anisotropic nematic phase breaking only rotational
symmetry. Here we report three transport phenomena at half-filling in ultra-low
disorder 2DES: a non-monotonic temperature dependence of the sample resistance,
dramatic onset of large time-dependent resistance fluctuations, and a sharp
feature in the differential resistance suggestive of depinning. These data
suggest that a sequence of symmetry-breaking phase transitions occurs as
temperature is lowered: first a transition from an isotropic liquid to a
nematic phase and finally to a liquid crystal smectic phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06652</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wiebe</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Ram Shankar Siva</forenames></author></authors><title>Hardening Quantum Machine Learning Against Adversaries</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR cs.LG</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Security for machine learning has begun to become a serious issue for present
day applications. An important question remaining is whether emerging quantum
technologies will help or hinder the security of machine learning. Here we
discuss a number of ways that quantum information can be used to help make
quantum classifiers more secure or private. In particular, we demonstrate a
form of robust principal component analysis that, under some circumstances, can
provide an exponential speedup relative to robust methods used at present. To
demonstrate this approach we introduce a linear combinations of unitaries
Hamiltonian simulation method that we show functions when given an imprecise
Hamiltonian oracle, which may be of independent interest. We also introduce a
new quantum approach for bagging and boosting that can use quantum
superposition over the classifiers or splits of the training set to aggregate
over many more models than would be possible classically. Finally, we provide a
private form of $k$--means clustering that can be used to prevent an all
powerful adversary from learning more than a small fraction of a bit from any
user. These examples show the role that quantum technologies can play in the
security of ML and vice versa. This illustrates that quantum computing can
provide useful advantages to machine learning apart from speedups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06657</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Louvet</keyname><forenames>Thibaud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houzet</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carpentier</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Signature of the Chiral Anomaly in Ballistic Magneto-Transport</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the magneto-conductance of a short junction made out of a Weyl
semi-metal. We show that it displays quantum oscillations at low magnetic field
and low temperature, before reaching a universal high-field regime where it
increases linearly with the field. Besides identifying a new characterization
of the physics of materials with Weyl singularities in their energy spectrum,
this ballistic regime corresponds to the simplest setup to study and understand
the manifestation of the so-called chiral anomaly of massless relativistic
particles in condensed matter. At low fields the algebraic in field
magneto-conductance incorporates contributions besides the anomalous chiral
current while the linear conductance at higher fields constitutes an
unambiguous signature of the chiral anomaly in a Weyl conductor. Finally, we
study the dependence of the ballistic magneto-conductance on the chemical
potential, and discuss the cross-over towards the diffusive regime when elastic
scattering is present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06667</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Haley</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagot</keyname><forenames>Paul A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moody</keyname><forenames>Michael P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atom Probe Analysis of Ex Situ Gas-Charged Stable Hydrides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Microscopy and Microanalysis, 23,2, 2017,pp. 307-313</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1431927616012630</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we report on the atom probe tomography analysis of two metallic
hydrides formed by pressurized charging using an ex situ hydrogen charging
cell, in the pressure range of 200-500 kPa (2-5 bar). Specifically we report on
the deuterium charging of Pd/Rh and V systems. Using this ex situ system, we
demonstrate the successful loading and subsequent atom probe analysis of
deuterium within a Pd/Rh alloy, and demonstrate that deuterium is likely
present within the oxide-metal interface of a native oxide formed on vanadium.
Through these experiments, we demonstrate the feasibility of ex situ hydrogen
analysis for hydrides via atom probe tomography, and thus a practical route to
three-dimensional imaging of hydrogen in hydrides at the atomic scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.06668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-20</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.06668</id><created>2017-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>McNulty</keyname><forenames>Ronan</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the LHCb collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Central Exclusive Production at LHCb</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Presented at EDS Blois, Prague, Czech Republic, June 26-30, 2017</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The installation of a new sub-detector has improved the ability of LHCb to
measure central exclusive production in Run 2 at the LHC. A measurement of
central exclusive $J/\psi$ production is presented and improvements for the
analysis of hadronic final states are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
