<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:58:14Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-11-03" from="2017-11-03" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7578</id><created>2014-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Philippen</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guguschev</keyname><forenames>Christo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimm</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Single crystal fiber growth of cerium doped strontium yttrate,
  SrY2O4:Ce3+</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Crystal Growth 459 (2017) 17-22</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcrysgro.2016.11.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  First single crystal fibers of cerium doped strontium yttrate are fabricated
using the laser-heated pedestal growth technique. Through thermodynamic
equilibrium calculations and by high-temperature mass spectrometry suitable
growth conditions can be determined. The atmosphere plays an important role
during crystallization. It affects the composition shift, on the one hand, and
the valence state of cerium, on the other hand. These properties can be
explained by combining X-ray diffraction, elemental analysis, and optical
spectroscopy. Crystallization in slightly reducing nitrogen atmosphere proves
to be a reasonable choice, because evaporation is suppressed and trivalent
cerium is stabilized. Strong green emission that depends on the oxygen fugacity
during crystallization can be excited using UV light. Optical transmission of
SrY2O4:Ce3+ is measured for the first time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4693</id><created>2014-12-15</created><updated>2017-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frasca</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Noncommutative geometry and stochastic processes</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures. Updated a reference. A version of this paper
  will appear in the proceedings of GSI2017, Geometric Science of Information,
  November 7th to 9th, Paris (France)</comments><journal-ref>F. Nielsen and F. Barbaresco (Eds.): GSI 2017, LNCS 10589, pp.
  486-494, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-68445-1_57</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent analysis on noncommutative geometry, showing quantization of the
volume for the Riemannian manifold entering the geometry, can support a view of
quantum mechanics as arising by a stochastic process on it. A class of
stochastic processes can be devised, arising as fractional powers of an
ordinary Wiener process, that reproduce in a proper way a stochastic process on
a noncommutative geometry. These processes are characterized by producing
complex values and so, the corresponding Fokker-Planck equation resembles the
Schroedinger equation. Indeed, by a direct numerical check, one can recover the
kernel of the Schroedinger equation starting by an ordinary Brownian motion.
This class of stochastic processes needs a Clifford algebra to exist. In four
dimensions, the full set of Dirac matrices is needed and the corresponding
stochastic process in a noncommutative geometry is easily recovered as is the
Dirac equation in the Klein-Gordon form being it the Fokker--Planck equation of
the process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.07857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.07857</id><created>2015-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Mryglod</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenna</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holovatch</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Predicting Results of the Research Excellence Framework using
  Departmental h-Index -- Revisited</title><categories>cs.DL physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientometrics 104 (2015) 1013-1017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11192-015-1567-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit our recent study [Predicting results of the Research Excellence
Framework using departmental h-index, Scientometrics, 2014, 1-16;
arXiv:1411.1996] in which we attempted to predict outcomes of the UK's Research
Excellence Framework (REF~2014) using the so-called departmental $h$-index.
Here we report that our predictions failed to anticipate with any accuracy
either overall REF outcomes or movements of individual institutions in the
rankings relative to their positions in the previous Research Assessment
Exercise (RAE~2008).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00238</id><created>2015-03-01</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heydari</keyname><forenames>Hoshang</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric formulation of quantum mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>42 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>K. Sienicki (Ed.), Quantum Mechanics Interpretations, Open
  Academic Press 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum mechanics is among the most important and successful mathematical
model for describing our physical reality. The traditional formulation of
quantum mechanics is linear and algebraic. In contrast classical mechanics is a
geometrical and non-linear theory that is defined on a symplectic manifold.
However, after invention of general relativity, we are convinced that geometry
is physical and effect us in all scale. Hence the geometric formulation of
quantum mechanics sought to give a unified picture of physical systems based on
its underling geometrical structures, e.g., now, the states are represented by
points of a symplectic manifold with a compatible Riemannian metric, the
observables are real-valued functions on the manifold, and the quantum
evolution is governed by a symplectic flow that is generated by a Hamiltonian
function. In this work we will give a compact introduction to main ideas of
geometric formulation of quantum mechanics. We will provide the reader with the
details of geometrical structures of both pure and mixed quantum states. We
will also discuss and review some important applications of geometric quantum
mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03468</id><created>2015-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Barreira</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Baojiu</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jennings</keyname><forenames>Elise</forenames><affiliation>Fermilab and KICP, Chicago</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Merten</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames><affiliation>Oxford</affiliation></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Lindsay</forenames><affiliation>Texas Dallas</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baugh</keyname><forenames>Carlton</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pascoli</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames><affiliation>Durham</affiliation></author></authors><title>Galaxy cluster lensing masses in modified lensing potentials</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>21 pages, 9 figures, 2 tables. Comments welcome</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-15-044-A</report-no><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 454,
  Issue 4, 21 December 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the concentration-mass relation of 19 X-ray selected galaxy
clusters from the CLASH survey in theories of gravity that directly modify the
lensing potential. We model the clusters as NFW haloes and fit their lensing
signal, in the Cubic Galileon and Nonlocal gravity models, to the lensing
convergence profiles of the clusters. We discuss a number of important issues
that need to be taken into account, associated with the use of nonparametric
and parametric lensing methods, as well as assumptions about the background
cosmology. Our results show that the concentration and mass estimates in the
modified gravity models are, within the errorbars, the same as in $\Lambda$CDM.
This result demonstrates that, for the Nonlocal model, the modifications to
gravity are too weak at the cluster redshifts, and for the Galileon model, the
screening mechanism is very efficient inside the cluster radius. However, at
distances $\sim \left[2-20\right] {\rm Mpc}/h$ from the cluster center, we find
that the surrounding force profiles are enhanced by $\sim20-40\%$ in the Cubic
Galileon model. This has an impact on dynamical mass estimates, which means
that tests of gravity based on comparisons between lensing and dynamical masses
can also be applied to the Cubic Galileon model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07452</id><created>2015-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Popova-Gorelova</keyname><forenames>Daria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging instantaneous electron flow with ultrafast resonant x-ray
  scattering</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 184303 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.184303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a novel way to image dynamical properties of nonstationary
electron systems using ultrafast resonant x-ray scattering. Employing a
rigorous theoretical analysis within the framework of quantum electrodynamics,
we demonstrate that a single scattering pattern from a nonstationary electron
system encodes the instantaneous interatomic electron current in addition to
the structural information usually obtained by resonant x-ray scattering from
stationary systems. Thus, inelastic contributions that are indistinguishable
from elastic processes induced by a broadband probe pulse, instead of being a
concern, serve as an advantage for time-resolved resonant x-ray scattering.
Thereby, we propose an approach combining elastic and inelastic resonant x-ray
scattering for imaging dynamics of nonstationary electron systems in both real
space and real time. In order to illustrate its power, we show how it can be
applied to image the electron hole current in an ionized diatomic molecule.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03078</id><created>2015-07-11</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sormani</keyname><forenames>Mattia C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binney</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magorrian</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas flow in barred potentials - III. Effects of varying the Quadrupole</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>accepted for publication in MNRAS. This version corrects a typo in
  the normalization factor that is present in the published version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We run hydrodynamical simulations of a 2D isothermal non self-gravitating
inviscid gas flowing in a rigidly rotating externally imposed potential formed
by only two components: a monopole and a quadrupole. We explore systematically
the effects of varying the quadrupole while keeping fixed the monopole and
discuss the consequences for the interpretation of longitude-velocity diagrams
in the Milky Way. We find that the gas flow can constrain the quadrupole of the
potential and the characteristics of the bar that generates it. The exponential
scale length of the bar must be at least $1.5\rm\, kpc$. The strength of the
bar is also constrained. Our global interpretation favours a pattern speed of
$\Omega=40\,\rm km s^{-1} {kpc}^{-1}$. We find that for most observational
features, there exist a value of the parameters that matches each individual
feature well, but is difficult to reproduce all the important features at once.
Due to the intractably high number of parameters involved in the general
problem, quantitative fitting methods that can run automatic searches in
parameter space are necessary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00046</id><created>2015-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Debabrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum oscillation and wave packet revival in conical graphene
  structure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 89 (2016) 57</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-60907-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present analytical expressions for the eigenstates and eigenvalues of
electrons confined in a graphene monolayer in the presence of a disclination.
The calculations are performed in the continuum limit approximation in the
vicinity of the Dirac points, solving Dirac equation by freezing out the
carrier radial motion. We include the effect of an external magnetic field and
show the appearence of Aharonov-Bohm oscillation and find out the conditions of
gapped and gapless states in the spectrum. We show that the gauge field due to
a disclination lifts the orbital degeneracy originating from the existence of
two valleys. The broken valley degeneracy has a clear signature on quantum
oscillations and wave packet dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06868</id><created>2015-10-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Erms</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Optics near an hyperbolic defect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92 (2015) 063806</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.063806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the properties of a new family of defects called hyperbolic
disclinations, and discuss their possible use for the design of perfect optical
absorbers. In hyperbolic metamaterials, the ratio of ordinary and extraordinary
permittivities is negative, which leads to an effective metric of Kleinian
signature (two timelike coordinates). Considering a disclination in the
hyperbolic nematic host matrix, we show that the timelike geodesics are Poinsot
spirals, i.e. whatever the impact parameter of an incident light beam, it is
confined and whirls about the defect core. The trapping effect does not require
light to be coherent. This property also remains in the wave formalism, which
may be the sign for many potential applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05797</id><created>2015-11-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Mryglod</keyname><forenames>Olesya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holovatch</keyname><forenames>Yurij</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenna</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying the evolution of a scientific topic: reaction of the
  academic community to the Chornobyl disaster</title><categories>cs.DL physics.soc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientometrics 106 (2016) 1151-1166</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11192-015-1820-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the reaction of academic communities to a particular urgent topic
which abruptly arises as a scientific problem. To this end, we have chosen the
disaster that occurred in 1986 in Chornobyl (Chernobyl), Ukraine, considered as
one of the most devastating nuclear power plant accidents in history. The
academic response is evaluated using scientific-publication data concerning the
disaster using the Scopus database to present the picture on an international
scale and the bibliographic database &quot;Ukrainika naukova&quot; to consider it on a
national level. We measured distributions of papers in different scientific
fields, their growth rates and properties of co-authorship networks. {The
elements of descriptive statistics and the tools of the complex network theory
are used to highlight the interdisciplinary as well as international effects.}
Our analysis allows to compare contributions of the international community to
Chornobyl-related research as well as integration of Ukraine in the
international research on this subject. Furthermore, the content analysis of
titles and abstracts of the publications allowed to detect the most important
terms used for description of Chornobyl-related problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08367</id><created>2015-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holovatch</keyname><forenames>Yurij</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kenna</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mryglod</keyname><forenames>Olesya</forenames></author></authors><title>Academic research groups: evaluation of their quality and quality of
  their evaluation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DL</categories><comments>Presented at the International Conference on Computer Simulation in
  Physics and Beyond in Moscow, 2015. The Proceedings will appear in Journal of
  Physics: Conference Series (JPCS)</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 681 (2016) 012004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/681/1/012004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years, evaluation of the quality of academic research has become an
increasingly important and influential business. It determines, often to a
large extent, the amount of research funding flowing into universities and
similar institutes from governmental agencies and it impacts upon academic
careers. Policy makers are becoming increasingly reliant upon, and influenced
by, the outcomes of such evaluations. In response, university managers are
increasingly attracted to simple indicators as guides to the dynamics of the
positions of their various institutions in league tables. However, these league
tables are frequently drawn up by inexpert bodies such as newspapers and
magazines, using rather arbitrary measures and criteria. Terms such as
&quot;critical mass' and &quot;metrics&quot; are often bandied about without proper
understanding of what they actually mean. Rather than accepting the rise and
fall of universities, departments and individuals on a turbulent sea of
arbitrary measures, we suggest it is incumbent upon the scientific community
itself to clarify their nature. Here we report on recent attempts to do that by
properly defining critical mass and showing how group size influences research
quality. We also examine currently predominant metrics and show that these fail
as reliable indicators of group research quality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00011</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Argyres</keyname><forenames>Philip C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotito</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;</keyname><forenames>Yongchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martone</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric constraints on the space of N=2 SCFTs II: Construction of
  special K\&quot;ahler geometries and RG flows</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Completely revised introduction and conclusion reflecting our
  current, deeper, understanding of the topic. Multiple references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second in a series of three papers on systematic analysis of rank
1 Coulomb branch geometries of four dimensional $\mathcal{N}$=2 SCFTs. In the
first paper we developed a strategy for classifying physical rank-1 CB
geometries of $\mathcal{N}$=2 SCFTs. Here we show how to carry out this
strategy computationally to construct the Seiberg-Witten curves and one-forms
for all the rank-1 SCFTs. Explicit expressions are given for all cases, with
the exception of the $N_f$=4 SU(2) gauge theory and the En SCFTs which were
previously constructed. Our classification includes all known rank-1 theories
plus a new one with an abelian flavor group, plus nine additional theories
whose existence is more speculative. Four of those, reported in our first
paper, depend on the assumption of new frozen rank-1 SCFTs. Here we also also
show that the assumption of the existence of certain rank-0 $\mathcal{N}$=2
SCFTs leads to five additional consistent rank-1 CB geometries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01657</id><created>2016-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric effects in the electronic transport of deformed nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Maple code available in pdf format upon request</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27 (2016) 135302</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/13/135302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quasi-two-dimensional systems may exibit curvature, which adds
three-dimensional influence to their internal properties. As shown by da Costa
\cite{dacosta}, charged particles moving on a curved surface experience a
curvature-dependent potential which greatly influence their dynamics. In this
paper, we study the electronic ballistic transport in deformed nanotubes. The
one-electron Schr\&quot;odinger equation with open boundary conditions is solved
numerically with a flexible MAPLE code made available as Supplementary Data. We
find that the curvature of the deformations have indeed strong effects on the
electron dynamics suggesting its use in the design of nanotube-based electronic
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06584</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Erms</forenames></author></authors><title>Propagation of acoustic waves in a von-K\'arm\'an vortex street like
  configuration of disclinations</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 90 (2017) 95</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-70384-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a simple model of 1D array of topological defects in a
crystalline environment is able to guide acoustic waves, depending on the angle
of the incident wave. We comment on a recently proposed geophysical mechanism
explaining the mantle dynamics by the presence, in some crystalline materials
there, of wedge disclinations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04864</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shamailov</keyname><forenames>Sophie S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brand</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark-soliton-like excitations in the Yang-Gaudin gas of attractively
  interacting fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>31 pages, 9 figures. Versions 4 and 5 are identical (up to the
  addition of this comment), and incorporate a corrigendum to the published NJP
  article, now also available on the NJP website. The correction affected the
  last paragraph of section 2.2 and Fig. 2. None of the main results or
  conclusions of the paper are affected</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 075004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/075004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Yrast states are the lowest energy states at given non-zero momentum and
provide a natural extension of the concept of dark solitons to
strongly-interacting one-dimensional quantum gases. Here we study the yrast
states of the balanced spin-$\frac{1}{2}$ Fermi gas with attractive
delta-function interactions in one dimension with the exactly solvable
Yang-Gaudin model. The corresponding Bethe-ansatz equations are solved for
finite particle number and in the thermodynamic limit. Properties corresponding
to the soliton-like nature of the yrast excitations are calculated including
the missing particle number, phase step, and inertial and physical masses. The
inertial to physical mass ratio, which is related to the frequency of
oscillations in a trapped gas, is found to be unity in the limits of strong and
weak attraction and falls to $\approx 0.78$ in the crossover regime. This
result is contrasted by one-dimensional mean field theory, which predicts a
divergent mass ratio in the weakly attractive limit. By means of an exact
mapping our results also predict the existence and properties of
dark-soliton-like excitations in the super Tonks-Girardeau gas. The prospects
for experimental observations are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00903</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00903</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spousta</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>On similarity of jet quenching and charmonia suppression</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, v3 fixes a typo in table 1</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 767 (2017) 10-15</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.01.041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We quantify the magnitude of the parton energy loss in jets in lead-lead
collisions at the LHC. We extract the effective color factor characterizing the
difference between the in-medium radiation of quark-initiated jets and
gluon-initiated jets from the data. Then, we examine the energy loss of prompt
charmonia and we point to a remarkable similarity between the quenching of
light-quark-initiated jets and the prompt charmonia suppression. Finally, we
discuss possible sources of this similarity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05748</id><created>2016-06-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malterre</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge transformations and conserved quantities in classical and quantum
  mechanics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Am. J. Phys. 84 (2016) 616-625</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4955153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are taught that gauge transformations in classical and quantum mechanics
do not change the physics of the problem. Nevertheless here we discuss three
broad scenarios where under gauge transformations: (i) conservation laws are
not preserved in the usual manner; (ii) non-gauge-invariant quantities can be
associated with physical observables; and (iii) there are changes in the
physical boundary conditions of the wave function that render it
non-single-valued. We give worked examples that illustrate these points, in
contrast to general opinions from classic texts. We also give a historical
perspective on the development of Abelian gauge theory in relation to our
particular points. Our aim is to provide a discussion of these issues at the
graduate level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07678</id><created>2016-09-24</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kretchmer</keyname><forenames>Joshua S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>Garnet Kin-Lic</forenames></author></authors><title>A real-time extension of density matrix embedding theory for
  non-equilibrium electron dynamics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce real-time density matrix embedding theory (DMET), a dynamical
quantum embedding theory for computing non-equilibrium electron dynamics in
strongly correlated systems. As in the previously developed static DMET,
real-time DMET partitions the system into an impurity corresponding to the
region of interest coupled to the surrounding environment, which is efficiently
represented by a quantum bath of the same size as the impurity. In this work,
we focus on a single-impurity time-dependent theory as a first step towards a
full multi-impurity theory. The equations of motion of the coupled impurity and
bath embedding problem in real-time DMET are then derived using the
time-dependent variational principle. The accuracy of real-time DMET is
compared to that of time-dependent complete active space self-consistent field
(TD-CASSCF) theory and time-dependent Hartree-Fock (TDHF) theory for a variety
of quantum quenches in the single impurity Anderson model (SIAM), in which the
Hamiltonian is suddenly changed (quenched) to induce a non-equilibrium state.
Real-time DMET shows a marked improvement over the meanfield TDHF, converging
to the exact answer even in the non-trivial Kondo regime of the SIAM. However,
as in static DMET, the increased dynamic flexibility of TD-CASSCF in comparison
to real-time DMET using a single impurity leads to faster convergence with
respect to active space size. Our results demonstrate that real-time DMET is an
efficient method well suited for the simulation of non-equilibrium electron
dynamics in which strong electron correlation plays an important role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08783</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>Akihito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanimura</keyname><forenames>Yoshitaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Heat Current under Non-perturbative and Non-Markovian
  Conditions: Applications to Heat Machines</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, updated in the published version</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Chemical Physics 145, 224105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4971370</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a quantum system strongly coupled to multiple heat baths at
different temperatures. Quantum heat transport phenomena in this system are
investigated using two definitions of the heat current, one in terms of the
system energy, and the other in terms of the bath energy. When we consider
correlations among system-bath interactions (CASBI) -- which have a purely
quantum mechanical origin -- the definition in terms of the bath energy becomes
different. We found that CASBI are necessary to maintain the consistency of the
heat current with thermodynamic laws in the case of strong system-bath
coupling. However, within the context of the quantum master equation approach,
both of these definitions are identical. Through a numerical investigation, we
demonstrate this point for a non-equilibrium spin-boson model and a three-level
heat engine model using the reduced hierarchal equations of motion approach
under strongly coupled and non-Markovian conditions. We observe cyclic behavior
of the heat currents and the work performed by the heat engine,and we find that
their phases depend on the system-bath coupling strength. Through consideration
of the bath heat current, we show that the efficiency of the heat engine
decreases as the strength of the system-bath coupling increases, due to the
CASBI contribution. In the case of a large system-bath coupling, the efficiency
increases further if the bath temperature is decreased, with fixed the ratio of
the bath temperatures, due to the discretized nature of energy eigenstates.
This is also considered to be a unique feature of quantum heat engines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02068</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spacek</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scannapieco</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Bhavin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauskopf</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author></authors><title>Searching For Fossil Evidence of AGN Feedback in WISE-Selected Stripe-82
  Galaxies By Measuring the Thermal Sunyaev-Zel'dovich Effect With the Atacama
  Cosmology Telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ. Updated to
  reflect the final changes made for the published paper. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1601.01330</comments><journal-ref>2017, ApJ 834 102</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/834/2/102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We directly measure the thermal energy of the gas surrounding galaxies
through the thermal Sunyaev-Zel'dovich (tSZ) effect. We perform a stacking
analysis of microwave background images from the Atacama Cosmology Telescope,
around 1179 massive quiescent elliptical galaxies at 0.5 &lt;= z &lt;= 1.0 ('low-z')
and 3274 galaxies at 1.0 &lt;= z &lt;= 1.5 ('high-z'), selected using data from the
Wide-Field Infrared Survey Explorer All-Sky Survey and the Sloan Digital Sky
Survey (SDSS) within the SDSS Stripe-82 field. The gas surrounding these
galaxies is expected to contain energy from past episodes of active galactic
nucleus (AGN) feedback, and after using modeling to subtract undetected
contaminants, we detect a tSZ signal at a significance of 0.9-sigma for our
low-z galaxies and 1.8-sigma for our high-z galaxies. We then include data from
the high-frequency Planck bands for a subset of 227 low-z galaxies and 529
high-z galaxies and find low-z and high-z tSZ detections of 1.0-sigma and
1.5-sigma, respectively. These results indicate an average thermal heating
around these galaxies of 5.6(+5.9/-5.6) x 10^60 erg for our low-z galaxies and
7.0(+4.7/-4.4) x 10^60 erg for our high-z galaxies. Based on simple heating
models, these results are consistent with gravitational heating without
additional heating due to AGN feedback.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04168</id><created>2016-10-13</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Saeed</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xfc;reci</keyname><forenames>Hakan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing role of interactions in synchronization of exciton-polariton
  condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures, updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 105008 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa89a0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical study of synchronization dynamics in incoherently
pumped exciton-polariton condensates in coupled polariton traps. Our analysis
is based on a coupled-mode theory for the generalized Gross-Pitaevskii
equation, which employs an expansion in non-Hermitian, pump-dependent modes
appropriate for the pumped geometry. We find that polariton-polariton and
reservoir-polariton interactions play competing roles and lead to qualitatively
different synchronized phases of the coupled polariton modes as pumping power
is increased. Crucially, these interactions can also act against each other to
hinder synchronization. We map out a phase diagram and discuss the general
characteristics of these phases using a generalized Adler equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05464</id><created>2016-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Peralta</keyname><forenames>Mayra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colmenarez</keyname><forenames>Luis</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic order induced on graphene by Ni/Co proximity effects</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94 (2016) 235407</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We build a tight-binding Hamiltonian describing Co/Ni over graphene,
contemplating ATOP (a Co/Ni atom on top of each Carbon atom of one graphene
sublattice) and HCP (one Co/Ni atom per Graphene plaquette) configurations. For
the ATOP configuration the orbitals involved, for the Co/Ni, are the
$d_{z^2-r^2}$ which most strongly couple to one graphene sublattice and the
$d_{xz}$, $d_{yz}$ orbitals that couple directly to the second sublattice site.
Such configuration is diagonal in pseudo-spin and spin space, yielding electron
doping of the graphene and antiferro-magnetic ordering in the primitive cell in
agreement with DFT calculations. The second, HCP configuration is symmetric in
the graphene sublattices and only involves coupling to the $d_{xz}$, $d_{yz}$
orbitals. The register of the lattices in this case allows for a new coupling
between nearest neighbour sites, generating non-diagonal terms in the
pseudo-spin space and novel spin-kinetic couplings mimicking a spin-orbit
coupling generated by a magnetic coupling. The resulting proximity effect in
this case yields ferromagnetic order in the graphene substrate. We derive the
band structure in the vicinity of the K points for both configurations, the
Bloch wavefunctions and their spin polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06000</id><created>2016-11-18</created><updated>2017-02-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Casal</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Ramos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moro</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Description of the $^{11}$Li$(p,d){^{10}}$Li transfer reaction using
  structure overlaps from a full three-body model</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures. Final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 767 (2017) 307</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.02.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent data on the differential angular distribution for the transfer
reaction $^{11}$Li(p,d)$^{10}$Li at $E/A=5.7$ MeV in inverse kinematics are
analysed within the DWBA reaction framework, using the overlap functions
calculated within a three-body model of $^{11}$Li. The weight of the different
$^{10}$Li configurations in the system's ground state is obtained from the
structure calculations unambiguously. The effect of the $^{9}$Li spin in the
calculated observables is also investigated. We find that, although all the
considered models succeed in reproducing the shape of the data, the magnitude
is very sensitive to the content of $p_{1/2}$ wave in the $^{11}$Li
ground-state wave function. Among the considered models, the best agreement
with the data is obtained when the $^{11}$Li ground state contains a $\sim$31\%
of $p_{1/2}$ wave in the $n$-$^9$Li subsystem. Although this model takes into
account explicitly the splitting of the $1^+$ and $2^+$ resonances due to the
coupling of the $p_{1/2}$ wave to the $3/2^-$ spin of the core, a similar
degree of agreement can be achieved with a model in which the $^{9}$Li spin is
ignored, provided that it contains a similar p-wave content.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07501</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-10-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xd6;vg&#xfc;n</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jusufi</keyname><forenames>Kimet</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable Dyonic Thin-Shell Wormholes in Low-Energy String Theory</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, will appear in Advances in High Energy Physics</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics Volume 2017, 1215254 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2017/1215254</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Considerable attention has been devoted to the wormhole physics in the past
30 years by exploring the possibilities of finding traversable wormholes
without the need of exotic matter. In particular the thin-shell wormhole
formalism has been widely investigated by exploiting the cut-and-paste
technique to merge two space-time regions and, to research the stability of
these wormholes developed by Visser. This method helps us to minimize the
amount of the exotic matter. In this paper we construct a four dimensional,
spherically symmetric, dyonic thin-shell wormhole with electric charge $Q$,
magnetic charge $P$, and dilaton charge $\Sigma$, in the context of
Einstein-Maxwell-dilaton theory. We have applied Darmois-Israel formalism and
the cut-and-paste method by joining together two identical spacetime solutions.
We carry out the dyonic thin-shell wormhole stability analyses by using a
linear barotropic gas, Chaplygin gas, and logarithmic gas for the exotic
matter. It is shown that by choosing suitable parameter values as well as
equation of state parameter, under specific conditions we obtain a stable
dyonic thin-shell wormhole solution. Finally we argue that, the stability
domain of the dyonic thin-shell wormhole can be increased in terms of electric
charge, magnetic charge, and dilaton charge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04066</id><created>2016-12-13</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Sirshendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Subinay</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics in quantum Ising chain driven by inhomogeneous transverse
  magnetization</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2017) 90: 140</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2017-80174-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics caused by transport of transverse magnetization in one
dimensional transverse Ising chain at zero temperature. We observe that a class
of initial states having product structure in fermionic momentum-space and
satisfying certain criteria, produce spatial variation in transverse
magnetization. Starting from such a state, we obtain the transverse
magnetization analytically and then observe its dynamics in presence of a
homogeneous constant field $\Gamma$. In contradiction with general expectation,
whatever be the strength of the field, the magnetization of the system does not
become homogeneous even after infinite time. At each site, the dynamics is
associated with oscillations having two different timescales. The envelope of
the larger timescale oscillation decays algebraically with an exponent which is
invariant for all such special initial states. The frequency of this
oscillation varies differently with external field in ordered and disordered
phases. The local magnetization after infinite time also characterizes the
quantum phase transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08155</id><created>2016-12-24</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lepori</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dell'Anna</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-range topological insulators and weakened bulk-boundary
  correspondence</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 103030 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa84d0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formalize the appearance of new types of insulators in long-range (LR)
fermionic systems. These phases are not included in the &quot;ten-fold way
classification&quot; (TWC) for the short-range (SR) topological insulators. This
conclusion is obtained studying at first specific one-dimensional LR examples,
in particular their phase diagrams and contents in symmetries and entanglement.
The purely long-range phases (LRP) are signaled by the violation of the
area-law for the Von Neumann entropy and by corresponding peculiar
distributions for the entanglement spectrum (ES). The origin of the deviations
from the TWC is analyzed from a more general point of view and in any
dimension. In particular, it is found related with a particular type of
divergences occurring in the spectrum, due to the LR couplings. A satisfying
characterization for the LRP can be achieved at least for one-dimensional
systems, as well as the connected definition of a nontrivial topology, provided
a careful evaluation of the LR contributions. Our results lead to reconsider
the definition of correlation length in LR systems. The same analysis also
allows to infer, at least for one-dimensional models, the weakening of the
bulk-boundary correspondence, due to the important correlations between bulk
and edges, and consequently to clarify the nature of the massive edge states
appearing in the topological LR. The emergence of this peculiar edge structure
is signaled by the bulk ES. The stability of the LRP against finite-size
effects, relevant in current experiments, and against local disorder is
discussed, showing that the latter ingredient can even strengthen the effect of
the LR couplings. Finally, we analyze the entanglement content of the
paradigmatic LR Ising spin chain, inferring again important deviations from the
SR regime, and the limitations of bulk-boundary (tensor-network based)
approaches to classify LR spin models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08532</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miura</keyname><forenames>Tatsuya</forenames></author></authors><title>Overhanging of membranes and filaments adhering to periodic graph
  substrates</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. D 355 (2017), 34--44</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper mathematically studies membranes and filaments adhering to
periodic patterned substrates in a one-dimensional model. The problem is
formulated by the minimizing problem of an elastic energy with a contact
potential on graph substrates. Global minimizers (ground states) are mainly
considered in view of their graph representations. Our main results exhibit
sufficient conditions for the graph representation and examples of situations
where any global minimizer must overhang.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01150</id><created>2017-01-04</created><updated>2017-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertolero</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeo</keyname><forenames>B. T. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Esposito</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Diverse Club: The Integrative Core of Complex Networks</title><categories>q-bio.NC physics.soc-ph</categories><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-01189-w</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A complex system can be represented and analyzed as a network, where nodes
represent the units of the network and edges represent connections between
those units. For example, a brain network represents neurons as nodes and axons
between neurons as edges. In many networks, some nodes have a
disproportionately high number of edges. These nodes also have many edges
between each other, and are referred to as the rich club. In many different
networks, the nodes of this club are assumed to support global network
integration. However, another set of nodes potentially exhibits a connectivity
structure that is more advantageous to global network integration. Here, in a
myriad of different biological and man-made networks, we discover the diverse
club--a set of nodes that have edges diversely distributed across the network.
The diverse club exhibits, to a greater extent than the rich club, properties
consistent with an integrative network function--these nodes are more highly
interconnected and their edges are more critical for efficient global
integration. Moreover, we present a generative evolutionary network model that
produces networks with a diverse club but not a rich club, thus demonstrating
that these two clubs potentially evolved via distinct selection pressures.
Given the variety of different networks that we analyzed--the c. elegans, the
macaque brain, the human brain, the United States power grid, and global air
traffic--the diverse club appears to be ubiquitous in complex networks. These
results warrant the distinction and analysis of two critical clubs of nodes in
all complex systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03966</id><created>2017-01-14</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schick</keyname><forenames>Joseph T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopakumar</keyname><forenames>Abhijith M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappe</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Descriptors for thermal expansion in solids</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>R187</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal expansion in materials can be accurately modeled with careful
anharmonic phonon calculations within density functional theory. However,
because of interest in controlling thermal expansion and the time consumed
evaluating thermal expansion properties of candidate materials, either
theoretically or experimentally, an approach to rapidly identifying materials
with desirable thermal expansion properties would be of great utility. When the
ionic bonding is important in a material, we show that the fraction of crystal
volume occupied by ions, (based upon ionic radii), the mean bond coordination,
and the deviation of bond coordination are descriptors that correlate with the
room-temperature coefficient of thermal expansion for these materials found in
widely accessible databases. Correlation is greatly improved by combining these
descriptors in a multi-dimensional fit. This fit reinforces the physical
interpretation that open space combined with low mean coordination and a
variety of local bond coordinations leads to materials with lower coefficients
of thermal expansion, materials with single-valued local coordination and less
open space have the highest coefficients of thermal expansion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04195</id><created>2017-01-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Um</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Junhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Shuoming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing -Ning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>L. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yum</keyname><forenames>Dahyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Kihwan</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-qubit quantum memory exceeding $10$-minute coherence time</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 11, 646-650 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41566-017-0007-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A long-time quantum memory capable of storing and measuring quantum
information at the single-qubit level is an essential ingredient for practical
quantum computation and com-munication. Recently, there have been remarkable
progresses of increasing coherence time for ensemble-based quantum memories of
trapped ions, nuclear spins of ionized donors or nuclear spins in a solid.
Until now, however, the record of coherence time of a single qubit is on the
order of a few tens of seconds demonstrated in trapped ion systems. The qubit
coherence time in a trapped ion is mainly limited by the increasing magnetic
field fluctuation and the decreasing state-detection efficiency associated with
the motional heating of the ion without laser cooling. Here we report the
coherence time of a single qubit over $10$ minutes in the hyperfine states of a
\Yb ion sympathetically cooled by a \Ba ion in the same Paul trap, which
eliminates the heating of the qubit ion even at room temperature. To reach such
coherence time, we apply a few thousands of dynamical decoupling pulses to
suppress the field fluctuation noise. A long-time quantum memory demonstrated
in this experiment makes an important step for construction of the memory zone
in scalable quantum computer architectures or for ion-trap-based quantum
networks. With further improvement of the coherence time by techniques such as
magnetic field shielding and increase of the number of qubits in the quantum
memory, our demonstration also makes a basis for other applications including
quantum money.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06890</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tirandari</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saaidi</keyname><forenames>Kh.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic inflation in Brans-Dicke gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics B,925, 2017, 403-4014</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.10.017</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We study anisotropic inflation in the Brans-Dicke gravity in the presence of
an abelian gauge field where the gauge field is non-minimally coupled to the
inflaton. We show that the degree of anisotropy, under slow-roll
approximations, is proportional to slow roll parameter of the theory. As
demonstration, we consider the displaced quadratic potential for the inflation.
We do the numerical calculation of the model to investigate the behavior of
anisotropy by changing the parameter in the Brans-Dicke model. We find out
that, the solution is an attractor in the phase space, and anisotropy grows
with number of e-folds. Anisotropy depends on Brans-Dicke parameter, $ \omega
$, initial values of the scalar field and constant parameter of the coupling
function of the scalar field and the abelian gauge field, $ c $. If we consider
upper bound on the number of e-folds from CMB i.e. $ 60 $ e-folds, by
increasing $ \omega $ and $ c $, anisotropy do not have time to exit the
horizon and suppressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00831</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gorban</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karlin</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond Navier--Stokes equations: Capillarity of ideal gas</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Corrected misprints in Eqs (7) and (22), thanks to E. Azadi</comments><journal-ref>Contemporary Physics, 58(1) (2017), 70-90</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00107514.2016.1256123</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The system of Navier--Stokes--Fourier equations is one of the most celebrated
systems of equations in modern science. It describes dynamics of fluids in the
limit when gradients of density, velocity and temperature are sufficiently
small, and loses its applicability when the flux becomes so non-equilibrium
that the changes of velocity, density or temperature on the length compatible
with the mean free path are non-negligible. The question is: how to model such
fluxes? This problem is still open. (Despite the fact that the first `final
equations of motion' modified for analysis of thermal creep in rarefied gas
were proposed by Maxwell in 1879.) There are, at least, three possible answers:
(i) use molecular dynamics with individual particles, (ii) use kinetic
equations, like Boltzmann's equation, or (iii) find a new system of equations
for description of fluid dynamics with better accounting of non-equilibrium
effects. These three approaches work at different scales. We explore the third
possibility using the recent findings of capillarity of internal layers in
ideal gases and of saturation effect in dissipation (there is a limiting
attenuation rate for very short waves in ideal gas and it cannot increase
infinitely). One candidate equation is discussed in more detail, the Korteweg
system proposed in 1901. The main ideas and approaches are illustrated by a
kinetic system for which the problem of reduction of kinetics to fluid dynamics
is analytically solvable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01512</id><created>2017-02-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Xinsheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yuxin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Guangming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Haifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zidan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Realizing and manipulating space-time inversion symmetric topological
  semimetal bands with superconducting quantum circuits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>npj Quantum Materials 2, 60, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41535-017-0062-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have experimentally realized novel space-time inversion (P-T) invariant
Z2-type topological semimetal-bands, via an analogy between the momentum space
and a controllable parameter space in superconducting quantum circuits. By
measuring the whole energy spectrum of system, we imaged clearly an exotic
tunable gapless band structure of topological semimetals. Two topological
quantum phase transitions from a topological semimetal to two kinds of
insulators can be manipulated by continuously tuning the different parameters
in the experimental setup, one of which captures the Z2 topology of the PT
semimetal via merging a pair of nontrivial Z2 Dirac points. Remarkably, the
topological robustness was demonstrated unambiguously, by adding a perturbation
that breaks only the individual T and P symmetries but keeps the joint PT
symmetry. In contrast, when another kind of PT -violated perturbation is
introduced, a topologically trivial insulator gap is fully opened.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02346</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02346</id><created>2017-02-08</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Magyar</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Doorsselaere</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goossens</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized phase mixing: Turbulence-like behaviour from
  unidirectionally propagating MHD waves</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph physics.space-ph</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 14820 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-13660-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of three-dimensional (3D) ideal magnetohydrodynamics
(MHD) simulations on the dynamics of a perpendicularly inhomogeneous plasma
disturbed by propagating Alfv\'enic waves. Simpler versions of this scenario
have been extensively studied as the phenomenon of phase mixing. We show that,
by generalizing the textbook version of phase mixing, interesting phenomena are
obtained, such as turbulence-like behavior and complex current-sheet structure,
a novelty in longitudinally homogeneous plasma excited by unidirectionally
propagating waves. This constitutes an important finding for turbulence-related
phenomena in astrophysics in general, relaxing the conditions that have to be
fulfilled in order to generate turbulent behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04847</id><created>2017-02-15</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Zihao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Codecido</keyname><forenames>Emilio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquez</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Yuanhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heremans</keyname><forenames>Joseph P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myers</keyname><forenames>Roberto C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalable Nernst Thermoelectric Power using a Coiled Galfenol Wire</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, and Supplementary Information</comments><journal-ref>AIP Advances 7, 095017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.5003611</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The Nernst thermopower usually is considered far too weak in most metals for
waste heat recovery. However, its transverse orientation gives it an advantage
over the Seebeck effect on non-flat surfaces. Here, we experimentally
demonstrate the scalable generation of a Nernst voltage in an air-cooled metal
wire coiled around a hot cylinder. In this geometry, a radial temperature
gradient generates an azimuthal electric field in the coil. A Galfenol
(Fe$_{0.85}$Ga$_{0.15}$) wire is wrapped around a cartridge heater, and the
voltage drop across the wire is measured as a function of axial magnetic field.
As expected, the Nernst voltage scales linearly with the length of the wire.
Based on heat conduction and fluid dynamic equations, finite-element method is
used to calculate the temperature gradient across the Galfenol wire and
determine the Nernst coefficient. A giant Nernst coefficient of -2.6
${\mu}$V/KT at room temperature is estimated, in agreement with measurements on
bulk Galfenol. We expect that the giant Nernst effect in Galfenol arises from
its magnetostriction, presumably through enhanced magnon-phonon coupling. Our
results demonstrate the feasibility of a transverse thermoelectric generator
capable of scalable output power from non-flat heat sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06061</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06061</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chin</keyname><forenames>Seungbeom</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Coherence Concurrence and Path distinguishability</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>9 pages, Revtex 4.1; (v3) new analysis on the application of
  generalized coherence concurrence to multi-path interference problems, former
  title &quot;Generalized Coherence Concurrence and Coherence Number&quot;, (v4) minor
  error corrections</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 475302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa908d</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new family of coherence monotones, named the \emph{generalized
coherence concurrence} (or coherence $k$-concurrence), which is an analogous
concept to the generalized entanglement concurrence. The coherence
$k$-concurrence of a state is nonzero if and only if the coherence number (a
recently introduced discrete coherence monotone) of the state is not smaller
than $k$, and a state can be converted to a state with nonzero entanglement
$k$-concurrence via incoherent operations if and only if the state has nonzero
coherence $k$-concurrence. We apply the coherence concurrence family to the
problem of wave-particle duality in multi-path interference phenomena. We
obtain a sharper equation for path distinguishability (which witness the
duality) than the known value and show that the amount of each concurrence for
the quanton state determines the number of slits which are identified
unambiguously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00831</id><created>2017-03-02</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jakov&#xe1;c</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaposv&#xe1;ri</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patk&#xf3;s</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudo-Goldstone excitations in chiral Yukawa-theories with quadratic
  explicit symmetry breaking</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 076018 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.076018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The symmetry breakdown pattern is studied in models containing one fermion
flavor multiplet and a multicomponent scalar field, supplemented with a chiral
Yukawa-interaction, and in presence of an explicit symmetry breaking source
quadratic in the scalar field. In a detailed investigation of the model with
$U_L(1) \times U_R(1)$ chiral symmetry it is shown that by diminishing the
strength of quadratic explicit symmetry breaking one can still keep stable the
mass ratio of the fermionic and the pseudo-Goldstone excitation. At the same
time the mass ratio of the two bosonic excitations appears to approach a
limiting value depending only on the infrared value of the first ratio, but not
on the microscopic (ultraviolet) coupling values. The observations receive a
general interpretation by the existence of an ultraviolet fixed point located
in the symmetric phase. Understanding the general conditions for its existence
allows the construction of a similar theory with $U_L(2) \times U_R(2)$ chiral
symmetry. All results of the present investigation were obtained with
nonperturbative functional renormalisation group technique making use of the
first two approximations to the gradient expansion of the effective action.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02746</id><created>2017-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Protopopov</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gefen</keyname><forenames>Yuval</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirlin</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport in a disordered $\nu=2/3$ fractional quantum Hall junction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 Figures, detailed presentation in Annals of Physics style</comments><journal-ref>Annals of phys. 385, 287 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.07.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electric and thermal transport properties of a $\nu=2/3$ fractional quantum
Hall junction are analyzed. We investigate the evolution of the electric and
thermal two-terminal conductances, $G$ and $G^Q$, with system size $L$ and
temperature $T$. This is done both for the case of strong interaction between
the 1 and 1/ 3 modes (when the low-temperature physics of the interacting
segment of the device is controlled by the vicinity of the strong-disorder
Kane-Fisher-Polchinski fixed point) and for relatively weak interaction, for
which the disorder is irrelevant at $T=0$ in the renormalization-group sense.
The transport properties in both cases are similar in several respects. In
particular, $G(L)$ is close to 4/3 (in units of $e^2/h$) and $G^Q$ to 2 (in
units of $\pi T / 6 \hbar$) for small $L$, independently of the interaction
strength. For large $L$ the system is in an incoherent regime, with $G$ given
by 2/3 and $G^Q$ showing the Ohmic scaling, $G^Q\propto 1/L$, again for any
interaction strength. The hallmark of the strong-disorder fixed point is the
emergence of an intermediate range of $L$, in which the electric conductance
shows strong mesoscopic fluctuations and the thermal conductance is $G^Q=1$.
The analysis is extended also to a device with floating 1/3 mode, as studied in
a recent experiment [A. Grivnin et al, Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 266803 (2014)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05831</id><created>2017-03-16</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guerra</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9; G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Francisco</keyname><forenames>Frederico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gil</keyname><forenames>Paulo J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertolami</keyname><forenames>Orfeu</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimating the thermally induced acceleration of the New Horizons
  spacecraft</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 124027 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.124027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Residual accelerations due to thermal effects are estimated through a model
of the New Horizons spacecraft and a Monte Carlo simulation. We also discuss
and estimate the thermal effects on the attitude of the spacecraft. The work is
based on a method previously used for the Pioneer and Cassini probes, which
solve the Pioneer anomaly problem. The results indicate that after the
encounter with Pluto there is a residual acceleration of the order of
$10^{-9}~\mathrm{m/s^2}$, and that rotational effects should be difficult,
although not impossible, to detect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05933</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zu</keyname><forenames>Qun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Ya-Fang</forenames></author></authors><title>The Unit Cell Reconstruction and Related Thermal Activation Process
  within Coherent Twin Boundary Migration in Magnesium</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By analyzing the interface defect loop nucleation and the interface
disconnection expansion in dynamic simulations, the elementary migration
process of coherent twin boundary of magnesium is identified to be independent
unit cell reconstruction. The atomistic pathways of the unit cell
reconstruction prove their collective behavior as a stochastic response to
thermal fluctuation at a stressed state, and also the onset mechanism of
interface disconnection gliding: predominant pure-shuffle basal-prismatic
transformation along with atomistic shear movements. The athermal shear
strength, the migration barrier, the critical length of disconnection dipole
and other parameters characterizing the thermal activation process are
reported.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07899</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Avalos</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lira</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the proof of the Thin Sandwich Conjecture in arbitrary dimensions</title><categories>gr-qc math.DG</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 58, 102502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4989573</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we show the validity, under certain geometric conditions, of
Wheeler's thin sandwich conjecture for higher dimensional theories of gravity.
We extend the results shown by R. Bartnik and G. Fodor for the 3-dimensional
case in two ways. On the one hand, we show that the results obtained by the
mentioned authors are valid in arbitrary dimensions, and on the other hand we
show that the geometric hypotheses needed for the proofs can always be
satisfied, which constitutes in itself a new result for the 3-dimensional case.
In this way, we show that on any compact n-dimensional manifold, n greater or
equal to 3, there is an open set in the space of all possible initial data
where the thin sandwich problem is well-posed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09212</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barreira</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames><affiliation>MPA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames><affiliation>MPA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Responses in Large-Scale Structure</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages + appendices and references. 5 figures. Comments welcomed</comments><journal-ref>JCAP06(2017)053</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/06/053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a rigorous definition of general power-spectrum responses as
resummed vertices with two hard and $n$ soft momenta in cosmological
perturbation theory. These responses measure the impact of long-wavelength
perturbations on the local small-scale power spectrum. The kinematic structure
of the responses (i.e., their angular dependence) can be decomposed
unambiguously through a &quot;bias&quot; expansion of the local power spectrum, with a
fixed number of physical response coefficients, which are only a function of
the hard wavenumber $k$. Further, the responses up to $n$-th order completely
describe the $(n+2)$-point function in the squeezed limit, i.e. with two hard
and $n$ soft modes, which one can use to derive the response coefficients. This
generalizes previous results, which relate the angle-averaged squeezed limit to
isotropic response coefficients. We derive the complete expression of first-
and second-order responses at leading order in perturbation theory, and present
extrapolations to nonlinear scales based on simulation measurements of the
isotropic response coefficients. As an application, we use these results to
predict the non-Gaussian part of the angle-averaged matter power spectrum
covariance ${\rm Cov}^{\rm NG}_{\ell = 0}(k_1,k_2)$, in the limit where one of
the modes, say $k_2$, is much smaller than the other. Without any free
parameters, our model results are in very good agreement with simulations for
$k_2 \lesssim 0.06\ h/{\rm Mpc}$, and for any $k_1 \gtrsim 2 k_2$. The
well-defined kinematic structure of the power spectrum response also permits a
quick evaluation of the angular dependence of the covariance matrix. While we
focus on the matter density field, the formalism presented here can be
generalized to generic tracers such as galaxies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00010</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>Warren P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kneller</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino Intensity Interferometry: Measuring Proto-neutron Star Radii
  During Core-Collapse Supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 1 ancillary file of derivations. Version updated
  to match PRL publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 051101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.051101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intensity interferometry is a technique that has been used to measure the
size of sources ranging from the quark-gluon plasma formed in heavy ion
collisions to the radii of stars. We investigate using the same technique to
measure proto-neutron star (PNS) radii with the neutrino signal received from a
core-collapse supernovae. Using a full wave-packet analysis, including the
neutrino mass for the first time, we derive criteria where the effect can be
expected to provide the desired signal, and find that neutrinos from the next
Galactic supernova should contain extractable PNS radius information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01283</id><created>2017-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berche</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medina</keyname><forenames>Ernesto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Fernando A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Using torsion to manipulate spin currents</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>EPL 117 (2017) 47007</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/117/47007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the problem of quantum particles moving on a manifold
characterised by the presence of torsion along a preferential axis. In fact,
such a torsion may be taylored by the presence of a single screw dislocation,
whose Burgers vector measures the torsion amplitude. The problem, first treated
in the relativistic limit describing fermions that couple minimally to torsion,
is then analysed in the Pauli limit We show that torsion induces a geometric
potential and also that it couples generically to the phase of the wave
function, giving rise to the possibility of using torsion to manipulate spin
currents in the case of spinor wave functions. These results emerge as an
alternative strategy for using screw dislocations in the design of
spintronic-based devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03685</id><created>2017-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Mortazavi</keyname><forenames>Bohayra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lherbier</keyname><forenames>Aur&#xe9;lien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Zheyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harju</keyname><forenames>Ari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabczuk</keyname><forenames>Timon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charlier</keyname><forenames>Jean-Christophe</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal and electronic transport characteristics of highly stretchable
  graphene kirigami</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>29 pages, 9 figures, 1 supplementary figure</comments><journal-ref>Nanoscale, 2017, 9, 16329 - 16341</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7NR05231F</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For centuries, cutting and folding the papers with special patterns have been
used to build beautiful, flexible and complex three-dimensional structures.
Inspired by the old idea of kirigami (paper cutting), and the outstanding
properties of graphene, recently graphene kirigami structures were fabricated
to enhance the stretchability of graphene. However, the possibility of further
tuning the electronic and thermal transport along the 2D kirigami structures
have remained original to investigate. We therefore performed extensive
atomistic simulations to explore the electronic, heat and load transfer along
various graphene kirigami structures. The mechanical response and thermal
transport were explored using classical molecular dynamics simulations. We then
used a real-space Kubo-Greenwood formalism to investigate the charge transport
characteristics in graphene kirigami. Our results reveal that graphene kirigami
structures present highly anisotropic thermal and electrical transport.
Interestingly, we show the possibility of tuning the thermal conductivity of
graphene by four orders of magnitude. Moreover, we discuss the engineering of
kirigami patterns to further enhance their stretchability by more than 10 times
as compared with pristine graphene. Our study not only provides a general
understanding concerning the engineering of electronic, thermal and mechanical
response of graphene but more importantly can be useful to guide future studies
with respect to the synthesis of other 2D material kirigami structures, to
reach highly flexible and stretchable nanostructures with finely tunable
electronic and thermal properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07561</id><created>2017-04-25</created><updated>2017-09-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Lijing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sennett</keyname><forenames>Noah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buonanno</keyname><forenames>Alessandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wex</keyname><forenames>Norbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining nonperturbative strong-field effects in scalar-tensor
  gravity by combining pulsar timing and laser-interferometer
  gravitational-wave detectors</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures; accepted by Physical Review X</comments><report-no>LIGO-P1700073</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 041025 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.041025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pulsar timing and gravitational-wave (GW) detectors are superb laboratories
to study gravity theories in the strong-field regime. Here we combine those
tools to test the mono-scalar-tensor theory of Damour and Esposito-Far{\`e}se
(DEF), which predicts nonperturbative scalarization phenomena for neutron stars
(NSs). First, applying Markov-chain Monte Carlo techniques, we use the absence
of dipolar radiation in the pulsar-timing observations of five binary systems
composed of a NS and a white dwarf, and eleven equations of state (EOSs) for
NSs, to derive the most stringent constraints on the two free parameters of the
DEF scalar-tensor theory. Since the binary-pulsar bounds depend on the NS mass
and the EOS, we find that current pulsar-timing observations leave
scalarization windows, i.e., regions of parameter space where scalarization can
still be prominent. Then, we investigate if these scalarization windows could
be closed and if pulsar-timing constraints could be improved by
laser-interferometer GW detectors, when spontaneous (or dynamical)
scalarization sets in during the early (or late) stages of a binary NS (BNS)
evolution. For the early inspiral of a BNS carrying constant scalar charge, we
employ a Fisher matrix analysis to show that Advanced LIGO can improve
pulsar-timing constraints for some EOSs, and next-generation detectors, such as
the Cosmic Explorer and Einstein Telescope, will be able to improve those
bounds for all eleven EOSs. Using the late inspiral of a BNS, we estimate that
for some of the EOSs under consideration the onset of dynamical scalarization
can happen early enough to improve the constraints on the DEF parameters
obtained by combining the five binary pulsars. Thus, in the near future the
complementarity of pulsar timing and direct observations of GWs on the ground
will be extremely valuable in probing gravity theories in the strong-field
regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01555</id><created>2017-05-03</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bj&#xf6;rkeroth</keyname><forenames>Fredrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Anda</keyname><forenames>Francisco J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Stephen F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdomo</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>A natural $ S_4 \times SO(10) $ model of flavour</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 4 figures. Matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 10 (2017) 148</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2017)148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a natural $ S_4 \times SO(10) $ supersymmetric grand unified
theory of flavour with an auxiliary $\mathbb{Z}_4^2 \times \mathbb{Z}_4^R$
symmetry, based on small Higgs representations (nothing larger than an adjoint)
and hence a type-I seesaw mechanism. The Yukawa structure of all fermions is
determined by the hierarchical vacuum expectation values of three $ S_4 $
triplet flavons, with CSD3 vacuum alignments, where up-type quarks and
neutrinos couple to one Higgs $\mathbf{10}$, and the down-type quarks and
charged leptons couple to a second Higgs $\mathbf{10}$. The Yukawa matrices are
obtained from sums of low-rank matrices, where each matrix in the sum naturally
accounts for the mass of a particular family, as in sequential dominance in the
neutrino sector, which predicts a normal neutrino mass hierarchy. The model
accurately fits all available quark and lepton data, with predictions for the
leptonic $CP$ phase in 95$\%$ credible intervals given by $ 281^\circ &lt;
\delta^\ell &lt; 308^\circ $ and $ 225^\circ &lt; \delta^\ell &lt; 253^\circ $. The
model reduces to the MSSM, with the two Higgs doublets emerging from the two
Higgs $\mathbf{10}$s without mixing, and we demonstrate how a $\mu$ term of
$\mathcal{O}$(TeV) can be realised, as well as doublet-triplet splitting, with
Planck scale operators controlled by symmetry, leading to acceptable proton
decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06841</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konishi</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouscal</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yagami</keyname><forenames>Tomoya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Yoshiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin dependent inelastic collisions between metastable state
  two-electron atoms and ground state alkali-atoms</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 103039 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa8cec</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimentally the spin dependence of inelastic collisions between ytterbium
(Yb) in the metastable 3P0 state and lithium (Li) in the Li ground state
manifold is investigated at low magnetic fields. Using selective excitation all
magnetic sublevels mJ of 174Yb(3P0) are accessed and four of the six lowest
lying magnetic sublevels of 6Li are prepared by optical pumping. On the one
hand, mJ-independence of collisions involving Li(F=1/2) atoms is found. A
systematic mJ-dependence in collisions with Li(F=3/2) atoms, in particular
suppressed losses for stretched collisional states, is observed on the other
hand. Further, mJ-changing processes are found to be of minor relevance. The
span of observed inelastic collision rates is between 1*10^{-11} cm^3/s and
40*10^{-11} cm^3/s, and a possible origin of the observed behavior is
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07525</id><created>2017-05-21</created><updated>2017-09-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borzou</keyname><forenames>Ahmad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cleaver</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirza</keyname><forenames>Behrouz</forenames></author></authors><title>Lorentz Gauge Theory of Gravity in Electron Positron Colliders</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in CQG</comments><journal-ref>Classical and Quantum Gravity, 34 (2017) 225013</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/aa8f7c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lorentz gauge theory (LGT) is a feasible candidate for theory of quantum
gravity in which routine field theory calculations can be carried out
perturbatively without encountering too many divergences. In LGT spin of matter
also gravitates. The spin-generated gravity is expected to be extremely
stronger than that generated by mass and could be explored in current
colliders. In this article the observable signals of the theory in an
electron-positron collider is investigated. We specifically study pair
annihilation into two gravitons, and LGT corrections to processes like
$e^-+e^+\rightarrow \mu^-+\mu^+$ and $e^-+e^+\rightarrow e^-+e^+$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09102</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09102</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bisset</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serafini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iseni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbiero</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bienaim&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamporesi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalfovo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observation of a Spinning Top in a Bose-Einstein Condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 053605 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.053605</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boundaries strongly affect the behavior of quantized vortices in
Bose-Einstein condensates, a phenomenon particularly evident in elongated
cigar-shaped traps where vortices tend to orient along a short direction to
minimize energy. Remarkably, contributions to the angular momentum of these
vortices are tightly confined to the region surrounding the core, in stark
contrast to untrapped condensates where all atoms contribute $\hbar$. We
develop a theoretical model and use this, in combination with numerical
simulations, to show that such localized vortices precess in an analogous
manner to that of a classical spinning top. We experimentally verify this
spinning-top behavior with our real-time imaging technique that allows for the
tracking of position and orientation of vortices as they dynamically evolve.
Finally, we perform an in-depth numerical investigation of our real-time
expansion and imaging method, with the aim of guiding future experimental
implementation, as well as outlining directions for its improvement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10775</id><created>2017-05-30</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhuk</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chopovsky</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fakhr</keyname><forenames>Seyed Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shulga</keyname><forenames>Valerii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak-field limit of Kaluza-Klein models with spherically symmetric
  static scalar field: observational constraints</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2017) 77: 721</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5311-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a multidimensional Kaluza-Klein model with Ricci-flat internal space, we
study the gravitational field in the weak-field limit. This field is created by
two coupled sources. First, this is a point-like massive body which has a
dust-like equation of state in the external space and an arbitrary parameter
$\Omega$ of equation of state in the internal space. The second source is a
static spherically symmetric massive scalar field centered at the origin where
the point-like massive body is. The found perturbed metric coefficients are
used to calculate the parameterized post-Newtonian (PPN) parameter $\gamma$. We
define under which conditions $\gamma$ can be very close to unity in accordance
with the relativistic gravitational tests in the Solar system. This can take
place for both massive or massless scalar fields. For example, to have $\gamma
\approx 1$ in the Solar system, the mass of scalar field should be $\mu \gtrsim
5.05\times 10^{-49}$g $\sim 2.83\times 10^{-16}$eV. In all cases, we arrive at
the same conclusion that to be in agreement with the relativistic gravitational
tests, the gravitating mass should have tension: $\Omega=-1/2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01060</id><created>2017-06-04</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Faustov</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynenko</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynenko</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorokin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative nonrecoil nuclear finite size corrections of order $\alpha(Z
  \alpha)^5$ to the Lamb shift in light muonic atoms</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 Figure</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the basis of quasipotential method in quantum electrodynamics we calculate
nuclear finite size radiative corrections of order $\alpha(Z \alpha)^5$ to the
Lamb shift in muonic hydrogen and helium. To construct the interaction
potential of particles, which gives the necessary contributions to the energy
spectrum, we use the method of projection operators to states with a definite
spin. Separate analytic expressions for the contributions of the muon
self-energy, the muon vertex operator and the amplitude with spanning photon
are obtained. We present also numerical results for these contributions using
modern experimental data on the electromagnetic form factors of light nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02111</id><created>2017-06-07</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Bellido</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesseris</keyname><forenames>Savvas</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational wave bursts from Primordial Black Hole hyperbolic
  encounters</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures, changes match published version</comments><report-no>IFT-UAM/CSIC-17-049</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Dark Univ., 18 (2017) 123-126</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.dark.2017.10.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose that Gravitational Wave (GW) bursts with millisecond durations can
be explained by the GW emission from the hyperbolic encounters of Primordial
Black Holes in dense clusters. These bursts are single events, with the bulk of
the released energy happening during the closest approach, and emitted in
frequencies within the AdvLIGO sensitivity range. We provide expressions for
the shape of the GW emission in terms of the peak frequency and amplitude, and
estimate the rates of these events for a variety of mass and velocity
configurations. We study the regions of parameter space that will allow
detection by both AdvLIGO and, in the future, LISA. We find for realistic
configurations, with total mass $M\sim60\,M_\odot$, relative velocities $v\sim
0.01\,c$, and impact parameters $b\sim10^{-3}$ AU, for AdvLIGO an expected
event rate is ${\cal O}(10)$ events/yr/Gpc$^3$ with millisecond durations. For
LISA, the typical duration is in the range of minutes to hours and the
event-rate is ${\cal O}(10^3)$ events/yr/Gpc$^3$ for both $10^3\,M_\odot$ IMBH
and $10^6\,M_\odot$ SMBH encounters. We also study the distribution functions
of eccentricities, peak frequencies and characteristic timescales that can be
expected for a population of scattering PBH with a log-normal distribution in
masses, different relative velocities and a flat prior on the impact parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02738</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berthier</keyname><forenames>Ludovic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charbonneau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flenner</keyname><forenames>Elijah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zamponi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of ultrastability in vapor-deposited glasses</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Five pages and five figures. Data relevant to this work have been
  archived and can be accessed at https://doi.org/10.7924/G8P26W5G</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 188002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.188002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Glass films created by vapor-depositing molecules onto a substrate can
exhibit properties similar to those of ordinary glasses aged for thousands of
years. It is believed that enhanced surface mobility is the mechanism that
allows vapor deposition to create such exceptional glasses, but it is unclear
how this effect is related to the final state of the film. Here we use
molecular dynamics simulations to model vapor deposition and an efficient Monte
Carlo algorithm to determine the deposition rate needed to create ultra-stable
glassy films. We obtain a scaling relation that quantitatively captures the
efficiency gain of vapor deposition over bulk annealing, and demonstrates that
surface relaxation plays the same role in the formation of vapor-deposited
glasses as bulk relaxation does in ordinary glass formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00886</id><created>2017-07-04</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Meng-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong-Sheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational Wave Detection via Weak Measurements Amplification</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>Part I of series work, Comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A universal amplification scheme of ultra-small phase based on weak
measurements is given and a weak measurements amplification based laser
interferometer gravitational-wave observatory (WMA-LIGO) is suggested. The
WMA-LIGO has potential to amplify the ultra-small phase signal to at least
$10^{3}$ order of magnitude such that the sensitivity and bandwidth of
gravitational-wave detector can be further improved. Our results not only shed
a new light on the quantum measurement but also open a new way to the
gravitational-wave detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01073</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01073</id><created>2017-07-04</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bertini</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tartaglia</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Quench in the Infinitely Repulsive Hubbard Model: the Stationary
  State</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>23 pages, 2 figures. This is an author-created, un-copyedited version
  of an article published in Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and
  Experiment. IOP Publishing Ltd is not responsible for any errors or omissions
  in this version of the manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version
  of Record is available online at https://doi.org/10.1088/1742-5468/aa8c2c</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 103107</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa8c2c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the Quench Action approach to study the non-equilibrium dynamics after
a quantum quench in the Hubbard model in the limit of infinite interaction. We
identify a variety of low-entangled initial states for which we can directly
compute the overlaps with the Hamiltonian's eigenstates. For these initial
states, we analytically find the rapidity distributions of the stationary state
characterising the expectation values of all local observables. Some of the
initial states considered are not reflection symmetric and lead to
non-symmetric rapidity distributions. To study such cases, we have to introduce
a generalised form for the reduced entropy which measures the entropy
restricted to states with non-zero overlap. The initial states considered are
of direct experimental realisability and also represent ideal candidates for
studying non-equilibrium dynamics in the Hubbard model for finite interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01669</id><created>2017-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Blind</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coarer</keyname><forenames>E. Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kern</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gousset</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectrographs for astrophotonics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>29 pages, 17 figures; accepted for publication in Optics Express,
  feature issue &quot;Recent Advances in Astrophotonics&quot;</comments><doi>10.1364/OE.25.027341</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The next generation of Extremely Large Telescopes (ELT), with diameters up to
39 meters, is planned to begin operation in the next decade and promises new
challenges in the development of instruments since the instrument size
increases in proportion to the telescope diameter D, and the cost as D2 or
faster. The growing field of astrophotonics (the use of photonic technologies
in astronomy) could solve this problem by allowing mass production of fully
integrated and robust instruments combining various optical functions, with the
potential to reduce the size, complexity and cost of instruments.
Astrophotonics allows for a broad range of new optical functions, with
applications ranging from sky background filtering, high spatial and spectral
resolution imaging and spectroscopy. In this paper, we want to provide
astronomers with valuable keys to understand how photonics solutions can be
implemented (or not) according to the foreseen applications. The paper
introduces first key concepts linked to the characteristics of photonics
technologies, placed in the framework of astronomy and spectroscopy. We then
describe a series of merit criteria that help us determine the potential of a
given micro-spectrograph technology for astronomy applications, and then take
an inventory of the recent developments in integrated micro-spectrographs with
potential for astronomy. We finally compare their performance, to finally draw
a map of typical science requirements and pin the identified integrated
technologies on it. We finally emphasize the necessary developments that must
support micro-spectrograph in the coming years.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02295</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Lyubchyk</keyname><forenames>Olena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kontar</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voitenko</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melrose</keyname><forenames>Donald</forenames></author></authors><title>Solar plasma radio emission in the presence of imbalanced turbulence of
  kinetic-scale Alfv\'en waves</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in Solar Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-017-1140-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the influence of kinetic-scale Alfv\'enic turbulence on the
generation of plasma radio emission in the solar coronal regions where the
plasma/magnetic pressure ratio $\beta $ is smaller than the electron/ion mass
ratio $m_{e}/m_{i}$. The present study is motivated by the phenomenon of solar
type I radio storms associated with the strong magnetic field of active
regions. The measured brightness temperature of the type I storms can be up to
$10^{10}$ K for continuum emission, and can exceed $10^{11}$ K for type I
bursts. At present, there is no generally accepted theory explaining such high
brightness temperatures and some other properties of the type I storms. We
propose the model with the imbalanced turbulence of kinetic-scale Alfv\'en
waves producing an asymmetric quasilinear plateau on the upward half of the
electron velocity distribution. The Landau damping of resonant Langmuir waves
is suppressed and their amplitudes grow spontaneously above the thermal level.
The estimated saturation level of Langmuir waves is high enough to generate
observed type I radio emission at the fundamental plasma frequency. Harmonic
emission does not appear in our model because the backward-propagating Langmuir
waves undergo a strong Landau damping. Our model predicts $100\%$ polarization
in the sense of the ordinary (o-) mode of type I emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02694</id><created>2017-07-10</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasai</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miura</keyname><forenames>Yoshio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hono</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant interfacial perpendicular magnetic anisotropy in
  Fe/CuIn$_{1-x}$Ga$_x$Se$_2$ beyond Fe/MgO</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 174401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.174401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study interfacial magnetocrystalline anisotropies in various
Fe/semiconductor heterostructures by means of first-principles calculations. We
find that many of those systems show perpendicular magnetic anisotropy (PMA)
with a positive value of the interfacial anisotropy constant $K_{\rm i}$. In
particular, the Fe/CuInSe$_2$ interface has a large $K_{\rm i}$ of $\sim
2.3\,{\rm mJ/m^2}$, which is about 1.6 times larger than that of Fe/MgO known
as a typical system with relatively large PMA. We also find that the values of
$K_{\rm i}$ in almost all the systems studied in this work follow the
well-known Bruno's relation, which indicates that minority-spin states around
the Fermi level provide dominant contributions to the interfacial
magnetocrystalline anisotropies. Detailed analyses of the local density of
states and wave-vector-resolved anisotropy energy clarify that the large
$K_{\rm i}$ in Fe/CuInSe$_2$ is attributed to the preferable $3d$-orbital
configurations around the Fermi level in the minority-spin states of the
interfacial Fe atoms. Moreover, we have shown that the locations of interfacial
Se atoms are the key for such orbital configurations of the interfacial Fe
atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05281</id><created>2017-07-17</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aggarwal</keyname><forenames>Priya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Anubha</forenames></author></authors><title>Double Temporal Sparsity Based Accelerated Reconstruction in Compressed
  Sensing fMRI</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Computers in Biology and Medicine. This
  manuscript should be cited with details of journal citation provided below</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Biol. Med. 91 (2017) 255-266</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.compbiomed.2017.10.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A number of reconstruction methods have been proposed recently for
accelerated functional Magnetic Resonance Imaging (fMRI) data collection.
However, existing methods suffer with the challenge of greater artifacts at
high acceleration factors. This paper addresses the issue of accelerating fMRI
collection via undersampled k-space measurements combined with the proposed
Double Temporal Sparsity based Reconstruction (DTSR) method with the l1 -l1
norm constraint. The robustness of the proposed DTSR method has been thoroughly
evaluated both at the subject level and at the group level on real fMRI data.
Results are presented at various acceleration factors. Quantitative analysis in
terms of Peak Signal-to-Noise Ratio (PSNR) and other metrics, and qualitative
analysis in terms of reproducibility of brain Resting State Networks (RSNs)
demonstrate that the proposed method is accurate and robust. In addition, the
proposed DTSR method preserves brain networks that are important for studying
fMRI data. Compared to the existing accelerated fMRI reconstruction methods,
the DTSR method shows promising potential with an improvement of 10-12dB in
PSNR with acceleration factors upto 3.5. Simulation results on real data
demonstrate that DTSR method can be used to acquire accelerated fMRI with
accurate detection of RSNs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06306</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Trifunovic</keyname><forenames>Luka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brouwer</keyname><forenames>Piet</forenames></author></authors><title>Bott periodicity for the topological classification of gapped states of
  matter with reflection symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 195109 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.195109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a dimensional reduction scheme based on scattering theory, we show that
the classification tables for topological insulators and superconductors with
reflection symmetry can be organized in two period-two and four period-eight
cycles, similar to the Bott periodicity found for topological insulators and
superconductors without spatial symmetries. With the help of the dimensional
reduction scheme the classification in arbitrary dimensions $d \ge 1$ can be
obtained from the classification in one dimension, for which we present a
derivation based on relative homotopy groups and exact sequences to classify
one-dimensional insulators and superconductors with reflection symmetry. The
resulting classification is fully consistent with a comprehensive
classification obtained recently by Shiozaki and Sato [Phys.\ Rev.\ B {\bf 90},
165114 (2014)]. The use of a scattering-matrix inspired method allows us to
address the second descendant $\bZ_2$ phase, for which the topological
nontrivial phase was previously reported to be vulnerable to perturbations that
break translation symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08969</id><created>2017-07-27</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armata</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calajo</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaako</keyname><forenames>Tuomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Harvesting Multiqubit Entanglement from Ultrastrong Interactions in
  Circuit Quantum Electrodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 183602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.183602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze a multiqubit circuit QED system in the regime where the
qubit-photon coupling dominates over the system's bare energy scales. Under
such conditions a manifold of low-energy states with a high degree of
entanglement emerges. Here we describe a time-dependent protocol for extracting
these quantum correlations and converting them into well-defined multipartite
entangled states of noninteracting qubits. Based on a combination of various
ultrastrong-coupling effects, the protocol can be operated in a fast and robust
manner, while still being consistent with experimental constraints on switching
times and typical energy scales encountered in superconducting circuits.
Therefore, our scheme can serve as a probe for otherwise inaccessible
correlations in strongly coupled circuit QED systems. It also shows how such
correlations can potentially be exploited as a resource for entanglement-based
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09620</id><created>2017-07-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Schilling</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoop</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lotsch</keyname><forenames>B. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dressel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pronin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Flat optical conductivity in ZrSiS due to two-dimensional Dirac bands</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 187401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.187401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ZrSiS exhibits a frequency-independent interband conductivity $\sigma(\omega)
= \rm{const}(\omega) \equiv \sigma_{\rm{flat}}$ in a broad range from 250 to
2500 cm$^{-1}$ (30 - 300 meV). This makes ZrSiS similar to
(quasi)two-dimensional Dirac electron systems, such as graphite and graphene.
We assign the flat optical conductivity to the transitions between
quasi-two-dimensional Dirac bands near the Fermi level. In contrast to
graphene, $\sigma_{\rm{flat}}$ is not supposed to be universal but related to
the length of the nodal line in the reciprocal space, $k_{0}$. When
$\sigma_{\rm{flat}}$ and $k_{0}$ are connected by a simple model, we find good
agreement between experiment and theory. Due to the spin-orbit coupling, the
discussed Dirac bands in ZrSiS possess a small gap $\Delta$, for which we
determine an upper bound max($\Delta$) = 30 meV from our optical measurements.
At low temperatures the momentum-relaxation rate collapses, and the
characteristic length scale of momentum relaxation is of the order of microns
below 50 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.00019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.00019</id><created>2017-07-31</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shoom</keyname><forenames>Andrey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Metamorphoses of a photon sphere</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 084056 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.084056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are circular planar null geodesics at $r=3M$ around a Schwarzschild
black hole of mass $M$. These geodesics form a photon sphere. Null geodesics of
the Schwarzschild space-time which do not form the photon sphere are either
escape to null infinity or get captured by the black hole. Thus, from the
dynamical point of view, the photon sphere represents a smooth basin boundary
that separates the basins of escape and capture of the dynamical system
governing the null geodesics. Here we consider a Schwarzschild black hole
distorted by an external, static, and axisymmetric quadrupolar gravitational
field. We study null geodesics around such a black hole and show that the
photon sphere transforms into a fractal basin boundary that indicates chaotic
behavior of the null geodesics. We calculate the box-counting fractal dimension
of the basin boundary and the related uncertainty exponent, which depend on the
value of the quadrupole moment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.02764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.02764</id><created>2017-08-09</created><updated>2017-10-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bayar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debastiani</keyname><forenames>V. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>$a_0(980) - f_0(980)$ mixing in $\chi_{c1} \to \pi^0 f_0(980) \to \pi^0
  \pi^+ \pi^-$ and $\chi_{c1} \to \pi^0 a_0(980) \to \pi^0 \pi^0 \eta$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>revised manuscript, new figures, new references; 8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 775, 94 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.10.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the isospin breaking in the reactions $\chi_{c1} \to \pi^0 \pi^+
\pi^-$ and $\chi_{c1} \to \pi^0 \pi^0 \eta$ and its relation to the $a_0(980) -
f_0(980)$ mixing, which was measured by the BESIII Collaboration. We show that
the same theoretical model previously developed to study the $\chi_{c1} \to
\eta \pi^+ \pi^-$ reaction (also measured by BESIII), and further explored in
the predictions to the $\eta_{c} \to \eta \pi^+ \pi^-$, can be successfully
employed in the present study. We assume that the $\chi_{c1}$ behaves as an
$SU(3)$ singlet to find the weight in which trios of pseudoscalars are created,
followed by the final state interaction of pairs of mesons to describe how the
$a_0(980)$ and $f_0(980)$ are dynamically generated, using the chiral unitary
approach in coupled channels. The isospin violation is introduced through the
use of different masses for the charged and neutral kaons, either in the
propagators of the pairs of mesons created in the $\chi_{c1}$ decay, or in the
propagators inside the $T$ matrix, constructed through the unitarization of the
scattering and transition amplitudes of pairs of pseudoscalar mesons. We find
that violating isospin inside the $T$ matrix makes the $\pi^0\eta \to
\pi^+\pi^-$ amplitude nonzero, which gives an important contribution and also
enhances the effect of the $K\bar{K}$ term. Also, we find that in the total
amplitude the most important effect is the isospin breaking inside the $T$
matrix, due to the constructive sum of $\pi^0\eta \to \pi^+\pi^-$ and $K\bar{K}
\to \pi^+ \pi^-$, which is essential to get a good agreement with the
experimental measurement of the mixing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.03086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.03086</id><created>2017-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsumura</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Takayoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanida</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sera</keyname><forenames>Masafumi</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature-Dependent Cycloidal Magnetic Structure in
  GdRu$_{2}$Al$_{10}$ Studied by Resonant X-ray Diffraction</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 094709 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.094709</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed resonant X-ray diffraction experiments on the
antiferromagnet GdRu$_{2}$Al$_{10}$ and have clarified that the magnetic
structure in the ordered state is cycloidal with the moments lying in the $bc$
plane and propagating along the $b$ axis. The propagation vector shows a
similar temperature dependence to the magnetic order parameter, which can be
interpreted as being associated with the gap opening in the conduction band and
the resultant change in the magnetic exchange interaction. Although the $S=7/2$
state of Gd is almost isotropic, the moments show slight preferential ordering
along the $b$ axis. The $c$ axis component in the cycloid develops with
decreasing temperature through a tiny transition in the ordered phase. We also
show that the scattering involves the $\sigma$-$\sigma'$ process, which is
forbidden in normal $E1$-$E1$ resonance of magnetic dipole origin. We discuss
the possibility of the $E1$-$E2$ resonance originating from a toroidal moment
due to the lack of inversion symmetry at the Gd site. The spin-flop transition
in a magnetic field is also described in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.00414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.00414</id><created>2017-09-01</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Milton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Stuart L.</forenames></author></authors><title>GRMHD simulations of prompt-collapse neutron star mergers: the absence
  of jets</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 084063 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.084063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspiraling and merging binary neutron stars are not only important source of
gravitational waves, but also promising candidates for coincident
electromagnetic counterparts. These systems are thought to be progenitors of
short gamma-ray bursts (sGRBs). We have shown previously that binary neutron
star mergers that undergo {\it delayed} collapse to a black hole surrounded by
a {\it weighty} magnetized accretion disk can drive magnetically-powered jets.
We now perform magnetohydrodynamic simulations in full general relativity of
binary neutron stars mergers that undergo {\it prompt} collapse to explore the
possibility of jet formation from black hole-{\it light} accretion disk
remnants. We find that after $t-t_{\rm BH}\sim 26(M_{\rm NS}/1.8M_\odot)$ms
[$M_{\rm NS}$ is the ADM mass] following prompt black hole formation, there is
no evidence of mass outflow or magnetic field collimation. The rapid formation
of the black hole following merger prevents magnetic energy from approaching
force-free values above the magnetic poles, which is required for the launching
of a jet by the usual Blandford--Znajek mechanism. Detection of gravitational
waves in coincidence with sGRBs may provide constraints on the nuclear equation
of state (EOS): the fate of an NSNS merger--delayed or prompt collapse, and
hence the appearance or nonappearance of an sGRB--depends on a critical value
of the total mass of the binary, and this value is sensitive to the EOS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.01163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.01163</id><created>2017-08-31</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mistry</keyname><forenames>Ravi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>Sudhaker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Ahmed Farag</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author></authors><title>Hawking Radiation Power Equations for Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures, Accepted in Nucl. Phys. B, amended</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys. B923 (2017) 378-393</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.08.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the Hawking radiation power equations for black holes in
asymptotically flat, asymptotically Anti-de Sitter (AdS) and asymptotically de
Sitter (dS) black holes, This is done by using the greybody factor for these
black holes. We observe that the radiation power equation for asymptotically
flat black holes, corresponding to greybody factor at low frequency, depends on
both the Hawking temperature and the horizon radius. However, for the greybody
factors at asymptotic frequency, it only depends on the Hawking temperature. We
also obtain the power equation for asymptotically AdS black holes both below
and above the critical frequency. The radiation power equation for at
asymptotic frequency is same for both Schwarzschild AdS and
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om AdS solutions and only depends on the Hawking temperature.
We also discuss the power equation for asymptotically dS black holes at low
frequency, for both even or odd dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.01925</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.01925</id><created>2017-09-06</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Connor</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donahue</keyname><forenames>Megan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelson</keyname><forenames>Daniel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moustakas</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coe</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postman</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bradley</keyname><forenames>Larry D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koekemoer</keyname><forenames>Anton M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchior</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umetsu</keyname><forenames>Keiichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voit</keyname><forenames>G. Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Crowded Field Galaxy Photometry: Precision Colors in the CLASH Clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>24 pages, 13 figures. Published in ApJ, 2017</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J.848:37,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa8ad5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new method for photometering objects in galaxy clusters. We
introduce a mode-filtering technique for removing spatially variable
backgrounds, improving both detection and photometric accuracy (roughly halving
the scatter in the red sequence compared to previous catalogs of the same
clusters). This method is based on robustly determining the distribution of
background pixel values and should provide comparable improvement in
photometric analysis of any crowded fields. We produce new multiwavelength
catalogs for the 25 CLASH cluster fields in all 16 bandpasses from the UV
through the near IR, as well as rest-frame magnitudes. A comparison with
spectroscopic values from the literature finds a ~30% decrease in the redshift
deviation from previously-released CLASH photometry. This improvement in
redshift precision, in combination with a detection scheme designed to maximize
purity, yields a substantial upgrade in cluster member identification over the
previous CLASH galaxy catalog. We construct luminosity functions for each
cluster, reliably reaching depths of at least 4.5 mag below M* in every case,
and deeper still in several clusters. We measure M* , $\alpha$, and their
redshift evolution, assuming the cluster populations are coeval, and find
little to no evolution of $\alpha$, $-0.9\lesssim\langle\alpha\rangle\lesssim
-0.8$, and M* values consistent with passive evolution. We present a catalog of
galaxy photometry, photometric and spectroscopic redshifts, and rest-frame
photometry for the full fields of view of all 25 CLASH clusters. Not only will
our new photometric catalogs enable new studies of the properties of CLASH
clusters, but mode-filtering techniques, such as those presented here, should
greatly enhance the data quality of future photometric surveys of crowded
fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.04957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.04957</id><created>2017-09-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kushwaha</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiita</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaur</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pino</keyname><forenames>E. M. de Gouveia Dal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhagwan</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurtanidze</keyname><forenames>O. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larionov</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damljanovic</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uemura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semkov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strigachev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bachev</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vince</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Minfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borman</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grishina</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirochi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itoh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopatskaya</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurtanidze</keyname><forenames>S. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larionova</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larionova</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozova</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakaoka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolashvili</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savchenko</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troitskaya</keyname><forenames>Yu. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troitsky</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasilyev</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-wavelength temporal and spectral variability of the blazar OJ 287
  during and after the December 2015 flare: a major accretion disc contribution</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>24 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables, MNRAS in press</comments><journal-ref>2018, MNRAS, 473, 1145</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2394</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a multi-wavelength spectral and temporal analysis of the blazar OJ
287 during its recent activity between December 2015 -- May 2016, showing
strong variability in the near-infrared (NIR) to X-ray energies with detection
at $\gamma$-ray energies as well. Most of the optical flux variations exhibit
strong changes in polarization angle and degree. All the inter-band time lags
are consistent with simultaneous emissions. Interestingly, on days with
excellent data coverage in the NIR--UV bands, the spectral energy distributions
(SEDs) show signatures of bumps in the visible--UV bands, never seen before in
this source. The optical bump can be explained as accretion-disk emission
associated with the primary black hole of mass $\sim \rm 1.8 \times10^{10}
M_{\odot}$ while the little bump feature in the optical-UV appears consistent
with line emission. Further, the broadband SEDs extracted during the first
flare and during a quiescent period during this span show very different
$\gamma$-ray spectra compared to previously observed flare or quiescent
spectra. The probable thermal bump in the visible seems to have been clearly
present since May 2013, as found by examining all available NIR-optical
observations, and favors the binary super-massive black hole model. The
simultaneous multi-wavelength variability and relatively weak $\gamma$-ray
emission that shows a shift in the SED peak is consistent with $\gamma$-ray
emission originating from inverse Compton scattering of photons from the line
emission that apparently contributes to the little blue bump.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05811</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05811</id><created>2017-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zenitani</keyname><forenames>Seiji</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipation in Relativistic Pair-plasma Reconnection: Revisited</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.plasm-ph physics.space-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>Plasma Physics and Controlled Fusion, 60, 014028 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6587/aa8f17</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Basic properties of relativistic magnetic reconnection in electron-positron
pair plasmas are investigated by using a particle-in-cell (PIC) simulation. We
first revisit a problem by Hesse &amp; Zenitani (2007), who examined the kinetic
Ohm's law across the X line. We formulate a relativistic Ohm's law by
decomposing the stress-energy tensor. Then, the role of the new term, called
the heat-flow inertial term, is examined in the PIC simulation data. We further
evaluate the energy balance in the reconnection system. These analyses
demonstrate physically transparent ways to diagnose relativistic kinetic data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05981</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05981</id><created>2017-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Suganuma</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto U</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>Takahiro M.</forenames><affiliation>RIKEN</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Redlich</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames><affiliation>Wroclaw U</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Chihiro</forenames><affiliation>Wroclaw U</affiliation></author></authors><title>Relating Quark Confinement and Chiral Symmetry Breaking in QCD</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1611.08742</comments><journal-ref>J.Phys. G44 (2017) no.12, 124001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa8e2f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the relation between quark confinement and chiral symmetry breaking
in QCD. Using lattice QCD formalism, we analytically express the various
&quot;confinement indicators&quot;, such as the Polyakov loop, its fluctuations, the
Wilson loop, the inter-quark potential and the string tension, in terms of the
Dirac eigenmodes. In the Dirac spectral representation, there appears a power
of the Dirac eigenvalue $\lambda_n$ such as $\lambda_n^{N_t-1}$, which behaves
as a reduction factor for small $\lambda_n$. Consequently, since this reduction
factor cannot be cancelled, the low-lying Dirac eigenmodes give negligibly
small contribution to the confinement quantities,while they are essential for
chiral symmetry breaking. These relations indicate no direct, one-to-one
correspondence between confinement and chiral symmetry breaking in QCD. In
other words, there is some independence of quark confinement from chiral
symmetry breaking, which can generally lead to different transition
temperatures/densities for deconfinement and chiral restoration. We also
investigate the Polyakov loop in terms of the eigenmodes of the Wilson, the
clover and the domain-wall fermion kernels, respectively, and find the similar
results. The independence of quark confinement from chiral symmetry breaking
seems to be natural, because confinement is realized independently of quark
masses and heavy quarks are also confined even without the chiral symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08382</id><created>2017-09-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsumura</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kita</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubo</keyname><forenames>Koya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshikawa</keyname><forenames>Yugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michimura</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inami</keyname><forenames>Toshiya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kousaka</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inoue</keyname><forenames>Katsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohara</keyname><forenames>Shigeo</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral Soliton Lattice Formation in Monoaxial Helimagnet
  Yb(Ni$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$)$_3$Al$_9$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 18 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 124702 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.124702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Helical magnetic structures and its responses to external magnetic fields in
Yb(Ni$_x$Cu$_{1-x}$)$_3$Al$_9$, with a chiral crystal structure of the space
group $R32$, have been investigated by resonant X-ray diffraction. It is shown
that the crystal chirality is reflected to the helicity of the magnetic
structure by a one to one relationship, indicating that there exists an
antisymmetric exchange interaction mediated via the conduction electrons. When
a magnetic field is applied perpendicular to the helical axis ($c$ axis), the
second harmonic peak of $(0, 0, 2q)$ develops with increasing the field. The
third harmonic peak of $(0, 0, 3q)$ has also been observed for the $x$=0.06
sample. This result provides a strong evidence for the formation of a chiral
magnetic soliton lattice state, a periodic array of the chiral twist of spins,
which has been suggested by the characteristic magnetization curve. The helical
ordering of magnetic octupole moments, accompanying with the magnetic dipole
order, has also been detected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08899</id><created>2017-09-26</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goto</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Tatsuma D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizuguchi</keyname><forenames>Yoshikazu</forenames></author></authors><title>SnAs-based layered superconductor NaSn2As2</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 table, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 123701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.123701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconductivity with exotic properties has often been discovered in
materials with a layered (two-dimensional) crystal structure. The low
dimensionality affects the electronic structure of materials, which could
realize a high transition temperature (Tc) and/or unconventional pairing
mechanisms. Here, we report the superconductivity in a layered tin arsenide
NaSn2As2. The crystal structure consists of (Sn2As2)2- bilayers, which is bound
by van-der-Waals forces, separated by Na+ ions. Measurements of electrical
resistivity and specific heat confirm the bulk nature of superconductivity of
NaSn2As2 with Tc of 1.3 K. Our results propose that the SnAs layers will be a
basic structure providing another universality class of a layered
superconducting family, and it provides a new platform for the physics and
chemistry of low-dimensional superconductors with lone pair electrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00581</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00581</id><created>2017-10-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Dom&#xe9;nech</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlemmer</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asvany</keyname><forenames>Oskar</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate frequency determination of vibration-rotation and rotational
  transitions of SiH+</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables Accepted for publication in the
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 849:60 (4pp), 2017 November 1</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa8fca</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The fundamental 28SiH+ ion has been characterized in a collaborative work,
utilizing a hollow-cathode-discharge laser-spectrometer and a cryogenic ion
trap spectrometer. Twenty-three vibration-rotation transitions around 4.75 um
have been detected with high accuracy. This has facilitated the first direct
measurement of the pure rotational transition J=1&lt;-0 at 453056.3632(4) MHz in
the trap spectrometer. The measured and accurately predicted transitions enable
the search for this ion in space with IR and sub-mm telescopes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.05834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.05834</id><created>2017-10-16</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>LIGO Scientific Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Virgo Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Monitor</keyname><forenames>Fermi Gamma-Ray Burst</forenames></author><author><keyname>INTEGRAL</keyname></author></authors><title>Gravitational Waves and Gamma-rays from a Binary Neutron Star Merger:
  GW170817 and GRB 170817A</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>27 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><proxy>Lvc Publications</proxy><report-no>LIGO-P1700308</report-no><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, 848:L13 (27pp), 2017 October 20</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8213/aa920c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On 2017 August 17, the gravitational-wave event GW170817 was observed by the
Advanced LIGO and Virgo detectors, and the gamma-ray burst (GRB) GRB 170817A
was observed independently by the Fermi Gamma-ray Burst Monitor, and the
Anticoincidence Shield for the Spectrometer for the International Gamma-Ray
Astrophysics Laboratory. The probability of the near-simultaneous temporal and
spatial observation of GRB 170817A and GW170817 occurring by chance is
$5.0\times 10^{-8}$. We therefore confirm binary neutron star mergers as a
progenitor of short GRBs. The association of GW170817 and GRB 170817A provides
new insight into fundamental physics and the origin of short gamma-ray bursts.
We use the observed time delay of $(+1.74 \pm 0.05)\,$s between GRB 170817A and
GW170817 to: (i) constrain the difference between the speed of gravity and the
speed of light to be between $-3\times 10^{-15}$ and $+7\times 10^{-16}$ times
the speed of light, (ii) place new bounds on the violation of Lorentz
invariance, (iii) present a new test of the equivalence principle by
constraining the Shapiro delay between gravitational and electromagnetic
radiation. We also use the time delay to constrain the size and bulk Lorentz
factor of the region emitting the gamma rays. GRB 170817A is the closest short
GRB with a known distance, but is between 2 and 6 orders of magnitude less
energetic than other bursts with measured redshift. A new generation of
gamma-ray detectors, and subthreshold searches in existing detectors, will be
essential to detect similar short bursts at greater distances. Finally, we
predict a joint detection rate for the Fermi Gamma-ray Burst Monitor and the
Advanced LIGO and Virgo detectors of 0.1--1.4 per year during the 2018-2019
observing run and 0.3--1.7 per year at design sensitivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.06530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.06530</id><created>2017-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>Souichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanimura</keyname><forenames>Yoshitaka</forenames></author></authors><title>An exciton-coupled electron transfer process controlled by non-Markovian
  environments</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other q-bio.BM</categories><comments>J. Phys. Chem. Lett. accepted</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 8, 5390-5394 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.7b01535</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate an exciton-coupled electron transfer (XCET)
process that is conversion of an exciton into a charge transfer state. This
conversion happens in an exciton transfer (XT) process, and the electron moves
away in an electron transfer(ET) process in multiple environments (baths). This
XCET process plays an essential role in the harvesting of solar energy in
biological and photovoltaic materials. We develop a practical theoretical model
to study the efficiency of XCET process that occurs either in consecutive or
concerted processes under the influence of non-Markovian baths. The role of
quantum coherence in the XT-ET system and the baths is investigated using
reduced hierarchal equations of motion (HEOM). This model includes independent
baths for each XT and ET state, in addition to a XCET bath for the conversion
process. We found that, while quantum system-bath coherence is important in the
XT and ET processes, coherence between the XT and ET processes must be
suppressed in order to realize efficient irreversible XCET process through the
weak off-diagonal interaction between the XT and ET bridge sites arises from a
XCET bath.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.07108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.07108</id><created>2017-10-19</created><updated>2017-10-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petkova</keyname><forenames>Maya A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laibe</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonnell</keyname><forenames>Ian A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast and accurate Voronoi density gridding from Lagrangian hydrodynamics
  data</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO astro-ph.EP astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>26 pages, 6 figures. Accepted for publication in Journal of
  Computational Physics. For a sample implementation of the described
  algorithm, see https://github.com/mapetkova/kernel-integration</comments><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2017.10.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Voronoi grids have been successfully used to represent density structures of
gas in astronomical hydrodynamics simulations. While some codes are explicitly
built around using a Voronoi grid, others, such as Smoothed Particle
Hydrodynamics (SPH), use particle-based representations and can benefit from
constructing a Voronoi grid for post-processing their output. So far,
calculating the density of each Voronoi cell from SPH data has been done
numerically, which is both slow and potentially inaccurate. This paper proposes
an alternative analytic method, which is fast and accurate. We derive an
expression for the integral of a cubic spline kernel over the volume of a
Voronoi cell and link it to the density of the cell. Mass conservation is
ensured rigorously by the procedure. The method can be applied more broadly to
integrate a spherically symmetric polynomial function over the volume of a
random polyhedron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09270</id><created>2017-10-20</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gurappa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Foundations of Quantum Mechanics: Wave-Particle Non-Duality and
  the Nature of Physical Reality</title><categories>physics.gen-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>Latex2e, 18 pages, 4 figures, Corrected typos, Small irrelevant
  portion removed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Schr\&quot;odinger's wave function can naturally be realized as an
'instantaneous resonant spatial mode' in which quantum particle moves and hence
the Born's rule is derived after identifying its origin. This realization
facilitates the visualization of `what's really going on?' in the Young's
double-slit experiment which is known to be the central mystery of quantum
mechanics. Also, an actual mechanism underlying the
`spooky-action-at-a-distance', another mystery regarding the entangled quantum
particles, is revealed. Wheeler's delayed choice experiments, delayed choice
quantum eraser experiment and delayed choice entanglement swapping experiments
are unambiguously and naturally explained at a single quantum level. The
reality of Nature represented by the quantum mechanical formalism is
conceptually intuitive and is independent of the measurement problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.09977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.09977</id><created>2017-10-26</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Masiero</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Palomar Optical Spectrum of Hyperbolic Near-Earth Object A/2017 U1</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>updated in response to referee comments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present optical spectroscopy of the recently discovered hyperbolic
near-Earth object A/2017 U1, taken on 25 Oct 2017 at Palomar Observatory.
Although our data are at a very low signal-to-noise, they indicate a very red
surface at optical wavelengths without significant absorption features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.10696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.10696</id><created>2017-10-29</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Orlov</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Links between quantum chaos and counting problems</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>My talk at XXXVI Workshop in Geometric Method in Physics, Bialystok,
  June 3-8, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Hurwitz numbers may be generated by certain correlation
functions which appear in quantum chaos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.11318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.11318</id><created>2017-10-31</created><updated>2017-11-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Huanfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leng</keyname><forenames>Siyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Luonan</forenames></author></authors><title>Data-based prediction and causality inference of nonlinear dynamics</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures, it has been accepted for publication in SCIENCE
  CHINA Mathematics</comments><msc-class>92B05, 57R40, 37D45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Natural systems are typically nonlinear and complex, and it is of great
interest to be able to reconstruct a system in order to understand its
mechanism, which can not only recover nonlinear behaviors but also predict
future dynamics. Due to the advances of modern technology, big data becomes
increasingly accessible and consequently the problem of reconstructing systems
from measured data or time series plays a central role in many scientific
disciplines. In recent decades, nonlinear methods rooted in state space
reconstruction have been developed, and they do not assume any model equations
but can recover the dynamics purely from the measured time series data. In this
review, the development of state space reconstruction techniques will be
introduced and the recent advances in systems prediction and causality
inference using state space reconstruction will be presented. Particularly, the
cutting-edge method to deal with short-term time series data will be focused.
Finally, the advantages as well as the remaining problems in this field are
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00060</id><created>2017-10-31</created><updated>2017-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanlon</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbasi</keyname><forenames>Rasha</forenames></author></authors><title>Proton-Air Cross Section and Composition of Ultra High Energy Cosmic
  Rays Observed by Telescope Array</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, Presented at EDS Blois 2017, Prague, Czech
  Republic, June 26-30, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra high energy cosmic rays (UHECRs) provide a natural source of particles
accelerated to energies beyond those that can be attained in the laboratory.
UHECRs have been observed with energies exceeding $10^{20}$ eV, which is
equivalent to 433 TeV in the center-of-momentum frame. Using this natural
source of particles physicists can extend the measurement of the $pp$ cross
section an order of magnitude above what is achievable in the lab, possibly
identifying hints of new physics. The proton-air cross section and other
properties of UHECR QCD physics are also important in their own right to the
study of the sources and composition of UHECRs, but hadronic modelling at these
energies is still reliant upon phenomenological and the theoretical
extrapolations based upon terrestrial accelerator data. UHECR data can be used
to improve these extrapolations of the proton-air cross section, but large
uncertainties remain for other hadronic model parameters. We present the most
recent measurement of the inelastic proton-air cross section at $\sqrt{s} = 95$
TeV measured by Telescope Array using high quality $X_{\mathrm{max}}$ data
collected in hybrid observing mode. This measurement is also used to infer the
total proton-proton cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00453</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>C. de la Fuente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>R. de la Fuente</forenames></author></authors><title>Transient Co-orbitals of Venus: An Update</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Research Notes of the AAS, Volume 1, Number 1, Article 3 (2017
  October 27)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2515-5172/aa95b5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Venus has no known satellites, but has four known co-orbitals: (322756) 2001
CK32, 2002 VE68, 2012 XE133, and 2013 ND15. Here, we present numerical evidence
suggesting that 2015 WZ12 is a possible Venus co-orbital; it might have been
until recently a transient Trojan. Follow-up observations of this target in the
near future will be difficult, though.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00496</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Paik</keyname><forenames>Hanjong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lochocki</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidner</keyname><forenames>Ariel H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanen</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Jisung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>ShunLi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Bi-Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xfc;tzam</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uecker</keyname><forenames>Reinhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zi-Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jena</keyname><forenames>Debdeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Kyle M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muller</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlom</keyname><forenames>Darrell G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Adsorption-controlled growth of La-doped BaSnO3 by molecular-beam
  epitaxy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Epitaxial La doped BaSnO3 films were grown in an adsorption controlled regime
by molecular beam epitaxy, where the excess volatile SnOx desorbs from the film
surface. A film grown on a (001) DyScO3 substrate exhibited a mobility of 183
cm^2 V^-1 s^-1 at room temperature and 400 cm^2 V^-1 s^-1 at 10 K, despite the
high concentration (1.2x10^11 cm^-2) of threading dislocations present. In
comparison to other reports, we observe a much lower concentration of (BaO)2
Ruddlesden Popper crystallographic shear faults. This suggests that in addition
to threading dislocations that other defects possibly (BaO)2 crystallographic
shear defects or point defects significantly reduce the electron mobility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00505</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00505</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y. Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel discoveries on the mathematical foundation of linear hydrodynamic
  stability theory</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math-ph math.AP math.MP nlin.CD physics.ao-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present some new discoveries on the mathematical foundation of linear
hydrodynamic stability theory. The new discoveries are: 1. Linearized Euler
equations fail to provide a linear approximation on inviscid hydrodynamic
stability. 2. Eigenvalue instability predicted by high Reynolds number
linearized Navier-Stokes equations cannot capture the dominant instability of
super fast growth. 3. As equations for directional differentials, Rayleigh
equation and Orr-Sommerfeld equation cannot capture the nature of the full
differentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00512</id><created>2017-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Abdulsttar</keyname><forenames>Marwah M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al-Rubaiee</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cherenkov Light Lateral Distribution Function Estimation as a Function
  of Zenith Angle</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, Journal of Applied Physical Science International</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The simulation of Cherenkov light lateral distribution function (CLLDF) in
Extensive Air Showers (EAS) was performed by using the Monte Carlo CORSIKA code
for configurations of Tunka-133 EAS Cherenkov array. This simulation was
carried out for different primary particles (e+, e-, p, O, Ar and Fe) around
the knee region with the energy 3.10^15 eV at different zenith angles. By
depending on the Breit-Wigner function a parameterization of CLLDF was
reconstructed on the basis of this simulation as a function of the zenith
angle. The parameterized CLLDF was verified for four fixed zenith angles in
comparison with the simulation that performed using CORSIKA code for each
primary particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00517</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Kouzakov</keyname><forenames>Konstantin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Studenikin</keyname><forenames>Alexander I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic interactions of neutrinos in processes of low-energy
  elastic neutrino-electron scattering</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, based on the presentation at TAUP 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron energy and angular distributions in the process of low-energy
elastic neutrino-electron scattering are treated in the free-electron
approximation. The effects of the millicharges, magnetic, electric, and anapole
moments of massive neutrinos along with the flavor change of neutrinos
traveling from the source to the detector are taken into account under the
assumption of three-neutrino mixing. The footprints of neutrino electromagnetic
interactions in the electron energy and angle distributions are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00523</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00523</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Freund</keyname><forenames>Peter G. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>p-adic Strings Then and Now</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages; This invited paper at the Sixth International Conference on
  p-adic Mathematical Physics and its Applications, Mexico-City, October 2017
  is dedicated to my friend, the distinguished physicist, Thomas Curtright on
  the occasion of his ecliptic 69th birthday</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After a brief review of the idea and main results of the original p-adic
string work, I describe the recent interest in p-adic strings in the context of
AdS/CFT duality
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00528</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>Barry</forenames></author></authors><title>Tosio Kato's Work on Non--Relativistic Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>math-ph math.HO math.MP</categories><comments>This is intended for Bull. Math. Sci. which intends to split it in
  two parts</comments><msc-class>81Q10, 81U05, 47A55, 35Q40, 46N50, 81Q15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the work of Tosio Kato on the mathematics of non--relativistic
quantum mechanics and some of the research that was motivated by this. Topics
include analytic and asymptotic eigenvalue perturbation theory, Temple--Kato
inequality, self--adjointness results, quadratic forms including monotone
convergence theorems, absence of embedded eigenvalues, trace class scattering,
Kato smoothness, the quantum adiabatic theorem and Kato's ultimate Trotter
Product Formula.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00534</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Eskin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynenko</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elekina</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>The correction of hadronic nucleus polarizability to hyperfine structure
  of light muonic atoms</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, Talk presented at 23th International Workshop on
  High Energy Physics and Quantum Field Theory (QFTHEP 2017)</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf. 158 (2017) 07002</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201715807002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The calculation of hadronic polarizability contribution of the nucleus to
hyperfine structure of muonic hydrogen and helium is carried out within the
unitary isobar model and experimental data on the polarized structure functions
of deep inelastic lepton-proton and lepton-deuteron scattering. The calculation
of virtual absorption cross sections of transversely and longitudinally
polarized photons by nucleons in the resonance region is performed in the
framework of the program MAID.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00536</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Aiello</keyname><forenames>Luca M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schifanella</keyname><forenames>Rossano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redi</keyname><forenames>Miriam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svetlichnaya</keyname><forenames>Stacey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osindero</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Beautiful and damned. Combined effect of content quality and social ties
  on user engagement</title><categories>cs.SI cs.AI cs.CV cs.MM physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures, final version published in IEEE Transactions on
  Knowledge and Data Engineering (Volume: PP, Issue: 99)</comments><doi>10.1109/TKDE.2017.2747552</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  User participation in online communities is driven by the intertwinement of
the social network structure with the crowd-generated content that flows along
its links. These aspects are rarely explored jointly and at scale. By looking
at how users generate and access pictures of varying beauty on Flickr, we
investigate how the production of quality impacts the dynamics of online social
systems. We develop a deep learning computer vision model to score images
according to their aesthetic value and we validate its output through
crowdsourcing. By applying it to over 15B Flickr photos, we study for the first
time how image beauty is distributed over a large-scale social system.
Beautiful images are evenly distributed in the network, although only a small
core of people get social recognition for them. To study the impact of exposure
to quality on user engagement, we set up matching experiments aimed at
detecting causality from observational data. Exposure to beauty is
double-edged: following people who produce high-quality content increases one's
probability of uploading better photos; however, an excessive imbalance between
the quality generated by a user and the user's neighbors leads to a decline in
engagement. Our analysis has practical implications for improving link
recommender systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00539</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Stepanov</keyname><forenames>Anton D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilson</keyname><forenames>Erik P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaganovich</keyname><forenames>Igor D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidl</keyname><forenames>Peter A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persaud</keyname><forenames>Arun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schenkel</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedman</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnard</keyname><forenames>John J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grote</keyname><forenames>David P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing Beam Transport in Rapidly Compressing Beams on the
  Neutralized Drift Compression Experiment - II</title><categories>physics.acc-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Neutralized Drift Compression Experiment-II (NDCX-II) is an induction
linac that generates intense pulses of 1.2 MeV helium ions for heating matter
to extreme conditions. Here, we present recent results on optimizing beam
transport. The NDCX-II beamline includes a 1-meter-long drift section
downstream of the last transport solenoid, which is filled with
charge-neutralizing plasma that enables rapid longitudinal compression of an
intense ion beam against space-charge forces. The transport section on NDCX-II
consists of 28 solenoids. Finding optimal field settings for a group of
solenoids requires knowledge of the envelope parameters of the beam. Imaging
the beam on scintillator gives the radius of the beam, but the envelope angle
dr/dz is not measured directly. We demonstrate how the parameters of the beam
envelope (r, dr/dz, and emittance) can be reconstructed from a series of images
taken at varying B-field strengths of a solenoid upstream of the scintillator.
We use this technique to evaluate emittance at several points in the NDCX-II
beamline and for optimizing the trajectory of the beam at the entry of the
plasma-filled drift section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00552</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Meoni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuznetsov</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menichetti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rum&#x161;evi&#x10d;ius</keyname><forenames>Justinas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boccali</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonacorsi</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploiting Apache Spark platform for CMS computing analytics</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to ACAT 2017 conference proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CERN IT provides a set of Hadoop clusters featuring more than 5 PBytes of
raw storage with different open-source, user-level tools available for
analytical purposes. The CMS experiment started collecting a large set of
computing meta-data, e.g. dataset, file access logs, since 2015. These records
represent a valuable, yet scarcely investigated, set of information that needs
to be cleaned, categorized and analyzed. CMS can use this information to
discover useful patterns and enhance the overall efficiency of the distributed
data, improve CPU and site utilization as well as tasks completion time. Here
we present evaluation of Apache Spark platform for CMS needs. We discuss two
main use-cases CMS analytics and ML studies where efficient process billions of
records stored on HDFS plays an important role. We demonstrate that both Scala
and Python (PySpark) APIs can be successfully used to execute extremely I/O
intensive queries and provide valuable data insight from collected meta-data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00566</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rashidi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Erika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huff</keyname><forenames>Taleana R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achal</keyname><forenames>Roshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taucer</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croshaw</keyname><forenames>Jeremiah J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolkow</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resolving and Tuning Carrier Capture Rates at a Single Silicon Atom Gap
  State</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1021/acsnano.7b07068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on tuning the carrier capture events at a single dangling bond (DB)
midgap state by varying the substrate temperature, doping type, and doping
concentration. All-electronic time-resolved scanning tunneling microscopy
(TR-STM) is employed to directly measure the carrier capture rates on the
nanosecond time scale. A characteristic negative differential resistance (NDR)
feature is evident in the scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) and scanning
tunneling spectroscopy (STS) measurements of DBs on both n and p-type doped
samples. It is found that a common model accounts for both observations.
Atom-specific Kelvin probe force microscopy (KPFM) measurements confirm the
energetic position of the DB's charge transition levels, corroborating STS
studies. It is shown that under different tip-induced fields the DB can be
supplied from two distinct reservoirs: the bulk conduction band and/or the
valence band. We measure the filling and emptying rates of the DBs in the
energy regime where electrons are supplied by the bulk valence band. By adding
point charges in the vicinity of a DB, Coulombic interactions are shown to
shift observed STS and NDR features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00570</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Epstein</keyname><forenames>Ryan J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-Weight Pauli Hamiltonian Sequences for Noise-Resilient Quantum Gates</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple protocol based on low-weight Pauli Hamiltonians is introduced for
performing quantum gates that are robust to control noise. Gates are
implemented by an adiabatic sequence of single-qubit fields and two-qubit
interactions with a single ancillary qubit, whereas related techniques require
three-qubit interactions, perturbation gadgets, higher dimensional subsystems,
and/or more ancilla qubits. Low-weight interactions and low qubit overhead open
a viable path to experimental investigation, while operation in a degenerate
ground space allows for physical qubit designs that are immune to energy
relaxation. Simulations indicate that two-qubit gate error due to control noise
can be as low as $10^{-5}$, for realizable coupling strengths and time-scales,
with low-frequency noise that is as high as 15% of the control pulse amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00576</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Dharmavarapu</keyname><forenames>Raghu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juodkazis</keyname><forenames>Saulius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Shanti</forenames></author></authors><title>Engineering the axial intensity of Bessel beams</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bessel beams (BBs) appear immune to diffraction over finite propagation
distances due to the conical nature of light propagation along the optical
axis. This offers promising advantages in laser fabrication. However, BBs
exhibit a significant intensity variation along the direction of propagation.
We present a simple technique to engineer the axial intensity of the BB over
centimeters-long propagation distances without expansion of the incoming laser
beam. This method uses two diffractive optical elements (DOEs), one converts
the input Gaussian intensity profile to an intermediate intensity distribution,
which illuminates the second DOE, a binary axicon. BBs of desired axial
intensity distribution over few centimeters length can be fabricated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00606</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Joo</keyname><forenames>Min-Kyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Youngjo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>Byoung Hee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sanghyub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Young Hee</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron-hole pair condensation in Graphene/MoS2 heterointerface</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Excitons are electron-hole (e-h) pair quasiparticles, which may form a
Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC) and collapse into the phase coherent state at
low temperature. However, because of ephemeral strength of pairing, a clear
evidence for BEC in electron-hole system has not yet been observed. Here, we
report electron-hole pair condensation in graphene (Gr)/MoS2 heterointerface at
10K without magnetic field. As a direct indication of e-h pair condensation, we
demonstrate a vanished Hall drag voltage and the resultant divergence of drag
resistance. While strong excitons are formed at Gr/MoS2 heterointerface without
insulating layer, carrier recombination via interlayer tunneling of carriers is
suppressed by the vertical p-Gr/n-MoS2 junction barrier, consequently yielding
high BEC temperature of 10K, ~1000 times higher than that of two-dimensional
electron gas in III-V quantum wells. The observed excitonic transport is mainly
governed by the interfacial properties of the Gr/MoS2 heterostructure, rather
than the intrinsic properties of each layer. Our approach with available
large-area monolayer graphene and MoS2 provides a high feasibility for quantum
dissipationless electronics towards integration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00611</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Xianliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Zhiliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Qiuhao</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance of two-dimensional tidal turbine arrays in free surface flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>36 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Encouraged by recent studies on the performance of tidal turbine arrays, we
extend the classical momentum actuator disc theory to include the free surface
effects and allow the vertical arrangement of turbines. Most existing
literatures concern one dimensional arrays with single turbine in the vertical
direction, while the arrays in this work are two dimensional (with turbines in
both the vertical and lateral directions) and also partially block the channel
which width is far larger than height. The vertical mixing of array scale flow
is assumed to take place much faster than lateral one. This assumption has been
verified by numerical simulations. Fixing the total turbine area and utilized
width, the comparison between two-dimensional and traditional one-dimensional
arrays is investigated. The results suggest that the two dimensional
arrangements of smaller turbines are preferred to one dimensional arrays from
both the power coefficient and efficiency perspectives. When channel dynamics
are considered, the power increase would be partly offset according to the
parameters of the channel but the optimal arrangement is unchangeable.
Furthermore, we consider how to arrange finite number of turbines in a channel.
It is shown that an optimal distribution of turbines in two directions is
found. Finally, the scenario of arranging turbines in infinite flow, which is
the limiting condition of small blockages, is analysed. A new maximum power
coefficient 0.869 occurs when $Fr=0.2$, greatly increasing the peak power
compared with existing results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00619</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Pouya</keyname><forenames>Eskandar Ahmadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajabi</keyname><forenames>Ali Akbar</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to Comment on &quot;Six-body bound system calculations in the case of
  effective Alpha-core structure&quot;</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The present paper is provided in response to the comment of M. R. Hadizadeh
et.al on our original paper Six-body bound system calculations in the case of
effective Alpha-core structure [Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131: 240].In this
paper we have presented our clarifications on their arguments about of the
accuracy of the procedure of the calculations. In this paper our arguments turn
out to be very efficient mainly discussed from the authors misunderstanding of
the issues discussed in the original paper. In fact, their comment aims to
exaggeratedly show that our paper is poor,but our following statements
demonstrate that their comment is misleading and consequently unacceptable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00631</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00631</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Chhabra</keyname><forenames>Rahul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author></authors><title>In-medium properties of pseudoscalar $D_s$ and $B_s$ mesons</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>34 pages annd 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C, 77 11 (2017) 726</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5277-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the shift in masses and decay constants of $D_s(1968)$ and
$B_s(5370)$ mesons in hot and dense asymmetric strange hadronic matter using
QCD sum rules and chiral SU(3) model. In-medium strange quark condensates
$\left\langle \bar{s}s\right\rangle_{\rho_B}$, and gluon condensates
$\left\langle \frac{\alpha_{s}}{\pi} {G^a}_{\mu\nu} {G^a}^{\mu\nu}
\right\rangle_{\rho_B}$ to be used in the QCD sum rules for pseudoscalar $D_s$
and $B_s$ mesons are calculated using chiral SU(3) model. As an application of
our present work, we calculate the in-medium decay widths of the excited
(c$\bar{s}$) states $D_s^*(2715)$ and $D_s^*(2860)$ decaying to
($D_s(1968)$,$\eta$) mesons. The medium effects in their decay widths are
incorporated through the mass modification of the $D_s(1968)$ and $\eta$
mesons. Results of the present investigation may be helpful to understand the
possible outcomes of the future experiments like CBM and PANDA under the FAIR
facility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00643</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishino</keyname><forenames>Masamichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyashita</keyname><forenames>Seiji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rikvold</keyname><forenames>Per Arne</forenames></author></authors><title>Nontrivial phase diagram for an elastic interaction model of spin
  crossover materials with antiferromagnetic-like short-range interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 144425 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.144425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the phase diagram of an elastic interaction model for spin crossover
(SC) materials with antiferromagnetic-like short-range interactions. In this
model, the interplay between the short-range interaction and the long-range
interaction of elastic origin causes complex phase transitions. For relatively
weak elastic interactions, the phase diagram is characterized by tricritical
points, at which antiferromagnetic (AF) -like and ferromagnetic (F) -like
spinodal lines and a critical line merge. On the other hand, for relatively
strong elastic interactions, unusual &quot;horn structures,&quot; which are surrounded by
the F-like spinodal lines, disorder (D) spinodal lines, and the critical line,
are realized at higher temperatures. These structures are similar to those
obtained in our previous study [Phys. Rev. B {\bf 93}, 064109 (2016)] of an
Ising antiferromagnet with infinite-range ferromagnetic interactions, and we
find universal features caused by the interplay between the competing
short-range and long-range interactions. The long-range interaction of elastic
origin is irrelevant (inessential) for the critical line. In contrast, the
AF-like, F-like, and D spinodal lines result from the long-range interaction of
elastic origin. This difference causes qualitatively different features of
domain formation or nucleation of the new phase: clustering occurs in the
former case, while clustering is absent in the latter. Based on the phase
diagrams, we discuss the patterns and clustering features of two-step SC
transitions, in which the AF-like phase is realized in the intermediate
temperature region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00654</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00654</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Connor</keyname><forenames>Patrick L. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of jet properties in CMS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, conference proceedings</comments><report-no>CMS CR-2017/358</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of the inclusive jet production at centre-of-mass
energies of 8 and 13 TeV, and of multijets at 8 TeV. These measurements allow
to constrain PDFs and the strong coupling constant. Two measurements of the
azimuthal correlations at 8 and 13 TeV are also presented, testing higher order
QCD calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00663</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Sugano</keyname><forenames>Junpei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kouno</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yahiro</keyname><forenames>Masanobu</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD-inequality analyses on pion condensate at real and imaginary isospin
  chemical potentials under finite imaginary quark chemical potential</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By employing QCD inequalities, we discuss appearance of the pion condensate
for both real and imaginary isospin chemical potentials, taking also into
account imaginary quark chemical potential. We show that the charged pion can
condense for real isospin chemical potential, but not for imaginary one.
Furthermore, we evaluate the expectation value of the neutral-pion field for
imaginary isospin chemical potential by using framework of the twisted mass. As
a result, it is found that the expectation value becomes zero for the finite
current-quark mass, whereas the Banks-Casher relation is obtained in the
massless limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00664</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixed interactions of localized waves in the three-component coupled
  derivative nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Darboux transformation of the three-component coupled derivative
nonlinear Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equations is constructed, based on the special vector
solution elaborately generated from the corresponding Lax pair, various
interactions of localized waves are derived. Here, we focus on the higher-order
interactional solutions among higher-order rogue waves (RWs), multi-soliton and
multi-breather. Instead of considering various arrangements among the three
components $q_1$, $q_2$ and $q_3$, we define the same combination as the same
type solution. Based on our method, these interactional solutions are
completely classified into six types among these three components $q_1$, $q_2$
and $q_3$. In these six types interactional solutions, there are four mixed
interactions of localized waves in three different components. In particular,
the free parameters $\alpha$ and $\beta$ paly an important role in dynamics
structures of the interactional solutions, for example, different nonlinear
localized waves merge with each other by increasing the absolute values of
$\alpha$ and $\beta$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00676</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Beneke</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauh</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz-Femen&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Electroweak and non-resonant corrections to top-pair production near
  threshold at NNLO</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures. contribution to the 13th International Symposium
  on Radiative Corrections (RADCOR 2017)</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP-1105/17, IPPP/17/81, FTUAM-17-25, IFT-UAM/CSIC-17-106</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The top-quark mass can be determined with very high precision from a scan of
the total $e^+e^-\to b\bar{b}W^+W^-X$ cross section near the top-pair
production threshold. We present the full calculation of electroweak and
non-resonant corrections to this process at NNLO. We discuss the size of the
new contributions and estimate the theory uncertainty on the top-quark mass in
the PS mass scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00678</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>McBride</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames></author></authors><title>Scientists in silico?</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The end (for human scientists) is nigh? The posit of this discourse is that
the majority, if not all, scientific research will eventually be undertaken by
one, or a number of, weak artificial intelligences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00686</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Ryan L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bremner</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Complexity of Random Quantum Computations and the Jones
  Polynomial</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is a natural relationship between Jones polynomials and quantum
computation. We use this relationship to show that the complexity of evaluating
relative-error approximations of Jones polynomials can be used to bound the
classical complexity of approximately simulating random quantum computations.
We prove that random quantum computations cannot be classically simulated up to
a constant total variation distance, under the assumption that (1) the
Polynomial Hierarchy does not collapse and (2) the average-case complexity of
relative-error approximations of the Jones polynomial matches the worst-case
complexity over a constant fraction of random links. Our results provide a
straightforward relationship between the approximation of Jones polynomials and
the complexity of random quantum computations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00697</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Lancien</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;cilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Approximating quantum channels by completely positive maps with small
  Kraus rank</title><categories>quant-ph math.FA math.PR</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the problem of approximating a quantum channel by one with as few
Kraus operators as possible (in the sense that, for any input state, the output
states of the two channels should be close to one another). Our main result is
that any quantum channel mapping states on some input Hilbert space
$\mathrm{A}$ to states on some output Hilbert space $\mathrm{B}$ can be
compressed into one with order $d\log d$ Kraus operators, where
$d=\max(|\mathrm{A}|,|\mathrm{B}|)$, hence much less than
$|\mathrm{A}||\mathrm{B}|$. In the case where the channel's outputs are all
very mixed, this can be improved to order $d$. We discuss the optimality of
this result as well as some consequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00703</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Seifert</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>The linearized Korteweg-de-Vries equa- tion on general metric graphs</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.FA math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the linearized Korteweg-de-Vries equa- tions, sometimes called
Airy equation, on general metric graphs with edge lengths bounded away from
zero. We show that pro- perties of the induced dynamics can be obtained by
studying boundary operators in the corresponding boundary space indu- ced by
the vertices of the graph. In particular, we characterize unitary dynamics and
contractive dynamics. We demonstrate our results on various special graphs,
including those recently treated in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00717</id><created>2017-10-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuepper</keyname><forenames>Tilman</forenames><affiliation>Hochschule Muenchen</affiliation></author></authors><title>Simulation of Shive wave machines using GNU Octave, Python and C++ /
  Simulation von Wellenmaschinen mit GNU Octave, Python und C++</title><categories>physics.ed-ph physics.class-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, in German</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In &quot;Shive wave machines - Wave propagation, dispersion, reflection,
simulation&quot; (arXiv:1503.02088) technical details of Shive wave machines are
discussed. Wave propagation on these machines is simulated using the commercial
numerical computing environment MATLAB. The MATLAB functions are compatible
with GNU Octave, a free MATLAB alternative. The lower execution speed compared
to MATLAB can be somewhat compensated by converting the underlying differential
equations to matrix form. With Python or C++, these and similar simulations can
also be performed easily. Suitable vector and matrix libraries, ODE solvers and
plotting libraries for these programming languages are available free of charge
on the internet.
  -----
  In &quot;Die Wellenmaschine - Grundlagen der Wellenausbreitung, Dispersion,
Reflexion, Simulation&quot; (arXiv:1503.02088) werden die in Schule und Hochschule
verbreiteten Wellenmaschinen n\&quot;aher betrachtet und die Wellenausbreitung auf
solchen Maschinen mithilfe von MATLAB simuliert. Die kommerzielle Software
MATLAB ist freilich nicht \&quot;uberall verf\&quot;ugbar, sodass sich die Frage nach
freien Alternativen stellt. Der MATLAB-Quelltext im genannten Artikel kann zum
Beispiel mit GNU Octave ausgef\&quot;uhrt werden. Die im Vergleich zu MATLAB
geringere Ausf\&quot;uhrungsgeschwindigkeit l\&quot;asst sich durch Umformung des zu
l\&quot;osenden Differentialgleichungssystems in Matrixschreibweise zumindest
teilweise kompensieren. Aber auch mit klassischen Programmiersprachen wie
Python oder C++ lassen sich diese und \&quot;ahnliche Simulationen leicht
durchf\&quot;uhren. Passende Bibliotheken zur Arbeit mit Vektoren und Matrizen, zum
L\&quot;osen von Differentialgleichungen und zur animierten Darstellung der
Simulationsergebnisse werden im Artikel vorgestellt.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00729</id><created>2017-11-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Dahiya</keyname><forenames>Harleen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Randhawa</keyname><forenames>Monika</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic and Axial-Vector Form Factors of the Quarks and Nucleon</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 11 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1606.06441, arXiv:1505.03304</comments><journal-ref>Int. Jol. of Mod. Phys. A, Vol. 32 (2017) 1750185</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17501858</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In light of the improved precision of the experimental measurements and
enormous theoretical progress, the nucleon form factors have been evaluated
with an aim to understand how the static properties and dynamical behavior of
nucleons emerge from the theory of strong interactions between quarks. We have
analysed the vector and axial-vector nucleon form factors ($G^{p,n}_{E,M}(Q^2)$
and $G^{p,n}_{A}(Q^2)$) using the spin observables in the chiral constituent
quark model ($\chi$CQM) which has made a significant contribution to the
unraveling of the internal structure of the nucleon in the nonperturbative
regime. We have also presented a comprehensive analysis of the flavor
decomposition of the form factors ($G^{q}_{E}(Q^2)$, $G^{q}_{M}(Q^2)$ and
$G^{q}_{A}(Q^2)$for $q=u,d,s$) within the framework of $\chi$CQM with emphasis
on the extraction of the strangeness form factors which are fundamental to
determine the spin structure and test the chiral symmetry breaking effects in
the nucleon. The $Q^2$ dependence of the vector and axial-vector form factors
of the nucleon has been studied using the conventional dipole form of
parametrization. The results are in agreement with the available experimental
data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00736</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00736</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Kriuchevskyi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wittmer</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baschnagel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear modulus and shear-stress fluctuations in polymer glasses</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figure, published at PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett., 119, 147802 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.147802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using molecular dynamics simulation of a standard coarse-grained polymer
glass model we investigate by means of the stress-fluctuation formalism the
shear modulus $\mu$ as a function of temperature $T$ and sampling time $\Delta
t$. While the ensemble-averaged modulus $\mu(T)$ is found to decrease
continuously for all $\Delta t$ sampled, its standard deviation $\delta \mu(T)$
is non-monotonous with a striking peak at the glass transition. Confirming the
effective time-translational invariance of our systems, $\mu(\Delta t)$ can be
understood using a weighted integral over the shear-stress relaxation modulus
$G(t)$. While the crossover of $\mu(T)$ gets sharper with increasing $\Delta
t$, the peak of $\delta \mu(T)$ becomes more singular. % It is thus elusive to
predict the modulus of a single configuration at the glass transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00761</id><created>2017-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fabbri</keyname><forenames>Renato</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Le&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Fernando Gularte</forenames></author></authors><title>A Statistical Distance Derived From The Kolmogorov-Smirnov Test:
  specification, reference measures (benchmarks) and example uses</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>Scripts and benchmark tables in
  https://github.com/ttm/kolmogorov-smirnov</comments><report-no>ISSN 2527-2357, ISBN 978-85-5676-019-7</report-no><journal-ref>Anais do XX ENMC - Encontro Nacional de Modelagem Computacional e
  VIII ECTM - Encontro de Ci\^encias e Tecnologia de Materiais, Nova Friburgo,
  RJ - 16 a 19 Outubro 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Statistical distances quantifies the difference between two statistical
constructs. In this article, we describe reference values for a distance
between samples derived from the Kolmogorov-Smirnov statistic $D_{F,F'}$. Each
measure of the $D_{F,F'}$ is a measure of difference between two samples. This
distance is normalized by the number of observations in each sample to yield
the $c'=D_{F,F'}\sqrt{\frac{n n'}{n+n'}}$ statistic, for which high levels
favor the rejection of the null hypothesis (that the samples are drawn from the
same distribution). One great feature of $c'$ is that it inherits the
robustness of $D_{F,F'}$ and is thus suitable for use in settings where the
underlying distributions are not known. Benchmarks are obtained by comparing
samples derived from standard distributions. The supplied example applications
of the $c'$ statistic for the distinction of samples in real data enables
further insights about the robustness and power of such statistical distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00764</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Pande</keyname><forenames>Varad R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanjilal</keyname><forenames>Som</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Debmalya</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Strong Measurements Give a Better Direct Measurement of the
  Quantum Wave Function&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>1 page</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a comment on &quot;Strong Measurements Give a Better Direct Measurement of
the Quantum Wave Function&quot; which was published as PRL 116, 040502 (2016). We
show that there is crucial normalization error in this Letter which invalidates
the proposal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00767</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Morgante</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-SUSY WIMPS: simplified models and Dark Matter at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings of 13th Rencontres du Vietnam on Exploring the Dark
  Universe</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I discuss the construction of Simplified Models for Dark Matter searches at
the LHC. After reviewing the phylosophy and some simple example, I turn the
attention to the aspect of the theoretical consistency of these models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00824</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Si</keyname><forenames>Mengwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lingming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Peide D.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\beta$-Ga$_2$O$_3$ Nano-membrane Negative Capacitance Field-effect
  Transistor with Steep Subthreshold Slope for Wide Bandgap Logic Applications</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Omega, 2017, 2(10), pp. 7136-7140</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsomega.7b01289</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Steep-slope $\beta$-Ga$_2$O$_3$ nano-membrane negative capacitance
field-effect transistors (NC-FETs) are demonstrated with ferroelectric hafnium
zirconium oxide in gate dielectric stack. Subthreshold slope less than 60
mV/dec at room temperature is obtained for both forward and reverse gate
voltage sweeps with a minimum value of 34.3 mV/dec at reverse gate voltage
sweep and 53.1 mV/dec at forward gate voltage sweep at $V_{DS}$=0.5 V.
Enhancement-mode operation with threshold voltage ~0.4 V is achieved by tuning
the thickness of $\beta$-Ga$_2$O$_3$ membrane. Low hysteresis of less than 0.1
V is obtained. The steep-slope, low hysteresis and enhancement-mode
$\beta$-Ga$_2$O$_3$ NC-FETs are promising as nFET candidate for future wide
bandgap CMOS logic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00835</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Blind</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conod</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wildi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Few-mode fibers and AO-assisted high resolution spectroscopy: coupling
  efficiency and modal noise mitigation</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures. Proceeding of the AO4ELT5 conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NIRPS (Near Infra-Red Planet Searcher) is an AO-assisted and fiber-fed
spectrograph for high precision radial velocity measurements that will operate
in the YJH-bands. While using an AO system in such instrument is generally
considered to feed a single-mode fiber, NIRPS is following a different path by
using a small multi-mode fiber (more specifically called &quot;few-mode fiber&quot;).
This choice offers an excellent trade-off by allowing to design a compact
cryogenic spectrograph, while maintaining a high coupling efficiency under bad
seeing conditions and for faint stars. The main drawback resides in a much more
important modal-noise, a problem that has to be tackled for allowing 1m/s
precision radial velocity measurements. We study the impact of using an AO
system to couple light into few-mode fibers. We focus on two aspects: the
coupling efficiency into few-mode fibers and the question of modal noise and
scrambling. We show first that NIRPS can reach coupling &gt;= 50% up to magnitude
I=12, and offer a gain of 1-2 magnitudes over a single-mode solution. We
finally show that the best strategy to mitigate modal noise with the AO system
is among the simplest: a continuous tip-tilt scanning of the fiber core.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1711.00839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1711.00839</id><created>2017-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Jen-Chieh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Wen-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platchkov</keyname><forenames>Stephane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawada</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Valence Quark and Gluon Distributions of Kaon from J/Psi Production</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The only experimental information on the parton distribution of kaons was
obtained from the scarce kaon-induced Drell-Yan cross section data. From these
data, evidence for a valence $u$ quark distribution of kaon softer than that of
pion was found. We study the feasibility to extract kaon's valence quark
distribution via the existing kaon-induced J/psi production data. We compare
the NA3 data on the K- / pi- and K+ / pi+ ratios for J/psi production on a
platinum target with theoretical calculations based on the color-evaporation
model. We show that the NA3 data on J/psi production provide an independent
evidence for a valence $u$ quark distribution softer in kaon than in pion. The
data also suggest different gluon distributions for kaon and pion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0004032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0004032</id><created>2000-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pittel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Bartol Research Institute, U. of Delaware</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nuclear structure from random interactions</title><categories>nucl-th nlin.CD</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables, invited talk `XXIII Symposium on
  Nuclear Physics', Oaxtepec, Mexico. to be published by Revista Mexicana de
  Fisica</comments><journal-ref>Rev Mex Fis S 46 (1), 47 (2000)</journal-ref><abstract>  Low-lying states in nuclei are investigated using an ensemble of random
interactions. Both in the nuclear shell model and in the interacting boson
model we find a dominance of $J^P=0^+$ ground states. It is shown that this
feature is not due to time reversal symmetry. In the shell model, evidence is
found for the occurrence of pairing properties, and in the interacting boson
model for both vibrational and rotational band structures. Our results suggest
that these features represent general and robust properties of the model space,
and do not depend on details of the interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0006028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0006028</id><created>2000-06-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author></authors><title>Collective states from random interactions</title><categories>nucl-th nlin.CD</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, 1 tables, to be published in the proceedings of
  Bologna 2000</comments><journal-ref>Structure of the nucleus at the dawn of the century, 398 (2001)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812799753_0077</doi><abstract>  The anharmonic vibrator and rotor regions in nuclei are investigated in the
framework of the interacting boson model using an ensemble of random one- and
two-body interactions. Despite the randomness of the interactions (in sign and
size) we find a predominance of L(P)=0(+) ground states and strong evidence for
the occurrence of both vibrational and rotational band structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0008066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0008066</id><created>2000-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew U., Israel</affiliation></author></authors><title>Algebraic model of baryon structure</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 tables, invited talk Bologna 2000: Structure of the
  Nucleus at the Dawn of the Century</comments><journal-ref>Structure of the nucleus at the dawn of the century, 193 (2001)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812810922_0036</doi><abstract>  We discuss properties of baryon resonances belonging to the Nucleon, Delta,
Sigma, Lambda, Xi and Omega families in a collective string-like model for the
nucleon, in which the radial excitations are interpreted as rotations and
vibrations of the string configuration. We find good overall agreement with the
available data. The main discrepancies are found for low lying S-wave states,
in particular N(1535), N(1650), Sigma(1750), Lambda*(1405), Lambda(1670) and
Lambda(1800).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0103052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0103052</id><created>2001-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew U., Israel</affiliation></author></authors><title>Strange decays from strange resonances</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 tables, 6 figures, invited talk XXIV Symposium on Nuclear
  Physics, Taxco, Mexico, January 3-6 2001. To be published in Revista Mexicana
  de Fisica</comments><journal-ref>Rev Mex Fis S 47 (2), 37 (2001)</journal-ref><abstract>  We discuss the mass spectrum and strong decays of baryon resonances belonging
to the N, Delta, Sigma, Lambda, Xi and Omega families in a collective
string-like model for the nucleon. We find good overall agreement with the
available data. Systematic discrepancies are found for lowlying S-wave states,
in particular in the strong decays of N(1535), N(1650), Sigma(1750),
Lambda(1405), Lambda(1670) and Lambda(1800).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0105027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0105027</id><created>2001-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author></authors><title>Randomness and Emerging Order in Nuclear Structure</title><categories>nucl-th nlin.CD</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 tables, 6 figures, invited talk XXIV Symposium on Nuclear
  Physics, Taxco, Mexico, Rev. Mex. Fis., in press</comments><journal-ref>Rev Mex Fis S 47 (2), 11 (2001)</journal-ref><abstract>  In order to investigate to what extent is the low-lying behavior of even-even
nuclei dependent on particular nucleon-nucleon interactions, we consider
systems of bosons where these interactions are taken as gaussian random numbers
with equal likelyhood of being attractive or repulsive. We find a statistical
dominance of L=0 ground states and other correlations, which we analyze in
terms of a mean field approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0107048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0107048</id><created>2001-07-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Barea</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Sevilla</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Loyola</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author></authors><title>Single-Particle Transfer and Nuclear Supersymmetry. Pick-Up and
  Stripping with SUSY</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 table, 2 figures, Physical Review C, in press</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C64 (2001) 064313</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.64.064313</doi><abstract>  Transfer reactions constitute a stringent test for nuclear supersymmetry, a
theory that simultaneously describes neighboring nuclei with bosonic and
fermionic character. We construct and analytically evaluate one-nucleon
transfer matrix elements between supersymmetric partners with the U(6/4) case
as an example, and stress the need for a careful treatment of bosonic and
fermionic operators in the construction of mixed tensor operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0108054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0108054</id><created>2001-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-Unam, CCF-Unam, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-Unam, CCF-Unam, Mexico</affiliation></author></authors><title>Randomly interacting bosons, mean-fields and L=0 ground states</title><categories>nucl-th nlin.CD</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, Invited talk at NP2001, Goettingen, March 2001,
  World Scientific (2001), in press</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Structure Physics, 155 (2001)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812811233_0016</doi><abstract>  Random interactions are used to investigate to what extent the low-lying
behavior of even-even nuclei depend on particular nucleon-nucleon interactions.
The surprising results that were obtained for the interacting boson model, i.e.
the dominance of ground states with L=0 and the occurrence of both vibrational
and rotational structure, are interpreted and explained in terms of a
mean-field analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0303069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0303069</id><created>2003-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>Roelof</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape phase transitions and random interactions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, invited talk at Computational and Group
  Theoretical Methods in Nuclear Physics, Playa del Carmen, Mexico, February
  18-21, 2003</comments><journal-ref>Computational and group-theoretical methods in nuclear physics, 60
  (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812703026_0006</doi><abstract>  The phenomenom of emerging regular spectral features from random interactions
is addressed in the context of the interacting boson model. A mean-field
analysis links different regions of the parameter space with definite geometric
shapes. The results provide a clear and transparent interpretation of the high
degree of order that has been observed before in numerical studies.}
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0304033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0304033</id><created>2003-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Barea</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author></authors><title>Everything you always wanted to know about SUSY, but were afraid to ask</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, proceedings of `Symmetries in Nuclear Structure',
  March 23-29, 2003, Erice, Italy</comments><journal-ref>Symmetries in Nuclear Structure, 117 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/9789812702760_0013</doi><abstract>  New experimental tests of nuclear supersymmetry are suggested. They involve
the measurement of one- and two-nucleon transfer reactions between nuclei that
belong to the same supermultiplet. These reactions provide a direct test of the
`fermionic' sector, i.e. of the operators that change a boson into a fermion or
vice versa. We present some theoretical predictions for the supersymmetric
quartet of nuclei: 194Pt, 195Pt, 195Au and 196Au.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/9609014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/9609014</id><created>1996-09-05</created><updated>1996-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew U., Israel</affiliation></author></authors><title>Algebraic model of an oblate top</title><categories>nucl-th chem-ph hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages with 4 figures and 2 tables. Invited talk at `Symmetries in
  Science IX', Bregenz, Austria, August 6-10, 1996. Revised version</comments><journal-ref>Symmetries in Science IX, 9 (1997)</journal-ref><abstract>  We consider an algebraic treatment of a three-body system. In particular, we
develop the formalism for a system of three identical objects and discuss an
application to nonstrange baryon resonances which are interpreted as
vibrational and rotational excitations of an oblate symmetric top. We derive
closed expressions for a set of elementary form factors that appear in the
calculation of both electromagnetic, strong and weak couplings of baryons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/9701037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/9701037</id><created>1997-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew U., Israel</affiliation></author></authors><title>Algebraic model of baryon resonances</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 table and 2 figures, proceedings of the `First Latin
  American Symposium on High Energy Physics', November 4-6, 1996, Merida,
  Mexico</comments><journal-ref>AIP CP 400, 220 (1997)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.53219</doi><abstract>  We discuss recent calculations of electromagnetic form factors and strong
decay widths of nucleon and delta resonances. The calculations are done in a
collective constituent model of the nucleon, in which the baryons are
interpreted as rotations and vibrations of an oblate top.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/9706042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/9706042</id><created>1997-06-17</created><updated>1997-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew U., Israel</affiliation></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic Form Factors of the Nucleon</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages with 6 figures and aipproc.sty file, invited talk at 6th
  Conference on the Intersections of Particle and Nuclear Physics, Big Sky,
  Montana, June 1997</comments><journal-ref>AIP CP 412, 519 (1997)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.54256</doi><abstract>  We reanalyze the world data on the electromagnetic form factors of the
nucleon. The calculations are performed in the framework of an algebraic model
of the nucleon combined with vector meson dominance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/9811013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/9811013</id><created>1998-11-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Jerusalem</affiliation></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic form factors of baryons</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, contribution to proceedings of Baryons '98, Bonn, September
  22-26, 1998</comments><journal-ref>Baryons 98, 470 (1999)</journal-ref><abstract>  Nucleon elastic and transition form factors are analyzed in the framework of
a collective model of baryons. Effects of meson cloud couplings and
relativistic corrections are considered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/9906093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/9906093</id><created>1999-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN-UNAM, Mexico</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Leviatan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Hebrew University, Jerusalem</affiliation></author></authors><title>An algebraic model of baryon spectroscopy</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 tables and 2 figures. Invited talk at 2nd International
  Conference on Perspectives in Hadronic Physics, May 10-14, 1999, ICTP,
  Triese. To be published by World Scientific</comments><journal-ref>2nd International Conference on Perspectives in Hadronic Physics,
  273 (2000)</journal-ref><abstract>  We discuss recent calculations of the mass spectrum, electromagnetic and
strong couplings of baryon resonances. The calculations are done in a
collective constituent model for the nucleon, in which the resonances are
interpreted as rotations and vibrations of a symmetric top with a prescribed
distribution of the charge and magnetization. We analyze recent data on
eta-photo- and eta-electroproduction, and the tensor analyzing power in
deuteron scattering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/9611027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-11-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/9611027</id><created>1996-11-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lemus</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico and Sevilla, Spain</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Perez-Bernal</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico and Sevilla, Spain</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico and Sevilla, Spain</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bijker</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico and Sevilla, Spain</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Arias</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames><affiliation>ICN/UNAM, Mexico and Sevilla, Spain</affiliation></author></authors><title>Application of a symmetry-adapted algebraic model to the vibratioinal
  spectrum of methane</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, invited talk at ``21st International Colloquium on Group
  Theoretical Methods in Physics'', Goslar, Germany, July 15-20, 1996</comments><journal-ref>Group 21, 805 (1997)</journal-ref><abstract>  The stretching and bending vibrations of methane are studied in the framework
of a symmetry-adapted algebraic model. The model is based on the realization of
the one-dimensional Morse potential in terms of a $U(2)$ algebra. For the 44
observed energies we obtain a fit with a r.m.s. deviation of 1.16 cm$^{-1}$
which is an order of magnitude more accurate than previous algebraic
calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
