<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:30:07Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-14" from="2017-07-14" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1002.4590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1002.4590</id><created>2010-02-24</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutra</keyname><forenames>A. de Souza</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>R. A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Paula</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emerging 2D isospectral configurations for position-dependent mass
  quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we construct a general class of exactly solvable
non-relativistic bi-dimensional quantum systems with position-dependent masses
(PDM). These systems are isospectral to a given system with constant mass. The
case of a charged particle with a PDM interacting with an external magnetic
field is included in the present investigation. We apply the approach in order
to construct the SU(2) coherent states in some examples which are isospectral
to the two-dimensional anisotropic harmonic oscillator, and discuss the impact
of the introduction of special non-homogeneous external magnetic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.3623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.3623</id><created>2013-12-12</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pallis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Linking Starobinsky-Type Inflation in no-Scale Supergravity to MSSM</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Erratum addressing issues in the derivation of the mu parameter of
  MSSM is included</comments><journal-ref>JCAP04(2014)024; JCAP07(2017)E01</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2014/04/024; 10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/E01</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel realization of the Starobinsky inflationary model within a moderate
extension of the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model (MSSM) is presented. The
proposed superpotential is uniquely determined by applying a continuous R and a
Z_2 discrete symmetry, whereas the Kahler potential respects a no-scale-type
SU(54,1)/SU(54)x U(1)_R x Z_2 symmetry too. The inflaton is identified with a
Higgs-like modulus whose the vacuum expectation value controls the
gravitational strength. Thanks to a strong enough coupling (with a parameter cT
involved) between the inflaton and the Ricci scalar curvature, inflation can be
attained even for subplanckian values of the inflaton with cT&gt;76 and the
corresponding effective theory being valid up to the Planck scale. The
inflationary observables turn out to be in agreement with the current data and
the inflaton mass is predicted to be 3x10^13 GeV. At the cost of a relatively
small superpotential coupling constant, the model offers also a resolution to
the mu problem of the MSSM. Supplementing MSSM by three right-handed neutrinos
we show that spontaneously arising couplings between the inflaton and the
particle content of MSSM not only ensure a sufficiently low reheating
temperature but also support a scenario of non-thermal leptogenesis
consistently with the neutrino oscillation parameters for gravitino heavier
than about 10^4 GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.5016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.5016</id><created>2014-08-21</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>D0 Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the effective weak mixing angle in $p\bar{p}\rightarrow
  Z/\gamma^{*}\rightarrow e^{+}e^{-}$ events</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>submitted to Phys. Rev. Lett</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-14-288-E</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 041801 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.041801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a measurement of the fundamental parameter of the standard model,
the weak mixing angle, in $p\bar{p}\rightarrow Z/\gamma^{*}\rightarrow
e^{+}e^{-}$ events at a center of mass energy of 1.96 TeV, using data
corresponding to 9.7 fb$^{-1}$ of integrated luminosity collected by the D0
detector at the Fermilab Tevatron. The effective weak mixing angle is extracted
from the forward-backward charge asymmetry as a function of the invariant mass
around the Z boson pole. The measured value of
$\sin^2\theta_{\text{eff}}^{\text{$\ell$}}=0.23147 \pm 0.00047$ is the most
precise measurement from light quark interactions to date, with a precision
close to the best LEP and SLD results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.0491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.0491</id><created>2014-12-01</created><updated>2015-06-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cipollone</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Surrey, CMCC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Barbieri</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>Surrey</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Navr&#xe1;til</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>TRIUMF</affiliation></author></authors><title>Chiral three-nucleon forces and the evolution of correlations along the
  oxygen isotopic chain</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>13 pages, accepted for publication on Phys. Rev. C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C92, 014306 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.92.014306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The impact of three-nucleon forces (3NFs) along the oxygen chain is
investigated for the spectral distribution for attachment and removal of a
nucleon, spectroscopic factors and matter radii. We employ self-consistent
Green's function (SCGF) theory which allows a comprehensive calculation of the
single particle spectral function. For the closed subshell isotopes, $^{14}$O,
$^{16}$O, $^{22}$O, $^{24}$O and $^{28}$O, we perform calculations with the
Dyson-ADC(3) method. The remaining open shell isotopes are studied using the
newly developed Gorkov-SCGF formalism up to second order. We produce plots for
the full-fledged spectral distributions. The spectroscopic factors for the
dominant quasiparticle peaks are found to depend very little on the leading
order (NNLO) chiral 3NFs. The latters have small impact on the calculated
matter radii, which, however are consistently obtained smaller than experiment.
Similarly, single particle spectra tend to be diluted with respect to
experiment. This effect might hinder, to some extent, the onset of correlations
and screen the quenching of calculated spectroscopic factors. The most
important effects of 3NFs is thus the fine tuning of the energies for the
dominant quasiparticle states, which govern the shell evolution and the
position of driplines. Although present chiral NNLO 3NFs interactions do
reproduce the binding energies correctly in this mass region, the details of
the nuclear wave function remain at odd with the experiment showing too small
radii and a too dilute single particle spectrum, similar to what already
pointed out for larger masses. This suggests a lack of repulsion in the present
model of NN+3N interactions which is mildly apparent already for masses in the
A=14--28 range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06721</id><created>2015-06-22</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fayngold</keyname><forenames>Moses</forenames></author></authors><title>A new paradox in superluminal signaling</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new causal paradox in superluminal signaling is presented. In contrast to
the Tolman paradox with tachyon exchange between two parties, the new paradox
appears already in a one-way superluminal signaling, even without creating the
time loop. This produces a universal ban on superluminal signals, which is
stronger than the ban imposed by the Tolman paradox. The analysis also shows
that records of evolution of a superluminal object observed from two different
reference frames may be time-reversed with respect to each other. Interactions
with such objects could add some new features to spectroscopy.
  Even though relativity embraces superluminal motions, thus making the world
symmetric with respect to the invariant speed barrier, their ineptness for
signaling makes the symmetry incomplete.
  Key words: superluminal signaling, tachyons, the Tolman paradox
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03068</id><created>2015-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jieun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mak</keyname><forenames>Kin Fai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical control of the valley Hall effect in bilayer MoS2 transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Nanotechnology 11, 421 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nnano.2015.337</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The valley degree of freedom of electrons in solids has been proposed as a
new type of information carriers beyond the electronic charge and spin. Recent
experimental demonstrations of the optical orientation of the valley
polarization and generation of the valley current through the valley Hall
effect in monolayer MoS2 have shown the potential of two-dimensional
semiconductor transition metal dichalcogenides for valley based electronic and
optoelectronic applications. The valley Hall conductivity in monolayer MoS2, a
non-centrosymmetric crystal, however, cannot be easily tuned, presenting a
challenge for valley-based applications. Here we report the control of the
valley Hall effect in bilayer MoS2 transistors through a gate. The inversion
symmetry present in bilayer MoS2 was broken by the gate applied electric field
perpendicular to the plane. The valley polarization near the edges of the
device channels induced by the longitudinal electrical current was imaged by
use of Kerr rotation microscopy. The polarization is out-of-plane, has opposite
sign for the two edges, and is strongly dependent on the gate voltage. The
observation is consistent with the symmetry dependent Berry curvature and
valley Hall conductivity in bilayer MoS2. Our results are another step towards
information processing based on the valley degree of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05025</id><created>2015-08-20</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bachmann</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genoud</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Mean-field limit and phase transitions for nematic liquid crystals in
  the continuum</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>Substantial revision due to a mistake in the proof of the
  'Gross-Pitaevskii' limit. The paper now focuses on the mean-field regime.
  Title and abstract modified. Remark 2 comments on the restriction to
  homogeneous systems made throughout the phase transition analysis. This
  version will appear in J. Stat. Phys</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss thermotropic nematic liquid crystals in the mean-field regime. In
the first part of this article, we rigorously carry out the mean-field limit of
a system of $N$ rod-like particles as $N\to\infty$, which yields an effective
`one-body' free energy functional. In the second part, we focus on spatially
homogeneous systems, for which we study the associated Euler-Lagrange equation,
with a focus on phase transitions for general axisymmetric potentials. We prove
that the system is isotropic at high temperature, while anisotropic
distributions appear through a transcritical bifurcation as the temperature is
lowered. Finally, as the temperature goes to zero we also prove, in the
concrete case of the Maier-Saupe potential, that the system converges to
perfect nematic order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00597</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mishchenko</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Chueng-Ryong</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter phenomenology of high speed galaxy cluster collisions</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform a general computational analysis of possible post-collision mass
distributions in high-speed galaxy cluster collisions in the presence of weakly
self-interacting dark matter. Using this analysis, we show that weakly
self-scattering dark matter can impart subtle yet measurable features in the
mass distributions of colliding galaxy clusters even without significant
disruptions to the dark matter halos of the colliding galaxy clusters
themselves. Most profound such evidences are found to reside in the tails of
dark matter halos' distributions, in the space between the colliding galaxy
clusters. This feature appears in our simulations as shells of scattered dark
matter expanding in alignment with the outgoing original galaxy clusters,
contributing significant densities to projected mass distributions at large
distances from collision centers and large scattering angles up to $90^\circ$.
Our simulations indicate that as much as 20% of the total collision's mass may
be deposited into such structures without noticeable disruptions to the main
galaxy clusters. Such structures at large scattering angles are forbidden
however in purely gravitational high-speed galaxy cluster collisions.
Convincing identification of such structures in real colliding galaxy clusters
would be a clear indication of the self-interacting nature of dark matter. Our
findings may explain the dark matter ring feature recently found in the
long-range reconstructions of the mass distribution of the colliding galaxy
cluster CL0024+017.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02238</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>McDonald</keyname><forenames>Jamie I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shore</keyname><forenames>Graham M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Leptogenesis from loop effects in curved spacetime</title><categories>hep-ph gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Some corrections to the results for diagram (3)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a new mechanism - radiatively-induced gravitational leptogenesis
- for generating the matter-antimatter asymmetry of the Universe. We show how
quantum loop effects in C and CP violating theories cause matter and antimatter
to propagate differently in the presence of gravity, and prove this is
forbidden in flat space by CPT and translation symmetry. This generates a
curvature-dependent chemical potential for leptons, allowing a
matter-antimatter asymmetry to be generated in thermal equilibrium in the early
Universe. The time-dependent dynamics necessary for leptogenesis is provided by
the interaction of the virtual self-energy cloud of the leptons with the
expanding curved spacetime background, which violates the strong equivalence
principle and allows a distinction between matter and antimatter. We show here
how this mechanism is realised in a particular BSM theory, the see-saw model,
where the quantum loops involve the heavy sterile neutrinos responsible for
light neutrino masses. We demonstrate by explicit computation of the relevant
two-loop Feynman diagrams how these radiative corrections display the necessary
dependence on the sterile neutrino masses to generate an asymmetry, and show
how the induced lepton asymmetry may be sufficiently large to play an important
role in determining the baryon-to-photon ratio of the Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05649</id><created>2016-01-21</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Danning</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on stability of new hyperbolic AdS black holes and phase
  transitions in R\'{e}nyi entropies</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>40 Pages, 18 figures. Title changed, References updated, Structure
  reorganized, Typos and Mistakes corrected. Accepted by NPB</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a series of new hyperbolic black hole solutions in
Einstein-Scalar system and we apply holographic approach to investigate the
spherical R\'{e}nyi entropy in various deformations of dual conformal field
theories (CFTs). Especially, we introduce various powers of scalars in the
scalar potentials for massive and massless scalar. These scalar potentials
correspond to deformation of dual CFTs. Then we solve asymptotically hyperbolic
AdS black hole solutions numerically. We map the instabilities of these black
hole solutions to phase transitions of field theory in terms of CHM mapping
between hyperbolic hairy AdS black hole and spherical R\'{e}nyi entropy in dual
field theories. Based on these solutions, we study the temperature dependent
condensation of dual operator of massive and massless scalar respectively.
These condensations show that there might exist phase transitions in dual
deformed CFTs. We also compare free energy between asymptotically hyperbolic
AdS black hole solutions and hyperbolic AdS Schwarz (AdS-SW) black hole to test
phase transitions. In order to confirm the existence of phase transitions, we
turn on linear in-homogenous perturbation to test stability of these hyperbolic
hairy AdS black holes. In this paper, we show how potential parameters affect
the stability of hyperbolic black holes in several specific examples. For
general values of potential parameters, it needs further studies to see how the
transition happens. Finally, we comment on these instabilities associated with
spherical R\'{e}nyi entropy in dual deformed CFTs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03416</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal restriction: The trichordal case</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>50 pages, to appear in PTRF</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of conformal restriction properties in two-dimensions has been
initiated by Lawler, Schramm and Werner who focused on the natural and
important chordal case: They characterized and constructed all random subsets
of a given simply connected domain that join two marked boundary points and
that satisfy the additional restriction property. The radial case (sets joining
an inside point to a boundary point) has then been investigated by Wu. In the
present paper, we study the third natural instance of such restriction
properties, namely the &quot;trichordal case&quot;, where one looks at random sets that
join three marked boundary points. This case involves somewhat more
technicalities than the other two, as the construction of this family of random
sets relies on special variants of SLE$_{8/3}$ processes with a drift term in
the driving function that involves hypergeometric functions. It turns out that
such a random set can not be a simple curve simultaneously in the neighborhood
of all three marked points, and that the exponent $\alpha = 20/27$ shows up in
the description of the law of the skinniest possible symmetric random set with
this trichordal restriction property.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07278</id><created>2016-02-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Muljarov</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langbein</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Normalization of quasinormal modes in leaky optical cavities
  and plasmonic resonators&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. This is a Comment on [Kristensen et al., PRA 92,
  053810 (2015)]</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 017801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.017801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, Kristensen, Ge and Hughes have compared [Phys. Rev. A 92, 053810
(2015)] three different methods for normalization of quasinormal modes in open
optical systems, and concluded that they all provide the same result. We show
here that this conclusion is incorrect and illustrate that the normalization of
[Opt. Lett. 37, 1649 (2012)] is divergent for any optical mode having a finite
quality factor, and that the Silver-Mueller radiation condition is not
fulfilled for quasinormal modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03224</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barrett</keyname><forenames>Owen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkhardt</keyname><forenames>Paula</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeWitt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dorward</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Steven J.</forenames></author></authors><title>One-Level density for holomorphic cusp forms of arbitrary level</title><categories>math.NT math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Version 2.0, 26 pages</comments><msc-class>11M26 (primary), 11M41, 15A52 (secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2000 Iwaniec, Luo, and Sarnak proved for certain families of $L$-functions
associated to holomorphic newforms of square-free level that, under the
Generalized Riemann Hypothesis, as the conductors tend to infinity the
one-level density of their zeros matches the one-level density of eigenvalues
of large random matrices from certain classical compact groups in the
appropriate scaling limit. We remove the square-free restriction by obtaining a
trace formula for arbitrary level by using a basis developed by Blomer and
Mili\'cevi\'c, which is of use for other problems as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06613</id><created>2016-04-22</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kosyakov</keyname><forenames>B P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>E Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vronskii</keyname><forenames>M A</forenames></author></authors><title>Could the static properties of nuclei be deduced from the dynamics of a
  single quark?</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures; v2: published version, the title is somewhat
  changed, several conceptual clarifications are added</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2017) 53: 82</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12275-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the static properties of a nucleus could arise from a single
quark moving in a mean field generated by all other constituents of this
nucleus. The resulting model provides a way for determining the nuclear sizes
characteristic of the liquid drop model, and reasonably accurate values of
magnetic moments of different nuclei with the aid of two parameters $\alpha_s$
and $\sigma$ appearing in the Cornell potential intended for use in quarkonium
physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01965</id><created>2016-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Vaccaro</keyname><forenames>Joan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>An anomaly in space and time and the origin of dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, 1 equation. Invited essay for volume on &quot;Space,
  Time, and Frontiers of Human Understanding&quot;</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-44418-5_15</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Hamiltonian defines the dynamical properties of the universe. Evidence
from particle physics shows that there is a different version of the
Hamiltonian for each direction of time. As there is no physical basis for the
universe to be asymmetric in time, both versions must operate equally. However,
conventional physical theories accommodate only one version of the Hamiltonian
and one direction of time. This represents an unexplained anomaly in
conventional physics and calls for a reworking of the concepts of time and
space. Here I explain how the anomaly can be resolved by allowing dynamics to
emerge phenomenologically. The resolution offers a picture of time and space
that lies below our everyday experience, and one in which their differences are
epiphenomenal rather than elemental.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01367</id><created>2016-06-04</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Chitradip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Manoranjan P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of polarization on the structure of electromagnetic field and
  spatiotemporal distribution of $e^+e^-$ pairs by colliding laser pulses</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Experimental and Theoretical Physics, 2017, Vol. 125,
  No. 1, pp. 12-21</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776117060097</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron-positron pair production by means of vacuum polarization in the
presence of strong electromagnetic (EM) field of two counterpropagating laser
pulses is studied. A 3-dimensional model of the focused laser pulses based on
the solution of the Maxwell's equations proposed by Narozhny and Fofanov is
used to find the structure of EM field of the circularly polarized
counterpropagating pulses. Analytical calculations show that the electric and
magnetic fields are almost parallel to each other in the focal region when
pulses are completely transverse either in electric (e-wave) or magnetic
(h-wave) field. On the other hand the electric and magnetic fields are almost
orthogonal when the counterpropagating pulses are made up of equal mixture of
e- and h- polarized waves. It is found that while the latter configuration of
the colliding pulses has much larger threshold for pair production it can
provide much shorter electron/positron pulses compared to the former case. The
dependence of pair production and its spatiotemporal distribution on
polarization of the laser pulses is analyzed using the structure of the EM
field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00379</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lahoche</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samary</keyname><forenames>Dine Ousmane</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional renormalization group for the $U(1)$-$T_5^6$ tensorial group
  field theory with closure constraint</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 045013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.045013</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is focused on the functional renormalization group applied to the
$T_5^6$ tensor model on the Abelian group $U(1)$ with closure constraint. For
the first time, we derive the flow equations for the couplings and mass
parameters in a suitable truncation around the marginal interactions with
respect to the perturbative power counting. For the second time, we study the
behavior around the Gaussian fixed point, and show that the theory is
nonasymptotically free. Finally, we discuss the UV completion of the theory. We
show the existence of several nontrivial fixed points, study the behavior of
the renormalization group flow around them, and point out evidence in favor of
an asymptotically safe theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07144</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sangmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seong</keyname><forenames>Rak-Kyeong</forenames></author></authors><title>Orbifold Reduction and 2d (0,2) Gauge Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>32 pages, 25 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1703:016,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce Orbifold Reduction, a new method for generating $2d$ $(0,2)$
gauge theories associated to D1-branes probing singular toric Calabi-Yau
4-folds starting from $4d$ $\mathcal{N}=1$ gauge theories on D3-branes probing
toric Calabi-Yau 3-folds. The new procedure generalizes dimensional reduction
and orbifolding. In terms of T-dual configurations, it generates brane brick
models starting from brane tilings. Orbifold reduction provides an agile
approach for generating $2d$ $(0,2)$ theories with a brane realization. We
present three practical applications of the new algorithm: the connection
between $4d$ Seiberg duality and $2d$ triality, a combinatorial method for
generating theories related by triality and a $2d$ $(0,2)$ generalization of
the Klebanov-Witten mass deformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07796</id><created>2016-09-25</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Behfarnia</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eslami</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Error Correction Coding Meets Cyber-Physical Systems: Message-Passing
  Analysis of Self-Healing Interdependent Networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1606.00955</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coupling cyber and physical systems gives rise to numerous engineering
challenges and opportunities. An important challenge is the contagion of
failure from one system to another, which can lead to large-scale cascading
failures. However, the self-healing ability emerges as a valuable opportunity
where the overlaying cyber network can cure failures in the underlying physical
network. To capture both self-healing and contagion, this paper considers a
graphical model representation of an interdependent cyber-physical system, in
which nodes represent various cyber or physical functionalities, and edges
capture the interactions between the nodes. A message-passing algorithm is
proposed for this representation to study the dynamics of failure propagation
and healing. By conducting a density evolution analysis for this algorithm,
network reaction to initial disruptions is investigated. It is proved that as
the number of message-passing iterations increases, the network reaches a
steady-state condition that would be either a complete healing or a complete
collapse. Then, a sufficient condition is derived to select the network
parameters to guarantee the complete healing of the system. The result of the
density evolution analysis is further employed to jointly optimize the design
of cyber and physical networks for maximum resiliency. This analytical
framework is then extended to the cases where propagation of failures in the
physical network is faster than the healing responses of the cyber network.
Such scenarios are of interest in many real-life applications such as smart
grid. Finally, extensive numerical results are presented to verify the analysis
and investigate the impact of the network parameters on the resiliency of the
network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08045</id><created>2016-09-26</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Zhongtao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolech</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Derivation of matrix product states for the Heisenberg spin chain with
  open boundary conditions</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 032127 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.032127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the algebraic Bethe ansatz, we derive a matrix product representation
of the exact Bethe-ansatz states of the six-vertex Heisenberg chain (either XXX
or XXZ and spin-$\frac{1}{2}$) with open boundary conditions. In this
representation, the components of the Bethe eigenstates are expressed as traces
of products of matrices which act on a tensor product of auxiliary spaces. As
compared to the matrix product states of the same Heisenberg chain but with
periodic boundary conditions, the dimension of the exact auxiliary matrices is
enlarged as if the conserved number of spin-flips considered would have been
doubled. This result is generic for any non-nested integrable model, as is
clear from our derivation and we further show by providing an additional
example of the same matrix product state construction for a well known model of
a gas of interacting bosons. Counterintuitively, the matrices do not depend on
the spatial coordinate despite the open boundaries and thus suggest generic
ways of exploiting (emergent) translational invariance both for finite size and
in the thermodynamic limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06938</id><created>2016-10-21</created><updated>2017-01-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Manashov</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skvortsov</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-spin currents in the Gross-Neveu model at $1/n^2$</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures; replaced with the revised version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2017)132</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the anomalous dimensions of higher-spin currents, both singlet
and non-singlet, in the Gross-Neveu model at the $1/n^2$ order. It was
conjectured that in the critical regime this model is dual to a higher-spin
gauge theory on $AdS_4$. The $AdS/CFT$ correspondence predicts that the masses
of higher-spin fields correspond to the scaling dimensions of the singlet
currents in the Gross-Neveu model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05237</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beau</keyname><forenames>Mathieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>del Campo</keyname><forenames>Adolfo</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear quantum metrology of many-body open systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5+9 pp, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 010403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.010403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce general bounds for the parameter estimation error in nonlinear
quantum metrology of many-body open systems in the Markovian limit. Given a
$k$-body Hamiltonian and $p$-body Lindblad operators, the estimation error of a
Hamitonian parameter using a Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) state as a probe
is shown to scale as $N^{-\left(k-\frac{p}{2}\right)}$, surpassing the
shot-noise limit for $2k&gt;p+1$. Metrology equivalence between initial product
states and maximally entangled states is established for $p\geq 1$. We further
show that one can estimate the system-environment coupling parameter with
precision $N^{-\frac{p}{2}}$, while many-body decoherence enhances the
precision to $N^{-k}$ in the noise-amplitude estimation of a fluctuating
$k$-body Hamiltonian. For the long-range Ising model we show that the precision
of this parameter beats the shot-noise limit when the range of interactions is
below a threshold value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06859</id><created>2016-12-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sangmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seong</keyname><forenames>Rak-Kyeong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vafa</keyname><forenames>Cumrun</forenames></author></authors><title>Quadrality for Supersymmetric Matrix Models</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>46 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1707:053,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new duality for $\mathcal{N}=1$ supersymmetric gauged matrix
models. This $0d$ duality is an order 4 symmetry, namely an equivalence between
four different theories, hence we call it Quadrality. Our proposal is motivated
by mirror symmetry, but is not restricted to theories with a D-brane
realization and holds for general $\mathcal{N}=1$ matrix models. We present
various checks of the proposal, including the matching of: global symmetries,
anomalies, deformations and the chiral ring. We also consider quivers and the
corresponding quadrality networks. Finally, we initiate the study of matrix
models that arise on the worldvolume of D(-1)-branes probing toric Calabi-Yau
5-folds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07095</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07095</id><created>2016-12-21</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Anisur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasmin</keyname><forenames>Safia</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauged Floreanini-Jackiw type chiral boson and its BRST quantization</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages latex, slight changes in references and minor changesin the
  body</comments><journal-ref>Annals Phys. 383 (2017) 497-510</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gauged model of Siegel type chiral boson is considered. It has been shown
that the action of gauged model of Floreanini-Jackiw (FJ) type chiral boson is
contained in it in an interesting manner. A BRST invariant action corresponding
to the action of gauged FJ type chiral boson has been formulated using Batalin,
Fradkin and Vilkovisky based improved Fujiwara, Igarishi and Kubo (FIK)
formalism. An alternative quantization of the gauge symmetric action has been
made with a Lorentz gauge and an attempt has been made to establish the
equivalence between the gauge symmetric version of the extended phase space and
original gauge non-invariant version of the usual phase space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01693</id><created>2017-01-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kromer</keyname><forenames>Justus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khaledi-Nasab</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimansky-Geier</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neiman</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent stochastic oscillations and signal detection in tree networks
  of excitable elements</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.AO q-bio.NC</categories><comments>15 pages 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 3956 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-04193-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the stochastic dynamics of strongly-coupled excitable elements on a
tree network. The peripheral nodes receive independent random inputs which may
induce large spiking events propagating through the branches of the tree and
leading to global coherent oscillations in the network. This scenario may be
relevant to action potential generation in certain sensory neurons, which
possess myelinated distal dendritic tree-like arbors with excitable nodes of
Ranvier at peripheral and branching nodes and exhibit noisy periodic sequences
of action potentials.
  We focus on the spiking statistics of the central node, which fires in
response to a noisy input at peripheral nodes. We show that, in the strong
coupling regime, relevant to myelinated dendritic trees, the spike train
statistics can be predicted from an isolated excitable element with rescaled
parameters according to the network topology. Furthermore, we show that by
varying the network topology the spike train statistics of the central node can
be tuned to have a certain firing rate and variability, or to allow for an
optimal discrimination of inputs applied at the peripheral nodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07700</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07700</id><created>2017-01-26</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hohmann</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Post-Newtonian parameter $\gamma$ and the deflection of light in
  ghost-free massive bimetric gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>36 pages, 1 figure; journal version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 124049 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.124049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the parametrized post-Newtonian (PPN) limit of ghost-free massive
bimetric gravity with two mutually non-interacting matter sectors coupled to
the two metrics. Making use of a gauge-invariant differential decomposition of
the metric perturbations, we solve the field equations up to the linear PPN
order for a static, point-like mass source. From the result we derive the PPN
parameter $\gamma$ for spherically symmetric systems, which describes the
gravitational deflection of light by visible matter. By a comparison to its
value measured in the solar system we obtain bounds on the parameters of the
theory. We further discuss the deflection of light by dark matter and find an
agreement with the observed light deflection by galaxies. We finally speculate
about a possible explanation for the observed distribution of dark matter in
galactic mergers such as Abell 520 and Abell 3827.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07772</id><created>2017-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Serbyn</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abanin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Loschmidt Echo in Many-Body Localized Phase</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>NSF-KITP-17-015</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 014202 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.014202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Loschmidt echo, defined as the overlap between quantum wave function
evolved with different Hamiltonians, quantifies the sensitivity of quantum
dynamics to perturbations and is often used as a probe of quantum chaos. In
this work we consider the behavior of the Loschmidt echo in the many body
localized phase, which is characterized by emergent local integrals of motion,
and provides a generic example of non-ergodic dynamics. We demonstrate that the
fluctuations of the Loschmidt echo decay as a power law in time in the
many-body localized phase, in contrast to the exponential decay in few-body
ergodic systems. We consider the spin-echo generalization of the Loschmidt
echo, and argue that the corresponding correlation function saturates to a
finite value in localized systems. Slow, power-law decay of fluctuations of
such spin-echo-type overlap is related to the operator spreading and is present
only in the many-body localized phase, but not in a non-interacting Anderson
insulator. While most of the previously considered probes of dephasing dynamics
could be understood by approximating physical spin operators with local
integrals of motion, the Loschmidt echo and its generalizations crucially
depend on the full expansion of the physical operators via local integrals of
motion operators, as well as operators which flip local integrals of motion.
Hence, these probes allow to get insights into the relation between physical
operators and local integrals of motion, and access the operator spreading in
the many-body localized phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.07973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.07973</id><created>2017-01-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kockum</keyname><forenames>Anton Frisk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macr&#xec;</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garziano</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savasta</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency conversion in ultrastrong cavity QED</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, 5313 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-04225-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new method for frequency conversion of photons which is both
versatile and deterministic. We show that a system with two resonators
ultrastrongly coupled to a single qubit can be used to realize both single- and
multiphoton frequency-conversion processes. The conversion can be exquisitely
controlled by tuning the qubit frequency to bring the desired
frequency-conversion transitions on or off resonance. Considering recent
experimental advances in ultrastrong coupling for circuit QED and other
systems, we believe that our scheme can be implemented using available
technology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02307</id><created>2017-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiranzaei</keyname><forenames>Mahroo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parhizgar</keyname><forenames>Fariborz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheraghchi</keyname><forenames>Hosein</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Rashba splitting on RKKY interaction in topological insulator
  thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024413 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we have investigated the effect of Rashba splitting on the RKKY
interaction in TI thin film both at finite and zero chemical potential. We find
that the spin susceptibility of Rashba materials including TI thin film is
strongly dependent on the direction of distance vector. Moreover, we find
another term in the off-diagonal terms of the spin-susceptibility tensor which
in contrast to the well-known DM-like term is symmetric. We show how one can
tune the RKKY interaction by using electric field applied perpendicularly to
the surface plane and by small chemical doping giving rise to enhance the RKKY
term, drastically. We have presented our results for two different situations,
namely inter-surface pairing of magnetic impurities as well as intra-surface
one. The behavior of these two situations is completely different which we
describe it by mapping the density of states of each surface on the band
dispersion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02948</id><created>2017-02-09</created><updated>2017-06-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghim</keyname><forenames>Dongwook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sangmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seong</keyname><forenames>Rak-Kyeong</forenames></author></authors><title>Elliptic Genera of 2d (0,2) Gauge Theories from Brane Brick Models</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>56 pages, 15 figures; v2. references added; v3. a reference and a
  comment on a fixed point index theorem added</comments><report-no>CCNY-HEP-17-01, SNUTP17-002, UUITP-05/17</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1706:068,2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the elliptic genus of abelian 2d (0,2) gauge theories
corresponding to brane brick models. These theories are worldvolume theories on
a single D1-brane probing a toric Calabi-Yau 4-fold singularity. We identify a
match with the elliptic genus of the non-linear sigma model on the same
Calabi-Yau background, which is computed using a new localization formula. The
matching implies that the quantum effects do not drastically alter the
correspondence between the geometry and the 2d (0,2) gauge theory. In theories
whose matter sector suffers from abelian gauge anomaly, we propose an ansatz
for an anomaly cancelling term in the integral formula for the elliptic genus.
We provide an example in which two brane brick models related to each other by
Gadde-Gukov-Putrov triality give the same elliptic genus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03774</id><created>2017-02-13</created><updated>2017-04-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>U. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia-Flores</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lograsso</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barberis</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaknin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Granado</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nematic Fluctuations and Phase Transitions in LaFeAsO: a Raman
  Scattering Study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 014506 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.014506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Raman scattering experiments on LaFeAsO with splitted antiferromagnetic
(T_AFM = 140 K) and tetragonal-orthorhombic (T_S = 155 K) transitions show a
quasi-elastic peak (QEP) in B2g symmetry (2 Fe tetragonal cell) that fades away
below ~T_AFM and is ascribed to electronic nematic fluctuations. A scaling of
the reported shear modulus with the T-dependence of the QEP height rather than
the QEP area indicates that magnetic degrees of freedom drive the structural
transition. The large separation between T_S and T_AFM in LaFeAsO compared with
their coincidence in BaFe2As2 manifests itself in slower dynamics of nematic
fluctuations in the former.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03784</id><created>2017-02-13</created><updated>2017-06-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Bongjae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khmelevskyi</keyname><forenames>Sergii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agterberg</keyname><forenames>D. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franchini</keyname><forenames>Cesare</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropy of magnetic interactions and symmetry of the order parameter
  in unconventional superconductor Sr$_{2}$RuO$_{4}$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>npj Quantum Materials 2 37 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41535-017-0041-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sr$_2$RuO$_4$ is the best candidate for spin-triplet superconductivity, an
unusual and elusive superconducting state of fundamental importance. In the
last three decades Sr$_2$RuO$_4$ has been very carefully studied and despite
its apparent simplicity when compared with strongly correlated high-$T_{c}$
cuprates, for which the pairing symmetry is understood, there is no scenario
that can explain all the major experimental observations, a conundrum that has
generated tremendous interest. Here we present a density-functional based
analysis of magnetic interactions in Sr$_{2}$RuO$_{4}$ and discuss the role of
magnetic anisotropy in its unconventional superconductivity. Our goal is
twofold. First, we access the possibility of the superconducting order
parameter rotation in an external magnetic field of 200 Oe, and conclude that
the spin-orbit interaction in this material is several orders of magnitude too
strong to be consistent with this hypothesis. Thus, the observed invariance of
the Knight shift across $T_{c}$ has no plausible explanation, and casts doubt
on using the Knight shift as an ultimate litmus paper for the pairing symmetry.
Second, we propose a quantitative double-exchange-like model for combining
itinerant fermions with an anisotropic Heisenberg magnetic Hamiltonian. This
model is complementary to the Hubbard-model-based calculations published so
far, and forms an alternative framework for exploring superconducting symmetry
in Sr$_{2}$RuO$_{4}.$ As an example, we use this model to analyze the
degeneracy between various $p-$triplet states in the simplest mean-field
approximation, and show that it splits into a single and two doublets with the
ground state defined by the competition between the &quot;Ising&quot; and &quot;compass&quot;
anisotropic terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04210</id><created>2017-02-14</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ljubotina</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Znidaric</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prosen</keyname><forenames>Tomaz</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin diffusion from an inhomogeneous quench in an integrable system</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures, version as accepted by Nature Communications</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 16117 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms16117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generalised hydrodynamics predicts universal ballistic transport in
integrable lattice systems when prepared in generic inhomogeneous initial
states. However, the ballistic contribution to transport can vanish in systems
with additional discrete symmetries. Here we perform large scale numerical
simulations of spin dynamics in the anisotropic Heisenberg $XXZ$ spin $1/2$
chain starting from an inhomogeneous mixed initial state which is symmetric
with respect to a combination of spin-reversal and spatial reflection. In the
isotropic and easy-axis regimes we find non-ballistic spin transport which we
analyse in detail in terms of scaling exponents of the transported
magnetisation and scaling profiles of the spin density. While in the easy-axis
regime we find accurate evidence of normal diffusion, the spin transport in the
isotropic case is clearly super-diffusive, with the scaling exponent very close
to $2/3$, but with universal scaling dynamics which obeys the diffusion
equation in nonlinearly scaled time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05009</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dabbech</keyname><forenames>Arwa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolz</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratley</keyname><forenames>Luke</forenames></author><author><keyname>McEwen</keyname><forenames>Jason D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiaux</keyname><forenames>Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>The w-effect in interferometric imaging: from a fast sparse measurement
  operator to super-resolution</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1775</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern radio telescopes, such as the Square Kilometre Array (SKA), will probe
the radio sky over large fields-of-view, which results in large w-modulations
of the sky image. This effect complicates the relationship between the measured
visibilities and the image under scrutiny. In algorithmic terms, it gives rise
to massive memory and computational time requirements. Yet, it can be a
blessing in terms of reconstruction quality of the sky image. In recent years,
several works have shown that large w-modulations promote the spread spectrum
effect. Within the compressive sensing framework, this effect increases the
incoherence between the sensing basis and the sparsity basis of the signal to
be recovered, leading to better estimation of the sky image. In this article,
we revisit the w-projection approach using convex optimisation in realistic
settings, where the measurement operator couples the w-terms in Fourier and the
de-gridding kernels. We provide sparse, thus fast, models of the Fourier part
of the measurement operator through adaptive sparsification procedures.
Consequently, memory requirements and computational cost are significantly
alleviated, at the expense of introducing errors on the radio-interferometric
data model. We present a first investigation of the impact of the sparse
variants of the measurement operator on the image reconstruction quality. We
finally analyse the interesting super-resolution potential associated with the
spread spectrum effect of the w-modulation, and showcase it through
simulations. Our C++ code is available online on GitHub.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06424</id><created>2017-02-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiranzaei</keyname><forenames>Mahroo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parhizgar</keyname><forenames>Fariborz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fransson</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheraghchi</keyname><forenames>Hosein</forenames></author></authors><title>Impurity scattering on the surface of topological insulator thin films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235429 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235429</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the electronic structure of the surface states of topological
insulator thin films with embedded local non-magnetic and magnetic impurities.
Using the $T$-matrix expansion of the real space Green's function, we derive
the local density of electrons states and corresponding spin resolved
densities. We show that the effects of the impurities can be tuned by applying
an electric field between the surface layers. The emerging magnetic states are
expected to play an important role both in ferromagnetic mechanism of magnetic
topological insulators as well as in its transport properties. In the case of
magnetic impurities, we have categorized the possible cases for different
spin-directions of the impurities as well as the spin-direction in which the
spin resolved density of electron states is calculated and related this to the
spin susceptibility of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06603</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06603</id><created>2017-02-21</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tyson</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghose</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Thermal Motion in Halide Perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solar cells based on hybrid perovskites have shown high efficiency while
possessing simple processing methods. To gain a fundamental understanding of
their properties on an atomic level, we investigate single crystals of
CH3NH3PbI3 with a narrow transition (~5 K) near 327 K. Temperature dependent
structural measurements reveal a persistent tetragonal structure with smooth
changes in the atomic displacement parameters (ADPs) on crossing T*. We show
that the ADPs for I ions yield extended flat regions in the potential wells
consistent with the measured large thermal expansion parameter. Molecular
dynamics simulations reveal that this material exhibits significant high
asymmetries in the Pb-I pair distribution functions. We also show that the
intrinsically enhanced freedom of motion of the iodine atoms enables large
deformations. This flexibility (softness) of the atomic structure results in
highly localized atomic relaxation about defects and hence accounts for both
the high carrier mobility as well as the structural instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06928</id><created>2017-02-22</created><updated>2017-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamada</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>Min-Seok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiu</keyname><forenames>Gary</forenames></author></authors><title>Memory in de Sitter space and BMS-like supertranslations</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figures, published version</comments><report-no>MAD-TH-17-01</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 023509 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.023509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that the memory effect in flat spacetime is parametrized by
the BMS supertranslation. We investigate the relation between the memory effect
and diffeomorphism in de Sitter spacetime. We find that gravitational memory is
parametrized by a BMS-like supertranslation in the static patch of de Sitter
spacetime. We also show a diffeomorphism that corresponds to gravitational
memory in the Poincare/cosmological patch. Our method does not need to assume
the separation between the source and the detector to be small compared with
the Hubble radius, and can potentially be applicable to other FLRW universes,
as well as &quot;ordinary memory&quot; mediated by massive messenger particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00300</id><created>2017-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruglov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barzda</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified Gibbs's representation of rotation matrix</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Annales de la Fondation Louis de Broglie, Vol. 42, No 2 (2017)
  1-15</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A modified Gibbs's rotation matrix is derived and the connection with the
Euler angles, quaternions, and Cayley$-$Klein parameters is established. As
particular cases, the Rodrigues and Gibbs parameterizations of the rotation are
obtained. The composition law of two rotations from the quaternion
representation is presented showing a convenient expression for calculating the
successive rotations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01630</id><created>2017-03-05</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of double-differential cross sections for top quark pair
  production in pp collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV and impact on parton
  distribution functions</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with the published version. Added the journal reference and
  DOI. All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/TOP-14-013</comments><report-no>CMS-TOP-14-013, CERN-EP-2017-030</report-no><journal-ref>EPJC 77 (2017) 459</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4984-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Normalized double-differential cross sections for top quark pair (t t-bar)
production are measured in pp collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV
with the CMS experiment at the LHC. The analyzed data correspond to an
integrated luminosity of 19.7 inverse femtobarns. The measurement is performed
in the dilepton e+/- mu-/+ final state. The t t-bar cross section is determined
as a function of various pairs of observables characterizing the kinematics of
the top quark and t t-bar system. The data are compared to calculations using
perturbative quantum chromodynamics at next-to-leading and approximate
next-to-next-to-leading orders. They are also compared to predictions of Monte
Carlo event generators that complement fixed-order computations with parton
showers, hadronization, and multiple-parton interactions. Overall agreement is
observed with the predictions, which is improved when the latest global sets of
proton parton distribution functions are used. The inclusion of the measured t
t-bar cross sections in a fit of parametrized parton distribution functions is
shown to have significant impact on the gluon distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04472</id><created>2017-03-13</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dhont</keyname><forenames>Guillaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwai</keyname><forenames>Toshihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhilinskii</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Phase Transition in a Molecular Hamiltonian with Symmetry
  and Pseudo-Symmetry, Studied through Quantum, Semi-Quantum and Classical
  Models</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP physics.chem-ph</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><journal-ref>SIGMA 13 (2017), 054, 34 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2017.054</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  The redistribution of energy levels between energy bands is studied for a
family of simple effective Hamiltonians depending on one control parameter and
possessing axial symmetry and energy-reflection symmetry. Further study is made
on the topological phase transition in the corresponding semi-quantum and
completely classical models, and finally the joint spectrum of the two
commuting observables $(H=E,J_z)$ (also called the lattice of quantum states)
is superposed on the image of the energy-momentum map for the classical model.
Through these comparative analyses, mutual correspondence is demonstrated to
exist among the redistribution of energy levels between energy bands for the
quantum Hamiltonian, the modification of Chern numbers of eigenline bundles for
the corresponding semi-quantum Hamiltonian, and the presence of Hamiltonian
monodromy for the complete classical analog. In particular, as far as the band
rearrangement is concerned, a fine agreement is found between the
redistribution of the energy levels described in terms of joint spectrum of
energy and momentum in the full quantum model and the evolution of
singularities of the energy-momentum map of the complete classical model. The
topological phase transition observed in the present semi-quantum and the
complete classical models are analogous to topological phase transitions of
matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04596</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prolhac</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author></authors><title>Perturbative solution for the spectral gap of the weakly asymmetric
  exclusion process</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>28 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 315001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa77de</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the weakly asymmetric exclusion process with $N=L/2$ particles on
a periodic lattice of $L$ sites, and hopping rates $1$ and $q=1-\mu/\sqrt{L}$
respectively in the forward and in the backward direction. Using Bethe ansatz,
we obtain a systematic perturbative expansion of the spectral gap near $\mu=0$
by solving order by order a simple functional equation. A key point is that
when $\mu\to0$, Bethe roots at a distance $1/\sqrt{L}$ from the edge of the
Fermi sea should not be considered as a continuum, but converge instead at
large $L$ to the complex zeroes of $1+\mathrm{erf}(x)$ after a rescaling by
$\sqrt{L}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04899</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Due&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastrandrea</keyname><forenames>Rossana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barigozzi</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fagiolo</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatio-Temporal Patterns of the International Merger and Acquisition
  Network</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper analyses the world web of mergers and acquisitions (M&amp;As) using a
complex network approach. We use data of M&amp;As to build a temporal sequence of
binary and weighted-directed networks for the period 1995-2010 and 224
countries (nodes) connected according to their M&amp;As flows (links). We study
different geographical and temporal aspects of the international M&amp;A network
(IMAN), building sequences of filtered sub-networks whose links belong to
specific intervals of distance or time. Given that M&amp;As and trade are
complementary ways of reaching foreign markets, we perform our analysis using
statistics employed for the study of the international trade network (ITN),
highlighting the similarities and differences between the ITN and the IMAN. In
contrast to the ITN, the IMAN is a low density network characterized by a
persistent giant component with many external nodes and low reciprocity.
Clustering patterns are very heterogeneous and dynamic. High-income economies
are the main acquirers and are characterized by high connectivity, implying
that most countries are targets of a few acquirers. Like in the ITN,
geographical distance strongly impacts the structure of the IMAN: link-weights
and node degrees have a non-linear relation with distance, and an assortative
pattern is present at short distances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00251</id><created>2017-04-02</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Setare</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adami</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropy Formula and Conserved Charges of Spin-3 Chern-Simons-Like
  Theories of Gravity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present the generalization of Chern-Simons-like theories of
gravity (CSLTG) to spin-3. We propose a Lagrangian describing the spin-3 fields
coupled to Chern-Simons-like theories of gravity. Then we obtain conserved
charges of these theories by using a quasi-local formalism. We find a general
formula for entropy of black holes solutions of Spin-3 CSLTG. As an example, we
apply our formalism to the spin-3 Generalized minimal massive gravity (GMMG)
model. We analysis this model at linearized level and show that this model
propagate two massive spin-2 modes and two massive spin-3 modes. We find
no-ghost and no-tachyon conditions, which can be satisfy in the parameter space
of the model. Then we find energy, angular momentum and entropy of a special
black hole solution of this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00750</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paz</keyname><forenames>Gil</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher dimensional HQET parameters</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, updated version based on version 2 of arXiv:1702.08904
  [hep-ph]</comments><report-no>WSU-HEP-1704</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effective field theories such as Heavy Quark Effective Theory (HQET) are
indispensable tools in controlling the effects of the strong interaction. The
increasing experimental precision requires the knowledge of higher dimensional
operators. We present a general method that allows for an easy construction of
HQET operators that contain two heavy quarks and any number of covariant
derivatives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03333</id><created>2017-04-08</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruggieri</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Guang Xiong</forenames></author></authors><title>La forma della Terra: una lezione sulla gravit\`a Newtoniana</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Lecture in Italian language, intended to be used in high school and
  university classes on general physics, as well as in introductory courses on
  the scientific method. 15 pages, 8 figures, uses gdf latex class</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest a lecture on Newtonian gravity, discussing how the use of the
scientific method allows to rule out some of the models for the shape of Earth
leaving a spherical Earth as the only possibility, in agreement with empirical
observation. In particular, we suggest to focus on a physical quantity, namely
the gravitational acceleration, that can be both computed theoretically and
measured in experiments. Rather than insisting on the numerical code for the
evaluation of the gravitational acceleration -- that can be computed anyway in
any numerical analysis course -- we want to focus on the formal setting of the
problem, emphasizing the importance of having a mathematical formulation
capable of quantitative predictions, present the result and discuss it both
qualitatively and quantitatively, comparing it with daily experience. We let
the student notice that assuming a non-spherical Earth would result in a
parallel component of the gravitational acceleration, in disagreement with
measurement; moreover, in case we consider a disk-shaped Earth we show that
this parallel component becomes more and more important as the boundaries of
Earth are approached by an observer. Finally, we make quantitative predictions
on how this abnormal component of the gravitational force would affect the free
fall motion. We think that the topics discussed here can be presented both in
high school and university classes of general physics, as well as in
introductory classes about the scientific method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05106</id><created>2017-04-17</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barnum</keyname><forenames>Howard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ciar&#xe1;n M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scandolo</keyname><forenames>Carlo Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selby</keyname><forenames>John H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ruling out higher-order interference from purity principles</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18+8 pages. Comments welcome. v2: Minor correction to Lemma 5.1, main
  results are unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 2017, 19(6), 253, Special issue &quot;Quantum Information and
  Foundations&quot; editors G. M. D'Ariano and P. Perinotti</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19060253</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As first noted by Rafael Sorkin, there is a limit to quantum interference.
The interference pattern formed in a multi-slit experiment is a function of the
interference patterns formed between pairs of slits, there are no genuinely new
features resulting from considering three slits instead of two. Sorkin has
introduced a hierarchy of mathematically conceivable higher-order interference
behaviours, where classical theory lies at the first level of this hierarchy
and quantum theory theory at the second. Informally, the order in this
hierarchy corresponds to the number of slits on which the interference pattern
has an irreducible dependence. Many authors have wondered why quantum
interference is limited to the second level of this hierarchy. Does the
existence of higher-order interference violate some natural physical principle
that we believe should be fundamental? In the current work we show that such
principles can be found which limit interference behaviour to second-order, or
&quot;quantum-like&quot;, interference, but that do not restrict us to the entire quantum
formalism. We work within the operational framework of generalised
probabilistic theories, and prove that any theory satisfying Causality, Purity
Preservation, Pure Sharpness, and Purification---four principles that formalise
the fundamental character of purity in nature---exhibits at most second-order
interference. Hence these theories are, at least conceptually, very &quot;close&quot; to
quantum theory. Along the way we show that systems in such theories correspond
to Euclidean Jordan algebras. Hence, they are self-dual and, moreover,
multi-slit experiments in such theories are described by pure projectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06414</id><created>2017-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Soobeom</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>Naoto</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Yuichiro</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Miwa</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames><affiliation>Osaka Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Yoshishige</forenames><affiliation>Osaka Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Koike</keyname><forenames>Hayato</forenames><affiliation>TDK Co</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shiraishi</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author></authors><title>Investigation of spin scattering mechanism in silicon channels of
  Fe/MgO/Si lateral spin valves</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures (to appear in Applied Physics Letters)</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4982966</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The temperature evolution of spin relaxation time, {\tau}sf, in degenerate
silicon (Si)-based lateral spin valves is investigated by means of the Hanle
effect measurements. {\tau}sf at 300 K is estimated to be 1.68+-0.03 ns and
monotonically increased with decreasing temperature down to 100 K. Below 100 K,
in contrast, it shows almost a constant value of ca. 5 ns. The temperature
dependence of the conductivity of the Si channel shows a similar behavior to
that of the {\tau}sf, i.e., monotonically increasing with decreasing
temperature down to 100 K and a weak temperature dependence below 100 K. The
temperature evolution of conductivity reveals that electron scattering due to
magnetic impurities is negligible. A comparison between {\tau}sf and momentum
scattering time reveals that the dominant spin scattering mechanism in the Si
is the Elliott-Yafet mechanism, and the ratio of the momentum scattering time
to the {\tau}sf attributed to nonmagnetic impurities is approximately
3.77*10^-6, which is more than two orders of magnitude smaller than that of
copper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07006</id><created>2017-04-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohshima</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Klingler</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames><affiliation>Walther-Meissner-Institut</affiliation><affiliation>TU-Muenchen</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dushenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ando</keyname><forenames>Yuichiro</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Weiler</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames><affiliation>Walther-Meissner-Institut</affiliation><affiliation>TU-Muenchen</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huebl</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames><affiliation>Walther-Meissner-Institut</affiliation><affiliation>TU-Muenchen</affiliation><affiliation>Nanosystems Initiative Munich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shinjo</keyname><forenames>Teruya</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goennenwein</keyname><forenames>Sebastian T. B.</forenames><affiliation>Walther-Meissner-Institut</affiliation><affiliation>TU-Muenchen</affiliation><affiliation>Nanosystems Initiative Munich</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shiraishi</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto Univ</affiliation></author></authors><title>Spin injection into silicon detected by broadband ferromagnetic
  resonance spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.acc-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other physics.app-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 Figures, 2 Tables (to appear Applied Physics Letters)</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4983012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We studied the spin injection in a NiFe(Py)/Si system using broadband
ferromagnetic resonance spectroscopy. The Gilbert damping parameter of the Py
layer on top of the Si channel was determined as a function of the Si doping
concentration and Py layer thickness. For fixed Py thickness we observed an
increase of the Gilbert damping parameter with decreasing resistivity of the Si
channel. For a fixed Si doping concentration we measured an increasing Gilbert
damping parameter for decreasing Py layer thickness. No increase of the Gilbert
damping parameter was found Py/Si samples with an insulating interlayer. We
attribute our observations to an enhanced spin injection into the
low-resistivity Si by spin pumping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07277</id><created>2017-04-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Shamirzaev</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rautert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakovlev</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debus</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gornov</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazov</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivchenko</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin dynamics and magnetic-field-induced polarization of excitons in
  ultrathin GaAs/AlAs quantum wells with indirect band gap and type-II band
  alignment</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exciton spin dynamics are investigated both experimentally and
theoretically in two-monolayer-thick GaAs/AlAs quantum wells with an indirect
band gap and a type-II band alignment. The magnetic-field-induced circular
polarization of photoluminescence, $P_c$, is studied as function of the
magnetic field strength and direction as well as sample temperature. The
observed nonmonotonic behaviour of these functions is provided by the interplay
of bright and dark exciton states contributing to the emission. To interpret
the experiment, we have developed a kinetic master equation model which
accounts for the dynamics of the spin states in this exciton quartet, radiative
and nonradiative recombination processes, and redistribution of excitons
between these states as result of spin relaxation. The model offers
quantitative agreement with experiment and allows us to evaluate, for the
studied structure, the heavy-hole $g$ factor, $g_{hh}=+3.5$, and the spin
relaxation times of electron, $\tau_{se} = 33~\mu$s, and hole, $\tau_{sh} =
3~\mu$s, bound in the exciton.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07318</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Skripnikov</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical study of HfF$^+$ cation to search for the T,P-odd
  interactions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 147, 021101 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The combined all-electron and two-step approach is applied to calculate the
molecular parameters which are required to interpret the ongoing experiment to
search for the effects of manifestation of the T,P-odd fundamental interactions
in the HfF$^+$ cation by Cornell/Ye group [Science 342, 1220 (2013); J. Mol.
Spectrosc. 300, 12 (2014)]. The effective electric field that is required to
interpret the experiment in terms of the electron electric dipole moment is
found to be 22.5 GV/cm. In Ref. [Phys. Rev. D 89, 056006 (2014)] it was shown
that another source of T,P-odd interaction, the scalar-pseudoscalar
nucleus-electron interaction with the dimensionless strength constant $k_{T,P}$
can dominate over the direct contribution from the electron EDM within the
standard model and some of its extensions. Therefore, for the comprehensive and
correct interpretation of the HfF$^+$ experiment one should also know the
molecular parameter $W_{T,P}$ the value of which is reported here to be 20.1
kHz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.07459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.07459</id><created>2017-04-24</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sekania</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baeriswyl</keyname><forenames>Dionys</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jibuti</keyname><forenames>Luka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Japaridze</keyname><forenames>George I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mass-Imbalanced Ionic Hubbard Chain</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035116 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A repulsive Hubbard model with both spin-asymmetric hopping (${t_\uparrow\neq
t_\downarrow}$) and a staggered potential (of strength $\Delta$) is studied in
one dimension. The model is a compound of the mass-imbalanced (${t_\uparrow\neq
t_\downarrow}$, ${\Delta=0}$) and ionic (${t_\uparrow = t_\downarrow}$,
${\Delta&gt;0}$) Hubbard models, and may be realized by cold atoms in engineered
optical lattices. We use mostly mean-field theory to determine the phases and
phase transitions in the ground state for a half-filled band (one particle per
site). We find that a period-two modulation of the particle (or charge) density
and an alternating spin density coexist for arbitrary Hubbard interaction
strength, ${U\geqslant 0}$. The amplitude of the charge modulation is largest
at ${U=0}$, decreases with increasing $U$ and tends to zero for
${U\rightarrow\infty}$. The amplitude for spin alternation increases with $U$
and tends to saturation for ${U\rightarrow\infty}$. Charge order dominates
below a critical value $U_c$, whereas magnetic order dominates above. The
mean-field Hamiltonian has two gap parameters, $\Delta_\uparrow$ and
$\Delta_\downarrow$, which have to be determined self-consistently. For
${U&lt;U_c}$ both parameters are positive, for ${U&gt;U_c}$ they have different
signs, and for ${U=U_c}$ one gap parameter jumps from a positive to a negative
value. The weakly first-order phase transition at $U_c$ can be interpreted in
terms of an avoided criticality (or metallicity). The system is reluctant to
restore a symmetry that has been broken explicitly.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08123</id><created>2017-04-26</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chubykalo</keyname><forenames>Andrew E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Espinoza</keyname><forenames>Augusto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosyakov</keyname><forenames>B P</forenames></author></authors><title>The origin of the energy-momentum conservation law</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages, no figures; v2: typos fixed; accepted for publication in
  Annals of Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interplay between the action-reaction principle and the energy-momentum
conservation law is revealed by the examples of the Maxwell-Lorentz and
Yang-Mills-Wong theories, and general relativity. These two statements are
shown to be equivalent in the sense that both hold or fail together. Their
mutual agreement is demonstrated most clearly in the self-interaction problem
by taking account of the rearrangement of degrees of freedom appearing in the
action of the Maxwell-Lorentz and Yang-Mills-Wong theories. The failure of
energy-momentum conservation in general relativity is attributed to the fact
that this theory allows solutions having nontrivial topologies. The total
energy and momentum of a system with nontrivial topological content is found to
be ambiguous, coordintization-dependent quantities. For example, the energy of
a Schwarzschild black hole may take any positive value greater than, or equal
to, the mass of the body whose collapse is responsible for arising this black
hole. We draw the analogy to the paradoxial Banach-Tarski theorem; the measure
becomes a poorly defined concept if initial three-dimensional bounded sets are
rearranged in topologically nontrivial ways through the action of free
non-Abelian isometry groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00197</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00197</id><created>2017-04-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Liebermann</keyname><forenames>Niklas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Main</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wunner</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author></authors><title>Exceptional points in the elliptical three-disk scatterer using
  semiclassical periodic orbit quantization</title><categories>nlin.CD quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>EPL 118 (2017) 30006</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/30006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The three-disk scatterer has served as a paradigm for semiclassical periodic
orbit quantization of classical chaotic systems using Gutzwiller's trace
formula. It represents an open quantum system, thus leading to spectra of
complex eigenenergies. An interesting general feature of open quantum systems
described by non-Hermitian operators is the possible existence of exceptional
points where not only the complex eigenvalues but also their respective
eigenvectors coincide. Using Gutzwiller's periodic orbit theory we show that
exceptional points exist in a three-disk scatterer if the system's geometry is
modified by extending the system from circular to elliptical disks. The
extension is implemented in such a way that the system's characteristic
$C_{3\mathrm{v}}$ symmetry is preserved. The two-dimensional parameter plane of
the system is then spanned by the distance between and the excentricity of the
elliptical disks. As typical signatures of exceptional points we observe the
permutation of two resonances when an exceptional point is encircled in
parameter space, and a non-Lorentzian resonance line shape in the weighted
density of states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05220</id><created>2017-06-16</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kudryavtsev</keyname><forenames>Alexey N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Purtov</keyname><forenames>Petr A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trashkeev</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlocal tensor order parameter of the deformed state of liquid crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>29 pages, 4 figures, 46 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A generalized notion of a nonlocal tensor order parameter is introduced
within the framework of the phenomenological approach. This parameter has the
form of a traceless tensor correlation function or a tensor integral operator.
Based on this form, the governing relations are written, which determine the
steady states and phase transitions of the deformed liquid crystal. Linear
relations for eigenfunctions of the introduced operator are derived. A
principal drawback of currently available models of liquid crystals based on
the local presentation of the tensor order parameter (equality of two Frank
constants in the case of a quadratic form of the strain part of the free
energy) is eliminated. Particular examples are considered, which demonstrate
the model workability and the absence of contradictions in the model as well as
its adequacy when describing small-scale structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00550</id><created>2017-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Hofbrucker</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volotka</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritzsche</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoelectron distribution of non-resonant two-photon ionization of
  neutral atoms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013409 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photoelectron angular distributions following the non-resonant two-photon
K-shell ionization of neutral atoms are studied theoretically. Using the
independent particle approximation and relativistic second-order perturbation
theory, the contributions of screening and relativistic effects to the
photoelectron angular distribution are evaluated. A simple nonrelativistic
expression is presented for the angle-differential cross section in dipole
approximation for two-photon ionization by elliptically polarized photons, and
its limitations are analyzed numerically. Moreover, we show that screening
effects of the inactive electrons can significantly affect the photoelectron
distributions and can also lead to a strong elliptical dichroism. Numerical
results are resented for the case of two-photon K-shell ionization of neutral
Ne, Ge, Xe, and U atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01982</id><created>2017-07-06</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fargion</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author></authors><title>No Tau? No Astronomy!</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, ICRC 2017; additional minor misprint corrections</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since 2013 IceCube cascade showers sudden overabundance have shown a fast
flavor change above 30-60 TeV up to PeV energy. This flavor change from
dominant muon tracks at TeVs to shower events at higher energies, has been
indebted to a new injection of a neutrino astronomy. However the recent
published 54 neutrino HESE, high energy starting events, as well as the 38
external muon tracks made by trough going muon formed around the IceCube, none
of them are pointing to any expected X-gamma or radio sources: no one in
connection to GRB, no toward active BL Lac, neither to AGN source in Fermi
catalog. No clear correlation with nearby mass distribution (Local Group), nor
to galactic plane. Moreover there have not been any record (among a dozen of
200 TeV energetic events) of the expected double bang due to the tau neutrino
birth and decay. An amazing and surprising unfair distribution in flavor versus
expected democratic one. Finally there is not a complete consistence of the
internal HESE event spectra and the external crossing muon track ones. Moreover
the apparent sudden astrophysical neutrino flux rise at 60 TeV might be
probably also suddenly cut at a few PeV in order to hide the (unobserved , yet)
Glashow resonance peak at 6.3 PeV. A more mondane prompt charmed atmospheric
neutrino component may explain most of the IceCube puzzles. If this near
future, 2017-2018, it does not shine tau neutrino signals somewhere (by tau
airshowers in AUGER, TA, ASHRA or double bang in IceCube) there are a list of
consequences to face. These missing correlations and in particular the tau
signature absence force us to claim : No Tau? No neutrino Astronomy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02339</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02339</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Unger</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farrar</keyname><forenames>Glennys R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainties in the Magnetic Field of the Milky Way</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, to appear in the Proceedings of the 35th
  International Cosmic Ray Conference 10-20 July, 2017 Bexco, Busan, Korea</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We improve on the model of the Galactic Magnetic Field (GMF) from Jansson \&amp;
Farrar (2012), which was constrained using all-sky rotation measures of
extragalactic sources and polarized and unpolarized synchrotron emission data
from WMAP. We have developed several alternative functional forms for the
coherent and random components, used newer synchrotron products from Planck and
WMAP and testes new models of the densities of thermal electrons and cosmic-ray
electrons. The differences in the resultant GMF models, depending on which
parameterization of the field, synchrotron product and electron densities are
used, provides a measure of the uncertainty in our inference of the GMF. We
discuss the impact of these uncertainties on charged-particle astronomy at
ultra-high energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02357</id><created>2017-07-05</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barmina</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudkov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simakin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafeev</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stable products of laser-induced breakdown of aqueous colloidal
  solutions of nanoparticles</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.app-ph</categories><comments>The paper was presented at 18th International Symposium on Laser
  Precision Microfabrication, June 3-8, Toyama, Japan</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formation of stable products of water decomposition under laser exposure
of aqueous colloidal solutions of nanoparticles is experimentally studied.
Laser exposure of colloidal solutions leads to formation of H2, O2, and H2O2.
The dependence of the yield of these products depends on the energy density of
laser radiation inside the liquid and concentration of nanoparticles. The ratio
H2/O2 depends on laser fluence and is shifted towards H2. There are at least to
sources of H2O2, namely, laser-induced breakdown plasma and ultrasound induced
by laser pulses in the liquid. The formation of both H2 and O2 is tentatively
assigned to direct dissociation of H2O molecules by electron impact from
laser-induced plasma.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02949</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02949</id><created>2017-07-10</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kanal</keyname><forenames>Ilana Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutchison</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rapid Computational Optimization of Molecular Properties using Genetic
  Algorithms: Searching Across Millions of Compounds for Organic Photovoltaic
  Materials</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.chem-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conjugated organic molecules represent an important area of materials
chemistry for both fundamental scientific exploration and technological
applications. Using a genetic algorithm to computationally screen up to ~25-50
million molecules for organic photovoltaic properties, we find that our methods
find top monomers 6,000-8,000 times faster than brute force search. By testing
multiple runs and establishing convergence criteria, we show the computational
scaling with search space size, common molecular motifs, and discuss the
reliability to choose the same molecules independent of initial data set size.
We outline remaining areas of difficulty in growing to larger search spaces,
potential solutions, and filtering criteria for potential organic photovoltaic
materials. Efficient genetic algorithm searches promise to address a wide range
of property-driven inverse design problems in chemistry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03377</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03377</id><created>2017-07-11</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qunzhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sornette</keyname><forenames>Didier</forenames></author></authors><title>Learning like humans with Deep Symbolic Networks</title><categories>cs.AI cond-mat.dis-nn cs.LG</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the Deep Symbolic Network (DSN) model, which aims at becoming
the white-box version of Deep Neural Networks (DNN). The DSN model provides a
simple, universal yet powerful structure, similar to DNN, to represent any
knowledge of the world, which is transparent to humans. The conjecture behind
the DSN model is that any type of real world objects sharing enough common
features are mapped into human brains as a symbol. Those symbols are connected
by links, representing the composition, correlation, causality, or other
relationships between them, forming a deep, hierarchical symbolic network
structure. Powered by such a structure, the DSN model is expected to learn like
humans, because of its unique characteristics. First, it is universal, using
the same structure to store any knowledge. Second, it can learn symbols from
the world and construct the deep symbolic networks automatically, by utilizing
the fact that real world objects have been naturally separated by
singularities. Third, it is symbolic, with the capacity of performing causal
deduction and generalization. Fourth, the symbols and the links between them
are transparent to us, and thus we will know what it has learned or not - which
is the key for the security of an AI system. Fifth, its transparency enables it
to learn with relatively small data. Sixth, its knowledge can be accumulated.
Last but not least, it is more friendly to unsupervised learning than DNN. We
present the details of the model, the algorithm powering its automatic learning
ability, and describe its usefulness in different use cases. The purpose of
this paper is to generate broad interest to develop it within an open source
project centered on the Deep Symbolic Network (DSN) model towards the
development of general AI.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03683</id><created>2017-06-26</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baskal</keyname><forenames>Sibel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Young S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noz</keyname><forenames>Marilyn E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Loop Representation of Wigner's Little Groups</title><categories>physics.gen-ph hep-th</categories><comments>LaTex 26 pages, with 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Symmetry 2017, 9(7), 97</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/sym9070097</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wigner's little groups are the subgroups of the Lorentz group whose
transformations leave the momentum of a given particle invariant. They thus
define the internal space-time symmetries of relativistic particles. These
symmetries take different mathematical forms for massive and for massless
particles. However, it is shown possible to construct one unified
representation using a graphical description. This graphical approach allows us
to describe vividly parity, time reversal, and charge conjugation of the
internal symmetry groups. As for the language of group theory, the two-by-two
representation is used throughout the paper. While this two-by-two
representation is for spin-1/2 particles, it is shown possible to construct the
representations for spin-0 particles, spin-1 particles, as well as for
higher-spin particles, for both massive and massless cases. It is shown also
that the four-by-four Dirac matrices constitute a two-by-two representation of
Wigner's little group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03818</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Lingchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Guoqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Zhipeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiaodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Liejia</forenames></author></authors><title>Diode-pumped mode-locked femtosecond 2-um Tm:CaYAlO4 laser</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Continuous-wave mode-locked femtosecond 2 um solid-state laser with a c-cut
Tm:CaYAlO4 as gain medium was experimentally demonstrated. The mode locked
laser generated stable pulses with average output power as high as 531 mW,
pulse duration of 496 fs, and repetition rate of 97 MHz at 1975 nm. The
research results show that Tm:CaYAlO4 is an excellent gain medium for
femtosecond pulse generation at 2um wavelength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03834</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Fuhrman</keyname><forenames>Wesley T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chamorro</keyname><forenames>Juan R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alekseev</keyname><forenames>Pavel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mignot</keyname><forenames>Jean-Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolic</keyname><forenames>Predrag</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>Tyrel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broholm</keyname><forenames>Collin L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Screened moments in a Kondo insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Long known to have thermodynamic properties at odds with its insulating
electrical transport, SmB6 has been the subject of great debate as it is
unclear whether its unusual properties are related to the bulk or novel
metallic surface states. We have observed a bulk moment-screening effect in
nominally pure and Gd-doped SmB6 via heat capacity, magnetization, and
resistivity measurements, and show this new Kondo-impurity like effect provides
an unexpected but intuitive explanation for metal-like phenomena stemming from
the strongly interacting host system. This affords a coherent understanding for
decades of mysteries in strongly-correlated insulators, reveals the expanded
utility of techniques previously only utilized for metals, and presents the
novel effect of even highly-dilute impurities in strongly correlated
insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03844</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03844</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Claudia Mendes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amram</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quint</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres-Flores</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barba</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author></authors><title>First results from SAM-FP: Fabry-Perot observations with ground-layer
  adaptive optics - the structure and kinematics of the core of 30 Doradus</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 469, 3424, 2017 MNRAS, 469, 3424, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx976</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is to present the first data set obtained with SOAR
Adaptive Module-Fabry-Parot (SAM-FP), a Fabry-Perot instrument mounted inside
the SOAR telescope Adaptive-Optics Module. This is the only existing imaging
Fabry-Perot interferometer using laser-assisted ground-layer adaptive optics.
SAM-FP was used to observe the ionized gas, traced by Halpha, in the centre of
the 30 Doradus starburst (the Tarantula Nebula) in the Large Magellanic Cloud,
with high spatial (~0.6&quot; or 0.15 pc) and spectral (R=11200) resolution. Radial
velocity, velocity dispersion and monochromatic maps were derived. The region
displays a mix of narrow, sigma ~ 20 km/s profiles and multiple broader
profiles with sigma ~ 70-80 km/s, indicating the complex nature of the nebula
kinematics. A comparison with previously obtained VLT/FLAMES spectroscopy
demonstrates that the data agree well in the regions of overlap, but the
Fabry-Perot data are superior in spatial coverage. A preliminary analysis of
the observations finds a new expanding bubble south of R136, with a projected
radius of r=5.6 pc and an expansion velocity of 29 +/- 4 km/s. In addition, the
first-time detailed kinematic maps derived here for several complexes and
filaments of 30 Doradus allow identification of kinematically independent
structures. These data exemplify the power of the combination of a high-order
Fabry-Perot with a wide-field imager (3' x 3' GLAO-corrected field of view) for
high-resolution spatial and spectral studies. In particular, SAM-FP data cubes
are highly advantageous over multifibre or long-slit data sets for nebula
structure studies and to search for small-scale bubbles, given their greatly
improved spatial coverage. For reference, this paper also presents two
appendices with detailed descriptions of the usage of Fabry-Perot devices,
including formulae and explanations for understanding Fabry-Perot observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03849</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Paschen</keyname><forenames>Timo</forenames></author><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rster</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;ger</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemell</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wachter</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Libisch</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madlener</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgd&#xf6;rfer</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hommelhoff</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>High Visibility in Two-Color Above-Threshold Photoemission from Tungsten
  Nanotips in a Coherent Control Scheme</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Mod. Opt. 64, 10-11, 1054-1060 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2017.1281453</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we present coherent control of above-threshold photoemission
from a tungsten nanotip achieving nearly perfect modulation. Depending on the
pulse delay between fundamental (1560 nm) and second harmonic (780 nm) pulses
of a femtosecond fiber laser at the nanotip, electron emission is significantly
enhanced or depressed during temporal overlap. Electron emission is studied as
a function of pulse delay, optical near-field intensities, DC bias field, and
final photoelectron energy. Under optimized conditions modulation amplitudes of
the electron emission of 97.5% are achieved. Experimental observations are
discussed in the framework of quantum- pathway interference supported by local
density of states (LDOS) simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03850</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03850</id><created>2017-07-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ray</keyname><forenames>Manjil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xiufeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>Song-Charng</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of Drop Impact on a Hot Wall using SPH Method with
  Peng-Robinson Equation of State</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 10th U.S. National Combustion Meeting, April
  23-26, 2017, College Park, Maryland</comments><report-no>1C12</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This study presents a smoothed particle hydrodynamics (SPH) method with
Peng-Robinson equation of state for simulating drop vaporization and drop
impact on a hot surface. The conservation equations of momentum and energy and
Peng-Robinson equation of state are applied to describe both the liquid and gas
phases. The governing equations are solved numerically by the SPH method. The
phase change between the liquid and gas phases are simulated directly without
using any phase change models. The numerical method is validated by comparing
numerical results with analytical solutions for the vaporization of n-heptane
drops at different temperatures. Using the SPH method, the processes of
n-heptane drops impacting on a solid wall with different temperatures are
studied numerically. The results show that the size of the film formed by drop
impact decreases when temperature increases. When the temperature is high
enough, the drop will rebound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03857</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03857</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Alberto</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malheiro</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frederico</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Castro</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalizing spin and pseudospin symmetries for relativistic spin 1/2
  fermions</title><categories>quant-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5th International Conference on Mathematical Modeling in Physical
  Sciences (IC-MSquare 2016), 5 pages, uses jpconf style</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 738 (2016) 012033</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/738/1/012033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a generalization of pseudospin and spin symmetries, the SU(2)
symmetries of Dirac equation with scalar and vector mean-field potentials
originally found independently in the 70's by Smith and Tassie, and Bell and
Ruegg. As relativistic symmetries, they have been extensively researched and
applied to several physical systems for the last 18 years. The main feature of
these symmetries is the suppression of the spin-orbit coupling either in the
upper or lower components of the Dirac spinor, thereby turning the respective
second-order equations into Schr\&quot;odinger-like equations, i.e, without a matrix
structure. In this paper we use the original formalism of Bell and Ruegg to
derive general requirements for the Lorentz structures of potentials in order
to have these SU(2) symmetries in the Dirac equation, again allowing for the
suppression of the matrix structure of the second-order equation of either the
upper or lower components of the Dirac spinor. Furthermore, we derive
equivalent conditions for spin and pseudospin symmetries with 2- and
1-dimensional potentials and list some possible candidates for 3, 2, and 1
dimensions. We suggest applications for physical systems in three and two
dimensions, namely electrons in graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03875</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tenorio</keyname><forenames>Gabriela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bucio</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escudero</keyname><forenames>R</forenames></author></authors><title>Filamentary superconductivity in semiconducting policrystalline ZrSe2
  compound with Zr vacancies</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Accepted in J of superconductivity and novel magnetism</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  ZrSe2 is a band semiconductor studied long time ago. It has interesting
electronic properties, and because its layers structure can be intercalated
with different atoms to change some of the physical properties. In this
investigation we found that Zr deficiencies alter the semiconducting behavior
and the compound can be turned into a superconductor. In this paper we report
our studies related to this discovery. The decreasing of the number of Zr atoms
in small proportion according to the formula ZrxSe2, where x is varied from
about 8.1 to 8.6 K, changing the semiconducting behavior to a superconductor
with transition temperatures ranging between 7.8 to 8.5 K, it depending of the
deficiencies. Outside of those ranges the compound behaves as semiconducting
with the properties already known. In our experiments we found that this new
superconductor has only a very small fraction of superconducting material
determined by magnetic measurements with applied magnetic field of 10 Oe. Our
conclusions is that superconductivity is filamentary. However, in one studied
sample the fraction was about 10.2 %, whereas in others is only about 1 % or
less. We determined the superconducting characteristics; the critical fields
that indicate a type two superonductor with Ginzburg-Landau ? parameter of the
order about 2.7. The synthesis procedure is quite normal fol- lowing the
conventional solid state reaction. In this paper are included, the electronic
characteristics, transition temperature, and evolution with temperature of the
critical fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03878</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Sabyasachi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Dusmanta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollick</keyname><forenames>Monique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Sandip K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transient nature of J195754+353513</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have searched for transient and/or variable radio sources in the field of
Galactic micro-quasar Cygnus X-1 in 1.4 GHz (L band) using data from the Karl
G. Jansky Very Large Array (JVLA). We used twenty years of data between 1983
and 2003. We found a source J195754+353513 showing transient behavior. The
source was also mentioned earlier in NVSS and WENSS catalog but its transient
nature was not reported earlier. The source is located 23.8 arcminutes far from
Cygnus X-1. It is detected many times during the span of our study and it
varied between less than 0.3 mJy to 201 mJy. J195754+353513 also showed high
intra-day variability. In one occasion, the source rose from ~20 mJy to ~180
mJy 700 second. For limited number of cases circularly polarized emission could
be detected from the source with V/I vary between 0.15 to 0.25. 2MASS
J19575420+3535152 may be the near-infrared counterpart of the source. We
compared the properties of the source with other Galactic transient sources
having similar properties. The nature of the source is still unknown. We
speculate on its possible nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03879</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Leslie</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bryant</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>I. -T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadler</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medling</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groves</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kewley</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bland-Hawthorn</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Croom</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>O. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brough</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tescari</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sweet</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharp</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>A. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fogarty</keyname><forenames>L. M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodwin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawrence</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konstantopoulos</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owers</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richards</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>The SAMI Galaxy Survey: Disk-halo interactions in radio-selected
  star-forming galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures. Published in MNRAS July 2017</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1673</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we compare the radio emission at 1.4 GHz with optical outflow
signatures of edge-on galaxies. We report observations of six edge-on
star-forming galaxies in the Sydney-AAO Multi-object Integral-field
spectrograph (SAMI) Galaxy Survey with 1.4 GHz luminosities $&gt; 1\times10^{21}$
W Hz$^{-1}$. Extended minor axis optical emission is detected with enhanced
\nii/H$\alpha$ line ratios and velocity dispersions consistent with galactic
winds in three of six galaxies. These galaxies may host outflows driven by a
combination of thermal and cosmic ray processes. We find that galaxies with the
strongest wind signatures have extended radio morphologies. Our results form a
baseline for understanding the driving mechanisms of galactic winds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03915</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Hengxu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yavas</keyname><forenames>Hakan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van der Giessen</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papanikolaou</keyname><forenames>Stefanos</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete Dislocation Dynamics Simulations of Nanoindentation with
  Pre-stress: Hardness and Statistics of Abrupt Plastic Events</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>27 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The yield surface in crystal plasticity can be approached from various
directions during mechanical loading. We consider the competition between
nanoindentation and tensile loading towards plastic yielding. For this purpose,
we develop a two-dimensional discrete dislocation model that is then utilized
to investigate the hardness and pop-in event statistics during nanoindentation
of single crystal under tensile pre-stress. Indentation is performed by using
cylindrical (circular in 2D) indentation with varying radius and under both
displacement and load control. Tensile in-plane stress, varying from zero to
yield strength, is assigned to investigate the effect of pre-stress on hardness
and pop-in statistics. At small indentation depths, the measured hardness is
found to be smaller for larger tensile pre-stress; therefore, we conclude that
nanoindentation can be used to detect plasticity. When indentation depth is
larger, the effect of pre-stress is barely seen. Moreover, we discuss event
statistics and the related effect of pre-stress.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03919</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Vaidya</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradeep</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murty</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilde</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Divinski</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radioactive isotopes reveal a non sluggish kinetics of grain boundary
  diffusion in high entropy alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High entropy alloys (HEAs) have emerged as a new class of multicomponent
materials, which have potential for high temperature applications. Phase
stability and creep deformation, two key selection criteria for high
temperature materials, are predominantly influenced by the diffusion of
constituent elements along the grain boundaries (GBs). For the first time, GB
diffusion of Ni in chemically homogeneous CoCrFeNi and CoCrFeMnNi HEAs is
measured by radiotracer analysis using the $^{63}$Ni isotope. Atom probe
tomography confirmed the absence of elemental segregation at GBs that allowed
reliable estimation of the GB width to be about 0.5 nm. Our GB diffusion
measurements prove that a mere increase in number of constituent elements does
not lower the diffusion rates in HEAs, but the nature of added constituents
plays a more decisive role. The GB energies in both HEAs are estimated at about
0.8-0.9 J/m$^2$, they are found to increase significantly with temperature and
the effect is more pronounced for the CoCrFeMnNi alloy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03929</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gay-Balmaz</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Putkaradze</keyname><forenames>Vakhtang</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric analysis of noisy perturbations to nonholonomic constraints</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose two types of stochastic extensions of nonholonomic constraints for
mechanical systems. Our approach relies on a stochastic extension of the
Lagrange-d'Alembert framework. We consider in details the case of invariant
nonholonomic systems on the group of rotations and on the special Euclidean
group. Based on this, we then develop two types of stochastic deformations of
the Suslov problem and study the possibility of extending to the stochastic
case the preservation of some of its integrals of motion such as the Kharlamova
or Clebsch-Tisserand integrals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03934</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Bao-zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-xi</forenames></author></authors><title>On Local Unitary Equivalence of Two and Three-qubit States</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7 (2017) 4869</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-04717-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the local unitary equivalence for two and three-qubit mixed states
by investigating the invariants under local unitary transformations. For
two-qubit system, we prove that the determination of the local unitary
equivalence of 2-qubits states only needs 14 or less invariants for arbitrary
two-qubit states. Using the same method, we construct invariants for
three-qubit mixed states.
  We prove that these invariants are sufficient to guarantee the LU equivalence
of certain kind of three-qubit states. Also, we make a comparison with earlier
works.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03957</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Advani</keyname><forenames>Madhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunin</keyname><forenames>Guy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehta</keyname><forenames>Pankaj</forenames></author></authors><title>Environmental engineering is an emergent feature of diverse ecosystems
  and drives community structure</title><categories>q-bio.PE cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A central question in ecology is to understand the ecological processes that
shape community structure. Niche-based theories have emphasized the important
role played by competition for maintaining species diversity. Many of these
insights have been derived using MacArthur's consumer resource model (MCRM) or
its generalizations. Most theoretical work on the MCRM has focused on small
ecosystems with a few species and resources. However theoretical insights
derived from small ecosystems many not scale up large ecosystems with many
resources and species because large systems with many interacting components
often display new emergent behaviors that cannot be understood or deduced from
analyzing smaller systems. To address this shortcoming, we develop a
sophisticated statistical physics inspired cavity method to analyze MCRM when
both the number of species and the number of resources is large. We find that
in this limit, species generically and consistently perturb their environments
and significantly modify available ecological niches. We show how our cavity
approach naturally generalizes niche theory to large ecosystems by accounting
for the effect of this emergent environmental engineering on species invasion
and ecological stability. Our work suggests that environmental engineering is a
generic feature of large, natural ecosystems and must be taken into account
when analyzing and interpreting community structure. It also highlights the
important role that statistical-physics inspired approaches can play in
furthering our understanding of ecology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03962</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03962</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Marzen</keyname><forenames>Sarah E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crutchfield</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction and Power in Molecular Sensors: Uncertainty and Dissipation
  When Conditionally Markovian Channels Are Driven by Semi-Markov Environments</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cs.IT math.IT q-bio.BM</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures,
  http://csc.ucdavis.edu/~cmg/compmech/pubs/piness.htm</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sensors often serve at least two purposes: predicting their input and
minimizing dissipated heat. However, determining whether or not a particular
sensor is evolved or designed to be accurate and efficient is difficult. This
arises partly from the functional constraints being at cross purposes and
partly since quantifying the predictive performance of even in silico sensors
can require prohibitively long simulations. To circumvent these difficulties,
we develop expressions for the predictive accuracy and thermodynamic costs of
the broad class of conditionally Markovian sensors subject to unifilar hidden
semi-Markov (memoryful) environmental inputs. Predictive metrics include the
instantaneous memory and the mutual information between present sensor state
and input future, while dissipative metrics include power consumption and the
nonpredictive information rate. Success in deriving these formulae relies
heavily on identifying the environment's causal states, the input's minimal
sufficient statistics for prediction. Using these formulae, we study the
simplest nontrivial biological sensor model---that of a Hill molecule,
characterized by the number of ligands that bind simultaneously, the sensor's
cooperativity. When energetic rewards are proportional to total predictable
information, the closest cooperativity that optimizes the total energy budget
generally depends on the environment's past hysteretically. In this way, the
sensor gains robustness to environmental fluctuations. Given the simplicity of
the Hill molecule, such hysteresis will likely be found in more complex
predictive sensors as well. That is, adaptations that only locally optimize
biochemical parameters for prediction and dissipation can lead to sensors that
&quot;remember&quot; the past environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03965</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>Luke A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fine-Tuning in the Context of Bayesian Theory Testing</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>14 Pages, 0 figures. Accepted for publication in the European Journal
  for Philosophy of Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fine-tuning in physics and cosmology is often used as evidence that a theory
is incomplete. For example, the parameters of the standard model of particle
physics are &quot;unnaturally&quot; small (in various technical senses), which has driven
much of the search for physics beyond the standard model. Of particular
interest is the fine-tuning of the universe for life, which suggests that our
universe's ability to create physical life forms is improbable and in need of
explanation, perhaps by a multiverse. This claim has been challenged on the
grounds that the relevant probability measure cannot be justified because it
cannot be normalized, and so small probabilities cannot be inferred. We show
how fine-tuning can be formulated within the context of Bayesian theory testing
(or \emph{model selection}) in the physical sciences. The normalizability
problem is seen to be a general problem for testing any theory with free
parameters, and not a unique problem for fine-tuning. Physical theories in fact
avoid such problems in one of two ways. Dimensional parameters are bounded by
the Planck scale, avoiding troublesome infinities, and we are not compelled to
assume that dimensionless parameters are distributed uniformly, which avoids
non-normalizability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03990</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cerdeno</keyname><forenames>David G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Romeri</keyname><forenames>Valentina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Lozano</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olive</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seto</keyname><forenames>Osamu</forenames></author></authors><title>The Constrained NMSSM with right-handed neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>IPPP/17/56; DCTP/17/112; IFT-UAM/CSIC-17-064; BONN-TH-2017-06;
  EPHOU-17-011; UMN-TH-3631/17; FTPI-MINN-17/13</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study the renormalization group equations of the
Next-to-Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model, and investigate universality
conditions on the soft supersymmetry-breaking parameters at the Grand
Unification scale. We demonstrate that the inclusion of right-handed neutrino
superfields can have a substantial effect on the running of the soft terms
(greatly contributing to driving the singlet Higgs mass- squared parameter
negative), which makes it considerably easier to satisfy the conditions for
radiative electroweak symmetry-breaking. The new fields also lead to larger
values of the Standard Model Higgs mass, thus making it easier to reproduce the
measured value. We investigate the phenomenology of this constrained scenario,
and focus on two viable benchmark points, which feature a neutral lightest
supersymmetric particle (either the lightest neutralino or the right-handed
sneutrino). We show that all bounds from colliders and low-energy observables
can be fulfilled in wide areas of the parameter space. However, the relic
density in these regions is generally too high requiring some form of late
entropy production to dilute the density of the lightest supersymmetric
particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03995</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03995</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhengwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Quon language: surface algebras and Fourier duality</title><categories>math.QA math-ph math.MP math.OA</categories><comments>22 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quon language is a 3D picture language that we can apply to simulate
mathematical concepts. We introduce the surface algebras as an extension of the
notion of planar algebras to higher genus surface. We prove that there is a
unique one-parameter extension. The 2D defects on the surfaces are quons, and
surface tangles are transformations. We use quon language to simulate graphic
states that appear in quantum information, and to simulate interesting
quantities in modular tensor categories. This simulation relates the pictorial
Fourier duality of surface tangles and the algebraic Fourier duality induced by
the S matrix of the modular tensor category. The pictorial Fourier duality also
coincides with the graphic duality on the sphere. For each pair of dual graphs,
we obtain an algebraic identity related to the $S$ matrix. These identities
include well-known ones, such as the Verlinde formula; partially known ones,
such as the 6j-symbol self-duality; and completely new ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03998</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Lassila</keyname><forenames>Toni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malossi</keyname><forenames>Cristiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevanella</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Votta</keyname><forenames>Emiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redaelli</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deparis</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of left ventricle fluid dynamics with mitral regurgitation
  from magnetic resonance images with fictitious elastic structure
  regularization</title><categories>physics.med-ph math.NA</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Computer modeling can provide quantitative insight into cardiac fluid
dynamics phenomena that are not evident from standard imaging tools. We propose
a new approach to modeling left ventricle fluid dynamics based on an
image-driven model-based description of ventricular motion. In this approach,
the end-diastolic geometry and time-dependent deformation of the left ventricle
cavity are obtained from cardiac magnetic resonance images and a fictitious
elastic structure is used to impose the contractile behavior of the left
ventricle. This allows seamless treatment of the isovolumic phases. Besides the
ventricular motion, the intracavitary fluid dynamics is controlled by the
mitral valve. Three different mitral valve models are included in the
simulation: an idealized diode (with or without regurgitation) and a lumped
parameter model accounting for the opening dynamics of the valve and including
regurgitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03999</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jieun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zefang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Hongchao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mak</keyname><forenames>Kin Fai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Valley Magnetoelectricity in Single-Layer MoS2</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/nmat4931</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetoelectric (ME) effect, the phenomenon of inducing magnetization by
application of an electric field or vice versa, holds great promise for
magnetic sensing and switching applications. Studies of the ME effect have so
far focused on the control of the electron spin degree of freedom (DOF) in
materials such as multiferroics and conventional semiconductors. Here, we
report a new form of the ME effect based on the valley DOF in two-dimensional
(2D) Dirac materials. By breaking the three-fold rotational symmetry in
single-layer MoS2 via a uniaxial stress, we have demonstrated the pure
electrical generation of valley magnetization in this material, and its direct
imaging by Kerr rotation microscopy. The observed out-of-plane magnetization is
independent of in-plane magnetic field, linearly proportional to the in-plane
current density, and optimized when the current is orthogonal to the
strain-induced piezoelectric field. These results are fully consistent with a
theoretical model of valley magnetoelectricity driven by Berry curvature
effects. Furthermore, the effect persists at room temperature, opening
possibilities for practical valleytronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04003</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jiaji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jialin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Linpeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuo</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly efficient quantitative phase microscopy using programmable
  annular LED illumination</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>18 page, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present a highly efficient quantitative phase imaging (QPI)
approach using programmable annular LED illumination based on traditional
bright-field microscope. As a new type of coded illumination, the LED array
provides a flexible and compatible way to realize QPI. The proposed method
modulates the transfer function of system by changing the LED illumination
pattern, which achieves twice resolution of objective NA and gives noise-robust
response of transfer function. The phase of a sample could be recovered from
the intensity images with the inversion of transfer function. Moreover, the
weak object transfer function (WOTF) of axisymmetric oblique source is derived,
and the noise-free and noisy simulation results sufficiently validate the
applicability of discrete annular source. The quantitative phase measurements
of micro polystyrene bead and visible blazed transmission grating demonstrate
the accuracy of proposed method. Finally, the experimental investigations of
unstained human cancer cells using different types objective are presented, and
these results show the possibility of widespread adoption of QPI in the
morphology study of cellular processes and biomedical community.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04017</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kucharski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reineke</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stosic</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su&#x142;kowski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author></authors><title>Knots-quivers correspondence</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.GN math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>43 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>CALT-2017-040</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce and explore the relation between knot invariants and quiver
representation theory, which follows from the identification of quiver quantum
mechanics in D-brane systems representing knots. We identify various structural
properties of quivers associated to knots, and identify such quivers explicitly
in many examples, including some infinite families of knots, all knots up to 6
crossings, and some knots with thick homology. Moreover, based on these
properties, we derive previously unknown expressions for colored HOMFLY-PT
polynomials and superpolynomials for various knots. For all knots, for which we
identify the corresponding quivers, the LMOV conjecture for all symmetric
representations (i.e. integrality of relevant BPS numbers) is automatically
proved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04023</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Caprini</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerino</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarracino</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vulpiani</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Fourier's Law in a Generalized Piston Model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 19, 350 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19070350</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simplified, but non trivial, mechanical model -- gas of $N$ particles of
mass $m$ in a box partitioned by $n$ mobile adiabatic walls of mass $M$ --
interacting with two thermal baths at different temperatures, is discussed in
the framework of kinetic theory. Following an approach due to Smoluchowski,
from an analysis of the collisions particles/walls, we derive the values of the
main thermodynamic quantities for the stationary non-equilibrium states. The
results are compared with extensive numerical simulations; in the limit of
large $n$, $mN/M\gg 1$ and $m/M \ll 1$, we find a good approximation of
Fourier's law.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04077</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zuo-Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Wei-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Hai-Qing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Chang-De</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Competition and Anomalous Thermal Evolution in High-Temperature
  Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics. Rev. B 96, 045110 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.045110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interplay of competing orders is relevant to high-temperature
superconductivity known to emerge upon suppression of a parent
antiferromagnetic order typically via charge doping. How such interplay evolves
at low temperature---in particular at what doping level the zero-temperature
quantum critical point (QCP) is located---is still elusive because it is masked
by the superconducting state. The QCP had long been believed to follow a smooth
extrapolation of the characteristic temperature $T^*$ for the strange normal
state well above the superconducting transition temperature. However, recently
the $T^*$ within the superconducting dome was reported to unexpectedly exhibit
back-bending likely in the cuprate Bi$_{2}$Sr$_{2}$CaCu$_{2}$O$_{8+\delta}$.
Here we show that the original and revised phase diagrams can be understood in
terms of weak and moderate competitions, respectively, between
superconductivity and a pseudogap state such as $d$-density-wave or
spin-density-wave, based on both Ginzburg-Landau theory and the realistic
$t$-$t^{\prime}$-$t^{\prime\prime}$-$J$-$V$ model for the cuprates. We further
found that the calculated temperature and doping-level dependence of the
quasiparticle spectral gap and Raman response qualitatively agrees with the
experiments. In particular, the $T^*$ back-bending can provide a simple
explanation of the observed anomalous two-step thermal evolution dominated by
the superconducting gap and the pseudogap, respectively. Our results imply that
the revised phase diagram is likely to take place in high-temperature
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04079</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wen-Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Shun-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Wei-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Chang-De</forenames></author></authors><title>Width-tuned magnetic order oscillation on zigzag edges of honeycomb
  nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nano Letters 17, 4400-4404 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.7b01474</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum confinement and interference often generate exotic properties in
nanostructures. One recent highlight is the experimental indication of a
magnetic phase transition in zigzag-edged graphene nanoribbons at the critical
ribbon width of about 7 nm [G. Z. Magda et al., Nature \textbf{514}, 608
(2014)]. Here we show theoretically that with further increase in the ribbon
width, the magnetic correlation of the two edges can exhibit an intriguing
oscillatory behavior between antiferromagnetic and ferromagnetic, driven by
acquiring the positive coherence between the two edges to lower the free
energy. The oscillation effect is readily tunable in applied magnetic fields.
These novel properties suggest new experimental manifestation of the edge
magnetic orders in graphene nanoribbons, and enhance the hopes of graphene-like
spintronic nanodevices functioning at room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04080</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Vencels</keyname><forenames>Juris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakovics</keyname><forenames>Andris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geza</keyname><forenames>Vadims</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scepanskis</keyname><forenames>Mihails</forenames></author></authors><title>EOF Library: Open-Source Elmer and OpenFOAM Coupler for Simulation of
  MHD With Free Surface</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An open-source library called EOF which provides efficient two-way coupling
between the finite element multi-physics simulation software Elmer and
computational fluid dynamics software OpenFOAM is presented. Library controls
interpolation and communication of fields between two codes. The main focus of
this code is industrial magnetohydrodynamics with free surface, but it can be
extended to other 2D and 3D multi-physics problems. Simulation results for 2D
axisymmetric problem of conductive fluid with free surface surrounded by
alternate electromagnetic field created by inductor are compared with analogous
simulation results made by another author.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04086</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>W&#xf3;jcik</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adamowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin filtering effect generated by the inter-subband spin-orbit coupling
  in the bilayer nanowire with the quantum point contact</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci.Rep., 2017; 7: 45346</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep45346</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin filtering effect in the bilayer nanowire with quantum point contact
is investigated theoretically. We demonstrate the new mechanism of the spin
filtering based on the lateral inter-subband spin-orbit coupling, which for the
bilayer nanowires has been reported to be strong. The proposed spin filtering
effect is explained as the joint effect of the Landau-Zener inter-subband
transitions caused by the hybridization of states with opposite spin (due to
the lateral Rashba SO interaction) and the confinement of carriers in the
quantum point contact region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04089</id><created>2017-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Chaozhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Maokang</forenames></author></authors><title>Bound states in the continuum of fractional Schr\&quot;odinger equation in
  the Earth's gravitational field and their effects in the presence of a
  minimal length: applications to distinguish ultralight particles</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the influence of the fractional dimensions of the L\'evy path
under the Earth's gravitational field is studied, and the phase transitions of
energy and wave functions are obtained: the energy changes from discrete to
continuous and wave functions change from non-degenerate to degenerate when
dimension of L\'evy path becomes from integer to non-integer. By analyzing the
phase transitions, we solve two popular problems. First, we find an exotic way
to produce the bound states in the continuum (BICs), our approach only needs a
simple potential, and does not depend on interactions between particles.
Second, we address the continuity of the energy will become strong when the
mass of the particle becomes small. By deeply analyze, it can provide a way to
distinguish ultralight particles from others types in the Earth's gravitational
field, and five popular particles are discussed. In addition, we obtain
analytical expressions for the wave functions and energy in the Earth's
gravitational field in the circumstance of a fractional fractal dimensional
L\'evy path. Moreover, to consider the influence of the minimal length, we
analyze the phase transitions and the BICs in the presence of the minimal
length. We find the phenomenon energy shift do not exist, which is a common
phenomenon in the presence of the minimal length, and hence such above
phenomena can still be found. Finally, relations between our results and
existing results are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04091</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tiwari</keyname><forenames>S C</forenames></author></authors><title>Spintronics: Maxwell-Dirac theory, charge and spin</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of spin current and the separation of charge current and spin
current are two of the fundamental questions in spintronics. For this purpose
the classical limit of the Maxwell-Dirac theory is investigated in the present
contribution. Since the Dirac equation reduces to the Weyl equation for
massless particles, a vortex solution is obtained for the Weyl equation and it
is argued that mass has stochastic origin. The Weyl vortex is embedded in a
Gaussian wavepacket to define physical vortex. Two-vortex internal structure of
electron is developed in terms of Weyl and sub-quantum Weyl vortices
characterized by $\hbar$ and $f=e^2/2\pi c$ respectively. It is suggested that
this model may find application in spintronics with a new perspective.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04110</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04110</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Yasuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jennifer I-Hsiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okuzumi</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Dust Growth and Magnetic Fields: from Cores to Disks (even down to
  Planets)</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Invited talk; 6 pages, 2 figures, 1 table; to appear in proceedings
  of SFDE conference, eds. D. Johnstone, T. Hoang, F. Nakamura, Q. N. Luong,
  and J. T. Tranh Van</comments><report-no>ICISE/SFDE16/005</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent rapid progress in observations of circumstellar disks and
extrasolar planets has reinforced the importance of understanding an intimate
coupling between star and planet formation. Under such a circumstance, it may
be invaluable to attempt to specify when and how planet formation begins in
star-forming regions and to identify what physical processes/quantities are the
most significant to make a link between star and planet formation. To this end,
we have recently developed a couple of projects. These include an observational
project about dust growth in Class 0 YSOs and a theoretical modeling project of
the HL Tauri disk. For the first project, we utilize the archive data of radio
interferometric observations, and examine whether dust growth, a first step of
planet formation, occurs in Class 0 YSOs. We find that while our observational
results can be reproduced by the presence of large ($\sim$ mm) dust grains for
some of YSOs under the single-component modified blackbody formalism, an
interpretation of no dust growth would be possible when a more detailed model
is used. For the second project, we consider an origin of the disk
configuration around HL Tauri, focusing on magnetic fields. We find that
magnetically induced disk winds may play an important role in the HL Tauri
disk. The combination of these attempts may enable us to move towards a
comprehensive understanding of how star and planet formation are intimately
coupled with each other.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04111</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Maheshwari</keyname><forenames>Shantanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hoef</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Line tension and wettability of nanodrops on curved surfaces</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Langmuir 32.1 (2015): 316-321</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.5b03925</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the formation of nanodrops on curved surfaces (both
convex and concave) by means of molecular dynamics simulations, where the
particles interact via a Lennard-Jones potential. We find that the contact
angle is not affected by the curvature of the substrate, in agreement with
previous experimental findings. This means that the change in curvature of the
drop in response to the change in curvature of the substrate can be predicted
from simple geometrical considerations, under the assumption that the drop's
shape is a spherical cap, and that the volume remains unchanged through the
curvature. The resulting prediction is in perfect agreement with the simulation
results, for both convex and concave substrates. In addition, we calculate the
line tension, namely by fitting the contact angle for different size drops to
the modified Young equation. We find that the line tension for concave surfaces
is larger than for convex surfaces, while for zero curvature it has a clear
maximum. This feature is found to be correlated with the number of particles in
the first layer of the liquid on the surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04116</id><created>2017-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Khurshudyan</keyname><forenames>Martiros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khurshudyan</keyname><forenames>Asatur</forenames></author></authors><title>On cosmology of interacting varying polytropic dark fluids</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper a possibility of the accelerated expansion of the large scale
universe with a varying polytropic fluid of a certain type is presented. About
a special role of non-gravitational interactions between dark energy and dark
matter, in particular, about a possibility of improvement and solution of
problems arising in modern cosmology, has been discussed for a long time. This
motivates us to consider new models, where non-gravitational interactions
between varying polytropic fluid and cold dark matter are allowed. Mainly
non-linear interactions of a specific type is considered, found in recent
literature. In order to understand the behavior of suggested cosmological
models, besides cosmographic analysis, $Om$ analysis is applied. Moreover, with
different datasets, including a strong gravitational lensing dataset, the
observational constraints on the model parameters are obtained using $\chi^{2}$
analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04150</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuhfittig</keyname><forenames>Peter K. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal-symmetry wormholes supported by a perfect fluid</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>New Horizons in Mathematical Physics, vol. 1, pp. 14-18, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a new wormhole solution by assuming that a homogeneously
distributed fluid with equation of state $p=\omega\rho$ can be adapted to an
anisotropic spacetime such as a wormhole and that this spacetime admits a
one-parameter group of conformal motions. The pressure $p$ in the equation of
state becomes the lateral pressure $p_t$ instead of the radial pressure $p_r$,
as assumed in previous studies. Given that $p_t=\omega\rho$, $p_r$ is then
determined from the Einstein field equations. A wormhole solution can be
obtained only if $\omega &lt;-1$ or $0&lt;\omega &lt;1$. Since the former case
corresponds to phantom dark energy, which has been the subject of earlier
studies, we concentrate mainly on the latter. This case implies that given the
above conditions, dark matter can support traversable wormholes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04153</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04153</id><created>2017-07-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Mu-Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Killing Vectors in Spacetime of the De Sitter Invariant Special
  Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we use the Killing vector method to formulate the de
Sitter/Anti-de Sitter invariant special relativity (dS/AdS-SR). Through solving
the Einstein equation with $\Lambda\neq 0$, the basic inertial metric for
dS/AdS-SR is determined to be the Beltrami metric $B_{\mu\nu}(x)$. The
corresponding Killing equations are system of ten simultaneous partial
differential equations of first order. Their most general solutions were
obtained, and all the ten independent Killing vectors were found out. These
results confirm that the Beltrami metric has maximal spacetime symmetry. The
ten Killing-Noether charges are obtained. They are energy, momenta, Lorentz
boost and angular momentum in SR-theory with $\Lambda\neq 0$. Consequently,
dS/AdS-SR is consistently established for the vacuum with $\Lambda\neq 0$ via
Killing vector method rather than the unpopular classical domain theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04157</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Hochet</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tailleux</keyname><forenames>Remi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhlbrodt</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames></author></authors><title>Isoneutral control of effective diapycnal mixing in numerical ocean
  models with neutral rotated diffusion tensors</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 Figures, first draft of a paper submitted to Ocean
  Sciences 13 July 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The current view about the mixing of heat and salt in the ocean is that it
should be parameterised by means of a rotated diffusion tensor based on mixing
directions parallel and perpendicular to the local neutral vector. However, the
impossibility to construct a density variable in the ocean that is exactly
neutral because of the coupling between thermobaricity and density-compensated
temperature/salinity anomalies implies that the effective diapycnal diffusivity
experienced by any possible density variable is partly controlled by isoneutral
diffusion when using neutral rotated diffusion. Here, this effect is quantified
by evaluating the effective diapycnal diffusion coefficient for five widely
used density variables: Jackett and McDougall (1997) $\gamma^n$, Lorenz
reference state density $\rho_{ref}$ of Winters et al. (1996), Saenz et al.
(2015), and three potential density variables $\sigma_0$, $\sigma_2$ and
$\sigma_4$.Computations use the World Ocean Circulation Experiment climatology,
assuming either a uniform value for isoneutral mixing or spatially varying
values inferred from an inverse calculation. Isopycnal mixing contributions to
the effective diapycnal mixing yields values systematically larger than
$10^{-3}$ $\text{m}^2/\text{s}$ in the deep ocean for all density variables,
with $\gamma^n$ suffering the least from the isoneutral control of effective
diapycnal mixing, and $\sigma_0$ the most. These high values are due to
spatially localised large values of non-neutrality, mostly in the deep Southern
Ocean. Removing only 5\% of these high values on each density surface reduces
the effective diapycnal diffusivities to less than $10^{-4}$
$\text{m}^2/\text{s}$. This work highlights the potential pitfalls of
estimating diapycnal diffusivities by means of Walin-like water masses analysis
or in using Lorenz reference state for diagnosing spurious numerical diapycnal
mixing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04159</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Matsuno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itagaki</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of cluster-shell competition and BCS-like pairing in $^{12}$C</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The antisymmetrized quasi-cluster model (AQCM) was proposed to describe
{\alpha}-cluster and $jj$-coupling shell models on the same footing. In this
model, the cluster-shell transition is characterized by two parameters; $R$
representing the distance between {\alpha} clusters and {\alpha} describing the
breaking of {\alpha} clusters, and the contribution of the spin-orbit
interaction, very important in the $jj$-coupling shell model, can be taken into
account starting with the {\alpha} cluster model wave function. Not only the
closure configurations of the major shells, but also the subclosure
configurations of the $jj$-coupling shell model can be described starting with
the {\alpha}-cluster model wave functions; however, the particle hole
excitations of single particles have not been fully established yet. In this
study we show that the framework of AQCM can be extended even to the states
with the character of single particle excitations. For $^{12}$C, two particle
two hole (2p2h) excitations from the subclosure configuration of $0p_{3/2}$
corresponding to BCS-like pairing are described, and these shell model states
are coupled with the three {\alpha} cluster model wave functions. The
correlation energy from the optimal configuration can be estimated not only in
the cluster part but also in the shell model part. We try to pave the way to
establish a generalized description of the nuclear structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04165</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Liqin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poplawsky</keyname><forenames>Jonathan D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Iver E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microstructural and magnetic property evolution with different
  heat-treatment conditions in an alnico alloy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Acta Materialia, 133:73 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2017.05.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Further property enhancement of alnico, an attractive near-term,
non-rare-earth permanent magnet alloy system, primarily composed of Al, Ni, Co,
and Fe, relies on improved morphology control and size refinement of its
complex spinodally decomposed nanostructure that forms during heat-treatment.
Using a combination of transmission electron microscopy and atom probe
tomography techniques, this study evaluates the magnetic properties and
microstructures of an isotropic 32.4Fe-38.1Co-12.9Ni-7.3Al-6.4Ti-3.0Cu
(wt.$\%$) alloy in terms of processing parameters such as annealing
temperature, annealing time, application of an external magnetic field, as well
as low-temperature &quot;draw&quot; annealing. Optimal spinodal morphology and spacing is
formed within a narrow temperature and time range ($\sim 840 \unicode{x2103}$
and 10 min during thermal-magnetic annealing (MA). The ideal morphology is a
mosaic structure consisting of periodically arrayed $\sim 40$ nm diameter
(Fe-Co)-rich rods ($\alpha_1$ phase) embedded in an (Al-Ni)-rich ($\alpha_2$
phase) matrix. A Cu-enriched phase with a size of $\sim$ 3-5 nm is located at
the corners of two adjacent $\{110\}$ facets of the $\alpha_1$ phase. The MA
process significantly increased remanence ($B_\text{r}$) ($\sim$ 40-70 $\%$) of
the alloy due to biased elongation of the $\alpha_1$ phase along the
$\langle100\rangle$ crystallographic direction, which is closest in orientation
to the applied magnetic field. The optimum magnetic properties of the alloy
with an intrinsic coercivity ($H_\text{cj}$) of 1845 Oe and a maximum energy
product ($BH_\text{max}$) of 5.9 MGOe were attributed to the uniformity of the
mosaic structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04167</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Galdi</keyname><forenames>Giovanni P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzone</keyname><forenames>Giusy</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability and Long-Time Behavior of a Pendulum with an Interior Cavity
  Filled with a Viscous Liquid</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show asymptotic, exponential stability of the equilibrium configuration,
$\smallL$, of a hollow physical pendulum with its inner part entirely filled
with a viscous liquid, corresponding to the center of mass being in the lowest
position. Moreover, we prove that every weak solution with initial data
possessing finite total initial energy and belonging to a &quot;large&quot; open set,
becomes eventually smooth and decays exponentially fast to the equilibrium
$\smallL$. These results are obtained also as byproduct of a &quot;generalized
linearization principle&quot; that we show for evolution equations with non-empty
&quot;slow&quot; center manifold.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04168</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Bajkova</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bobylev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Galactic Orbits of Selected Companions of the Milky Way</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, 5 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Reports, 2017, Vol. 61, No 9, pp. 727-738</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063772917080017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-accuracy absolute proper motions, radial velocities, and distances have
now been measured for a number of dwarf-galaxy companions of the Milky Way,
making it possible to study their 3D dynamics. Galactic orbits for 11 such
galaxies (Fornax, Sagittarius, Ursa Minor, LMC, SMC, Sculptor, Sextans, Carina,
Draco, Leo I, Leo II) have been derived using two previously refined models for
the Galactic potential with the Navarro-Frenk-White and Allen-Santill'an
expressions for the potential of the dark-matter halo, and two different masses
for the Galaxy within 200 kpc - 0.75x10^12 Mo and 1.45x10^12 Mo. The character
of the orbits of most of these galaxies indicates that they are tightly
gravitationally bound to the Milky Way, even with the lower-mass model for the
gravitational potential. One exception is the most distant galaxy in the list,
Leo I, whose orbit demonstrates that it is only weakly gravitationally bound,
even using the higher-mass model of the gravitational potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04169</id><created>2017-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Penrose</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlated &quot;noise&quot; in LIGO gravitational wave signals: an implication of
  Conformal Cyclic Cosmology</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has recently been reported by Cresswell et al. [1] that correlations in
the noise surrounding the observed gravitational wave signals, GW150194,
GW151226, and GW170194 were found by the two LIGO detectors in Hanford and
Livingston with the same time delay as the signals themselves. This raised some
issues about the statistical reliability of the signals themselves, which led
to much discussion, the current view appearing to support the contention that
there is something unexplained that may be of genuine astrophysical interest
[2]. In this note, it is pointed out that a resolution of this puzzle may be
found in a proposal very recently put forward by the author [3], see also [4],
that what seems to be spuriously generated noise may in fact be gravitational
events caused by the decay of dark-matter particles (erebons) of mass around
10^-5g, the existence of such events being a clear implication of the
cosmological scheme of conformal cyclic cosmology, or CCC [5], [6]. A brief
outline of the salient points of CCC is provided here, especially with regard
to its prediction of erebons and their impulsive gravitational signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04178</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ou</keyname><forenames>Yunbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Haiwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xucun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Qi-Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yongqing</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced electron dephasing in three-dimensional topological insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures, supplemental information available upon request
  or visit the ncomms website</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 16071 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms16071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Study of the dephasing in electronic systems is not only important for
probing the nature of their ground states, but also crucial to harnessing the
quantum coherence for information processing. In contrast to well-studied
conventional metals and semiconductors, it remains unclear which mechanism is
mainly responsible for electron dephasing in three-dimensional (3D) topological
insulators (TIs). Here, we report on using weak antilocalization effect to
measure the dephasing rates in highly tunable (Bi,Sb)$_2$Te$_3$ thin films. As
the transport is varied from a bulk-conducting regime to surface-dominant
transport, the dephasing rate is observed to evolve from a linear temperature
dependence to a sublinear power-law dependence. While the former is consistent
with the Nyquist electron-electron interactions commonly seen in ordinary 2D
systems, the latter leads to enhanced electron dephasing at low temperatures
and is attributed to the coupling between the surface states and the localized
charge puddles in the bulk of 3D TIs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04180</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>Liqin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skomski</keyname><forenames>Ralph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoffmann</keyname><forenames>Todd D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Duane D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Iver E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>C. -Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of alnico coercivity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters, 111(2):022403 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4992787</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Micromagnetic simulations of alnico show substantial deviations from
Stoner-Wohlfarth behavior due to the unique size and spatial distribution of
the rod-like Fe-Co phase formed during spinodal decomposition in an external
magnetic field. The maximum coercivity is limited by single-rod effects,
especially deviations from ellipsoidal shape, and by interactions between the
rods. Both the exchange interaction between connected rods and magnetostatic
interaction between rods are considered, and the results of our calculations
show good agreement with recent experiments. Unlike systems dominated by
magnetocrystalline anisotropy, coercivity in alnico is highly dependent on
size, shape, and geometric distribution of the Fe-Co phase, all factors that
can be tuned with appropriate chemistry and thermal-magnetic annealing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04181</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Barroso</keyname><forenames>Marta F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massunaga</keyname><forenames>M. S. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Brazilian National High School Examination: assessing student's learning
  in Physics</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures, 8 tables. Submitted to Physical Review Physics
  Education Research</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The entrance to public universities in Brazil depends on scores obtained by
students in Enem, Brazilian National Assessment of High School Education. This
exam consists of four multiple choice tests (Language, Maths, Natural and Human
Sciences) scored by Item Response Theory (IRT). It is a high stake exam for
students, allowing the use of its results of this exam to provide conditions
for monitoring high school learning and quality of education in Brazil. We
present a study of the Physics items of Enem from 2009 to 2014. The questions
were classified based on qualitative categories, providing a profile of the
Natural Sciences test: a disciplinary exam (Physics, Chemistry and Biology),
with mostly qualitative questions, long and time consuming items, only a few of
them demanding more complex reasoning and assessing some problem solving
skills. The answers of the students were analyzed, using basic statistical
exploration and IRT to draw the ICC of the Physics items. A comparison was made
between the qualitative analysis and the quantitative analysis for the Physics
questions. The study of student performance reveals the low attaining levels of
Physics learning at the end of high school, with a small percentage of correct
answers; students perform worse in questions that require disciplinary
knowledge or use of basic mathematical reasoning. It is also possible to
observe discrepancies on the results of two subsets of groups: female students
perform worse than male students in most items, and students that come from
federal and private high school perform significantly better that those from
state high school (75% of students in high school attend state or regional
schools). In conclusion, the combined analysis of student's performance and
content of the items reveal some of the characteristics of student's learning
in Brazil, at around 18 years, that can impact Physics Education system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04184</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Maheshwari</keyname><forenames>Shantanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hoef</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xuehua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohse</keyname><forenames>Detlef</forenames></author></authors><title>Stability of Surface Nanobubbles: A Molecular Dynamics Study</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Langmuir 32, no. 43 (2016): 11116-11122</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b00963</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stability and growth or dissolution of a single surface nanobubble on a
chemically patterned surface are studied by Molecular Dynamics (MD) simulations
of binary mixtures consisting of Lennard-Jones (LJ) particles. Our simulations
reveal how pinning of the three-phase contact line on the surface can lead to
the stability of the surface nanobubble, provided that the concentration of the
dissolved gas is oversaturated. We have performed equilibrium simulations of
surface nanobubbles at different gas oversaturation levels $\zeta&gt;0$. The
equilibrium contact angle $\theta_e$ is found to follow the theoretical result
of Lohse and Zhang (Phys. Rev. E 2015, 91, 031003(R)), namely $\sin\theta_e =
\zeta L/L_c$, where L is the pinned length of the footprint and $L_c =
4\gamma/P_0$ a capillary length scale, with $\gamma$ the surface tension and
$P_0$ the ambient pressure. For undersaturation $\zeta&lt;0$ the surface
nanobubble dissolves and the dissolution dynamics shows a &quot;stick-jump&quot;
behaviour of the three-phase contact line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04211</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04211</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Batra</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huan</keyname><forenames>Tran Doan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossetti,</keyname><forenames>George A.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Ramprasad</keyname><forenames>Rampi</forenames></author></authors><title>Dopants Promoting Ferroelectricity in Hafnia: Insights From A
  Comprehensive Chemical Space Exploration</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although dopants have been extensively employed to promote ferroelectricity
in hafnia films, their role in stabilizing the responsible ferroelectric
non-equilibrium Pca21 phase is not well understood. In this work, using first
principles computations, we investigate the influence of nearly 40 dopants on
the phase stability in bulk hafnia to identify dopants that can favor formation
of the polar Pca21 phase. Although no dopant was found to stabilize this polar
phase as the ground state, suggesting that dopants alone cannot induce
ferroelectricity in hafnia, Ca, Sr, Ba, La, Y and Gd were found to
significantly lower the energy of the polar phase with respect to the
equilibrium monoclinic phase. These results are consistent with the empirical
measurements of large remnant polarization in hafnia films doped with these
elements. Additionally, clear chemical trends of dopants with larger ionic
radii and lower electronegativity favoring the polar Pca21 phase in hafnia were
identified. For this polar phase, an additional bond between the dopant cation
and the 2nd nearest oxygen neighbor was identified as the root-cause of these
trends. Further, trivalent dopants (Y, La, and Gd) were revealed to stabilize
the polar Pca21 phase at lower strains when compared to divalent dopants (Sr
and Ba). Based on these insights, we predict that the lanthanide series metals,
the lower half of alkaline earth metals (Ca, Sr and Ba) and Y as the most
suitable dopants to promote ferroelectricity in hafnia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04223</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Sang June</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>Jung-Hun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalmau</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Kwangeun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Jeongpil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Deyin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Yei Hwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>In-Kyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Munho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xudong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moody</keyname><forenames>Weidong Zhou Baxter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Zhenqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>UVC LEDs on Bulk AlN Substrates Using Silicon Nanomembranes for
  Efficient Hole Injection</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As UV LEDs are explored at shorter wavelengths (&lt; 280 nm) into the UVC
spectral range, the crystalline quality of epitaxial AlGaN films with high Al
compositions and inefficient hole injection from p-type AlGaN severely limit
the LED performance and development. In this work, we report on 237 nm light
emission with a record light output power of 265 uW from AlN/Al0.72Ga028N
multiple quantum well UVC LEDs using bulk AlN substrates and p-type silicon
nanomembrane contact layers for significantly improved AlGaN film quality and
hole injection, respectively. No intensity degradation or efficiency droop was
observed up to a current density of 245 A/cm2, which is attributed to the low
dislocation density within AlGaN films, the large concentration of holes from
p-Si, and efficient hole-transport to the active region. Additionally, the
emission peak at 237 nm is dominant across the electroluminescence spectrum
with no significant parasitic emissions observed. This study demonstrates the
feasibility of using p-Si as a hole injector for UVC LEDs, which can be
extended to even shorter wavelengths where hole injection from chemically doped
AlGaN layers is not feasible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04230</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Michielsen</keyname><forenames>Kristel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lippert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Raedt</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete-event simulation unmasks the quantum Cheshire Cat</title><categories>quant-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Comp. Theor. Nanosci. 14, 2268 - 2283 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that discrete-event simulation accurately reproduces the
experimental data of a single-neutron interferometry experiment [T. Denkmayr
{\sl et al.}, Nat. Commun. 5, 4492 (2014)] and provides a logically consistent,
paradox-free, cause-and-effect explanation of the quantum Cheshire cat effect
without invoking the notion that the neutron and its magnetic moment separate.
Describing the experimental neutron data using weak-measurement theory is shown
to be useless for unravelling the quantum Cheshire cat effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04241</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cruikshank</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobs</keyname><forenames>Kurt</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of quantum measurements in physical processes and protocols</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>2017 Quantum Science and Technology 2 033001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2058-9565/aa6d3e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this mainly pedagogical article, we discuss under what circumstances
measurements play a special role in quantum processes. In particular we discuss
the following facts which appear to be a common area of confusion: i) from a
fundamental point of view measurements play no special role whatsoever: all
dynamics that can be generated by measurements can be generated by unitary
processes (for which post-selection is no exception), ii) from a purely
physical point of view, measurements are not &quot;outside&quot; of quantum mechanics,
iii) the only difference between the abilities of measurement-based protocols
and unitary circuits for quantum computing comes from practical (technology
dependent) constraints. We emphasize the importance of distinguishing between
differences that are i) fundamental but without physical import, ii)
fundamental and possess physical import, iii) are not fundamental but have
practical import. We also emphasize the importance of separating theoretical
and experimental elements of measurement, primarily projection and
amplification, which are physically very different. Note that since we are
concerned with facts regarding physical processes, this article has little if
anything to do with interpretations of quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04243</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Prvanovic</keyname><forenames>Slobodan</forenames></author></authors><title>Radioactive Decay Seen as Temporal Canonical Ensemble</title><categories>quant-ph nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The operator of time formalism is applied to radioactive decay. It appears
that the proposed approach offers better insight and understanding of the
phenomena in a way that the decay exponential-law becomes the Boltzmann
distribution in Gibbs treatment of canonical ensemble. The radioactive decay is
seen as temporal canonical ensemble where the radioactive constant appears as
the analog of the absolute temperature multiplied by Boltzmann constant. The
stochastic character of decay process becomes plausible in the proposed
approach and the explanation why decay is characterized by constant, and not by
some parameter, is offered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-14</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04250</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Elliott</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Mile</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>Jayne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Nana</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuous variable qumodes as non-destructive probes of quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the rise of quantum technologies, it is necessary to have practical and
preferably non-destructive methods to measure and read-out from such devices. A
current line of research towards this has focussed on the use of ancilla
systems which couple to the system under investigation, and through their
interaction, enable properties of the primary system to be imprinted onto and
inferred from the ancillae. We propose the use of continuous variable qumodes
as ancillary probes, and show that the interaction Hamiltonian can be fully
characterised and directly sampled from measurements of the qumode alone. We
suggest how such probes may also be used to determine thermodynamical
properties, including reconstruction of the partition function. We show that
the method is robust to realistic experimental imperfections such as
finite-sized measurement bins and squeezing, and discuss how such probes are
already feasible with current experimental setups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
