<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:27:12Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-03" from="2017-07-03" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0809.1225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0809.1225</id><created>2008-09-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>SangChul</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomaly-free representations of the holonomy-flux algebra</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We work on the uniqueness, gr-qc/0504147, of representations of the
holonomy-flux algebra in loop quantum gravity. We argue that for analytic
diffeomorphisms, the flux operators can be only constants as functions on the
configuration space in representations with no anomaly, which are zero in the
standard representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1011.1569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1011.1569</id><created>2010-11-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Yurchenko</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennyson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A variationally computed line list for hot NH3</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>the paper has been submitted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. R. astr. Soc., 13, 1828-1834 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1365-2966.2011.18261.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present 'BYTe', a comprehensive 'hot' line list for the ro-vibrational
transitions of ammonia, 14NH3, in its ground electronic state. This line list
has been computed variationally using the program suite TROVE, a new
spectroscopically-determined potential energy surface and an ab initio dipole
moment surface. BYTe, is designed to be used at all temperatures up to 1500K.
It comprises 1137650964 transitions in the frequency range from 0 to 12000
cm-1, constructed from 1366519 energy levels below 18000 cm-1 having J values
below 36. Comparisons with laboratory data confirm the accuracy of the line
list which is suitable for modelling a variety of astrophysical problems
including the atmospheres of extrasolar planets and brown dwarfs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.2121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.2121</id><created>2012-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Gerving</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoang</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Land</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anquez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamley</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chapman</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium dynamics of an unstable quantum pendulum</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>Main text 6 pages, 5 figures; Supplement 4 pages, 1 figure</comments><doi>10.1038/ncomms2179</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A pendulum prepared perfectly inverted and motionless is a prototype of
unstable equilibria and corresponds to an unstable hyperbolic fixed point in
the dynamical phase space. Unstable fixed points are central to understanding
Hamiltonian chaos in classical systems. In many-body quantum systems,
mean-field approximations fail in the vicinity of unstable fixed points and
lead to dynamics driven by quantum fluctuations. Here, we measure the
non-equilibrium dynamics of a many-body quantum pendulum initialized to a
hyperbolic fixed point of the phase space. The experiment uses a spin-1 Bose
condensate, which exhibits Josephson dynamics in the spin populations that
correspond in the mean-field limit to motion of a non-rigid mechanical
pendulum. The condensate is initialized to a minimum uncertainty spin state,
and quantum fluctuations lead to non-linear spin evolution along a separatrix
and non-Gaussian probability distributions that are measured to be in good
agreement with exact quantum calculations up to 0.25 s. At longer times, atomic
loss due to the finite lifetime of the condensate leads to larger spin
oscillation amplitudes compared to no loss case as orbits depart from the
separatrix. This demonstrates how decoherence of a many-body system can result
in more apparent coherent behaviour. This experiment provides new avenues for
studying macroscopic spin systems in the quantum limit and for investigations
of important topics in non-equilibrium quantum dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1207.5612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1207.5612</id><created>2012-07-24</created><updated>2013-02-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jahangir</keyname><forenames>Rabia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arshed</keyname><forenames>Nigum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toor</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum capacity of an amplitude-damping channel with memory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 Pages, 5 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Info Process 14, 765 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-014-0883-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the quantum capacity of an amplitude-damping channel with time
correlated Markov noise, for two channel uses. Our results show that memory of
the channel increases it's ability to transmit quantum information
significantly. We analyze and compare our findings with earlier numerical
results on amplitude-damping channel with memory. An upper bound on the amount
of quantum information transmitted over the channel in presence of memory, for
an arbitrary number of channel uses is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.7400</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.7400</id><created>2013-07-28</created><updated>2013-10-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beige</keyname><forenames>Almut</forenames></author></authors><title>Mollow triplet for cavity-mediated laser cooling</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, improved version, new title</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 88, 053417 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.88.053417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we analyse cavity-mediated laser cooling for an experimental setup with
an external trap which strongly confines the motion of a particle in the
direction of the cavity axis. It is shown that the stationary state phonon
number exhibits three sharp minima as a function of the atom-cavity detuning
due to a direct atom-phonon-photon coupling term in the system Hamiltonian.
These resonances have the same origin as the Mollow triplet in the resonance
fluorescence of a laser-driven atomic system. It is shown that a laser-Rabi
frequency-dependent atom-cavity detuning yields the lowest stationary state
phonon number for a wide range of experimental parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.2883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.2883</id><created>2013-11-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Butko</keyname><forenames>Yana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grothaus</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smolyanov</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>Feynman formulae and phase space Feynman path integrals for
  tau-quantization of some L\'evy-Khintchine type Hamilton functions</title><categories>math.FA math-ph math.AP math.MP math.PR</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 57, 023508 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4940697</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This note is devoted to representation of some evolution semigroups. The
semigroups are generated by pseudo-differential operators, which are obtained
by different (parametrized by a number $\tau$) procedures of quantization from
a certain class of functions (or symbols) defined on the phase space. This
class contains functions which are second order polynomials with respect to the
momentum variable and also some other functions. The considered semigroups are
represented as limits of $n$-fold iterated integrals when $n$ tends to infinity
(such representations are called Feynman formulae). Some of these
representations are constructed with the help of another pseudo-differential
operators, obtained by the same procedure of quantization (such representations
are called Hamiltonian Feynman formulae). Some representations are based on
integral operators with elementary kernels (these ones are called Lagrangian
Feynman formulae and are suitable for computations). A family of phase space
Feynman pseudomeasures corresponding to different procedures of quantization is
introduced. The considered evolution semigroups are represented also as phase
space Feynman path integrals with respect to these Feynman pseudomeasures. The
obtained Lagrangian Feynman formulae allow to calculate these phase space
Feynman path integrals and to connect them with some functional integrals with
respect to probability measures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.4692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.4692</id><created>2013-11-19</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yan-Ling</forenames></author></authors><title>Protecting qutrit-qutrit entanglement by weak measurement and reversal</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures. Some typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. D (2013) 67: 204</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjd/e2013-40036-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Entangled states in high dimensional systems are of great interest due to the
extended possibilities they provide in quantum information processing.
Recently, Sun et al. [Phys. Rev. A 82, 052323 (2010)] and Kim et al. [Nat.
Phys. 8, 117 (2012)] pointed out that weak measurement and quantum weak
measurement reversal can actively combat decoherence. We generalize their
studies from qubits to qutrits under amplitude damping decoherence. We find
that the qutrit-qutrit entanglement can be partially retrieved for certain
initial states when only weak measurement reversals are performed. However, we
can completely defeat amplitude damping decoherence for any initial states by
the combination of prior weak measurements and post optimal weak measurement
reversals. The experimental feasibility of our schemes is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02614</id><created>2015-03-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mora</keyname><forenames>Alcione</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastian</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biermann</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chassat</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindegren</keyname><forenames>Lennart</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serraller</keyname><forenames>I&#xf1;aki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serpell</keyname><forenames>Edmund</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Reeven</keyname><forenames>Wouter</forenames></author></authors><title>The Gaia Basic angle: measurement and variations</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Proceedings of The Milky Way Unravelled by Gaia.
  GREAT Science from the Gaia Data Releases, Barcelona (Spain) 1 - 5 December
  2014. EAS publication series, in press</comments><doi>10.1051/eas/1567010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ESA Gaia mission uses two telescopes to create the most ambitious survey
of the Galaxy. The angle between them must be known with exquisite precision
and accuracy. An interferometer: the Basic Angle Monitoring system measures its
variations. High quality data have been retrieved and analysed for more than a
year. A summary of the in-orbit performance and some early results are
presented
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02731</id><created>2015-04-10</created><updated>2015-12-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jagannath</keyname><forenames>Aukosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobasco</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author></authors><title>Some Properties of the Phase Diagram for Mixed $p$-Spin Glasses</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Edited to take into account referee comments. Results strengthened.
  To appear in Probability Theory and Related Fields. The final publication is
  available at Springer via http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00440-015-0691-z</comments><msc-class>60K35, 82B44, 82D30, 49S05, 49K21</msc-class><journal-ref>Probab. Theory Relat. Fields (2017) 167: 615</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00440-015-0691-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study the Parisi variational problem for mixed $p$-spin
glasses with Ising spins. Our starting point is a characterization of Parisi
measures whose origin lies in the first order optimality conditions for the
Parisi functional, which is known to be strictly convex. Using this
characterization, we study the phase diagram in the temperature-external field
plane. We begin by deriving self-consistency conditions for Parisi measures
that generalize those of de Almeida and Thouless to all levels of Replica
Symmetry Breaking (RSB) and all models. As a consequence, we conjecture that
for all models the Replica Symmetric (RS) phase is the region determined by the
natural analogue of the de Almeida-Thouless condition. We show that for all
models, the complement of this region is in the RSB phase. Furthermore, we show
that the conjectured phase boundary is exactly the phase boundary in the plane
less a bounded set. In the case of the Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model, we extend
this last result to show that this bounded set does not contain the critical
point at zero external field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07080</id><created>2015-05-26</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cabrera-Munguia</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Binary system of unequal counterrotating Kerr-Newman sources</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, 1 table, typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 91: 044005 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.044005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stationary axisymmetric binary systems of unequal counterrotating Kerr-Newman
sources with a massless strut in between are studied. By means of the choice of
a suitable parametrization, the axis conditions and the absence of individual
magnetic charges are fulfilled; thus, the entire metric reduces to a
6-parametric asymptotically flat exact solution. Later on, with the purpose to
describe interacting black holes, the analytic functional form of the horizon
half-length parameter $\sigma_{k}$ is obtained explicitly in terms of physical
Komar parameters: mass $M_{k}$, electric charge $Q_{k}$, angular momentum
$J_{k}$, and coordinate distance $R$, where the seven physical parameters
satisfy a simple algebraic relation. Finally, in the limit of extreme black
holes, the full metric is derived in a closed analytical form, and a study on
the absence or appearance of naked singularities off the axis is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03277</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baker</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poth&#xe9;rat</keyname><forenames>Alban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoust</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author></authors><title>Dimensionality, secondary flows and helicity in low-Rm MHD vortices</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.420</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we examine the dimensionality of a single electrically driven
vortex bounded by two no-slip and perfectly insulating horizontal walls distant
by $h$. The study was performed in the weakly inertial limit by means of an
asymptotic expansion, which is valid for any Hartmann number. We show that the
dimensionality of the leading order can be fully described using the single
parameter $l_z^\nu / h$, where $l_z^\nu$ represents the distance over which the
Lorentz force is able to act before being balanced by viscous dissipation. The
base flow happens to introduce inertial recirculations in the meridional plane
at the first order, which are shown to follow two radically different
mechanisms: inverse Ekman pumping driven by a vertical pressure gradient along
the axis of the vortex, or direct Ekman pumping driven by a radial pressure
gradient in the Hartman boundary layers. We demonstrate that when the base flow
is quasi-2D, the relative importance of direct and inverse pumping is solely
determined by the aspect ratio $\eta / h$, where $\eta$ refers to the width of
the vortex. Of both mechanisms, only inverse pumping appears to act as a
significant source of helicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00449</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diaz-Marin</keyname><forenames>Homero G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirichlet to Neumann operator for abelian Yang-Mills gauge fields</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Keywords: gauge fields; variational boundary value problems; Hodge
  theory; Dirichlet to Neumann operator Subject classification: Yang-Mills
  theory, topological field theo- ries, methods from differential geometry</comments><msc-class>58J32, 49S05, 58E15, 70S15</msc-class><doi>10.1142/S0219887817501535</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the Dirichlet to Neumann operator for abelian Yang- Mills
boundary conditions. We treat the case for space-time manifolds with general
smooth boundary components. The aim is constructing a complex structure for the
symplectic space of boundary conditions of Euler-Lagrange solutions modulo
gauge. Thus we prepare a suitable scenario for geometric quantization of
abelian gauge fields following a symplectic reduction procedure in a Lagrangian
setting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07160</id><created>2015-08-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Beige</keyname><forenames>Almut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>A cavity-mediated collective quantum effect in sonoluminescing bubbles</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, Proceedings of the 9th International Symposium on
  Cavitation CAV 2015</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Conf. Ser. 656, 012177 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/656/1/012177</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper discusses a collective quantum effect which might play an
important role in sonoluminescence experiments. We suggest that it occurs
during the final stages of the collapse phase and enhances the heating of the
particles inside the bubble.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02442</id><created>2015-09-04</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sutherland</keyname><forenames>Roderick</forenames></author></authors><title>Lagrangian Description for Particle Interpretations of Quantum Mechanics
  -- Entangled Many-Particle Case</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>37 pages</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, Vol.47, pp. 174-207 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0043-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Lagrangian formulation is constructed for particle interpretations of
quantum mechanics, a well-known example of such an interpretation being the
Bohm model. The advantages of such a description are that the equations for
particle motion, field evolution and conservation laws can all be deduced from
a single Lagrangian density expression. The formalism presented is Lorentz
invariant. This paper follows on from a previous one which was limited to the
single-particle case. The present paper treats the more general case of many
particles in an entangled state. It is found that describing more than one
particle while maintaining a relativistic description requires the
specification of final boundary conditions as well as the usual initial ones,
with the experimenter's controllable choice of the final conditions thereby
exerting a backwards-in-time influence. This retrocausality then allows an
important theoretical step forward to be made, namely that it becomes possible
to dispense with the usual, many-dimensional description in configuration space
and instead revert to a description in spacetime using separate,
single-particle wavefunctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05206</id><created>2015-10-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Korobov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koelemeij</keyname><forenames>Jeroen C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilico</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karr</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Test of the theoretical hyperfine structure of the molecular hydrogen
  ion at the 1-ppm level</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 053003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.053003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the $m \alpha^6 (m/M)$ order corrections to the hyperfine
splitting in the H$_2^+$ ion, and find a hitherto unrecognized second-order
relativistic contribution associated with the vibrational motion of the nuclei.
Inclusion of this correction term produces theoretical predictions which are in
excellent agreement with experimental data [K. B. Jefferts, Phys.\ Rev.\ Lett.\
\textbf{23}, 1476 (1969)], thereby concluding a nearly fifty years long
theoretical quest to explain the experimental results within their 1-ppm error.
The agreement between theory and experiment corroborates the proton structural
properties as derived from the hyperfine structure of atomic hydrogen. Our work
furthermore indicates that for future improvements, a full three-body
evaluation of the $m \alpha^6 (m/M)$ correction term will be mandatory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05720</id><created>2015-10-19</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>S.</keyname><forenames>A. Pinho S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendon&#xe7;a</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>New cosmological solutions in massive gravity theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, text revised</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Mex. Astron. Astrofis. 53, 17 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present some new cosmological solutions in massive gravity
theory. Some homogeneous and isotropic solutions correctly describe accelerated
evolutions for the universe. The study was realized considering a specific form
to the fiducial metric and found different functions and constant parameters of
the theory that guarantees the conservation of the energy momentum tensor.
Several accelerating cosmologies were found, all of them reproducing a
cosmological constant term proportional to the graviton mass, with a de Sitter
type solution for the scale factor. We have also verified that when the
fiducial metric is close to the physical metric the solutions are absent,
except for some specific open cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06731</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cacciapuoti</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finco</keyname><forenames>Domenico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noja</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teta</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>The point-like limit for a NLS equation with concentrated nonlinearity
  in dimension three</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages. Major changes in the introduction, updated references,
  corrected several minor misprints</comments><msc-class>35Q55, 81Q15, 35B25</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Funct. Anal. 273 (2017), no. 5, 1762-1809</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jfa.2017.04.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a scaling limit of a nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation (NLS) with
a nonlocal nonlinearity showing that it reproduces in the limit of cutoff
removal a NLS equation with nonlinearity concentrated at a point. The
regularized dynamics is described by the equation \begin{equation*}
i\frac{\partial }{\partial t} \psi^\varepsilon(t)= -\Delta \psi^\varepsilon(t)
+ g(\varepsilon,\mu,|(\rho^\varepsilon,\psi^\varepsilon(t))|^{2\mu})
(\rho^\varepsilon,\psi^\varepsilon(t)) \rho^\varepsilon \end{equation*} where
$\rho^{\varepsilon} \to \delta_0$ weakly and the function $g$ embodies the
nonlinearity and the scaling and has to be fine tuned in order to have a
nontrivial limit dynamics. The limit dynamics is a nonlinear version of point
interaction in dimension three and it has been previously studied in several
papers as regards the well-posedness, blow-up and asymptotic properties of
solutions. Our result is the first justification of the model as the point
limit of a regularized dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06762</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2017-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Annoni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guglielmi</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carminati</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sampietro</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>David A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melloni</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morichetti</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>All-optical mode unscrambling on a silicon photonic chip</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>23 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Light: Science &amp; Applications (2017) 6, e17110</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/lsa.2017.110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Propagation of light beams through scattering or multimode systems may lead
to randomization of the spatial coherence of the light. Although information is
not lost, its recovery requires a coherent interferometric reconstruction of
the original signals, which have been scrambled into the modes of the
scattering system. Here, we show that we can automatically unscramble four
optical beams that have been arbitrarily mixed in a multimode waveguide,
undoing the scattering and mixing between the spatial modes through a mesh of
silicon photonics Mach-Zehnder interferometers. Using embedded transparent
detectors and a progressive tuning algorithm, the mesh self-configures
automatically and reset itself after significantly perturbing the mixing,
without turning off the beams. We demonstrate the recovery of four separate 10
Gbits/s information channels, with residual cross-talk between beams of -20dB.
This principle of self-configuring and self-resetting in optical systems should
be applicable in a wide range of optical applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00657</id><created>2016-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Jagannath</keyname><forenames>Aukosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobasco</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author></authors><title>Low Temperature Asymptotics in Spherical Mean Field Spin Glasses</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. (2017) 352: 979</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-017-2864-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we study the low temperature limit of the spherical
Crisanti-Sommers variational problem. We identify the $\Gamma$-limit of the
Crisanti-Sommers functionals, thereby establishing a rigorous variational
problem for the ground state energy of spherical mixed $p$-spin glasses. As an
application, we compute moderate deviations of the corresponding minimizers in
the low temperature limit. In particular, for a large class of models this
yields moderate deviations for the overlap distribution. We then analyze the
ground state energy problem. We show that this variational problem is dual to
an obstacle-type problem. This duality is at the heart of our analysis. We
present the regularity theory of the optimizers of the primal and dual
problems. This culminates in a simple method for constructing a finite
dimensional space in which these optimizers live for any model. As a
consequence of these results, we unify independent predictions of
Crisanti-Leuzzi and Auffinger-Ben Arous regarding the 1RSB phase in this limit.
We find that the &quot;positive replicon eigenvalue&quot; and &quot;pure-like&quot; conditions are
together necessary for optimality, but that neither are themselves sufficient,
answering a question of Auffinger and Ben Arous in the negative. We end by
proving that these conditions completely characterize the 1RSB phase in
$2+p$-spin models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07993</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>Stephon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrow</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magueijo</keyname><forenames>Joao</forenames></author></authors><title>Turning on gravity with the Higgs mechanism</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Version which appeared in Classical and Quantum Gravity</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33, 14LT01 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/14/14LT01</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate how a Higgs mechanism could be responsible for the emergence
of gravity in extensions of Einstein theory. In this scenario, at high
energies, symmetry restoration could &quot;turn off&quot; gravity, with dramatic
implications for cosmology and quantum gravity. The sense in which gravity is
muted depends on the details of the implementation. In the most extreme case
gravity's dynamical degrees of freedom would only be unleashed after the Higgs
field acquires a non-trivial vacuum expectation value, with gravity reduced to
a topological field theory in the symmetric phase. We might also identify the
Higgs and the Brans-Dicke fields in such a way that in the unbroken phase
Newton's constant vanishes, decoupling matter and gravity. We discuss the broad
implications of these scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03129</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Devereaux</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shvaika</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohlfeld</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moritz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaix</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>W. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Z. -X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghiringhelli</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Braicovich</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directly characterizing the relative strength and momentum dependence of
  electron-phonon coupling using resonant inelastic x-ray scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 041019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.041019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The coupling between lattice and charge degrees of freedom in condensed
matter materials is ubiquitous and can often result in interesting properties
and ordered phases, including conventional superconductivity, charge density
wave order, and metal-insulator transitions. Angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy and both neutron and non-resonant x-ray scattering serve as
effective probes for determining the behavior of appropriate, individual
degrees of freedom -- the electronic structure and lattice excitation, or
phonon dispersion, respectively. However, each provides less direct information
about the mutual coupling between the degrees of freedom, usual through
self-energy effects, which tend to renormalize and broaden spectral features
precisely where the coupling is strong, impacting ones ability to quantitively
characterize the coupling. Here we demonstrate that resonant inelastic x-ray
scattering, or RIXS, can be an effective tool to directly determine the
relative strength and momentum dependence of the electron-phonon coupling in
condensed matter systems. Using a diagrammatic approach for an 8-band model of
copper oxides, we study the contributions from the lowest order diagrams to the
full RIXS intensity for a realistic scattering geometry, accounting for matrix
element effects in the scattering cross-section as well as the momentum
dependence of the electron-phonon coupling vertex. A detailed examination of
these maps offers a unique perspective into the characteristics of
electron-phonon coupling, which complements both neutron and non-resonant x-ray
scattering, as well as Raman and infrared conductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06306</id><created>2016-05-20</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kijowski</keyname><forenames>Jerzy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okolow</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>A modification of the projective construction of quantum states for
  field theories</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>22 pages, 1 figure, LaTeX2e</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 58, 062303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4989550</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The projective construction of quantum states for field theories may be
flawed--in some cases the construction may possibly lead to spaces of quantum
states which are &quot;too small&quot; to be used in quantization of field theories. Here
we present a slight modification of the construction which is free from this
flaw.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06092</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Midya</keyname><forenames>Bikashkali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomza</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lemeshko</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Rotation of cold molecular ions inside a Bose-Einstein condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Final version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 041601(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.041601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use recently developed angulon theory [Phys. Rev. Lett. 114, 203001
(2015)] to study the rotational spectrum of a cyanide molecular anion immersed
into Bose-Einstein condensates of rubidium and strontium. Based on $\textit {ab
initio}$ potential energy surfaces, we provide a detailed study of the
rotational Lamb shift and many-body-induced fine structure which arise due to
dressing of molecular rotation by a field of phonon excitations. We demonstrate
that the magnitude of these effects is large enough in order to be observed in
modern experiments on cold molecular ions. Furthermore, we introduce a novel
method to construct pseudopotentials starting from the $\textit {ab initio}$
potential energy surfaces, which provides a means to obtain effective coupling
constants for low-energy polaron models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08804</id><created>2016-07-29</created><updated>2017-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemoto</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lecomte</keyname><forenames>Vivien</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-Time and -Size Scalings in the Evaluation of Large Deviation
  Functions: Numerical Approach in Continuous Time</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures. Second part of pair of companion papers,
  following Part I arXiv:1607.04752</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062134 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rare trajectories of stochastic systems are important to understand --
because of their potential impact. However, their properties are by definition
difficult to sample directly. Population dynamics provides a numerical tool
allowing their study, by means of simulating a large number of copies of the
system, which are subjected to selection rules that favor the rare trajectories
of interest. Such algorithms are plagued by finite simulation time- and finite
population size- effects that can render their use delicate. In this paper, we
present a numerical approach which uses the finite-time and finite-size
scalings of estimators of the large deviation functions associated to the
distribution of rare trajectories. The method we propose allows one to extract
the infinite-time and infinite-size limit of these estimators which -- as shown
on the contact process -- provides a significant improvement of the large
deviation functions estimators compared to the the standard one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03388</id><created>2016-08-11</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Harpreet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dahiya</keyname><forenames>Harleen</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Moments of Octet Baryons in Hot and Dense Nuclear Matter</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>Accepted for Publication in Chinese Physics C</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/9/094104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated the in-medium magnetic moments of octet baryons in the
presence of hot and dense symmetric nuclear matter. Effective magnetic moments
of baryons have been derived from medium modified quark masses within chiral
SU(3) quark mean field model.
  Further, for better insight of medium modification of baryonic magnetic
moments, we have considered the explicit contributions from the valence quarks,
sea quarks as well as sea orbital angular momentum of sea quarks. These effects
have been successful in giving the description of baryonic magnetic moments in
vacuum.
  The magnetic moments of baryons are found to vary significantly as a function
of density of nuclear medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06427</id><created>2016-08-23</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Franceschet</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozzo</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Arbitrarily regularizable graphs</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  A graph is regularizable if it is possible to assign weights to its edges so
that all nodes have the same degree. Weights can be positive, nonnegative or
arbitrary as soon as the regularization degree is not null. Positive and
nonnegative regularizable graphs have been thoroughly investigated in the
literature. In this work, we propose and study arbitrarily regularizable
graphs. In particular, we investigate necessary and sufficient regularization
conditions on the topology of the graph and of the corresponding adjacency
matrix. Moreover, we study the computational complexity of the regularization
problem and characterize it as a linear programming model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07224</id><created>2016-08-25</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ara&#xfa;jo</keyname><forenames>Tanya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontainha</keyname><forenames>Elsa</forenames></author></authors><title>The specific shapes of gender imbalance in scientific authorships: a
  network approach</title><categories>cs.SI cs.DL physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>27 Pages, 10 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gender differences in collaborative research have received little attention
when compared with the growing importance that women hold in academia and
research. Unsurprisingly, most of bibliometric databases have a strong lack of
directly available information by gender. Although empirical-based network
approaches are often used in the study of research collaboration, the studies
about the influence of gender dissimilarities on the resulting topological
outcomes are still scarce. Here, networks of scientific subjects are used to
characterize patterns that might be associated to five categories of
authorships which were built based on gender. We find enough evidence that
gender imbalance in scientific authorships brings a peculiar trait to the
networks induced from papers published in Web of Science (WoS) indexed journals
of Economics over the period 2010-2015 and having at least one author
affiliated to a Portuguese institution. Our results show the emergence of a
specific pattern when the network of co-occurring subjects is induced from a
set of papers exclusively authored by men. Such a male-exclusive authorship
condition is found to be the solely responsible for the emergence that
particular shape in the network structure. This peculiar trait might facilitate
future network analyses of research collaboration and interdisciplinarity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.02157</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.02157</id><created>2016-09-07</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alba</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Out-of-equilibrium protocol for R\'enyi entropies via the Jarzynski
  equality</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.stat-mech hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages 7 figures. Added appendix. Similar to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062132 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062132</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In recent years entanglement measures, such as the von Neumann and the
R\'enyi entropies, provided a unique opportunity to access elusive feature of
quantum many-body systems. However, extracting entanglement properties
analytically, experimentally, or in numerical simulations can be a formidable
task. Here, by combining the replica trick and the Jarzynski equality we devise
a new effective out-of-equilibrium protocol for measuring the equilibrium
R\'enyi entropies. The key idea is to perform a quench in the geometry of the
replicas. The R\'enyi entropies are obtained as the exponential average of the
work performed during the quench. We illustrate an application of the method in
classical Monte Carlo simulations, although it could be useful in different
contexts, such as in Quantum Monte Carlo, or experimentally in cold-atom
systems. The method is most effective in the quasi-static regime, i.e., for a
slow quench, where it allows to obtain the R\'enyi entropies in a single
realization of the protocol. As a benchmark, we present results for the R\'enyi
entropies in the Ising universality class in $1$$+$$1$ dimensions, which are
found in perfect agreement with the well-known Conformal Field Theory (CFT)
predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08707</id><created>2016-09-27</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Raleigh L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kok</keyname><forenames>Jasper F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugenholtz</keyname><forenames>Chris H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barchyn</keyname><forenames>Thomas E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chamecki</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ellis</keyname><forenames>Jean T.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-frequency measurements of aeolian saltation flux: Field-based
  methodology and applications</title><categories>physics.geo-ph physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>61 pages, 14 main text figures, 4 supporting figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aeolian transport of sand and dust is driven by turbulent winds that
fluctuate over a broad range of temporal and spatial scales. However, commonly
used aeolian transport models do not explicitly account for such fluctuations,
likely contributing to substantial discrepancies between models and
measurements. Underlying this problem is the absence of accurate sand flux
measurements at the short time scales at which wind speed fluctuates. Here, we
draw on extensive field measurements of aeolian saltation to develop a
methodology for generating high-frequency (25 Hz) time series of total
(vertically-integrated) saltation flux, namely by calibrating high-frequency
(HF) particle counts to low-frequency (LF) flux measurements. The methodology
follows four steps: (1) fit exponential curves to vertical profiles of
saltation flux from LF saltation traps, (2) determine empirical calibration
factors through comparison of LF exponential fits to HF number counts over
concurrent time intervals, (3) apply these calibration factors to subsamples of
the saltation count time series to obtain HF height-specific saltation fluxes,
and (4) aggregate the calibrated HF height-specific saltation fluxes into
estimates of total saltation fluxes. When coupled to high-frequency
measurements of wind velocity, this methodology offers new opportunities for
understanding how aeolian saltation dynamics respond to variability in driving
winds over time scales from tens of milliseconds to days.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01351</id><created>2016-10-05</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Principe</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malyshev</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Point Source Detection and Flux Determination with PGWave</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 7 figures, published in proceedings for the Gamma 2016
  conference</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf.Proc. 1792 (2017) no.1, 070016</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4969013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the largest uncertainties in the Point Source (PS) studies, at
Fermi-LAT energies, is the uncertainty in the diffuse background. In general
there are two approaches for PS analysis: background-dependent methods, that
include modeling of the diffuse background, and background-independent methods.
In this work we study PGWave, which is one of the background-independent
methods, based on wavelet filtering to find significant clusters of gamma rays.
PGWave is already used in the Fermi-LAT catalog pipeline for finding candidate
sources. We test PGWave, not only for source detection, but especially to
estimate the flux without the need of a background model. We use Monte Carlo
(MC) simulation to study the accuracy of PS detection and estimation of the
flux. We present preliminary results of these MC studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01915</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Acerbi</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davini</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferri</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galbiati</keyname><forenames>Cristiano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovanetti</keyname><forenames>Graham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gola</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korga</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandarano</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcante</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paternoster</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piemonte</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Razeto</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Regazzoni</keyname><forenames>Veronica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sablone</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savarese</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zappal&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>Gaetano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zorzi</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Cryogenic Characterization of FBK HD Near-UV Sensitive SiPMs</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions on Electron Devices (Volume: 64, Issue: 2, Feb.
  2017) Page(s): 521 - 526</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TED.2016.2641586</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the characterization of near-ultraviolet high density silicon
photomultiplier (\SiPM) developed at Fondazione Bruno Kessler (\FBK) at
cryogenic temperature. A dedicated setup was built to measure the primary dark
noise and correlated noise of the \SiPMs\ between 40 and 300~K. Moreover, an
analysis program and data acquisition system were developed to allow the
precise characterization of these parameters, some of which can vary up to 7
orders of magnitude between room temperature and 40~K. We demonstrate that it
is possible to operate the \FBK\ near-ultraviolet high density \SiPMs\ at
temperatures lower than 100~K with a dark rate below 0.01 cps/mm$^2$ and total
correlated noise probability below 35\% at an over-voltage of 6~V. These
results are relevant for the development of future cryogenic particle detectors
using \SiPMs\ as photosensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06443</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2017-02-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hayakawa</keyname><forenames>Hisao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takada</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic theory of discontinuous shear thickening</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Powders and Grains 2017 (in press)</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web Conf. Volume 140, 09003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201714009003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple kinetic theory to exhibit a discontinuous shear thickening (DST) is
proposed. The model includes the collision integral and the friction from
environment as well as a thermostat term characterized by $T_{\rm ex}$. The
viscosity of this model is proportional to $\dot\gamma^2$ for large shear rate
$\dot\gamma$, while it is Newtonian for low $\dot\gamma$. The emergence of the
DST is enhanced for lower density and lower nonzero $T_{\rm ex}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06597</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xingang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xianyu</keyname><forenames>Zhong-Zhi</forenames></author></authors><title>Standard Model Background of the Cosmological Collider</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures. PRL accepted version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 261302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.261302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The inflationary universe can be viewed as a &quot;Cosmological Collider&quot; with
energy of Hubble scale, producing very massive particles and recording their
characteristic signals in primordial non-Gaussianities. To utilize this
collider to explore any new physics at very high scales, it is a prerequisite
to understand the background signals from the particle physics Standard Model.
In this paper we describe the Standard Model background of the Cosmological
Collider.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08877</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>B. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Z. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. -N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>J. -Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kong</keyname><forenames>L. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Y. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strocov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>H. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Y. -G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Observation of Three-Component 'New Fermions' in
  Topological Semimetal MoP</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature 546, 627-631 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature22390</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Condensed matter systems can host quasiparticle excitations that are
analogues to elementary particles such as Majorana, Weyl, and Dirac fermions.
Recent advances in band theory have expanded the classification of fermions in
crystals, and revealed crystal symmetry-protected electron excitations that
have no high-energy counterparts. Here, using angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy, we demonstrate the existence of a triply degenerate point in the
electronic structure of MoP crystal, where the quasiparticle excitations are
beyond the Majorana-Weyl-Dirac classification. Furthermore, we observe pairs of
Weyl points in the bulk electronic structure coexisting with the 'new
fermions', thus introducing a platform for studying the interplay between
different types of fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09723</id><created>2016-10-30</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Persaud</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feinberg</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidl</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waldron</keyname><forenames>W. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lal</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinayakumar</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ardanuc</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schenkel</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A compact linear accelerator based on a scalable
  microelectromechanical-system RF-structure</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Review of Scientific Instruments 88, 063304 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4984969</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new approach for a compact radio-frequency (RF) accelerator structure is
presented. The new accelerator architecture is based on the Multiple
Electrostatic Quadrupole Array Linear Accelerator (MEQALAC) structure that was
first developed in the 1980s. The MEQALAC utilized RF resonators producing the
accelerating fields and providing for higher beam currents through parallel
beamlets focused using arrays of electrostatic quadrupoles (ESQs). While the
early work obtained ESQs with lateral dimensions on the order of a few
centimeters, using printed circuits board (PCB), we reduce the characteristic
dimension to the millimeter regime, while massively scaling up the potential
number of parallel beamlets. Using Microelectromechanical systems scalable
fabrication approaches, we are working on further reducing the characteristic
dimension to the sub-millimeter regime. The technology is based on
RF-acceleration components and ESQs implemented in PCB or silicon wafers where
each beamlet passes through beam apertures in the wafer. The complete
accelerator is then assembled by stacking these wafers. This approach has the
potential for fast and inexpensive batch fabrication of the components and
flexibility in system design for application specific beam energies and
currents. For prototyping the accelerator architecture, the components have
been fabricated using PCB. In this paper, we present proof of concept results
of the principal components using PCB: RF acceleration and ESQ focusing.
Ongoing developments on implementing components in silicon and scaling of the
accelerator technology to high currents and beam energies are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09999</id><created>2016-10-31</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Friis</keyname><forenames>Nicolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orsucci</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skotiniotis</keyname><forenames>Michalis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekatski</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunjko</keyname><forenames>Vedran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briegel</keyname><forenames>Hans J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author></authors><title>Flexible resources for quantum metrology</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9+18 pages, many figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 063044 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa7144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum metrology offers a quadratic advantage over classical approaches to
parameter estimation problems by utilizing entanglement and nonclassicality.
However, the hurdle of actually implementing the necessary quantum probe states
and measurements, which vary drastically for different metrological scenarios,
is usually not taken into account. We show that for a wide range of tasks in
metrology, 2D cluster states (a particular family of states useful for
measurement-based quantum computation) can serve as flexible resources that
allow one to efficiently prepare any required state for sensing, and perform
appropriate (entangled) measurements using only single qubit operations.
Crucially, the overhead in the number of qubits is less than quadratic, thus
preserving the quantum scaling advantage. This is ensured by using a
compression to a logarithmically sized space that contains all relevant
information for sensing. We specifically demonstrate how our method can be used
to obtain optimal scaling for phase and frequency estimation in local
estimation problems, as well as for the Bayesian equivalents with Gaussian
priors of varying widths. Furthermore, we show that in the paradigmatic case of
local phase estimation 1D cluster states are sufficient for optimal state
preparation and measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00796</id><created>2016-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>Kristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neupert</keyname><forenames>Titus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pachos</keyname><forenames>Jiannis K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Quantum Liquids with Long-Range Couplings</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4+5 pages, 3+1 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 267002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.267002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Very few topological systems with long-range couplings have been considered
so far due to our lack of analytic approaches. Here we extend the Kitaev chain,
a 1D quantum liquid, to infinite-range couplings and study its topological
properties. We demonstrate that, even though topological phases are intimately
linked to the notion of locality, the infinite-range couplings give rise to
topological zero and non-zero energy Majorana end modes depending on the
boundary conditions of the system. We show that the analytically derived
properties are to a large degree stable against modifications to decaying
long-range couplings. Our work opens new frontiers for topological states of
matter that are relevant to current experiments where suitable interactions can
be designed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01013</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01013</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>J. M. Hoff</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Rubia dos</forenames></author></authors><title>Casimir effect for Elko fields</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages, text revised</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, 32, 1730016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732317300166</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Casimir effect for {mass dimension one fermion fields (sometimes called
Elko)} in $3+1$ dimension is obtained using Dirichlet boundary conditions. It
is shown the existence of a repulsive force four times greater than the case of
the scalar field. The precise reason for such differences are highlighted and
interpreted, as well as the right parallel of the Casimir effect due to scalar
and fermionic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02269</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2016-11-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Verlinde</keyname><forenames>Erik P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent Gravity and the Dark Universe</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>5 figures</comments><journal-ref>SciPost Phys. 2, 016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.21468/SciPostPhys.2.3.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent theoretical progress indicates that spacetime and gravity emerge
together from the entanglement structure of an underlying microscopic theory.
These ideas are best understood in Anti-de Sitter space, where they rely on the
area law for entanglement entropy. The extension to de Sitter space requires
taking into account the entropy and temperature associated with the
cosmological horizon. Using insights from string theory, black hole physics and
quantum information theory we argue that the positive dark energy leads to a
thermal volume law contribution to the entropy that overtakes the area law
precisely at the cosmological horizon. Due to the competition between area and
volume law entanglement the microscopic de Sitter states do not thermalise at
sub-Hubble scales: they exhibit memory effects in the form of an entropy
displacement caused by matter. The emergent laws of gravity contain an
additional `dark' gravitational force describing the `elastic' response due to
the entropy displacement. We derive an estimate of the strength of this extra
force in terms of the baryonic mass, Newton's constant and the Hubble
acceleration scale a_0 =cH_0, and provide evidence for the fact that this
additional `dark gravity~force' explains the observed phenomena in galaxies and
clusters currently attributed to dark matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03050</id><created>2016-11-09</created><updated>2017-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tervo</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhuomin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cola</keyname><forenames>Baratunde</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective Near-Field Thermal Emission from Polaritonic Nanoparticle
  Arrays</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Materials 1, 015201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.015201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spectral characteristics of near-field thermal emission from nanoparticle
arrays are explained by comparison to the dispersions for propagating modes.
Using the coupled dipole model, we analytically calculate the spectral emission
from single particles, chains, planes, and 3D arrays of SiO2 and SiC. We show
that the differences in their spectra are due to the existence or absence of
propagating surface phonon polariton modes and that the emission is dominated
by these modes when they are present. This work paves the way for understanding
and control of near-field radiation in nanofluids, nanoparticle beds, and
certain metamaterials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03904</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03904</id><created>2016-11-11</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robertson</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michel</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parentani</keyname><forenames>Renaud</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling and observing nonseparability of phonons created in
  time-dependent 1D atomic Bose condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas gr-qc</categories><comments>26 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 065020 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.065020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spectrum and entanglement of phonons produced by temporal
changes in homogeneous one-dimensional atomic condensates. To characterize the
experimentally accessible changes, we first consider the dynamics of the
condensate when varying the radial trapping frequency, separately studying two
regimes: an adiabatic one and an oscillatory one. Working in momentum space, we
then show that in situ measurements of the density-density correlation function
can be used to assess the nonseparability of the phonon state after such
changes. We also study time-of-flight (TOF) measurements, paying particular
attention to the role played by the adiabaticity of opening the trap on the
nonseparability of the final state of atoms. In both cases, we emphasize that
commuting measurements can suffice to assess nonseparability. Some recent
observations are analyzed, and we make proposals for future experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07317</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07317</id><created>2016-08-27</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mbuebue</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marie Tshitenge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muliwavyo</keyname><forenames>Albert Mbata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mwamba</keyname><forenames>Vincent Lukanda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phuati</keyname><forenames>Edmond Phuku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bantu</keyname><forenames>Albert Kazadi Mukenga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keto</keyname><forenames>Franck Tondozi</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-scale characteristics of Kasai river hydrological regime
  variability for 1940-1999</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Innovation and Applied Studies, 17,
  531-547 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The present study was undertaken with the aim of contributing to the
characterization of the nonstationary variability of the hydrological regime of
the Kasai River using the wavelet analysis for 1940-1999. The rainfalls and
discharge over Kasai Basin have marked fluctuations with a perceptible downward
trend and some shift around 1950, 1960, 1970, 1983 and 1994. The results show
that rainfalls over Kasai basin and the discharge at Ilebo station patterns
exhibit a strong annual oscillation and some intermittent oscillations in 2-8
years (1950-1975, 1983-1995) and 8-16 years (1970-1999) time scales. The
wavelet coherence analysis reveals a weak possible connection between
hydrological variables (rainfalls, discharge) and climate indices relative to
sea surface temperature and atmospheric circulation over Atlantic tropical,
Indian and Pacific Oceans (coherence less than 0.55).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09640</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gwak</keyname><forenames>Bogeun</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Censorship Conjecture in Kerr-Sen Black Hole</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages, published version in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 124050 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.124050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The validity of the cosmic censorship conjecture for the Kerr-Sen black hole,
which is a solution to the low-energy effective field theory for
four-dimensional heterotic string theory, is investigated using charged
particle absorption. When the black hole absorbs the particle, the charge on it
changes owing to the conserved quantities of the particle. Changes in the black
hole are constrained to the equation for the motion of the particle and are
consistent with the laws of thermodynamics. Particle absorption increases the
mass of the Kerr-Sen black hole to more than that of the absorbed charges such
as angular momentum and electric charge; hence, the black hole cannot be
overcharged. In the near-extremal black hole, we observe a violation of the
cosmic censorship conjecture for the angular momentum in the first order of
expansion and the electric charge in the second order. However, considering an
adiabatic process carrying the conserved quantities as those of the black hole,
we prove the stability of the black hole horizon. Thus, we resolve the
violation. This is consistent with the third law of thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04592</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monroy</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez</keyname><forenames>Crist&#xf3;bal</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the dynamical sinking of biogenic particles in oceanic flow</title><categories>physics.ao-ph cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nonlin. Processes Geophys., 24, 293-305 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.5194/npg-24-293-2017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the problem of sinking particles in a realistic oceanic flow, with
major energetic structures in the mesoscale, focussing in the range of particle
sizes and densities appropriate for marine biogenic particles. Our aim is to
unify the theoretical investigations with its applications in the oceanographic
context and considering a mesoscale simulation of the oceanic velocity field.
By using the equation of motion of small particles in a fluid flow, we assess
the influence of physical processes such as the Coriolis force and the inertia
of the particles, and we conclude that they represent negligible corrections to
the most important terms, which are passive motion with the velocity of the
flow, and a constant added vertical velocity due to gravity. Even if within
this approximation three-dimensional clustering of particles can not occur,
two-dimensional cuts or projections of the evolving three-dimensional density
can display inhomogeneities similar to the ones observed in sinking ocean
particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04845</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04845</id><created>2016-12-14</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Shovan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Erich J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective modes of a soliton train in a Fermi superfluid</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.PS</categories><comments>Published version: 4-page article + references + supplement.
  Supplement contains two new sections on (i) protocol to engineer soliton
  train states and (ii) convention for Bogoliubov operators. Results and
  conclusions unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 260402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.260402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize the collective modes of a soliton train in a
quasi-one-dimensional Fermi superfluid, using a mean-field formalism. In
addition to the expected Goldstone and Higgs modes, we find novel long-lived
gapped modes associated with oscillations of the soliton cores. The soliton
train has an instability that depends strongly on the interaction strength and
the spacing of solitons. It can be stabilized by filling each soliton with an
unpaired fermion, thus forming a commensurate Fulde-Ferrell-Larkin-Ovchinnikov
(FFLO) phase. We find that such a state is always dynamically stable, which
paves the way for realizing long-lived FFLO states in experiments via phase
imprinting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.05199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.05199</id><created>2016-12-15</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tobasco</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doering</keyname><forenames>Charles R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal wall-to-wall transport by incompressible flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math.AP</categories><comments>Edited to take into account referee comments. To appear in Phys. Rev.
  Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 264502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.264502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider wall-to-wall transport of a passive tracer by divergence-free
velocity vector fields $\mathbf{u}$. Given an enstrophy budget $\langle |\nabla
\mathbf{u}|^{2} \rangle \le Pe^{2}$ we construct steady two-dimensional flows
that transport at rates $Nu(\mathbf{u}) \gtrsim Pe^{2/3}/(\log Pe)^{4/3}$ in
the large enstrophy limit. Combined with the known upper bound
$Nu(\mathbf{u})\lesssim Pe^{2/3}$ for any such enstrophy-constrained flow, we
conclude that maximally transporting flows satisfy $Nu\sim Pe^{2/3}$ up to
possible logarithmic corrections. Combined with known transport bounds in the
context of Rayleigh-B\'enard convection this establishes that while suitable
flows approaching the &quot;ultimate&quot; heat transport scaling $Nu\sim Ra^{1/2}$
exist, they are not always realizable as buoyancy-driven flows. The result is
obtained by exploiting a connection between the wall-to-wall optimal transport
problem and a closely related class of singularly perturbed variational
problems arising in the study of energy-driven pattern formation in materials
science.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.06552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.06552</id><created>2016-12-20</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>Maciej A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarnowski</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of large time-lagged correlation matrices from Random Matrix
  Theory</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>44 pages, 11 figures; v2 typos corrected, final version</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2017) 063405</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa6504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the spectral properties of large, time-lagged correlation matrices
using the tools of random matrix theory. We compare predictions of the
one-dimensional spectra, based on approaches already proposed in the
literature. Employing the methods of free random variables and diagrammatic
techniques, we solve a general random matrix problem, namely the spectrum of a
matrix $\frac{1}{T}XAX^{\dagger}$, where $X$ is an $N\times T$ Gaussian random
matrix and $A$ is \textit{any} $T\times T$, not necessarily symmetric
(Hermitian) matrix. As a particular application, we present the spectral
features of the large lagged correlation matrices as a function of the depth of
the time-lag. We also analyze the properties of left and right eigenvector
correlations for the time-lagged matrices. We positively verify our results by
the numerical simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.08704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.08704</id><created>2016-12-27</created><updated>2017-04-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiete</keyname><forenames>Gregory A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet states in (LaNiO$_3$)$_2$/(LaAlO$_3$)$_N$ heterostructures grown
  along the (111) direction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235309 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using Floquet-Bloch theory we study the effect of circularly and linearly
polarized light on the electronic structure of (LaNiO$_3$)$_2$/(LaAlO$_3$)$_N$
heterostructure grown along the (111) direction. In equilibrium, a
tight-binding fit to the first principles band structure shows that
nearest-neighbor hopping plays a dominant role while second-neighbor hopping
breaks the particle-hole symmetry and determines the finer band features. The
four bands of the LaNiO$_3$ bilayer exhibit both quadratic band touching points
and Dirac points. By varying the amplitude of the incident light, one can
independently tune the first and second-neighbor hopping for fixed frequency,
which leads to considerable control over the Floquet band structure. We
investigate this control in detail, and study how the quadratic and Dirac band
touchings are influenced by the polarization and intensity of the light. We
derive effective 2-band Hamiltonians (for both quadratic and Dirac band
touching points) that accurately captures these results. We further study an
extended model which explicitly includes oxygen $p$-orbitals and compare the
results to the effective model that contains only the nickel $d$-orbitals. We
conclude with a computation of the frequency dependent optical Hall
conductivity using the full four band model and analyze the various inter-band
contributions of the Floquet modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01234</id><created>2017-01-05</created><updated>2017-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Hiroshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Failure of deterministic and stochastic thermostats to control
  temperature of molecular systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 075004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.075004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the ergodicity and &quot;hot solvent/cold solute&quot; problems in
molecular dynamics simulations. While the kinetic moments and the stimulated
Nos\'e--Hoover methods improve the ergodicity of a harmonic-oscillator system,
both methods exhibit the &quot;hot solvent/cold solute&quot; problem in a binary liquid
system. These results show that the devices to improve the ergodicity do not
resolve the &quot;hot solvent/cold solute&quot; problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02259</id><created>2017-01-09</created><updated>2017-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Jae Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiozaki</keyname><forenames>Toru</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical derivative coupling for multistate CASPT2 theory</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.7b00018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The probability of non-radiative transitions in photochemical dynamics is
determined by the derivative couplings, the couplings between different
electronic states through the nuclear degrees of freedom. Efficient and
accurate evaluation of the derivative couplings is, therefore, of central
importance to realize reliable computer simulations of photochemical reactions.
In this work, the derivative couplings for multistate multireference
second-order perturbation theory (MS-CASPT2) and its 'extended' variant
(XMS-CASPT2) are studied, in which we present an algorithm for their analytical
evaluation. The computational costs for evaluating the derivative couplings are
essentially the same as those for calculating the nuclear energy gradients. The
geometries and energies calculated with XMS-CASPT2 for small molecules at
minimum energy conical intersections (MECIs) are in good agreement with those
computed by multireference configuration interaction. As numerical examples,
MECIs are optimized using XMS-CASPT2 for stilbene and a GFP model chromophore
(the 4-para-hydroxybenzylidene-1,2-dimethyl-imidazolin-5-one anion).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03066</id><created>2017-01-11</created><updated>2017-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berglund</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Model Spaces of Regularity Structures for Space-Fractional SPDEs</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.AP math.CO math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages, 11 figures; submitted version</comments><msc-class>60H15, 35R11, 05C05, 82B20</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Physics, Vol. 168, No. 2, pp. 331-368
  (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-017-1801-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study model spaces, in the sense of Hairer, for stochastic partial
differential equations involving the fractional Laplacian. We prove that the
fractional Laplacian is a singular kernel suitable to apply the theory of
regularity structures. Our main contribution is to study the dependence of the
model space for a regularity structure on the three-parameter problem involving
the spatial dimension, the polynomial order of the nonlinearity, and the
exponent of the fractional Laplacian. The goal is to investigate the growth of
the model space under parameter variation. In particular, we prove several
results in the approaching subcriticality limit leading to universal growth
exponents of the regularity structure. A key role is played by the viewpoint
that model spaces can be identified with families of rooted trees. Our proofs
are based upon a geometrical construction similar to Newton polygons for
classical Taylor series and various combinatorial arguments. We also present
several explicit examples listing all elements with negative homogeneity by
implementing a new symbolic software package to work with regularity
structures. We use this package to illustrate our analytical results and to
obtain new conjectures regarding coarse-grained network measures for model
spaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03464</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03464</id><created>2017-01-12</created><updated>2017-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gullans</keyname><forenames>Michael J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Jacob M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imamoglu</keyname><forenames>Atac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghaemi</keyname><forenames>Pouyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafezi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Order Multipole Radiation from Quantum Hall States in Dirac
  Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>v2: 8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235439 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235439</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the optical response of strongly disordered quantum Hall
states in two-dimensional Dirac materials and find qualitatively different
effects in the radiation properties of the bulk versus the edge. We show that
the far-field radiation from the edge is characterized by large multipole
moments (&gt; 50) due to the efficient transfer of angular momentum from the
electrons into the scattered light. The maximum multipole transition moment is
a direct measure of the coherence length of the edge states. Accessing these
multipole transitions would provide new tools for optical spectroscopy and
control of quantum Hall edge states. On the other hand, the far-field radiation
from the bulk appears as random dipole emission with spectral properties that
vary with the local disorder potential. We determine the conditions under which
this bulk radiation can be used to image the disorder landscape. Such optical
measurements can probe sub-micron length scales over large areas and provide
complementary information to scanning probe techniques. Spatially resolving
this bulk radiation would serve as a novel probe of the percolation transition
near half-filling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04285</id><created>2017-01-16</created><updated>2017-06-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of the $QQ\bar{Q}\bar{Q}$ tetraquark states with QCD sum rules</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C77 (2017) 432</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-4997-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study the $J^{PC}=0^{++}$ and $2^{++}$ $QQ\bar{Q}\bar{Q}$
tetraquark states with the QCD sum rules, and obtain the predictions
$M_{X(cc\bar{c}\bar{c},0^{++})} =5.99\pm0.08\,\rm{GeV}$,
$M_{X(cc\bar{c}\bar{c},2^{++})} =6.09\pm0.08\,\rm{GeV}$,
$M_{X(bb\bar{b}\bar{b},0^{++})} =18.84\pm0.09\,\rm{GeV}$ and
$M_{X(bb\bar{b}\bar{b},2^{++})}=18.85\pm0.09\,\rm{GeV}$, which can be
confronted to the experimental data in the future. Furthermore, we illustrate
that the diquark-antidiquark type tetraquark state can be taken as a special
superposition of a series of meson-meson pairs and embodies the net effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05899</id><created>2017-01-20</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berdanier</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolodrubetz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasseur</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Joel E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet Dynamics of Boundary-Driven Systems at Criticality</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th</categories><comments>5 + 6 pages, 4 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 260602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.260602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A quantum critical system described at low energy by a conformal field theory
(CFT) and subjected to a time-periodic boundary drive displays multiple
dynamical regimes depending on the drive frequency. We compute the behavior of
quantities including the entanglement entropy and Loschmidt echo, confirming
analytic predictions from field theory by exact numerics on the transverse
field Ising model, and demonstrate universality by adding non-integrable
perturbations. The dynamics naturally separate into three regimes: a
slow-driving limit, which has an interpretation as multiple quantum quenches
with amplitude corrections from CFT; a fast-driving limit, in which the system
behaves as though subject to a single quantum quench; and a crossover regime
displaying heating. The universal Floquet dynamics in all regimes can be
understood using a combination of boundary CFT and Kibble-Zurek scaling
arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00555</id><created>2017-02-02</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>K$^{*}(892)^{0}$ and $\phi(1020)$ meson production at high transverse
  momentum in pp and Pb-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_\mathrm{NN}}$ = 2.76 TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 captioned figures, 3 tables, authors from page 21,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/3363</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-EP-2017-010</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 95, 064606 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.064606</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The production of K$^{*}(892)^{0}$ and $\phi(1020)$ mesons in proton-proton
(pp) and lead-lead (Pb-Pb) collisions at $\sqrt{s_\mathrm{NN}} =$ 2.76 TeV has
been analyzed using a high luminosity data sample accumulated in 2011 with the
ALICE detector at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC). Transverse momentum
($p_{\mathrm{T}}$) spectra have been measured for K$^{*}(892)^{0}$ and
$\phi(1020)$ mesons via their hadronic decay channels for $p_{\mathrm{T}}$ up
to 20 GeV/$c$. The measurements in pp collisions have been compared to model
calculations and used to determine the nuclear modification factor and particle
ratios. The K$^{*}(892)^{0}$/K ratio exhibits significant reduction from pp to
central Pb-Pb collisions, consistent with the suppression of the
K$^{*}(892)^{0}$ yield at low $p_{\mathrm{T}}$ due to rescattering of its decay
products in the hadronic phase. In central Pb-Pb collisions the
$p_{\mathrm{T}}$ dependent $\phi(1020)/\pi$ and K$^{*}(892)^{0}$/$\pi$ ratios
show an enhancement over pp collisions for $p_{\mathrm{T}}$ $\sim$3 GeV/$c$,
consistent with previous observations of strong radial flow. At high
$p_{\mathrm{T}}$, particle ratios in Pb-Pb collisions are similar to those
measured in pp collisions. In central Pb-Pb collisions, the production of
K$^{*}(892)^{0}$ and $\phi(1020)$ mesons is suppressed for $p_{\mathrm{T}}&gt; 8$
GeV/$c$. This suppression is similar to that of charged pions, kaons and
protons, indicating that the suppression does not depend on particle mass or
flavor in the light quark sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01087</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kubakaddi</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>Tutul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Tarun Kanti</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon-drag magnetoquantum oscillations in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures. To appear in Journal of Physics: Condens. Matter</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 29, 305301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa749c</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theory of low-temperature phonon-drag magnetothermopower $S_{xx}^g$ is
presented in graphene in a quantizing magnetic field. $S_{xx}^g$ is found to
exhibit quantum oscillations as a function of magnetic field $B$ and electron
concentration $n_e$. Amplitude of the oscillations is found to increase
(decrease) with increasing $B$ ($n_e$). The behavior of $S_{xx}^g$ is also
investigated as a function of temperature. A large value of $S_{xx}^g $($\sim$
few hundreds of $\mu $V/K) is predicted. Numerical values of $S_{xx}^g $ are
compared with the measured magnetothermopower $S_{xx}$ and the diffusion
component $S_{xx}^d$ from the modified Girvin-Jonson theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06127</id><created>2017-02-20</created><updated>2017-06-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>Sam R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stratton</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Rainbow scattering in the gravitational field of a compact object</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures. Added Figure 3 and text. To appear in Physical
  Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 124055 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.124055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the elastic scattering of a planar wave in the curved spacetime of a
compact object such as a neutron star, via a heuristic model: a scalar field
impinging upon a spherically-symmetric uniform density star of radius $R$ and
mass $M$. For $R &lt; r_c$, there is a divergence in the deflection function at
the light-ring radius $r_c = 3GM/c^2$, which leads to spiral scattering
(orbiting) and a backward glory; whereas for $R &gt; r_c$ there instead arises a
stationary point in the deflection function which creates a caustic and rainbow
scattering. As in nuclear rainbow scattering, there is an Airy-type oscillation
on a Rutherford-like cross section, followed by a shadow zone. We show that,
for $R \sim 3.5 GM/c^2$, the rainbow angle lies close to $180^\circ$, and thus
there arises enhanced back-scattering and glory. We explore possible
implications for gravitational wave astronomy, and dark matter models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06565</id><created>2017-02-21</created><updated>2017-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rupasinghe</keyname><forenames>P. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilas</keyname><forenames>N. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoenig</keyname><forenames>Eli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumder</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of hyperfine splittings and isotope shifts in the $8p$
  excited states of $^{205}$Tl and $^{203}$Tl using two-step laser spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1310.7216</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A two-step, two-color laser spectroscopy technique has been used to measure
the hyperfine splittings of the $8p$ excited states in $^{203}$Tl and
$^{205}$Tl, as well as the $7s - 8p$ transition isotope shifts. For the case of
the $8p_{3/2}$ state, our results show a hyperfine anomaly consistent with our
recent measurements of other hyperfine splittings, and in disagreement with
older results for this state. Our measurement of the $8p_{1/2}$ isotope shift
is also in disagreement with earlier work. In this series of experiments, a UV
laser was locked to the first-step transition and directed through a heated
vapor cell, while a second spatially overlapping red laser was scanned across
the two second-step transitions. To facilitate accurate frequency calibration,
radio-frequency modulation of the second-step laser was used to create
sidebands in the Doppler-free absorption spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.08219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.08219</id><created>2017-02-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Alon</keyname><forenames>Ofir E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solvable Model of a Generic Trapped Mixture of Interacting Bosons:
  Reduced Density Matrices and Proof of Bose-Einstein Condensation</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>31 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A 50, 295002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa78ad</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mixture of two kinds of identical bosons, species $1$ and species $2$, held
in a harmonic potential and interacting by harmonic intra-species and
inter-species particle-particle interactions is discussed. To prove
Bose-Einstein condensation of the mixture three steps are needed. First, we
integrate the all-particle density matrix, employing a four-parameter matrix
recurrence relations, down to the lowest-order intra-species and inter-species
reduced density matrices of the mixture. Second, the coupled Gross-Pitaevskii
(mean-field) equations of the mixture are solved analytically. Third, we
analyze the mixture's reduced density matrices in the limit of an infinite
number of particles of both species $1$ and $2$ (when the interaction
parameters, i.e., the products of the number of particles times the
intra-species and inter-species interaction strengths, are held fixed) and
prove that: (i) Both species $1$ and $2$ are 100\% condensed; (ii) The
inter-species reduced density matrix per particle is separable and given by the
product of the intra-species reduced density matrices per particle; and (iii)
The mixture's energy per particle, and reduced density matrices and densities
per particle all coincide with the Gross-Pitaevskii quantities. Finally, when
the infinite-particle limit is taken with respect to, say, species $1$ only
(with interaction parameters held fixed) we prove that: (iv) Only species $1$
is 100\% condensed and its reduced density matrix and density per particle, as
well as the mixture's energy per particle, coincide with the Gross-Pitaevskii
quantities of species $1$ alone; and (v) The inter-species reduced density
matrix per particle is nonetheless separable and given by the product of the
intra-species reduced density matrices per particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.00328</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.00328</id><created>2017-03-01</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baker</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poth&#xe9;rat</keyname><forenames>Alban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoust</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debray</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Rico</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlling the dimensionality of low-Rm MHD turbulence experimentally</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1007/s00348-017-2363-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper introduces an experimental apparatus, which drives turbulence
electrically in a liquid metal pervaded by a high magnetic field. Unlike past
magnetohydrodynamic (MHD) setups involving a shallow confinement, the
experiment presented here drives turbulence whose dimensionality can be set
anywhere between three-dimensional and quasi two-dimensional. In particular, we
show that the dimensionality and componentality of the turbulence thus
generated are in fact completely fixed by the single parameter lz(li)/h, which
quantifies the competition between the solenoidal component of the Lorentz
force and inertia acting on a turbulent structure of the size of the forcing
scale li. This parameter is fully tunable thanks to the three operating
settings at hand: the injection scale, the intensity of the electric forcing
and the magnitude of the magnetic field. Thanks to the very high number of
measuring probes and fast acquisition rate implemented in this experiment, it
is possible to reliably measure the finest features of the inertial range on a
scale-wise basis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03824</id><created>2017-03-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Utesov</keyname><forenames>O. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Syromyatnikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cascades of phase transitions in spiral magnets caused by dipolar forces</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 214420 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.214420</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a mean-field theory describing the influence of long-range dipolar
forces on the temperature transition from the paramagnetic to ordered phases in
frustrated Heisenberg spiral magnets. It is shown that the dipolar interaction
produces a cascade of first- and second- order phase transitions between the
paramagnetic and the spiral states upon temperature decreasing. Depending on
system parameters, the following intermediate phases can arise: an
incommensurate and a commensurate sinusoidally modulated states, spiral phases
in which perpendicular spin components have different amplitudes and are
modulated with the same and with different wave vectors. We distinguish six
possible sequences of phase transitions upon temperature decreasing at least
four of which were observed before experimentally in specific compounds. It is
found that the action of dipolar forces cannot always be modeled even
qualitatively by small one-ion anisotropic spin interactions. We demonstrate
that the dipolar interaction is responsible for successive phase transitions in
the triangular-lattice multiferroic MnI$_2$: almost all available experimental
findings are described quantitatively within the mean-field theory by taking
into account the exchange, the dipolar and small symmetry-allowed anisotropic
spin interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.04629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.04629</id><created>2017-03-14</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leane</keyname><forenames>Rebecca K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>Kenny C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beacom</keyname><forenames>John F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Powerful Solar Signatures of Long-Lived Dark Mediators</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures, updated with recent HAWC sensitivity, matches
  version published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 123016 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.123016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter capture and annihilation in the Sun can produce detectable
high-energy neutrinos, providing a probe of the dark matter-proton scattering
cross section. We consider the case when annihilation proceeds via long-lived
dark mediators, which allows gamma rays to escape the Sun and reduces the
attenuation of neutrinos. For gamma rays, there are exciting new opportunities,
due to detailed measurements of GeV solar gamma rays with Fermi, and
unprecedented sensitivities in the TeV range with HAWC and LHAASO. For
neutrinos, the enhanced flux, particularly at higher energies ($\sim$TeV),
allows a more sensitive dark matter search with IceCube and KM3NeT. We show
that these search channels can be extremely powerful, potentially improving
sensitivity to the dark matter spin-dependent scattering cross section by
several orders of magnitude relative to present searches for high-energy solar
neutrinos, as well as direct detection experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05310</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Klimenko</keyname><forenames>A. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetics of interactions of matter, antimatter and radiation consistent
  with antisymmetric (CPT-invariant) thermodynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>25 pages 6 figures (the published version)</comments><journal-ref>Entropy, 19(5), 202, 1-25 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19050202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work investigates the influence of directional properties of decoherence
on kinetics rate equations. The physical reality is understood as a chain of
unitary and decoherence events. The former are quantum-deterministic, while the
latter introduce uncertainty and increase entropy. For interactions of matter
and antimatter, two approaches are considered: symmetric decoherence, which
corresponds to conventional symmetric (CP-invariant) thermodynamics, and
antisymmetric decoherence, which corresponds to antisymmetric (CPT-invariant)
thermodynamics. Radiation, in its interactions with matter and antimatter, is
shown to be decoherence-neutral. The symmetric and antisymmetric assumptions
result in different interactions of radiation with matter and antimatter. The
theoretical predictions for these differences are testable by comparing
absorption (emission) of light by thermodynamic systems made of matter and
antimatter. Canonical typicality for quantum mixtures is briefly discussed in
the Appendix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.05369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.05369</id><created>2017-03-15</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gilmore</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohnet</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawyer</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britton</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bollinger</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Amplitude sensing below the zero-point fluctuations with a
  two-dimensional trapped-ion mechanical oscillator</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 263602 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.263602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a technique to measure the amplitude of a center-of-mass (COM)
motion of a two-dimensional ion crystal of $\sim$100 ions. By sensing motion at
frequencies far from the COM resonance frequency, we experimentally determine
the technique's measurement imprecision. We resolve amplitudes as small as 50
pm, 40 times smaller than the COM mode zero-point fluctuations. The technique
employs a spin-dependent, optical-dipole force to couple the mechanical
oscillation to the electron spins of the trapped ions, enabling a measurement
of one quadrature of the COM motion through a readout of the spin state. We
demonstrate sensitivity limits set by spin projection noise and spin
decoherence due to off-resonant light scattering. When performed on resonance
with the COM mode frequency, the technique demonstrated here can enable the
detection of extremely weak forces ($&lt; \,$1 yN) and electric fields ($&lt; \,$1
nV/m), providing an opportunity to probe quantum sensing limits and search for
physics beyond the standard model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.06082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.06082</id><created>2017-03-17</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Negash</keyname><forenames>Hluf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhatnagar</keyname><forenames>Shashank</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative decay widths of ground and excited states of vector charmonium
  and bottomonium</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1508.06131</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the radiative decay widths of vector quarkonia for the
process of $J/\psi(nS)\rightarrow\eta_{c}(nS)\gamma$ and
$\Upsilon(nS)\rightarrow\eta_{b}(nS)\gamma$ (for principal quantum numbers
$n=1, 2, 3$) in the framework of Bethe-Salpeter equation under the covariant
instantaneous ansatz using a $4\times 4$ form of BSE. The parameters of the
framework were determined by a fit to the mass spectrum of ground states of
pseudoscalar and vector quarkonia, such as; $\eta_{c}$, $\eta_{b}$, $J/\psi$
and $\Upsilon$. These input parameters so fixed were found to give good
agreements with data on mass spectra of ground and excited states of
pseudoscalar and vector quarkonia, leptonic decay constants of pseudoscalar and
vector quarkonia, two photon decays and two gluon decays of pseudoscalar
quarkonia in our recent paper. With these input parameters so fixed, the
radiative decay widths of ground (1S) and excited (2S, 3S) states of heavy
vector quarkonia ($J/\Psi$ and $\Upsilon$) are calculated and found to be in
reasonable agreement with data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08573</id><created>2017-03-24</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Veale</keyname><forenames>Melanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Chung-Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Jenny E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blakeslee</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McConnell</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Jonelle L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author></authors><title>The MASSIVE Survey - VII. The Relationship of Angular Momentum, Stellar
  Mass and Environment of Early-Type Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1639</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the environmental properties of 370 local early-type galaxies
(ETGs) in the MASSIVE and ATLAS3D surveys, two complementary volume-limited
integral-field spectroscopic (IFS) galaxy surveys spanning absolute $K$-band
magnitude $-21.5 &gt; M_K &gt; -26.6$, or stellar mass $8 \times 10^{9} &lt; M_* &lt; 2
\times 10^{12} M_\odot$. We find these galaxies to reside in a diverse range of
environments measured by four methods: group membership (whether a galaxy is a
brightest group/cluster galaxy, satellite, or isolated), halo mass, large-scale
mass density (measured over a few Mpc), and local mass density (measured within
the $N$th neighbour). The spatially resolved IFS stellar kinematics provide
robust measurements of the spin parameter $\lambda_e$ and enable us to examine
the relationship among $\lambda_e$, $M_*$, and galaxy environment. We find a
strong correlation between $\lambda_e$ and $M_*$, where the average $\lambda_e$
decreases from $\sim 0.4$ to below 0.1 with increasing mass, and the fraction
of slow rotators $f_{\rm slow}$ increases from $\sim 10$% to 90%. We show for
the first time that at fixed $M_*$, there are almost no trends between galaxy
spin and environment; the apparent kinematic morphology-density relation for
ETGs is therefore primarily driven by $M_*$ and is accounted for by the joint
correlations between $M_*$ and spin, and between $M_*$ and environment. A
possible exception is that the increased $f_{\rm slow}$ at high local density
is slightly more than expected based only on these joint correlations. Our
results suggest that the physical processes responsible for building up the
present-day stellar masses of massive galaxies are also very efficient at
reducing their spin, in any environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10870</id><created>2017-03-31</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galliano</keyname><forenames>Valent</forenames></author></authors><title>Superintegrable models on riemannian surfaces of revolution with
  integrals of any integer degree (I)</title><categories>math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>43 pages</comments><msc-class>32C05, 81V99, 37E99, 37K25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a family of superintegrable (SI) sytems living on a riemannian
surface of revolution and which exhibits one linear integral and two integrals
of any integer degree larger or equal to 2 in the momenta. When this degree is
2 one recovers a metric due to Koenigs. The local structure of these systems is
under control of a linear ordinary differential equation of order n which is
homogeneous for even integrals and weakly inhomogeneous for odd integrals. The
form of the integrals is explicitly given in the so-called simple case (see
definition 2). Some globally defined examples are worked out which live either
in H2 or in R2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01521</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01521</id><created>2017-04-05</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aghbolaghi</keyname><forenames>Roghayeh Asadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amooghorban</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahdifar</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering of nonlinear coherent state on sphere by an absorptive and
  dispersive dielectric slab</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we examine the modification of specific nonclassical
properties of the nonlinear coherent state on sphere upon perpendicular
propagation through an absorptive and dispersive dielectric slab at finite
temperature. For this purpose, by describing the dielectric dispersion of the
slab by Lorentz model, the quadrature squeezing and the Mandel parameter are
evaluated for the transmitted state. A generalization of single-mode nonlinear
coherent state to the continuum-mode is considered. The degree of second-order
coherence is instead calculated for a continuum nonlinear coherent state on
sphere, and the quantum noise effects produced by transmission through the slab
on the antibunching feature are examined. We find that near the medium
resonance the detrimental effect of the loss and thermal fluctuations of the
slab are not compensate with increasing the physical space curvature of the
incident state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01931</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eklund</keyname><forenames>Henrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masset</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of eccentricity and inclination of hot protoplanets embedded
  in radiative discs</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>13 pages, 16 figures. The videos showing the temperature excess
  around the planet along the epicycle and inclined motion can be found at
  https://www.fis.unam.mx/~masset/EklundMasset2017/</comments><journal-ref>Mon Not R Astron Soc (2017) 469 (1): 206-217</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx856</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the evolution of the eccentricity and inclination of protoplanetary
embryos and low-mass protoplanets (from a fraction of an Earth mass to a few
Earth masses) embedded in a protoplanetary disc, by means of three dimensional
hydrodynamics calculations with radiative transfer in the diffusion limit. When
the protoplanets radiate in the surrounding disc the energy released by the
accretion of solids, their eccentricity and inclination experience a growth
toward values which depend on the luminosity to mass ratio of the planet, which
are comparable to the disc's aspect ratio and which are reached over timescales
of a few thousand years. This growth is triggered by the appearance of a hot,
under-dense region in the vicinity of the planet. The growth rate of the
eccentricity is typically three times larger than that of the inclination. In
long term calculations, we find that the excitation of eccentricity and the
excitation of inclination are not independent. In the particular case in which
a planet has initially a very small eccentricity and inclination, the
eccentricity largely overruns the inclination. When the eccentricity reaches
its asymptotic value, the growth of inclination is quenched, yielding an
eccentric orbit with a very low inclination. As a side result, we find that the
eccentricity and inclination of non-luminous planets are damped more vigorously
in radiative discs than in isothermal discs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02297</id><created>2017-04-07</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akerib</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alsum</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aquino</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ara&#xfa;jo</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balajthy</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beltrame</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernard</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernstein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biesiadzinski</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boulton</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xe1;s</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byram</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cahn</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carmona-Benitez</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiller</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiller</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Currie</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cutter</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davison</keyname><forenames>T. J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobson</keyname><forenames>J. E. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Druszkiewicz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edwards</keyname><forenames>B. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faham</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fallon</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorucci</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaitskell</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehman</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghag</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>K. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilchriese</keyname><forenames>M. G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hall</keyname><forenames>C. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanhardt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haselschwardt</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hertel</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horn</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>D. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ignarra</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobsen</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamdin</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kazkaz</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khaitan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knoche</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenardo</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesko</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindote</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopes</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manalaysay</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mannino</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzioni</keyname><forenames>M. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKinsey</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mock</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moongweluwan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morad</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murphy</keyname><forenames>A. St. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nehrkorn</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>H. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neves</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Sullivan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliver-Mallory</keyname><forenames>K. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palladino</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pease</keyname><forenames>E. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichhart</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhyne</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shutt</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solmaz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solovov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorensen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stephenson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumner</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szydagis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tennyson</keyname><forenames>B. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terman</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiedt</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>To</keyname><forenames>W. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tripathi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tvrznikova</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uvarov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verbus</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Webb</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitis</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witherell</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolfs</keyname><forenames>F. L. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yazdani</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>First Searches for Axions and Axion-Like Particles with the LUX
  Experiment</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 261301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.261301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The first searches for axions and axion-like particles with the Large
Underground Xenon (LUX) experiment are presented. Under the assumption of an
axio-electric interaction in xenon, the coupling constant between axions and
electrons, gAe is tested, using data collected in 2013 with an exposure
totalling 95 live-days $\times$ 118 kg. A double-sided, profile likelihood
ratio statistic test excludes gAe larger than 3.5 $\times$ 10$^{-12}$ (90%
C.L.) for solar axions. Assuming the DFSZ theoretical description, the upper
limit in coupling corresponds to an upper limit on axion mass of 0.12
eV/c$^{2}$, while for the KSVZ description masses above 36.6 eV/c$^{2}$ are
excluded. For galactic axion-like particles, values of gAe larger than 4.2
$\times$ 10$^{-13}$ are excluded for particle masses in the range 1-16
keV/c$^{2}$. These are the most stringent constraints to date for these
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03747</id><created>2017-04-12</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stauber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parida</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trushin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulybyshev</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyda</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schliemann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interacting Electrons in Graphene: Fermi Velocity Renormalization and
  Optical Response</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages, 11 figures, typos fixed, refs. added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 266801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.266801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a Hartree-Fock theory for electrons on a honeycomb lattice
aiming to solve a long-standing problem of the Fermi velocity renormalization
in graphene. Our model employs no fitting parameters (like an unknown band
cutoff) but relies on a topological invariant (crystal structure function) that
makes the Hartree-Fock sublattice spinor independent of the electron-electron
interaction. Agreement with the experimental data is obtained assuming static
self-screening including local field effects. As an application of the model,
we derive an explicit expression for the optical conductivity and discuss the
renormalization of the Drude weight. The optical conductivity is also obtained
via precise quantum Monte Carlo calculations which compares well to our
mean-field approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.04228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.04228</id><created>2017-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Laurita</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcus</keyname><forenames>G. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trump</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kindervater</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McQueen</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broholm</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armitage</keyname><forenames>N. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low energy magnon dynamics and magneto-optics of the skyrmionic Mott
  insulator Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 235155 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.235155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present a comprehensive study of the low energy optical
magnetic response of the skyrmionic Mott insulator Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$ via high
resolution time-domain THz spectroscopy. In zero field, a new magnetic
excitation not predicted by spin-wave theory with frequency $f$ = 2.03 THz is
observed and shown, with accompanying time-of-flight neutron scattering
experiments, to be a zone folded magnon from the $\mathrm{R}$ to
$\mathrm{\Gamma}$ points of the Brillouin zone. Highly sensitive polarimetry
experiments performed in weak magnetic fields, $\mu_0$H $&lt;$ 200 mT, observe
Faraday and Kerr rotations which are proportional to the sample magnetization,
allowing for optical detection of the skyrmion phase and construction of a
magnetic phase diagram. From these measurements, we extract a critical exponent
of $\beta$ = 0.35 $\pm$ 0.04, in good agreement with the expected value for the
3D Heisenberg universality class of $\beta$ = 0.367. In large magnetic fields,
$\mu_0$H $&gt;$ 5 T, we observe the magnetically active uniform mode of the
ferrimagnetic field polarized phase whose dynamics as a function of field and
temperature are studied. In addition to extracting a $g_\text{eff}$ = 2.08
$\pm$ 0.03, we observe the uniform mode to decay through a non-Gilbert damping
mechanism and to possesses a finite spontaneous decay rate, $\Gamma_0$
$\approx$ 25 GHz, in the zero temperature limit. Our observations are
attributed to Dzyaloshinkii-Moriya interactions, which have been proposed to be
exceptionally strong in Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$ and are expected to impact the low
energy magnetic response of such chiral magnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08874</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08874</id><created>2017-04-28</created><updated>2017-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Golovnev</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Fedor</forenames></author></authors><title>Unusual square roots in the ghost-free theory of massive gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>24 pages; minor changes, final version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2017)130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A crucial building block of the ghost free massive gravity is the square root
function of a matrix. This is a problematic entity from the viewpoint of
existence and uniqueness properties. We accurately describe the freedom of
choosing a square root of a (non-degenerate) matrix. It has discrete and (in
special cases) continuous parts. When continuous freedom is present, the usual
perturbation theory in terms of matrices can be critically ill defined for some
choices of the square root. We consider the new formulation of massive and
bimetric gravity which deals directly with eigenvalues (in disguise of
elementary symmetric polynomials) instead of matrices. It allows for a
meaningful discussion of perturbation theory in such cases, even though certain
non-analytic features arise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08474</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08474</id><created>2017-05-23</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valentim</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Daniel Julio</forenames></author></authors><title>Second order perturbation theory to determine the magnetic state of
  finite size aromatic hydrocarbons molecules</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conjugated system have complex behaviors when increasing the number of
monomers, which is one of the reasons that makes long oligomers hard to be
characterized by numerical methods. An ex- ample of this are fused-azulene, a
molecule that has been reported to displays an increasing magnetic moment with
system size. A similar system composed of symmetric fused-benzene rings is
reported to be always no magnetic. Instead of the empiric parametrized
Pariser-Parr-Pople (PPP) Hamiltonian, a standard model for conjugated
molecules, we consider the Hubbard Hamiltonian to explore a range of low
electronic correlation by means of perturbation theory (PT). We show that a
simple second-order perturbation treatment of electronic correlations by means
of Rayleigh-Schroedinger PT allow to accurately infer about the magnetic state
of these long complex {\pi}-conjugated molecules. For fused-azulene our results
supports the hypothesis that the high-spin ground state on azulene oligomers
comes from the frustrated geometry of these chains. We validate this approach
using Density Matrix Renormalization Group (DMRG) calculations. Our procedure
procedure could be helpful to describe the magnetic ground state of a larger
set of conjugated molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.10617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.10617</id><created>2017-05-27</created><updated>2017-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Karapetyan</keyname><forenames>Gayane</forenames></author></authors><title>The nuclear configurational entropy impact parameter dependence in the
  Color-Glass Condensate</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figs, published version</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 118 (2017) 38001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/38001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The impact parameter (b) dependence on the saturation scale, in the framework
of the Color Glass Condensate (b-CGC) dipole model, is investigated from the
configurational point of view. During the calculations and analysis of the
quantum nuclear states, the critical points of stability in the configurational
entropy setup are computed, matching the experimental parameters that define
the onset of the quantum regime in the b-CGC in the literature with very good
accuracy. This new approach is crucial and important for understanding the
stability of quantum systems in study of deep inelastic scattering processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01585</id><created>2017-06-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Huanying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wenxian</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient generation of many-body singlet states of spin-1 bosons in
  optical superlattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, submitted to Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 063624 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.063624</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an efficient stepwise adiabatic merging (SAM) method to generate
many-body singlet states in antiferromagnetic spin-1 bosons in concatenated
optical superlattices with isolated double-well arrays, by adiabatically
ramping up the double-well bias. With an appropriate choice of bias sweeping
rate and magnetic field, the SAM protocol predicts a fidelity as high as 90%
for a sixteen-body singlet state and even higher fidelities for smaller
even-body singlet states. During their evolution, the spin-1 bosons exhibit
interesting squeezing dynamics, manifested by an odd-even oscillation of the
experimentally observable squeezing parameter. The generated many-body singlet
states may find practical applications in precision measurement of magnetic
field gradient and in quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01743</id><created>2017-06-06</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ou</keyname><forenames>Bao-Quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ping-Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>A theoretical analysis of extending frequency-bin entanglement from
  photon-photon to atom-photon hybrid systems</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by the recent developments in the research of atom-photon quantum
interface and energy-time entanglement between single photon pulses, we propose
to establish the concept of a special energy-time entanglement between a single
photon pulse and internal states of a single atom, which is analogous to the
frequency-bin entanglement between single photon pulses. We show that this type
of entanglement arises naturally in the interaction between frequency-bin
entangled single photon pulse pair and a single atom, via straightforward
atom-photon phase gate operations. We also discuss the properties of this type
of entanglement and show a preliminary example of its potential application in
quantum networking. Moreover, a quantum entanglement witness is constructed to
detect such entanglement from a reasonably large set of separable states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03954</id><created>2017-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Miyasaka</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uekubo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuji</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiota</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukuda</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tajima</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sagayama</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakao</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumai</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three superconducting phases with different categories of pairing in
  hole- and electron-doped LaFeAs$_{1-x}$P$_x$O</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures, accepted in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 95, 214515 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.214515</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phase diagram of LaFeAs$_{1-x}$P$_x$O system has been extensively studied
through hole- and electron-doping as well as As/P-substitution. It has been
revealed that there are three different superconducting phases with different
Fermi surface (FS) topologies and thus with possibly different pairing glues.
One of them is well understood as spin fluctuation-mediated superconductivity
within a FS nesting scenario. Another one with the FSs in a bad nesting
condition must be explained in a different context such as orbital or spin
fluctuation in strongly correlated electronic system. In both phases,
$T$-linear resistivity was commonly observed when the superconducting
transition temperature $T_{\rm c}$ becomes the highest value, indicating that
the strength of bosonic fluctuation determines $T_{\rm c}$. In the last
superconducting phase, the nesting condition of FSs and the related bosonic
fluctuation are moderate. Variety of phase diagram characterizes the multiple
orbital nature of the iron-based superconductors which are just near the
boundary between weak and strong correlation regimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05522</id><created>2017-06-17</created><updated>2017-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eliashvili</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kereselidze</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsitsishvili</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsitsishvili</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Edge States of a Periodic Chain with Four-Band Energy Spectrum</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 15 figures, typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn., Vol.86 (2017) 074712</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.074712</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tight-binding model on a finite chain is studied with four-fold alternated
hopping parameters $t_{1,2,3,4}$. Imposing the open boundary conditions, the
corresponding recursion is solved analytically with special attention paid to
the occurrence of edge states. Corresponding results are strongly corroborated
by numeric calculations. It is shown that in the system there exist four
different edge phases if the number of sites is odd, and eight edges phases if
the chain comprises even number of sites. Phases are labelled by
$\sigma_1\equiv{\rm sgn}(t_1t_3-t_2t_4)$, $\sigma_2\equiv{\rm
sgn}(t_1t_4-t_2t_3)$ and $\sigma_3\equiv{\rm sgn}(t_1t_2-t_3t_4)$. It is shown
that these quantities represent gauge invariant topological indices emerging in
the corresponding infinite chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06724</id><created>2017-06-20</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>Wencheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Peijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Lixin</forenames></author></authors><title>An all-dielectric bowtie waveguide with deep subwavelength mode
  confinement</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To fulfil both size and power requirements for future photonic integrated
circuits, an effective approach is to miniaturize photonic components. Surface
plasmon polariton (SPP) is one of the most promising candidates for
subwavelength mode confinement, however, structures based on SPP are subject to
inevitable high propagation loss. Here, we report an all-dielectric bowtie
(ADB) waveguide consisting of two identical silicon wedges embedded in a silica
cladding with a nanoscale gap. Because of successive slot and antislot effects,
the gap behaves as a 'capacitor-like' energy storage that makes the ADB
waveguide have similar or even smaller mode area than the hybrid plasmonic
waveguides recently reported. What is more important is that the ADB waveguide
supports a quasi-TM eigenmode, which is lossless fundamentally because of no
metal constituent. This makes our ADB waveguide have essential development in
propagation length compared with the plasmonic waveguide. The ADB waveguide is
fully compatible with semiconductor fabrication techniques and could give rise
to truly nanoscale semiconductor-based photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08966</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08966</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Voros</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>On a Morphology of Contact Scenario Space</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 figures. Appears as part of a special issue of
  Technological Forecasting &amp; Social Change, on 'General Morphological
  Analysis: Modelling, Forecasting and Innovation', editors Tom Ritchey and
  Tomasz Arciszewski</comments><doi>10.1016/j.techfore.2017.05.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to explore the possibility space of scenarios of
'contact'--the discovery of extra-terrestrial life, whether intelligent or
not--using a morphological approach utilising seven principal parameters,
chosen both for their descriptiveness of the scope of possibilities, as well as
for their relevance in examining potential societal impacts arising from
different scenarios, including, for example, the proximity of the discovery.
Several classes of contact scenario are examined, and existing approaches to
the search for extra-terrestrial life and intelligence are situated within the
range of possible search strategies and targets illuminated by this particular
choice of parameters, as are some examples of contact scenarios from popular
culture. The resulting possibility space can also suggest new search strategies
and potential targets, one of which is highlighted--that of 'galaxy-scale
macro-engineering'. It is hypothesised that an example of this might already be
known to us, namely the intriguing galaxy 'Hoag's Object' (PGC54559), and some
specific empirical observations are suggested in order to test this hypothesis.
Some possible extensions to the parameters used, as well as some preliminary
observations about modelling the range and extent of human societal responses
to contact, are also made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09687</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09687</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shubhchintak</keyname></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural effects of $^{34}$Na in the $^{33}$Na(n,$\gamma)^{34}$Na
  radiative capture reaction</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review C, 95, 065806 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.95.065806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The path towards the production of \textit{r}-process seed nuclei follows a
course where the neutron-rich light and medium mass nuclei play a crucial role.
The neutron capture rates for these exotic nuclei could dominate over their
$\alpha$-capture rates, thereby enhancing their abundances at or near the drip
line. We calculate the radiative neutron capture cross-section for the
$^{33}$Na(n,$\gamma)^{34}$Na reaction via the Coulomb dissociation of $^{34}$Na
as it undergoes elastic breakup on $^{208}$Pb when directed at a beam energy of
100 MeV/u using the entirely quantum mechanical theory of finite range
distorted wave Born approximation upgraded to incorporate deformation effects.
The non-resonant one neutron radiative capture cross-section for
$^{33}$Na(n,$\gamma)^{34}$Na is calculated and is found to increase with
increasing deformation of $^{34}$Na. An analytic scrutiny of the capture
cross-section with neutron separation energy as a parameter is also done at
different energy ranges. The calculated reaction rate is compared with the rate
of the $^{33}$Na($\alpha$,n)$^{36}$Al reaction (deduced from the
Hauser-Feshbach theory), and is found to be significantly higher below a
temperature of $T_9 = 2$. Further, at the equilibrium temperature of $T_9 =
0.62$, the rate for the neutron capture had a small but non-negligible
dependence on the structural parameters of $^{34}$Na. In addition, this neutron
capture rate exceeded that of the $\alpha$-capture reaction by orders of
magnitude, indicating that the $\alpha$-process should not break the
(n,$\gamma$) \textit{r-}process path at the $^{33}$Na isotope, thus,
effectively pushing the abundance of sodium isotopes towards the neutron drip
line.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09890</id><created>2017-06-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Dyakov</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gippius</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhigunov</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shalygina</keyname><forenames>O. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vabishchevich</keyname><forenames>P. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shcherbakov</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedyanin</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinins</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Presnov</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashkarov</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tikhodeev</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmon-polariton induced modification of silicon nanocrystals
  photoluminescence in presence of gold nanostripes</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the results of theoretical and experimental studies of
photoluminescence of silicon nanocrystals in the proximity of plasmonic modes
of different types. In our samples, the type of plasmonic mode is determined by
the filling ratio of a one-dimensional gold grating which covers the thin film
with silicon nanocrystals on a quartz substrate. We analyze the extinction and
photoluminesce spectra of silicon nanocrystals and show that the emitted light
is coupled to the corresponding plasmonic mode. We also demonstrate the
modification of the extinction and photoluminesce spectra under the transition
from surface plasmon-polaritons to waveguide plasmon-polaritons with the
decrease of the gold filling ratio from 1 to 0.35. Finally, we analyze the
contribution of individual silicon nanocrystals to the overall
photoluminescence intensity. We conclude that silicon nanocrystals ensemble can
be broken down into optically bright and optically dark nanocrystals. The
experimental extinction and photoluminescence spectra are in good agreement
with theoretical calculations performed by the Fourier modal method in the
scattering matrix form.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09899</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>The EAGLE team</keyname></author></authors><title>The EAGLE simulations of galaxy formation: Public release of particle
  data</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 2 figures. The particle data and halo catalogues for the
  EAGLE simulations are publicly available at
  http://icc.dur.ac.uk/Eagle/database.php. Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This manual accompanies the release of the particle data for 24 simulations
of the EAGLE suite of cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of galaxy
formation by the virgo consortium. It describes how to download these snapshots
and how to extract datasets from them, emphasising the meaning of variables,
and their units. We provide examples for extracting the particle data in
python. This data release complements our earlier release of numerous
integrated properties of the galaxies in EAGLE through an SQL relational
database. This database has been updated to include the additional simulations
that are part of the present data release. Scientists wanting to use EAGLE may
find it useful to first investigate whether their analysis can be performed
using the database, before accessing the particle data. The particles in the
snapshot files are indexed by a peano-hilbert key. This allows for an eased
extraction of simply connected spatial volumes, without needing to read the
entire snapshot. This makes it possible to analyse many aspects of galaxies
using modest computing resources, even when using EAGLE simulations with large
numbers of particles. A reading routine is provided to simplify this process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09900</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Kamenetzky</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rangwala</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glenn</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Warm and Cold Molecular Gas Conditions Modeled in 87 Galaxies Observed
  by the Herschel SPIRE Fourier Transform Spectrometer</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, additional figures available online. Accepted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1595</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have conducted two-component, non-LTE modeling of the CO lines from J =
1-0 through J = 13-12 in 87 galaxies observed by the Herschel SPIRE Fourier
Transform Spectrometer (FTS). We find the average pressure of the cold
molecular gas, traced especially by CO J = 1-0, is $\sim 10^{5.0 \pm 0.5}$ K
cm$^{-3}$. The mid- to high-J lines of CO trace higher-pressure gas at $10^{6.5
\pm 0.6}$ K cm$^{-3}$; this pressure is slightly correlated with LFIR. Two
components are often necessary to accurately fit the Spectral Line Energy
Distributions (SLEDs); a one-component fit often underestimates the flux of CO
J = 1-0 and the mass. If low-J lines are not included, mass is underestimated
by an order of magnitude. Even when modeling the low-J lines alone or using an
$\alpha_{CO}$ conversion factor, the mass should be considered to be uncertain
to a factor of at least 0.4 dex, and the vast majority of the CO luminosity
will be missed (median, 65%). We find a very large spread in our derived values
of $\alpha_{CO}$, though they do not have a discernible trend with LFIR; the
best fit is a constant 0.7 M$_{\odot}$/ (K kms$^{-1}$ pc$^2$), with a standard
deviation of 0.36 dex, and a range of 0.3-1.6 M$_{\odot}$/ (K kms$^{-1}$
pc$^2$). We find average molecular gas depletion times ($\tau_{dep}$) of $10^8$
yr that decrease with increasing SFR. Finally, we note that the J = 11-10/J =
1-0 line flux ratio is diagnostic of the warm component pressure, and discuss
the implications of this comprehensive study of SPIRE FTS extragalactic spectra
for future study post-Herschel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09919</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09919</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Cox</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stamp</keyname><forenames>Philip C. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Vortex Dynamics: Results for a 2-d Superfluid</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We model vortex dynamics in a 2-dimensional Bose superfluid using the
Thompson-Stamp (TS) equations of motion, which describes both the classical
Hall-Vinen-Iordanskii (HVI) dynamical regime and the fully developed quantum
regime, and the crossover between them. The TS equations can be written in the
form of a quantum Langevin equation. Analytic solutions are given for all of
these regimes for a single vortex in a 2-dimensional system. In the classical
regime we include the vortex inertial and Langevin noise terms, which are
dropped in the usual HVI analysis. In the quantum and crossover regimes the
effect of memory terms is important, and leads to clear differences from the
classical predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09938</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09938</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Hassan</keyname><forenames>Absar U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhen</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soljacic</keyname><forenames>Marin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khajavikhan</keyname><forenames>Mercedeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christodoulides</keyname><forenames>Demetrios N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamically encircling exceptional points: Exact evolution and
  polarization state conversion</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.118.093002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a two-level non-Hermitian Hamiltonian with constant off-diagonal
exchange elements can be analyzed exactly when the underlying exceptional point
is perfectly encircled in the complex plane. The state evolution of this system
is explicitly obtained in terms of an ensuing transfer matrix, even for large
encirclements, regardless of adiabatic conditions. Our results clearly explain
the direction-dependent nature of this process and why in the adiabatic limit
its outcome is dominated by a specific eigenstate irrespective of initial
conditions. Moreover, numerical simulations suggest that this mechanism can
still persist in the presence of nonlinear effects. We further show that this
robust process can be harnessed to realize an optical omni-polarizer: a
configuration that generates a desired polarization output regardless of the
input polarization state, while from the opposite direction it always produces
the counterpart eigenstate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09957</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Apostolovska</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donchev</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bebekovska</keyname><forenames>E. Vchkova</forenames></author></authors><title>Rotation period determination for asteroid 9021 Fagus</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in BlgAJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lightcurve analysis of the asteroid 9021 Fagus observed at the Bulgarian
National Astronomical Observatory Rozhen during two apparitions in 2013 and
2017 are presented. This asteroid was observed in 2013 accidentally in the
field of view in which our long-term target asteroid 901 Brunsia was
positioned. A search of the Asteroid Lightcurve Database (Warner et al. 2009)
did not find any previously reported results for the rotation period of 9021
Fagus. Unfortunately two nights observations in 2013 showed that the rotation
period could be only approximately assumed. The observations during two
neighbouring nights in 2017 March 20 and 21 revealed the period of $5.065 \pm
0.002$ h with amplitude of $0.73\pm0.02$ mag. Obtained lightcurves in
combination with other observational techniques, as well as with data gathered
from future space mission will contribute to the enlargement of the database
for rotational characteristics of the asteroids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09958</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Rahman</keyname><forenames>Abdullah F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aslan</keyname><forenames>Aslan</forenames></author></authors><title>The first global-scale 30 m resolution mangrove canopy height map using
  Shuttle Radar Topography Mission data</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  No high-resolution canopy height map exists for global mangroves. Here we
present the first global mangrove height map at a consistent 30 m pixel
resolution derived from digital elevation model data collected through shuttle
radar topography mission. Additionally, we refined the current global mangrove
area maps by discarding the non-mangrove areas that are included in current
mangrove maps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09975</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Roundy</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gire</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minot</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Zee</keyname><forenames>Emily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manogue</keyname><forenames>Corinne A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Paradigms in Physics 2.0</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 2016, the Department of Physics at Oregon State University began a process
to revise our Paradigms in Physics curriculum for physics majors. We began with
a colloquium to inform the department of our plans and request their
assistance, followed by a survey of students and faculty as well as individual
interviews with the faculty teaching each course. As we developed a plan to
address student- and faculty-identified challenges in the curriculum, we met
with each faculty member individually to explain and refine our proposal, which
was unanimously approved by the faculty. Major changes include major changes to
several courses (math methods, computational physics, modern physics,
electronics, and classical mechanics), including the introduction of two
sophomore-year courses designed specifically to help prepare students for their
upper-division courses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09979</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Edwards</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerber</keyname><forenames>Urs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trejo</keyname><forenames>Maria Anabel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>The Yukawa potential: ground state energy and critical screening</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ground state energy and the critical screening parameter of the
Yukawa potential in non-relativistic quantum mechanics. After a short review of
the existing literature on these quantities, we apply fifth-order perturbation
theory to the calculation of the ground state energy, using the exact solutions
of the Coulomb potential together with a cutoff on the principal number
summations. We also perform a variational calculation of the ground state
energy using a Coulomb-like radial wave function and the exact solution of the
corresponding minimization condition. For not too large values of the screening
parameter, close agreement is found between the perturbative and variational
results. For the critical screening parameter, we devise a novel method that
permits us to determine it to ten digits. This is the most precise calculation
of this quantity to date, and allows us to resolve some discrepancies between
previous results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09984</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Yong</keyname><forenames>Derrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Ding</forenames></author></authors><title>Lasing with cell-endogenous fluorophores: parameters and conditions</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The notion of lasing with biologics has recently been realized and has since
rapidly developed with the collective objective of creating lasers $\textit{in
vivo}$. One limitation of achieving this goal is the requirement of exogenous
laser dyes and fluorescent materials. To circumvent this, we investigate the
use of cell-endogenous fluorophores - sources of cell autofluorescence - as
laser gain material. In this work, we study the lasing potential and efficiency
of flavins and reduced nicotinamide adenine dinucleotide (phosphate) (NAD(P)H)
using a dye lasing model based on coupled rate equations. Analytical solutions
for one- and two-photon pumped system were used in multi-parameter studies. We
found that at physiological conditions, lasing can be supported by NAD(P)H with
cavity quality factors of $10^5$. With the further consideration of damage
thresholds, we recommend the use of flavins as they entail lower threshold
requirements. We then identify potential parameters for engineering to make the
lasing of flavins feasible even at their low physiological intracellular
concentrations. We also note the higher threshold requirements and lower
efficiencies of two-photon pumping, but recognize its potential for realizing
lasing $\textit{in vivo}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09989</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Khalil</keyname><forenames>Abdullah</forenames></author></authors><title>NLO Rutherford Scattering and the Kinoshita-Lee-Nauenberg Theorem</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>MSc. thesis. Advisor: W. A. Horowitz (University of Cape Town)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate to next-to-leading order accuracy the high-energy elastic
scattering cross section for an electron off of a classical point source. We
use the $\overline{\mathrm{MS}}$ renormalization scheme to tame the ultraviolet
divergences while the infrared singularities are dealt with using the well
known Kinoshita-Lee-Nauenberg theorem. We show for the first time how to
correctly apply the Kinoshita-Lee-Nauenberg theorem diagrammatically in a
next-to-leading order scattering process. We improve on previous works by
including all initial and final state soft radiative processes, including
absorption and an infinite sum of partially disconnected amplitudes. Crucially,
we exploit the Monotone Convergence Theorem to prove that our delicate
rearrangement of this formally divergent series is uniquely correct. This
rearrangement yields a factorization of the infinite contribution from the
initial state soft photons that then cancels in the physically observable cross
section. Since we use the $\overline{\mathrm{MS}}$ renormalization scheme, our
result is valid up to arbitrarily large momentum transfers between the source
and the scattered electron as long as $\alpha \log(1/\delta)\ll 1$ and $\alpha
\log(1/\delta)\log(\Delta/E)\ll 1$, where $\Delta$ and $\delta$ are the
experimental energy and angular resolutions, respectively, and $E$ is the
energy of the scattered electron. Our work aims at computing the NLO
corrections to the energy loss of a high energetic parton propagating in a
quark-gluon plasma.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09994</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Rui-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Guo-Qun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>Changliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Ryosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Pei-Xiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Monotonic quantum-to-classical transition enabled by
  positively-correlated biphotons</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 062341 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.062341</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multiparticle interference is a fundamental phenomenon in the study of
quantum mechanics.It was discovered in a recent experiment [Ra, Y.-S. et al,
Proc. Natl Acad. Sci. USA \textbf{110}, 1227(2013)] that spectrally
uncorrelated biphotons exhibited a nonmonotonic quantum-to-classical transition
in a four-photon Hong-Ou-Mandel (HOM) interference. In this work, we consider
the same scheme with spectrally correlated photons.By theoretical calculation
and numerical simulation, we found the transition not only can be nonmonotonic
with negative-correlated or uncorrelated biphotons, but also can be monotonic
with positive-correlated biphotons. The fundamental reason for this difference
is that the HOM-type multi-photon interference is a differential-frequency
interference. Our study may shed new light on understanding the role of
frequency entanglement in multi-photon behavior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10014</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Levie</keyname><forenames>Ilay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slepyan</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author></authors><title>The new concept of nano-device spectroscopy based on Rabi-Bloch
  oscillations for THz-frequency range</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 20 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We considered one-dimensional quantum chains of two-level Fermi particles
coupled via the tunneling driven both by ac and dc fields in the regimes of
strong and ultrastrong coupling. The frequency of ac field is matched with the
frequency of the quantum transition. Based on the fundamental principles of
electrodynamics and quantum theory, we developed a general model of quantum
dynamics for such interactions. We showed that the joint action of ac and dc
fields leads to the strong mutual influence of Rabi- and Bloch oscillations one
to another. We focused on the regime of ultrastrong coupling, for which Bloch-
and Rabi-frequencies are a significant values of the frequency of interband
transition. The Hamiltonian was solved numerically with account of
anti-resonant terms. It manifests by the appearance of great number of narrow
high-amplitude resonant lines in the spectra of tunneling current and dipole
moment. We proposed the new concept of THz spectroscopy promising for different
applications in future nanoelectronics and nano-photonics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10022</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Iris B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bigazzi</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharifi-Mood</keyname><forenames>Nima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stebe</keyname><forenames>Kathleen J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Curvature capillary repulsion</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Directed assembly of colloids is an exciting field in materials science to
form structures with new symmetries and responses. Fluid interfaces have been
widely exploited to make densely packed ordered structures. We have been
studying how interface curvature can be used in new ways to guide structure
formation. On a fluid interface, the area of the deformation field around
adsorbed microparticles depends on interface curvature; particles move to
minimize the excess area of the distortions that they make in the interface.
For particles that are sufficiently small, this area decreases as particles
move along principle axes to sites of high deviatoric curvature. We have
studied this migration for microparticles on a curved host interface with zero
mean curvature created by pinning an oil-water interface around a micropost.
Here, on a similar interface, we demonstrate capillary curvature repulsion,
that is, we identify conditions in which microparticles migrate away from high
curvature sites. Using theory and experiment, we discuss the origin of these
interactions and their relationship to the particle's undulated contact line.
We discuss the implications of this new type of interaction in various contexts
from materials science to microrobotics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10024</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamblyn</keyname><forenames>Isaac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quek</keyname><forenames>Su Ying</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Level Alignment at Hybridized Organic-metal Interfaces: the Role
  of Many-electron Effects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>main text - first 22 pages</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcc.7b00715</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hybridized molecule/metal interfaces are ubiquitous in molecular and organic
devices. The energy level alignment (ELA) of frontier molecular levels relative
to the metal Fermi level (EF) is critical to the conductance and functionality
of these devices. However, a clear understanding of the ELA that includes
many-electron self-energy effects is lacking. Here, we investigate the
many-electron effects on the ELA using state-of-the-art, benchmark GW
calculations on prototypical chemisorbed molecules on Au(111), in eleven
different geometries. The GW ELA is in good agreement with photoemission for
monolayers of benzene-diamine on Au(111). We find that in addition to static
image charge screening, the frontier levels in most of these geometries are
renormalized by additional screening from substrate-mediated intermolecular
Coulomb interactions. For weakly chemisorbed systems, such as amines and
pyridines on Au, this additional level renormalization (~1.5 eV) comes solely
from static screened exchange energy, allowing us to suggest computationally
more tractable schemes to predict the ELA at such interfaces. However, for more
strongly chemisorbed thiolate layers, dynamical effects are present. Our ab
initio results constitute an important step towards the understanding and
manipulation of functional molecular/organic systems for both fundamental
studies and applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10026</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10026</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Suchismita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanta</keyname><forenames>Rukmani</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the rare decays $B_{s,d}^* \to \mu^+ \mu^-$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 Pages, Contribution to the proceedings of XXII DAE-BRNS High Energy
  Physics Symposium, University of Delhi, India, Dec. 12-16, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study rare leptonic decays of vector $B$ mesons in the scalar leptoquark
and family non-universal $Z^\prime$ models. We constrain these new couplings by
using the measured branching fractions of $B_{s,d} \to \mu^+ \mu^-$ processes
and the existing $B_{s,d}^0-\bar B_{s,d}^0$ mixing data. We estimate the
branching fractions of $B_{s,d}^* \to \mu^+ \mu^-$ in both the models, which
are found to be reasonably enhanced from their corresponding standard model
values and within the reach of Run 2-3 of LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10035</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>van Eggermond</keyname><forenames>Michael A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Haohui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erath</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cebrian</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating the potential of social network data for transport demand
  models</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Location-based social network data offers the promise of collecting the data
from a large base of users over a longer span of time at negligible cost. While
several studies have applied social network data to activity and mobility
analysis, a comparison with travel diaries and general statistics has been
lacking. In this paper, we analysed geo-referenced Twitter activities from a
large number of users in Singapore and neighbouring countries. By combining
this data, population statistics and travel diaries and applying clustering
techniques, we addressed detection of activity locations, as well as spatial
separation and transitions between these locations. Kernel density estimation
performs best to detect activity locations due to the scattered nature of the
twitter data; more activity locations are detected per user than reported in
the travel survey. The descriptive analysis shows that determining home
locations is more difficult than detecting work locations for most planning
zones. Spatial separations between detected activity locations from Twitter
data - as reported in a travel survey and captured by public transport smart
card data - are mostly similarly distributed, but also show relevant
differences for very short and very long distances. This also holds for the
transitions between zones. Whether the differences between Twitter data and
other data sources stem from differences in the population sub-sample,
clustering methodology, or whether social networks are being used significantly
more at specific locations must be determined by further research. Despite
these shortcomings, location-based social network data offers a promising data
source for insights into activity locations and mobility patterns, especially
for regions where travel survey data is not readily available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10038</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Rudra</keyname><forenames>Moumin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maity</keyname><forenames>Ritwik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural and dielectric characterization of Sm2MgMnO6</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The polycrystalline Sm2MgMnO6 (SMMO) was synthesized at 1173K by means of
sol-gel technique. Rietveld refine-ment of X-ray diffraction (XRD) pattern
confirmed the formation of a single phase monoclinic structure with space group
P21/n. The band gap achieved from UV-vis spectra shows the semiconducting
nature of the material. To observe the effect of grains and grain-boundaries in
the conduction process and dielectric relaxation measurements are carried out
on SMMO sample at different frequencies between 313 K and 673 K. An electrical
equivalent circuit consisting of the resistance and constant phase element is
used to clarify the impedance data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10056</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rster</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab-initio Study of the Trimethylaluminum Atomic Layer Deposition Process
  on Carbon Nanotubes - An Alternative Initial Step</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables, supplemental: 2 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology A 35, 01B113 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1116/1.4968196</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electronic applications of carbon nanotubes (CNTs) require the deposition of
dielectric films on the tubes while conserving their excellent electronic
properties. In our density functional theory study we use the trimethylaluminum
(TMA) atomic layer deposition (ALD) as a model process for a
CNT-functionalization. Since this functionalization relies on the presence of
OH-groups, the CNTs are exposed to a water or oxygen pre-treatment. We show
that only CNTs with a single-vacancy defect are able to react with H$_{2}$O or
O$_{2}$. Further, the defect is preferably saturated by oxygen. This leaves the
CNT without the necessary hydroxyl groups for the first TMA addition.
Therefore, we propose an alternative initial step after which a classical TMA
ALD process can be performed on the CNT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10057</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Seo-Won</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sukegawa</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Nana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>Se-Hyeok</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMichael</keyname><forenames>Robert D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Kyung-Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-wave propagation in cubic anisotropic materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>NPG Asia Materials 9, e392 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/am.2017.87</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The information carrier of modern technologies is the electron charge whose
transport inevitably generates Joule heating. Spin-waves, the collective
precessional motion of electron spins, do not involve moving charges and thus
avoid Joule heating. In this respect, magnonic devices in which the information
is carried by spin-waves attract interest for low-power computing. However
implementation of magnonic devices for practical use suffers from low spin-wave
signal and on/off ratio. Here we demonstrate that cubic anisotropic materials
can enhance spin-wave signals by improving spin-wave amplitude as well as group
velocity and attenuation length. Furthermore, cubic anisotropic material shows
an enhanced on/off ratio through a laterally localized edge mode, which closely
mimics the gate-controlled conducting channel in traditional field-effect
transistors. These attractive features of cubic anisotropic materials will
invigorate magnonics research towards wave-based functional devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10064</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rster</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gemming</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical investigation of in situ k-restore processes for damaged
  ultra-low-k dielectrics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.app-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Microel. Eng. 156, 121 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.mee.2015.12.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultra-low-k (ULK) materials are essential for today's production of
integrated circuits (ICs). However, during the manufacturing process the ULK's
low dielectric constant (k-value) increases due to the replacement of
hydrophobic species with hydrophilic groups. We investigate the use of plasma
enhanced fragmented silylation precursors to repair this damage. The
fragmentation of the silylation precursors octamethylcyclotetrasiloxane (OMCTS)
and bis(dimethylamino)-dimethylsilane (DMADMS) and their possible repair
reactions are studied using density functional theory (DFT) and molecular
dynamics (MD) simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10065</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>F&#xf6;rster</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gemming</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical investigation of an in situ k-restore process for damaged
  ultra-low-k materials based on plasma enhanced fragmentation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology B 33, 052203 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1116/1.4927564</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present theoretical investigations of a k-restore process for damaged
pourous ultra-low-k (ULK) materials. The process is based on plasma enhanced
fragmented silylation precursors to replace k-value damaging, polar Si-OH and
Si-H bonds by k-value lowering Si-CH$_{3}$ bonds. We employ density functional
theory (DFT) to determine the favored fragments of silylation precursors and
show the successful repair of damaged bonds on our model system. This model
system consists of a small set of ULK-fragments which represent various damaged
states of ULK materials. Our approach provides a fast scanning method for a
wide variety of possible repair reactions. Further, we show that oxygen
containing fragments are required to repair Si-H bonds and fragments with
dangling Si-bonds are most effective to repair polar Si-OH bonds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10072</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10072</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Napoletano</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krauss</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames></author></authors><title>Bottom-quark mass effects in associated production with $Z$ and $H$
  bosons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>Proceedings of XXV International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic
  Scattering and Related Subjects, 3-7 April 2017, University of Birmingham,
  UK. 10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, predictions obtained in the four and in the five flavour
schemes are compared for two important processes involving heavy flavours at
the LHC: the production of a $Z$ or a Higgs boson in association with $b$
quarks. In particular we obtain predictions with \Sherpa's \MCatNLO
implementation for the four--flavour scheme, treating the $b$'s as massive, and
with multijet merging at leading and next-to leading order for the
five--flavour scheme. While differences between the two schemes, at the
inclusive level, are well understood from resummation of possibly large logs
into the $b$-PDFs, differences in shape present a major problem for
experimental measurements. We make use of data for $Z+b(\bar{b})$ production at
the $7$ TeV LHC to exhibit strengths and weaknesses of the different approaches
and we use these results to validate predictions for $b$-associated Higgs-boson
production at the 13 TeV Run II.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10075</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Manneville</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames><affiliation>LadHyX, Ecole Polytechnique, Palaiseau, France</affiliation></author></authors><title>Laminar-Turbulent Patterning in Transitional Flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.PS</categories><comments>29 pages, 5 illustrations, written for special issue on &quot;Complex
  Systems, Non-Equilibrium Dynamics and Self-Organisation&quot; of journal Entropy
  edited by Dr. G. Pruessner</comments><journal-ref>Entropy, 19, 316 (open access) (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e19070316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wall-bounded flows experience a transition to turbulence characterized by the
coexistence of laminar and turbulent domains in some range of Reynolds number
R, the natural control parameter. This transitional regime takes place between
an upper threshold Rt above which turbulence is uniform (featureless) and a
lower threshold Rg below which any form of turbulence decays, possibly at the
end of overlong chaotic transients. The most emblematic cases of flow along
flat plates transiting to/from turbulence according to this scenario are
reviewed. The coexistence is generally in the form of bands, alternatively
laminar and turbulent, and oriented obliquely with respect to the general flow
direction. The final decay of the bands at Rg points to the relevance of
directed percolation and criticality in the sense of statistical-physics phase
transitions. The nature of the transition at Rt where bands form is still
somewhat mysterious and does not easily fit the scheme holding for
pattern-forming instabilities at increasing control parameter on a laminar
background. In contrast, the bands arise at Rt out of a uniform turbulent
background at a decreasing control parameter. Ingredients of a possible theory
of laminar-turbulent patterning are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10083</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Pontuale</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gnoli</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reyes</keyname><forenames>Francisco Vega</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puglisi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative lateral walls are sufficient to trigger convection in
  vibrated granular gases</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, conference Powders and Grains 2017</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 140, 04002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201714004002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Buoyancy-driven (thermal) convection in dilute granular media, fluidized by a
vibrating base, is known to appear without the need of lateral boundaries in a
restricted region of parameters (inelasticity, gravity, intensity of energy
injection). We have recently discovered a second buoyancy-driven convection
effect which occurs at any value of the parameters, provided that the impact of
particles with the lateral walls is inelastic (Pontuale et al., Phys. Rev.
Lett. 117, 098006 (2016)). It is understood that this novel convection effect
is strictly correlated to the existence of perpendicular energy fluxes: a
vertical one, induced by both bulk and wall inelasticity, and a horizontal one,
induced only by dissipation at the walls. Here we first review those previous
results, and then present new experimental and numerical data concerning the
variations of box geometry, intensity of energy injection, number of particles
and width of the box.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10108</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Petrelli</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perugini</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Solving petrological problems through machine learning: the study case
  of tectonic discrimination using geochemical and isotopic data</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Contributions to Mineralogy and Petrology - Volume 171, Issue 10,
  1 October 2016, Article number 81</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00410-016-1292-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Machine learning methods are evaluated to study the intriguing and debated
topic of discrimination among different tectonic environments using geochemical
and isotopic data. Volcanic rocks characterized by a whole geochemical
signature of major elements (SiO2, TiO2, Al2O3, Fe2O3T, CaO, MgO, Na2O, K2O),
selected trace elements (Sr, Ba, Rb, Zr, Nb, La, Ce, Nd, Hf, Sm, Gd, Y, Yb, Lu,
Ta, Th) and isotopes (206Pb/204Pb, 207Pb/204Pb, 208Pb/204Pb, 87Sr/86Sr and
143Nd/144Nd) have been extracted from open-access and comprehensive
petrological databases (i.e. PetDB and GEOROC). The obtained dataset has been
analyzed using support vector machines, a set of supervised machine learning
methods, which are considered particularly powerful in classification problems.
Results from the application of the machine learning methods show that the
combined use of major, trace elements and isotopes allow associating the
geochemical composition of rocks to the relative tectonic setting with high
classification scores (93%, on average). The lowest scores are recorded from
volcanic rocks deriving from back-arc basins (65%). All the other tectonic
settings display higher classification scores, with oceanic islands reaching
values up to 99%. Results of this study could have a significant impact in
other petrological studies potentially opening new perspectives for
petrologists and geochemists. Other examples of applications include the
development of more robust geo-thermometers and geo-barometers and the
recognition of volcanic sources for tephra layers in tephro-chronological
studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10109</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10109</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Tom</keyname><forenames>Anvy Moly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajesh</keyname><forenames>Ravindran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vemparala</keyname><forenames>Satyavani</forenames></author></authors><title>Aggregation of flexible polyelectrolytes: Phase diagram and dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>13 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Similarly-charged polymers in solution, known as polyelectrolytes, are known
to form aggregated structures in the presence of oppositely charged
counterions. Understanding the dependence of the equilibrium phases and the
dynamics of the process of aggregation on parameters such as backbone
flexibility and charge density of such polymers is crucial for insights into
various biological processes which involve biological polyelectrolytes such as
protein, DNA etc., Here, we use large-scale coarse-grained molecular dynamics
simulations to obtain the phase diagram of the aggregated structures of
flexible charged polymers and characterize the morphology of the aggregates as
well as the aggregation dynamics, in the presence of trivalent counterions.
Three different phases are observed depending on the charge density: no
aggregation, a finite bundle phase where multiple small aggregates coexist with
a large aggregate, and a fully phase separated phase. We show that the
flexibility of the polymer backbone causes strong entanglement between charged
polymers leading to additional time scales in the aggregation process. Such
slowing down of the aggregation dynamics results in the exponent,
characterizing the power law decay of the number of aggregates with time, to be
dependent on the charge density of the polymers. These results are contrary to
those obtained for rigid polyelectrolytes, emphasizing the role of backbone
flexibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10113</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Hennes</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tailleur</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charron</keyname><forenames>Ga&#xeb;lle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daerr</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author></authors><title>Active depinning of bacterial droplets: the collective surfing of
  Bacillus subtilis</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures, SI: 5 movies, 10 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 114(23):
  5958--5963 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1703997114</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  How systems are endowed with migration capacity is a fascinating question
with implications ranging from the design of novel active systems to the
control of microbial populations. Bacteria, which can be found in a variety of
environments, have developed among the richest set of locomotion mechanisms
both at the microscopic and collective levels. Here, we uncover experimentally
a new mode of collective bacterial motility in humid environment through the
depinning of bacterial droplets. While capillary forces are notoriously
enormous at the bacterial scale, even capable of pinning water droplets of
millimetric size on inclined surfaces, we show that bacteria are able to
harness a variety of mechanisms to unpin contact lines, hence inducing a
collective slipping of the colony across the surface. Contrary to
flagella-dependent migration modes like swarming we show that this much faster
`colony surfing' still occurs in mutant strains of \textit{Bacillus subtilis}
lacking flagella. The active unpinning seen in our experiments relies on a
variety of microscopic mechanisms which could each play an important role in
the migration of microorganisms in humid environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10120</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Petrelli</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laeger</keyname><forenames>Kathrin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perugini</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>High spatial resolution trace element determination of geological
  samples by laser ablation quadrupole plasma mass spectrometry: implications
  for glass analysis in volcanic products</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Geosciences Journal, Volume 20, Issue 6, 1 December 2016, Pages
  851-863</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12303-016-0007-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Increasing the spatial resolution of Laser Ablation Inductively Coupled
Plasma Mass Spectrometry (LA-ICP-MS) is a challenge in microanalysis of
geological samples. Smaller sizes for the laser beam will allow for (1) high
resolution determination of trace element compositions, (2) accurate estimation
of crystal/melt partition coefficients, (3) detailed characterization of
diffusion profiles, and (4) analysis of fine volcanic glasses. Here, we report
about the figures of merit for LA-ICP Quadrupole MS down to a spatial
resolution of 5 {\mu}m. This study highlights the possibility to achieve
suitable limits of detection, accuracy and precision for geological samples
even at spatial resolutions of the order of 5 {\mu}m. At a beam size of 15
{\mu}m precision (measured as one sigma) and accuracy (expressed as relative
deviation from the reference value) are of the order of 10%. At a smaller beam
size of 8um, precision decreases to 15% for concentration above 1.7 {\mu}g g-1.
As the beam size is decreased to ~5 {\mu}m, precision declines to about 15% and
20% for concentrations above 10 {\mu}g g-1 using 42Ca and 29Si as internal
standard, respectively. Accuracy is better or equal to 10% and 13 % at beam
sizes of 15 and 10 {\mu}m respectively. When the spatial resolution is
increased to 8 {\mu}m, accuracy remains better than 15% and 20% for 42Ca and
29Si as internal standard, respectively. We employed such high-resolution
techniques to volcanic glasses in ash particles of the 2010 Eyjafjallaj\&quot;okull
eruption. Our results are well consistent with the previously reported data
obtained at lower spatial resolution, supporting the reliability of the method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10121</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Watson</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Trouilhet</keyname><forenames>JF.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Paletou</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>UPS-OMP-CNRS-IRAP, Toulouse</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gebran</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>NDU-Louaize, Lebanon</affiliation></author></authors><title>Sliced Inverse Regression for the inference of stellar fundamental
  parameters</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>in French. to appear in: http://www.gretsi.fr/ XXVI-th colloquium
  proc. (text in french; maths in maths)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We aim at finding the value of an explanatory variable, through its
expression in a large data-vector, without knowing the link function between
the explanatory variable and the data-space. Sliced Inverse Regression (SIR)
method allows for the projection of a data-vector onto a subspace consistent
with the explanatory variable variation. We suggest a method based on the SIR
subspace, that gives the most efficient estimation of an unknown explanatory
variable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10126</id><created>2017-06-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Middya</keyname><forenames>Sagnik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prabakar</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Si Orientation Dependent Release of SiO2 Microcantilevers by Wet
  Chemical Etching Method</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Micro-cantilevers (MCs) are widely used in sensing, probing and a variety of
other purposes. Apart from Si, the most versatile material in the micro domain,
SiO2 MCs have attracted much attention lately. In this study, fabrication of
SiO2 MCs using wet anisotropic etching technique is reported. Thermally grown
SiO2 (300 nm) layer on single crystalline(c-) Si is utilized for the
micro-fabrication. Standard lithographic procedure was followed and the
exposure of the photo-resist was performed by mask-less direct laser writer.
Various orientations on the c-Si wafer, their properties and implications on
the structure and integrity of the released SiO2 MC are discussed. The 110
direction was found to be much time consuming and sticking of the released
structures was almost evident. On the other hand 100 and 410 directions showed
lesser release time and higher stability of the released structures due to
under-etching along the width of the MCs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10127</id><created>2017-06-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Athari</keyname><forenames>Mir Hadi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying Cascading Overload Failures under High Penetration of Wind
  Generation</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>To be published (Accepted) in: Proceedings of the Power and Energy
  Society General Meeting (PESGM), Chicago, IL, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While power systems are reliable infrastructures, their complex
interconnectivities allow for propagation of disturbances through cascading
failures which causes blackouts. Meanwhile the ever increasing penetration
level of renewable generation into power grids introduces a massive amount of
uncertainty to the grid that might have a severe impact on grid vulnerability
to overload cascading failures. There are numerous studies in the literature
that focus on modeling cascading failures with different approaches. However,
there is a need for studies that simulate cascading failure considering the
uncertainty coming from high penetration of renewable generation. In this
study, the impacts of wind generation in terms of its penetration and
uncertainty levels on grid vulnerability to cascading overload failures are
studied. The simulation results on IEEE 300 bus system show that uncertainty
coming from wind energy have severe impact on grid vulnerability to cascading
overload failures. Results also suggest that higher penetration levels of wind
energy if not managed appropriately will add to this severity due to injection
of higher uncertainties into the grid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10129</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Saleh</keyname><forenames>Joseph Homer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Fan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku</keyname><forenames>Michelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Mitchell L. R.</forenames><suffix>II</suffix></author></authors><title>Electric propulsion reliability: statistical analysis of on-orbit
  anomalies and comparative analysis of electric versus chemical propulsion
  failure rates</title><categories>physics.space-ph stat.AP</categories><comments>36 pages, 18 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With a few hundred spacecraft launched to date with electric propulsion (EP),
it is possible to conduct an epidemiological study of EP on orbit reliability.
The first objective of the present work was to undertake such a study and
analyze EP track record of on orbit anomalies and failures by different
covariates. The second objective was to provide a comparative analysis of EP
failure rates with those of chemical propulsion. After a thorough data
collection, 162 EP-equipped satellites launched between January 1997 and
December 2015 were included in our dataset for analysis. Several statistical
analyses were conducted, at the aggregate level and then with the data
stratified by severity of the anomaly, by orbit type, and by EP technology.
Mean Time To Anomaly (MTTA) and the distribution of the time to anomaly were
investigated, as well as anomaly rates. The important findings in this work
include the following: (1) Post-2005, EP reliability has outperformed that of
chemical propulsion; (2) Hall thrusters have robustly outperformed chemical
propulsion, and they maintain a small but shrinking reliability advantage over
gridded ion engines. Other results were also provided, for example the
differentials in MTTA of minor and major anomalies for gridded ion engines and
Hall thrusters. It was shown that: (3) Hall thrusters exhibit minor anomalies
very early on orbit, which might be indicative of infant anomalies, and thus
would benefit from better ground testing and acceptance procedures; (4) Strong
evidence exists that EP anomalies (onset and likelihood) and orbit type are
dependent, a dependence likely mediated by either the space environment or
differences in thrusters duty cycles; (5) Gridded ion thrusters exhibit both
infant and wear-out failures, and thus would benefit from a reliability growth
program that addresses both these types of problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10136</id><created>2017-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Smy</keyname><forenames>Tom. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Shulabh</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrated Generalized Sheet Transition Conditions (GSTCs) in a Yee-Cell
  based Finite-Difference Time-Domain (FDTD) Simulation of Electromagnetic
  Metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) simulation of broadband
electromagnetic metasurfaces based on direct in- corporation of Generalized
Sheet Transition Conditions (GSTCs) inside a conventional Yee-cell region has
been proposed, for arbitrary wave excitations. This is achieved by inserting a
zero thickness metasurface inside bulk nodes of the Yee-cell region, giving
rise to three distinct cell configurations - Symmetric Cell (SC), Asymmetric
Cell (AC) and Tight Asymmetric Cell (TAC). In addition, the metasurface is
modelled using electric and magnetic surface susceptibilities exhibiting a
broadband Lorentzian response. As a result, the proposed model guarantees a
physical and causal response from the metasurface. Several full- wave results
are shown, and compared with analytical Fourier propagation methods showing
excellent results, for both 1D and 2D fields simulations. It is found that the
TAC provides the fastest convergence among the three methods with minimum
error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10142</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10142</id><created>2017-06-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>Nuria Martinez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borkar</keyname><forenames>Saurabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masoller</keyname><forenames>Cristina</forenames></author></authors><title>Predictability of Extreme Intensity Pulses in Optically Injected
  Semiconductor Lasers</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Spec. Top. 226, 1971 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2016-60391-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The predictability of extreme intensity pulses emitted by an optically
injected semiconductor laser is studied numerically, by using a well-known rate
equation model. We show that symbolic ordinal time-series analysis allows to
identify the patterns of intensity oscillations that are likely to occur before
an extreme pulse. The method also gives information about patterns which are
unlikely to occur before an extreme pulse. The specific patterns identified
capture the topology of the underlying chaotic attractor and depend on the
model parameters. The methodology proposed here can be useful for analyzing
data recorded from other complex systems that generate extreme fluctuations in
their output signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10148</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Nagarajan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chandiramouli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation on nickel ferrite nanowire device exhibiting negative
  differential resistance $-$ a first-principles investigation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el physics.app-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures</comments><proxy>Iryna Bzovska</proxy><journal-ref>Condens. Matter Phys., vol. 20, No. 2, 23301 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.5488/CMP.20.23301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The electronic property of NiFe$_2$O$_4$ nanowire device is investigated
through nonequilibrium Green's functions (NEGF) in combination with density
functional theory (DFT). The electronic transport properties of NiFe$_2$O$_4$
nanowire are studied in terms of density of states, transmission spectrum and
$I{-}V$ characteristics. The density of states gets modified with the applied
bias voltage across NiFe$_2$O$_4$ nanowire device, the density of charge is
observed both in the valence band and in the conduction band on increasing the
bias voltage. The transmission spectrum of NiFe$_2$O$_4$ nanowire device gives
the insights on the transition of electrons at different energy intervals. The
findings of the present work suggest that NiFe$_2$O$_4$ nanowire device can be
used as negative differential resistance (NDR) device and its NDR property can
be tuned with the bias voltage, which may be used in microwave device, memory
devices and in fast switching devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10149</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Brady</keyname><forenames>Robert M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samulski</keyname><forenames>Edward T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turban</keyname><forenames>David H P</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence that rotons in helium II are interstitial atoms</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superfluid helium II contains excitations known as rotons. Their properties
have been studied experimentally for more than 70 years but their structure is
not fully understood. Feynman's 1954 description, involving rotating flow
patterns, does not fully explain later experimental data. Here we identify
volumetric, thermodynamic, colloidal, excitation, x-ray and neutron scattering
evidence that rotons are composed of interstitial helium atoms. We show in
particular that they have the same mass, effective mass and activation energy
within experimental accuracy. They readily move through the substrate, and
couple through lattice vibrations to produce quantized, loss-free flow which
corresponds to the observed superflow. Our observations revive London's 1936
conclusion that helium II has a relatively open crystal-like lattice with
enough free volume for atoms to move relative to one another, and reconcile it
with London's 1938 description of a quantum fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10152</id><created>2017-06-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Afriat</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Logic of gauge</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>comments, corrections most welcome</comments><msc-class>01-02, 53-03, 53Z05, 83-03, 83D05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The logic of gauge theory is considered by tracing its development from
general relativity to Yang-Mills theory, through Weyl's two gauge theories. A
handful of elements---which for want of better terms can be called
\emph{geometrical justice}, \emph{matter wave}, \emph{second clock effect},
\emph{twice too many energy levels}---are enough to produce Weyl's second
theory; and from there, all that's needed to reach the Yang-Mills formalism is
a \emph{non-Abelian structure group} (say $\mathbb{SU}\textrm{(}N\textrm{)}$).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10155</id><created>2017-06-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Marimuthu</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inbanathan</keyname><forenames>S. S. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of various projectile interactions with Nuclear Emulsion
  Detector nuclei at ~ 1 GeV per nucleon using Coulomb modified Glauber model</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>29 pages, 6 figures and 5 tables Submitted, Nucl. Phys. A (2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The total nuclear reaction cross-section is calculated considering with and
without medium effect by employing Coulomb Modified Glauber Model (CMGM) for
interactions of projectiles 56^Fe_26, 84^Kr_36, 132^Xe_54, 197^Au_79 and
238^U_92 with nuclear emulsion detector (NED) nuclei at around 1 GeV per
nucleon incident kinetic energy. These calculated reaction cross-sections are
correlated with the different target groups of the NED nuclei. The average
value of various parameters are also calculated and compared with the
corresponding experimental results. The number of shower particles emitted in
an interaction is also calculated and showed good agreement with the
experimental result. We observed that the total reaction cross-section
increases with increasing the target mass number in case of all the considered
projectiles. In addition, it shows that the average value of reaction
cross-section with nuclear medium effect is in good agreement with the
experimental results for projectiles 56^Fe, 84^Kr, 132^Xe, although results of
projectiles 197^Au and 238^U are not in agreement with the experimental
observations. This study sheds some light on the energy dependence of the
nuclear reaction cross-section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10159</id><created>2017-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Palus</keyname><forenames>Milan</forenames></author></authors><title>Linked by dynamics: wavelet--based mutual information rate as a
  connectivity measure and scale-specific networks</title><categories>physics.data-an physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>To appear in: Tsonis, A.A. (ed.): Advances in Nonlinear Geosciences,
  Springer, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Experimentally observed networks of interacting dynamical systems are
inferred from recorded multivariate time series by evaluating a statistical
measure of dependence, usually the cross-correlation coefficient, or mutual
information. These measures reflect dependence in static probability
distributions, generated by systems' evolution, rather than coherence of
systems' dynamics. Moreover, these &quot;static&quot; measures of dependence can be
biased due to properties of dynamics underlying the analyzed time series.
Consequently, properties of local dynamics can be misinterpreted as properties
of connectivity or long-range interactions. We propose the mutual information
rate as a measure reflecting coherence or synchronization of dynamics of two
systems and not suffering by the bias typical for the &quot;static&quot; measures. We
demonstrate that a computationally accessible estimation method, derived for
Gaussian processes and adapted by using the wavelet transform, can be effective
for nonlinear, nonstationary and multiscale processes. The discussed problem
and the proposed method are illustrated using numerically generated data of
coupled dynamical systems as well as gridded reanalysis data of surface air
temperature as the source for the construction of climate networks. In
particular, scale-specific climate networks are introduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10161</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Patern&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbero</keyname><forenames>Nadia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galliano</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barolo</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanzani</keyname><forenames>Guglielmo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scotognella</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-Infrared Emitting Single Squaraine Dye Aggregate with large Stokes
  shift</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of supramolecular interactions and aggregation behaviour of
functional materials is of great importance to tune and extend their spectral
sensitivity and, hence, improve the optoelectronic response of related devices.
In this study, we resolve spatially and spectrally the absorption and emission
features of a squaraine aggregate by means of confocal microscopy and
absorption/photoluminescence spectroscopy. We observe that the aggregate
affords both a broad absorption spectrum (centred at 670 nm), likely originated
by a dyes configuration with allowed J- and H- arrangements, and a strong and
relatively narrow emission in the near-infrared (NIR) part of the spectrum
(centred at 780 nm), with a remarkable Stokes shift of 110 nm that is among the
largest exhibited by squaraine dyes. These peculiarities would be beneficial
for extending the spectral sensitivity of bot photovoltaic and light-emitting
diodes, and extremely appealing for possible applications of these aggregates
as NIR fluorescent probes in biomedical applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10172</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10172</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Yongjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karsai</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarraute</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minnoni</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleury</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Prepaid or Postpaid? That is the question. Novel Methods of Subscription
  Type Prediction in Mobile Phone Services</title><categories>cs.SI cs.LG physics.soc-ph stat.ML</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 figures; chapter to appear in Lecture Notes in Social
  Networks; Eds. R. Alhajj, U. Gl\&quot;asser, Springer Nature (2017)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate the behavioural differences between mobile phone
customers with prepaid and postpaid subscriptions. Our study reveals that (a)
postpaid customers are more active in terms of service usage and (b) there are
strong structural correlations in the mobile phone call network as connections
between customers of the same subscription type are much more frequent than
those between customers of different subscription types. Based on these
observations we provide methods to detect the subscription type of customers by
using information about their personal call statistics, and also their
egocentric networks simultaneously. The key of our first approach is to cast
this classification problem as a problem of graph labelling, which can be
solved by max-flow min-cut algorithms. Our experiments show that, by using both
user attributes and relationships, the proposed graph labelling approach is
able to achieve a classification accuracy of $\sim 87\%$, which outperforms by
$\sim 7\%$ supervised learning methods using only user attributes. In our
second problem we aim to infer the subscription type of customers of external
operators. We propose via approximate methods to solve this problem by using
node attributes, and a two-ways indirect inference method based on observed
homophilic structural correlations. Our results have straightforward
applications in behavioural prediction and personal marketing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10178</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lo</keyname><forenames>Chun-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catalano</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smithe</keyname><forenames>Kirby K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Luhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shengjiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pop</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Moon J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhihong</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-Dimensional h-BN and MoS2 as Diffusion Barriers for Ultra-Scaled
  Copper Interconnects</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages; 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Copper interconnects in modern integrated circuits require ultra-thin
barriers to prevent intermixing of Cu with surrounding dielectric materials.
Conventional barriers rely on metals like TaN, however their finite thickness
reduces the cross-sectional area and significantly increases the resistivity of
nanoscale interconnects. In this study, a new class of two-dimensional (2D) Cu
diffusion barriers, hexagonal boron nitride (h-BN) and molybdenum disulfide
(MoS2), is demonstrated for the first time. Using time-dependent dielectric
breakdown measurements and scanning transmission electron microscopy coupled
with energy dispersive X-ray spectroscopy and electron energy loss
spectroscopy, these 2D materials are shown to be promising barrier solutions
for ultra-scaled interconnect technology. The predicted lifetime of devices
with directly deposited 2D barriers can achieve three orders of magnitude
improvement compared to control devices without barriers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10183</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>More</keyname><forenames>Jai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Asmita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nair</keyname><forenames>Sreeraj</forenames></author></authors><title>Wigner Distributions of Quarks and Gluons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Prepared for XXV International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering
  and Related Subjects, 3-7 April 2017, University of Birmingham, UK</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a recent calculation of Wigner distributions of quarks and gluons
for a quark target state dressed with a gluon, using overlaps of light-front
wave functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10189</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Aghaeimeibodi</keyname><forenames>Shahriar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Je-Hyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waks</keyname><forenames>Edo</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-infrared Emission from Defect States in Few-layer Phosphorene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Atomically-thin films of phosphorene (also known as black phosphorus) are a
low dimensional optical material with direct exciton emission, whose wavelength
is tunable by controlling the number of layers. In addition to this excitonic
emission, recent works revealed the existence of emissions from defect states
and described new methods to manipulate them. Monolayer phosphorene exhibits
emission from localized defect states at wavelengths near 920 nm. Increasing
the number of layers should shift the defect emission to longer wavelengths,
enabling the material to span a broader spectral range. However, defect
emission from few-layer phosphorene has not yet been reported. In this paper,
we demonstrate the existence of a new class of near-infrared emission from
defect states in few-layer phosphorene. Photoluminescence measurements show a
bright emission around 1240 nm with a sublinear growth of emission intensity
when the excitation intensity is linearly increased, confirming the
defect-based nature of this emission. From time-resolved lifetime measurements
we determine an emission lifetime of 1.1 ns, in contrast with the exciton
lifetime from phosphorene, which has been previously reported to be in the
range of a few hundred picoseconds. This work shows that phosphorene defects
can act as a source of infrared light with potential applications in
optoelectronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10190</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yunmi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xiaoshan</forenames></author></authors><title>Large Deviations for Chiral Transition through Path Integral</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>0 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An noise-induced mechanism has been revealed by some authors recently for the
homochirality in a chiral system. Motivated by such stochastic process, we
study the noise-induced transition in the system. The chiral transition, say
the transition between chiral states, is impossible in the deterministic view
if the homochirality has been converged, but is a rare event when noise is
involved. We study the rare event by using the large deviation theory (LDT) and
figure out the LDT rate functional for the transition probability through the
Doi-Peliti second quantization path integral method. In order to check the
correctness of our work, we have derived the Langevin equations through the
path integral method by using the Hubbard-Stratonovich transformation, and
recover the equations reported by other authors through a different method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10196</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Marchewka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double valley Dirac fermions for 3D and 2D Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te with
  strong asymmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1605.09214 by other authors</comments><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/27004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the possibility to bring about the double- valley Dirac
fermions in some quantum structures is predicted. These quantum structures are:
strained 3D Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te topological insulator (TI) with strong interface
inversion asymmetry and the asymmetric Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te double quantum wells
(DQW). The numerical analysis of the dispersion relation for 3D TI
Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te for the proper Cd ($x$)-content of in the
Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te-compound clearly show that the inversion symmetry breaking
together with the unaxial tensile strain causes splitting each of Dirac nodes
(two belonging to two interfaces) into two in the proximity of $\Gamma$-point.
The similar effects can be obtained for asymmetric Hg$_{1-x}$Cd$_x$Te DQW with
the proper content of Cd and proper width of the quantum wells. The aim of this
work is to explore the inversion symmetry breaking in 3D TI and 2D DQWs mixed
HgCdTe-systems. It is shown that this symmetry breaking leads to the dependence
of carriers energy vs quasi-momentum similar to that of Weyl fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10201</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Parlakg&#xf6;r&#xfc;r</keyname><forenames>Tu&#x11f;&#xe7;e</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pashaev</keyname><forenames>Oktay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Cauchy-Riemann Equations and Liouville Equation For Conformal
  Metrics</title><categories>nlin.SI math.CV</categories><comments>44 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the Nonlinear Cauchy-Riemann equations as B\&quot;{a}cklund
transformations for several nonlinear and linear partial differential
equations. From these equations we treat in details the Laplace and the
Liouville equations by deriving general solution for the nonlinear Liouville
equation. By M\&quot;{o}bius transformation we relate solutions for the Poincare
model of hyperbolic geometry, the Klein model in half-plane and the
pseudo-sphere. Conformal form of the constant curvature metrics in these
geometries, stereographic projections and special solutions are discussed. Then
we introduce the hyperbolic analog of the Riemann sphere, which we call the
Riemann pseudosphere. We identify point at infinity on this pseudosphere and
show that it can be used in complex analysis as an alternative to usual Riemann
sphere to extend the complex plane. Interpretation of symmetric and antipodal
points on both, the Riemann sphere and the Riemann pseudo-sphere, are given. By
M\&quot;{o}bius transformation and homogenous coordinates, the most general solution
of Liouville equation as discussed by Crowdy is derived.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10218</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Basith</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmmad</keyname><forenames>Bashir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Md. Sarowar</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf8;lhave</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Preparation of high crystalline nanoparticles of rare-earth based
  complex pervoskites and comparison of their structural and magnetic
  properties with bulk counterparts</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/2053-1591/aa769e</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple route to prepare Gd$_{0.7}$Sr$_{0.3}$MnO$_3$ nanoparticles by
ultrasonication of their bulk powder materials is presented in this article.
For comparison, Gd$_{0.7}$Sr$_{0.3}$MnO$_3$ nanoparticles are also prepared by
ball milling. The prepared samples are characterized by X-ray diffraction
(XRD),field emission scanning electron microscope (FESEM), energy dispersive
X-ray (EDX), X-ray photoelectron spectroscope (XPS), and Superconducting
Quantum Interference Device (SQUID) magnetometer. XRD Rietveld analysis is
carried out extensively for the determination of crystallographic parameters
and the amount of crystalline and amorphous phases. FESEM images demonstrate
the formation of nanoparticles with average particle size in the range of
50-100 nm for both ultrasonication and 4 hours (h) of ball milling. The bulk
materials and nanoparticles synthesized by both ultrasonication and 4 h ball
milling exhibit a paramagnetic to spin-glass transition. However, nanoparticles
synthesized by 8 h and 12 h ball milling do not reveal any phase transition,
rather show an upturn of magnetization at low temperature. The degradation of
the magnetic properties in ball milled nanoparticles may be associated with
amorphization of the nanoparticles due to ball milling particularly for milling
time exceeding 8 h. This investigation demonstrates the potential of
ultrasonication as a simple route to prepare high crystalline rare-earth based
manganite nanoparticles with improved control compared to the traditional ball
milling technique.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10226</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10226</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Chowdhurya</keyname><forenames>Sayeed Shafayet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamal</keyname><forenames>Abu Hena Mostafa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hossain</keyname><forenames>Rana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasan</keyname><forenames>Mehedi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>Md. Fakhrul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmmad</keyname><forenames>Bashir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basith</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dy doped BiFeO$_3$ : A Bulk Ceramic with Improved Multiferroic
  Properties Compared to Nano Counterparts</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 Pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ceramics International 43 (2017) 9191-9199</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ceramint.2017.04.072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The synthesis as well as structural, multiferroic and optical
characterization of Dy doped BiFeO$_3$ multiferroic ceramic are presented. Bulk
polycrystalline Bi$_{0.9}$Dy$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ sample is synthesized by solid
state reaction, while their nano counterparts are prepared using ultrasonic
probe sonication technique. Significant improvement of phase purity in the as
synthesized samples is observed after the doping of Dy both in bulk
Bi$_{0.9}$Dy$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ sample and corresponding nanoparticles as evidenced
from Rietveld refinement. Magnetization measurements using SQUID magnetometer
exhibit enhanced magnetic properties for Dy doped bulk
Bi$_{0.9}$Dy$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ ceramic compared to their nanostructured
counterparts as well as undoped BiFeO$_3$. Within the applied field range,
saturation polarization is observed for Bi$_{0.9}$Dy$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ bulk
ceramic only. As a result, intrinsic ferroelectric behavior is obtained just
for this sample. Optical bandgap measurements reveal lower bandgap for Dy doped
bulk Bi$_{0.9}$Dy$_{0.1}$FeO$_3$ ceramic compared to that of corresponding
nanoparticles and undoped BiFeO$_3$. The outcome of this investigation
demonstrates the potential of Dy as a doping element in BiFeO$_3$ that provides
a bulk ceramic material with improved multiferroic and optical properties
compared to those of corresponding nanoparticles which involve rigorous
synthesis procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10243</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Kanal</keyname><forenames>Ilana Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owens</keyname><forenames>Steven G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharapov</keyname><forenames>Andrey B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutchison</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inverse Design of Conjugated Polymers from Computed Electronic Structure
  Properties: Model Chemistries of Polythiophenes</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 12 figures, submitted to J. Phys. Chem. C</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a diverse set of 100 oligothiophenes, extrapolated oligomer and polymer
HOMO, LUMO and HOMO-LUMO gaps are shown to be accurately estimated from the
computed values of the trimer HOMO, trimer LUMO and trimer HOMO-LUMO gaps.
These simple approximations can be improved further through easy to calculate
properties of monomers or small oligomers. Polymer reorganization energies,
related to the hole transport, are also shown to be predicted accurately from
small oligomers. Correlations between the HOMO slope with the HOMO polymer
energy and HOMO-LUMO gap slope with the polymer HOMO-LUMO gap energy suggest
that the degree of delocalization reflected in the slope is higher in monomers
and polymers with electron-rich, less negative HOMO eigenvalues. These
statistical models can serve as efficient screens for the computational
prediction of polythiophene properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10262</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Lozovik</keyname><forenames>Yu. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurbakov</keyname><forenames>I. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Pavel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic superfluidity of two-dimensional excitons in a periodic
  potential</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245430 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245430</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study anisotropies of helicity modulus, excitation spectrum, sound
velocity and angle-resolved luminescence spectrum in a two-dimensional system
of interacting excitons in a periodic potential. Analytical expressions for
anisotropic corrections to the quantities characterizing superfluidity are
obtained. We consider particularly the case of dipolar excitons in quantum
wells. For GaAs/AlGaAs heterostructures as well as MoS$_2$/hBN/MoS$_2$ and
MoSe$_2$/hBN/WSe$_2$ transition metal dichalcogenide bilayers estimates of the
magnitude of the predicted effects are given. We also present a method to
control superfluid motion and to determine the helicity modulus in generic
dipolar systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10275</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Mardani</keyname><forenames>Davood</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atia</keyname><forenames>George K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abouraddy</keyname><forenames>Ayman F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signal Reconstruction from Interferometric Measurements under Sensing
  Constraints</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper develops a unifying framework for signal reconstruction from
interferometric measurements that is broadly applicable to various applications
of interferometry. In this framework, the problem of signal reconstruction in
interferometry amounts to one of basis analysis. Its applicability is shown to
extend beyond conventional temporal interferometry, which leverages the
relative delay between the two arms of an interferometer, to arbitrary degrees
of freedom of the input signal. This allows for reconstruction of signals
supported in other domains (e.g., spatial) with no modification to the
underlying structure except for replacing the standard temporal delay with a
generalized delay, that is, a practically realizable unitary transformation for
which the basis elements are eigenfunctions. Under the proposed model, the
interferometric measurements are shown to be linear in the basis coefficients,
thereby enabling efficient and fast recovery of the desired information. While
the corresponding linear transformation has only a limited number of degrees of
freedom set by the structure of the interferometer giving rise to a highly
constrained sensing structure, we show that the problem of signal recovery from
such measurements can still be carried out compressively. This signifies
significant reduction in sample complexity without introducing any additional
randomization as is typically done in prior work leveraging compressive sensing
techniques. We provide performance guarantees under constrained sensing by
proving that the transformation satisfies sufficient conditions for successful
reconstruction of sparse signals using concentration arguments. We showcase the
effectiveness of the proposed approach using simulation results, as well as
actual experimental results in the context of optical modal analysis of spatial
beams.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
