<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:31:42Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-21" from="2017-07-21" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1010.1816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1010.1816</id><created>2010-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>B&#xf6;hm</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holler</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krotscheck</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panholzer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic Many-Body Theory. II. Dynamics of Strongly Correlated Fermi
  Fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>submitted to Phys. Rev. B</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.82.224505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a systematic theory of multi-particle excitations in strongly
interacting Fermi systems. Our work is the generalization of the time-honored
work by Jackson, Feenberg, and Campbell for bosons, that provides, in its most
advanced implementation, quantitative predictions for the dynamic structure
function in the whole experimentally accessible energy/momentum regime. Our
view is that the same physical effects -- namely fluctuations of the wave
function at an atomic length scale -- are responsible for the correct
energetics of the excitations in both Bose and Fermi fluids. Besides a
comprehensive derivation of the fermion version of the theory and discussion of
the approximations made, we present results for homogeneous He-3 and electrons
in three dimensions. We find indeed a significant lowering of the zero sound
mode in He-3 and a broadening of the collective mode due to the coupling to
particle-hole excitations in good agreement with experiments. The most visible
effect in electronic systems is the appearance of a ``double-plasmon''
excitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1106.4191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1106.4191</id><created>2011-06-21</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Giribet</keyname><forenames>Gaston</forenames></author></authors><title>Violating the string winding number maximally in Anti-de Sitter space</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages. V2 references added and minor typo corrected. V3, V4
  addendum on an alternative derivation of the main formula for short strings</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D84 (2011) 024045; Phys.Rev. D96 (2017) 024024</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.84.024045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study n-string scattering amplitudes in three-dimensional Anti-de Sitter
space (AdS3). We focus our attention on the processes in which the winding
number conservation is violated maximally; that is, those processes in which it
is violated in n-2 units. A worldsheet conformal field theory calculation leads
us to confirm a previous conjecture about the functional form of these
observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.1320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.1320</id><created>2012-08-06</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dexheimer</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Negreiros</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hempel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deconfinement to Quark Matter in Neutron Stars - The Influence of Strong
  Magnetic Fields</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR nucl-th</categories><comments>To appear in the proceedings of conference XII HADRON PHYSICS April,
  22-27, 2012, Bento Goncalves, Wineyards Valley Region, Rio Grande do Sul,
  Brazil Revised version with corrections made to the text in page 4</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4795968</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use an extended version of the hadronic SU(3) non-linear realization of
the sigma model that also includes quarks to study hybrid stars. Within this
approach, the degrees of freedom change naturally as the temperature/density
increases. Different prescriptions of charge neutrality, local and global, are
tested and the influence of strong magnetic fields and the anomalous magnetic
moment on the particle population is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02809</id><created>2015-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gajamannage</keyname><forenames>Kelum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butail</keyname><forenames>Sachit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porfiri</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bollt</keyname><forenames>Erik M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying manifolds underlying group motion in Vicsek agents</title><categories>math.DS cs.MA math-ph math.GT math.MP stat.ML</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures, journal article</comments><msc-class>57M60 (Primary), 37E99, 57N35 (Secondary)</msc-class><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2015-50088-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Collective motion of animal groups often undergoes changes due to
perturbations. In a topological sense, we describe these changes as switching
between low-dimensional embedding manifolds underlying a group of evolving
agents. To characterize such manifolds, first we introduce a simple mapping of
agents between time-steps. Then, we construct a novel metric which is
susceptible to variations in the collective motion, thus revealing distinct
underlying manifolds. The method is validated through three sample scenarios
simulated using a Vicsek model, namely switching of speed, coordination, and
structure of a group. Combined with a dimensionality reduction technique that
is used to infer the dimensionality of the embedding manifold, this approach
provides an effective model-free framework for the analysis of collective
behavior across animal species.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02083</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>A. E. C&#xe1;rcamo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varzielas</keyname><forenames>I. de Medeiros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumacher</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermion and scalar phenomenology of a 2-Higgs doublet model with $S_3$</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures, v2: version accepted in PRD</comments><report-no>DO-TH 15/12</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 016003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.016003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a 2-Higgs doublet model where the symmetry is extended by
$S_{3}\otimes Z_{3}\otimes Z_{3}^{\prime }\otimes Z_{14}$ and the field content
is enlarged by extra $SU(2)_{L}$ singlet scalar fields. $S_3$ makes the model
predictive and leads to viable fermion masses and mixing. The observed
hierarchy of the quark masses arises from the $Z_{3}^{\prime }$ and $Z_{14}$
symmetries. The light neutrino masses are generated through a type I seesaw
mechanism with two heavy Majorana neutrinos. In the lepton sector we obtain
mixing angles that are nearly tri-bi-maximal, in an excellent agreement with
the observed lepton parameters. The vacuum expectation values required for the
model are naturally obtained from the scalar potential, and we analyze the
scalar sector properties further constraining the model through the $\gamma
\gamma$ decay channel and the $T$ and $S$ parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.09135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.09135</id><created>2015-10-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Guohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czaplewski</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenferink</keyname><forenames>Erik J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanev</keyname><forenames>Teodor K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>Il Woong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Valley Polarization in Size-Tunable Monolayer Semiconductor Quantum Dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 7, Article number: 3324 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-03594-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three-dimensional confinement allows semiconductor quantum dots (QDs) to
exhibit size-tunable electronic and optical properties that enable a wide range
of opto-electronic applications from displays, solar cells and bio-medical
imaging to single-electron devices. Additional modalities such as spin and
valley properties can provide further degrees of freedom requisite for quantum
information and spintronics. When seeking to combine these material features
into QD structures, however, confinement can cause hybridization that inhibits
the robustness of these emergent properties for insertion into quantum devices.
Here, we show that a new class of laterally-confined materials, monolayer
MoS$_2$ QDs, can be created through top-down nanopatterning of an
atomically-thin two-dimensional semiconductor so that they exhibit the same
valley polarization as in a continuous monolayer sheet.
Semiconductor-compatible nanofabrication process allows for these
low-dimensional materials to be integrated into complex systems, an important
feature for advancing quantum information applications. The inherited bulk spin
and valley properties, the size dependence of excitonic energies, and the
ability to fabricate MoS$_2$ QDs using semiconductor-compatible processing
suggest that monolayer semiconductor QDs have the potential to be multimodal
building blocks of integrated quantum information and spintronics systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05638</id><created>2015-11-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Shabbir</keyname><forenames>Babar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiaolin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yanwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Shixue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Shishen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Liangmo</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong enhancement of critical current density in both low &amp; high fields
  and flux pinning mechanism under hydrostatic pressure in optimally doped
  (Ba,K)Fe2As2 single crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Nil</comments><doi>10.1038/srep23044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strong pinning depends on the pinning force strength and number density of
effective defects. Using hydrostatic pressure method, we demonstrate that
hydrostatic pressure up to 1.2 GPa can significantly enhance flux pinning or Jc
by a factor of up to 5 especially in both low and high fields in optimally
doped Ba0.6K0.4Fe2As2 crystals. Our analysis on the flux pining mechanism
indicate that both pinning centre number density (Np) and pinning force (Fp)
are greatly increased by the pressure and contribute to strong pinning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07420</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>A. E. C&#xe1;rcamo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varzielas</keyname><forenames>I. de Medeiros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neill</keyname><forenames>Nicol&#xe1;s A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A novel Randall-Sundrum model with $S_{3}$ flavor symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages. Final version published in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 033011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.033011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a simple and predictive model of fermion masses and mixing in a
warped extra dimension, with the smallest discrete non-Abelian group $S_{3}$
and the discrete symmetries $Z_{2}\otimes Z_{4}$. Standard Model fields
propagate in the bulk and the mass hierarchies and mixing angles are accounted
for the fermion zero modes localization profiles, similarly to the the
Randall-Sundrum (RS) model. To the best of our knowledge, this model is the
first implementation of an $S_{3}$ flavor symmetry in this type of warped extra
dimension framework. Our model successfully describes the fermion masses and
mixing pattern and is consistent with the current low energy fermion flavor
data. The discrete flavor symmetry in our model leads to predictive mixing
inspired textures, where the Cabbibo mixing arises from the down type quark
sector whereas up type quark sector contributes to the remaining mixing angles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01584</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2017-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tiefu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Yueyin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inomata</keyname><forenames>Kunihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshihara</keyname><forenames>Fumiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Siyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-photon-driven high-order sideband transitions in an ultrastrongly
  coupled circuit quantum electrodynamics system</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Accepted in Physical Review A. 12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 012325 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012325</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the experimental observation of high-order sideband transitions at
the single-photon level in a quantum circuit system of a flux qubit
ultrastrongly coupled to a coplanar waveguide resonator. With the coupling
strength reaching 10% of the resonator's fundamental frequency, we obtain clear
signatures of higher-order red and first-order blue-sideband transitions, which
are mainly due to the ultrastrong Rabi coupling. Our observation advances the
understanding of ultrastrongly-coupled systems and paves the way to study
high-order processes in the quantum Rabi model at the single-photon level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04048</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04048</id><created>2016-03-13</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Kruining</keyname><forenames>Koen</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;tte</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The conditions for the preservation of duality symmetry in a linear
  medium</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt 18, 085601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/8/085601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electric magnetic duality symmetry is well understood in vacuum. For light
propagating through a medium this symmetry is typically broken. We investigate
under what conditions duality transformation is preserved in a linear medium
and employ these conditions to generalise the definition of optical helicity to
a general linear medium. We will discuss some unique properties duality
symmetric media possess, provided they exist and reformulate Maxwell's equation
in such a way that they explicitly show the decoupling of opposite helicities.
The feasibility of constructing a duality symmetric medium is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01373</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vasylyev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Atmospheric Quantum Channels with Weak and Strong Turbulence</title><categories>quant-ph physics.ao-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 090501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.090501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The free-space transfer of high-fidelity optical signals between remote
locations has many applications, including both classical and quantum
communication, precision navigation, clock synchronization, etc. The physical
processes that contribute to signal fading and loss need to be carefully
analyzed in the theory of light propagation through the atmospheric turbulence.
Here we derive the probability distribution for the atmospheric transmittance
including beam wandering, beam shape deformation, and beam-broadening effects.
Our model, referred to as the elliptic-beam approximation, applies to weak,
weak-to-moderate, and strong turbulence and hence to the most important regimes
in atmospheric communication scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01216</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gerhards</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Reconstruction of Dipole Directions from Spherical Magnetic Field
  Measurements</title><categories>physics.geo-ph math.NA</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reconstructing magnetizations from measurements of the generated magnetic
potential is generally non-unique. The non-uniqueness still remains if one
restricts the magnetization to those induced by an ambient magnetic dipole
field (i.e., the magnetization is described by a scalar susceptibility and the
dipole direction). Here, we investigate the situation under the additional
constraint that the susceptibility is either spatially localized in a subregion
of the sphere or that it is band-limited. If the dipole direction is known,
then the susceptibility is uniquely determined under the spatial localization
constraint while it is only determined up to a constant under the the
assumption of band-limitedness. If the dipole direction is not known,
uniqueness is lost again. However, we show that all dipole directions that
could possibly generate the measured magnetic potential need to be zeros of a
certain polynomial which can be computed from the given potential. We provide
examples of non-uniqueness of the dipole direction and examples on how to find
admissible candidates for the dipole direction under the spatial localization
constraint.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01872</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01872</id><created>2016-08-05</created><updated>2016-09-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerer</keyname><forenames>Klemens</forenames></author></authors><title>Synchronization of Active Atomic Clocks via Quantum and Classical
  Channels</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 043841 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.043841</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superradiant lasers based on atomic ensembles exhibiting ultra-narrow optical
transitions can emit light of unprecedented spectral purity and may serve as
active atomic clocks. We consider two frequency-detuned active atomic clocks,
which are coupled in a cascaded setup, i.e. as master &amp; slave lasers, and study
the synchronization of the slave to the master clock. In a setup where both
atomic ensembles are coupled to a common cavity mode such synchronization
phenomena have been predicted by Xu et al. [Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 154101
(2014)] and experimentally observed by Weiner et al. [arXiv:1503.06464 (2015)].
Here we demonstrate that synchronization still occurs in cascaded setups but
exhibits distinctly different phase diagrams. We study the characteristics of
synchronization in comparison to the case of coupling through a common cavity.
We also consider synchronization through a classical channel where light of the
master laser is measured phase sensitively and the slave laser is injection
locked by feedback and compare to the results achievable by coupling through
quantum channels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08458</id><created>2016-08-30</created><updated>2017-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Shou-hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Exotic Higgs Decay $h\rightarrow\phi\phi\rightarrow 4b$ at the LHeC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures. Version accepted by EPJC. Tables and figures
  updated after correcting a mistake in signal event generation. Results
  essentially unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.7, 457</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5012-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the exotic decay of the 125 GeV Higgs boson ($h$) into a pair of
light spin-0 particles ($\phi$) which subsequently decays and results in a $4b$
final state. This decay mode is well motivated in the Next to Minimal
Supersymmetric Standard Model (NMSSM) and extended Higgs sector models. Instead
of searching at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) and the High Luminosity Large
Hadron Collider (HL-LHC) which are beset by large Standard Model (SM)
backgrounds, we investigate this decay channel at the much cleaner Large Hadron
Electron Collider (LHeC). With some simple selection cuts this channel becomes
nearly free of background at this $ep$ machine, in stark contrast with the
situation at the (HL-)LHC. With a parton level analysis we show that for the
$\phi$ mass range $[20,60]GeV$, with $100\,fb^{-1}$ luminosity the LHeC is
generally capable of constraining
$C_{4b}^2\equiv\kappa_{V}^2\times\text{Br}(h\rightarrow\phi\phi)\times\text{Br}^2(\phi\rightarrow
b\bar{b})$ ($\kappa_{V}$ denotes the $hVV(V=W,Z)$ coupling strength relative to
the SM value) to a few percent level ($95\%$ CLs). With $1\,ab^{-1}$ luminosity
$C_{4b}^2$ at a few per mille level can be probed. These sensitivities are much
better than the HL-LHC performance and demonstrate the important role expected
to be played by the LHeC in probing exotic Higgs decay processes, in addition
to the already proposed invisible Higgs decay channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01413</id><created>2016-09-06</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fujimoto</keyname><forenames>Yukihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Kouhei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishiwaki</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakamoto</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatsumi</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>6d Dirac fermion on a rectangle; scrutinizing boundary conditions, mode
  functions and spectrum</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 2 tables (v1); 39 pages, 3 tables, accepted to Nuclear
  Physics B (v2)</comments><report-no>KIAS-P16066, KOBE-TH-16-05</report-no><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. B922 (2017) 186-225</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2017.06.024</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We classify possible boundary conditions of a 6d Dirac fermion $\Psi$ on a
rectangle under the requirement that the 4d Lorentz structure is maintained,
and derive the profiles and spectrum of the zero modes and nonzero KK modes
under the two specific boundary conditions, (i) 4d-chirality positive
components being zero at the boundaries and (ii) 2d-chirality positive
components being zero at the boundaries. In the case of (i), twofold
degenerated chiral zero modes appear which are localized towards specific
directions of the rectangle pointed by an angle parameter $\theta$. This leads
to an implication for a new direction of pursuing the origin of three
generations in the matter fields of the standard model, even though
triple-degenerated zero modes are not realized in the six dimensions. The
emergence of the angle parameter $\theta$ originates from a rotational symmetry
in the degenerated chiral zero modes on the rectangle extra dimensions since
they do not feel the boundaries. In the case of (ii), this rotational symmetry
is promoted to the two-dimensional conformal symmetry though no chiral massless
zero mode appears. We also discuss the correspondence between our model on a
rectangle and orbifold models in some details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.03923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.03923</id><created>2016-09-12</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gajamannage</keyname><forenames>Kelum</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bollt</keyname><forenames>Erik M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>Mason A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dawkins</keyname><forenames>Marian S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the lowest-cost splitting of a herd of cows by optimizing a
  cost function</title><categories>q-bio.PE cs.MA math.DS nlin.AO</categories><comments>19 pages, 10 figures</comments><msc-class>37F99, 37M05</msc-class><journal-ref>Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, volume
  27, number 6, pages 063114, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4983671</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Animals live in groups to defend against predation and to obtain food.
However, for some animals --- especially ones that spend long periods of time
feeding --- there are costs if a group chooses to move on before their
nutritional needs are satisfied. If the conflict between feeding and keeping up
with a group becomes too large, it may be advantageous to some animals to split
into subgroups of animals with similar nutritional needs. We model the costs
and benefits of splitting by a herd of cows using a cost function (CF) that
quantifies individual variation in hunger, desire to lie down, and predation
risk. We model the costs associated with hunger and lying desire as the
standard deviations of individuals within a group, and we model predation risk
as an inverse exponential function of group size. We minimize the cost function
over all plausible groups that can arise from a given herd and study the
dynamics of group splitting. We explore our model using two examples: (1) we
consider group switching and group fission in a herd of relatively homogeneous
cows; and (2) we examine a herd with an equal number of adult males (larger
animals) and adult females (smaller animals).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05542</id><created>2016-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Shapiro</keyname><forenames>Avi M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pichler</keyname><forenames>Elgar</forenames></author></authors><title>Public Goods Games on Adaptive Coevolutionary Networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph nlin.AO q-bio.PE</categories><comments>11 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaos: An Interdisciplinary Journal of Nonlinear Science, 27 (7):
  073107 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4991679</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Productive societies feature high levels of cooperation and strong
connections between individuals. Public Goods Games (PGGs) are frequently used
to study the development of social connections and cooperative behavior in
model societies. In such games, contributions to the public good are made only
by cooperators, while all players, including defectors, can reap public goods
benefits. Classic results of game theory show that mutual defection, as opposed
to cooperation, is the Nash Equilibrium of PGGs in well-mixed populations,
where each player interacts with all others. In this paper, we explore the
coevolutionary dynamics of a low information public goods game on a network
without spatial constraints in which players adapt to their environment in
order to increase individual payoffs. Players adapt by changing their
strategies, either to cooperate or to defect, and by altering their social
connections. We find that even if players do not know other players' strategies
and connectivity, cooperation can arise and persist despite large short-term
fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.01821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.01821</id><created>2016-10-06</created><updated>2016-11-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kamano</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Modern Dynamical Coupled-Channels Calculations for Extracting and
  Understanding the Nucleon Spectrum</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures. Plenary talk at The 14th International
  Conference on Meson-Nucleon Physics and the Structure of the Nucleon
  (MENU2016), Kyoto, Japan, July 25-30, 2016</comments><journal-ref>JPS Conf. Proc. 13, 010012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSCP.13.010012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an overview of recent progress in the spectroscopic study of nucleon
resonances within the dynamical coupled-channels analysis of meson-production
reactions. The important role of multichannel reaction dynamics in
understanding various properties of nucleon resonances is emphasized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02038</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2017-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Pedro David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lodahl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Physics of quantum light emitters in disordered photonic nanostructures</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>Review accepted for publication in Annalen der Physik</comments><doi>10.1002/andp.201600351</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanophotonics focuses on the control of light and the interaction with matter
by the aid of intricate nanostructures. Typically, a photonic nanostructure is
carefully designed for a specific application and any imperfections may reduce
its performance, i.e., a thorough investigation of the role of unavoidable
fabrication imperfections is essential for any application. However, another
approach to nanophotonic applications exists where fabrication disorder is used
to induce functionalities by enhancing light-matter interaction. Disorder leads
to multiple scattering of light, which is the realm of statistical optics where
light propagation requires a statistical description. We review here the recent
progress on disordered photonic nanostructures and the potential implications
for quantum photonics devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.03147</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.03147</id><created>2016-11-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Lionel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movassagh</keyname><forenames>Ramis</forenames></author></authors><title>The gap of the area-weighted Motzkin spin chain is exponentially small</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1609.09160</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 255302 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa6cc4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the energy gap of the model proposed by Zhang, Ahmadain, and
Klich [1] is exponentially small in the square of the system size. In [2] a
class of exactly solvable quantum spin chain models was proposed that have
integer spins ($s$), with a nearest neighbors Hamiltonian, and a unique ground
state. The ground state can be seen as a uniform superposition of all
$s-$colored Motzkin walks. The half-chain entanglement entropy provably
violates the area law by a square root factor in the system's size
($\sim\sqrt{n}$) for $s&gt;1$. For $s=1$, the violation is logarithmic [3].
Moreover in [2] it was proved that the gap vanishes polynomially and is
$O(n^{-c})$ with $c\ge2$.
  Recently, a deformation of [2], which we call &quot;weighted Motzkin quantum spin
chain&quot; was proposed [1]. This model has a unique ground state that is a
superposition of the $s-$colored Motzkin walks weighted by
$t^{\text{area\{Motzkin walk\}}}$ with $t&gt;1$. The most surprising feature of
this model is that it violates the area law by a factor of $n$. Here we prove
that the gap of this model is upper bounded by $8ns\text{ }t^{-n^{2}/3}$ for
$t&gt;1$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06637</id><created>2016-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhouqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Peixiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Plasmonic Lattice Solitons in Semi-infinite Graphene Sheet
  Arrays</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1109/JLT.2017.2707601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the surface plasmonic lattice solitons (PLSs) in semi-infinite
graphene sheet arrays. The surface soliton is formed as the SPPs tunneling is
inhibited by the graphene nonlinearity, and meanwhile the incident power should
be above a threshold value. Thanks to the strong confinement of surface plasmon
polaritons (SPPs) on graphene, the effective width of surface PLSs can be
squeezed into deep-subwavelength scale of ~ 0.001{\lambda}. Based on the stable
propagation of surface PLSs, we find that the light propagation can be switched
from the array boundary to the inner graphene sheets by reducing the incident
power or increasing the chemical potential of graphene. The study may find
promising application in optical switches on deep-subwavelength scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07515</id><created>2016-11-22</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fagundes</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinmann</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Memory cost for simulating all quantum correlations of the Peres-Mermin
  scenario</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5+2 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 325302</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7ab3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sequences of compatible quantum measurements can be contextual and any
simulation with a classical model accounting for the quantum observations,
needs to use some internal memory. In Ref. [New J. Phys. 13, 113011 (2011)], it
was shown that simulating the sequences of compatible observables from the
Peres-Mermin scenario requires at least three different memory states in order
to be not in contradiction with the deterministic predictions of quantum
theory. We extend this analysis to the probabilistic quantum predictions and
ask how much memory is required to simulate the quantum correlations generated
by any quantum state. We find, that even in this comprehensive approach only
three internal states are required for the perfect simulation of the quantum
correlations in the Peres-Mermin scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01852</id><created>2016-12-06</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Furusawa</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sumiyoshi</keyname><forenames>Kohsuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Shoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Hideyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Supernova equations of state including full nuclear ensemble with
  in-medium effects</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>39 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables, Accepted for publication in Nucl.Phys.
  A. This article draws heavily from arXiv:1305.1508. The EOS table available
  at http://sites.google.com/site/furusawashun/eosdata</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Physics A 957 (2017) 188-207</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2016.09.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct new equations of state for baryons at sub-nuclear densities for
the use in core-collapse supernova simulations. The abundance of various nuclei
is obtained together with thermodynamic quantities. The formulation is an
extension of the previous model, in which we adopted the relativistic mean
field theory with the TM1 parameter set for nucleons, the quantum approach for
$d$, $t$, $h$ and $\alpha$ as well as the liquid drop model for the other
nuclei under the nuclear statistical equilibrium. We reformulate the model of
the light nuclei other than $d$, $t$, $h$ and $\alpha$ based on the
quasi-particle description. Furthermore, we modify the model so that the
temperature dependences of surface and shell energies of heavy nuclei could be
taken into account. The pasta phases for heavy nuclei and the Pauli- and
self-energy shifts for $d$, $t$, $h$ and $\alpha$ are taken into account in the
same way as in the previous model. We find that nuclear composition is
considerably affected by the modifications in this work, whereas
thermodynamical quantities are not changed much. In particular, the washout of
shell effect has a great impact on the mass distribution above $T \sim 1$ MeV.
This improvement may have an important effect on the rates of electron captures
and coherent neutrino scatterings on nuclei in supernova cores.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03894</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mielczarek</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trze&#x15b;niewski</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral dimension with deformed spacetime signature</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, v2 some extra results, comments and references
  added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 024012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.024012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Studies of the effective regime of loop quantum gravity (LQG) revealed that,
in the limit of Planckian curvature scales, spacetime may undergo a transition
from the Lorentzian to Euclidean signature. This effect is a consequence of
quantum modifications of the hypersurface deformation algebra, which in the
linearized case is equivalent to a deformed version of the Poincar\'e algebra.
In this paper the latter relation is applied to the LQG-inspired hypersurface
deformation algebra that is characterized by the above mentioned signature
change.
  While the exact form of the deformed Poincar\'e algebra is not uniquely
determined, the algebra under consideration is representative enough to capture
a number of qualitative features. In particular, the analysis reveals that the
signature change can be associated with two symmetric invariant energy scales,
which separate three physically disconnected momentum subspaces.
  Furthermore, the invariant measure on momentum space is derived, which allows
to properly define the average return probability, characterizing a fictitious
diffusion process on spacetime. The diffusion is subsequently studied in the
momentum representation for all possible variants of the model. Finally, the
spectral dimension of spacetime is calculated in each case as a function of the
scale parameter. In the most interesting case the deformation is of the
asymptotically ultralocal type and the spectral dimension undergoes a reduction
to $d_S = 1$ in the UV limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03921</id><created>2016-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanev</keyname><forenames>Teodor K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenferink</keyname><forenames>Erik J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced Conductivity Along Lateral Homojunction Interfaces of
  Atomically Thin Semiconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, supplementary information</comments><journal-ref>2D Materials 4, 021012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2053-1583/4/2/021012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Energy band realignment at the interfaces between materials in
heterostructures can give rise to unique electronic characteristics and
non-trivial low-dimensional charge states. In a homojunction of monolayer and
multilayer MoS$_2$, the thickness-dependent band structure implies the
possibility of band realignment and a new interface charge state with
properties distinct from the isolated layers. In this report, we probe the
interface charge state using scanning photocurrent microscopy and
gate-dependent transport with source-drain bias applied along the interface.
Enhanced photoresponse observed at the interface is attributed to band bending.
The effective conductivity of a material with a monolayer-multilayer interface
of MoS$_2$ is demonstrated to be higher than that of independent monolayers or
multilayers of MoS$_2$. A classic heterostructure model is constructed to
interpret the electrical properties at the interface. Our work reveals that the
band engineering at the transition metal dichalcogenides monolayer/multilayer
interfaces can enhance the longitudinal conductance and field-effect mobility
of the composite monolayer and multilayer devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.07920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.07920</id><created>2016-12-23</created><updated>2017-06-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frahm</keyname><forenames>Klaus M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zant</keyname><forenames>Samer El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaffr&#xe8;s-Runser</keyname><forenames>Katia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shepelyansky</keyname><forenames>Dima L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-cultural Wikipedia mining of geopolitics interactions leveraging
  reduced Google matrix analysis</title><categories>cs.SI nlin.CD physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>12 Pages, 6 figures, final version with slight modifications,
  accepted for publication in Physics Letters A. arXiv admin note: text overlap
  with arXiv:1609.01948</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A 381 (2017) 2677-2685</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2017.06.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Geopolitics focuses on political power in relation to geographic space.
Interactions among world countries have been widely studied at various scales,
observing economic exchanges, world history or international politics among
others. This work exhibits the potential of Wikipedia mining for such studies.
Indeed, Wikipedia stores valuable fine-grained dependencies among countries by
linking webpages together for diverse types of interactions (not only related
to economical, political or historical facts). We mine herein the Wikipedia
networks of several language editions using the recently proposed method of
reduced Google matrix analysis. This approach allows to establish direct and
hidden links between a subset of nodes that belong to a much larger directed
network. Our study concentrates on 40 major countries chosen worldwide. Our aim
is to offer a multicultural perspective on their interactions by comparing
networks extracted from five different Wikipedia language editions, emphasizing
English, Russian and Arabic ones. We demonstrate that this approach allows to
recover meaningful direct and hidden links among the 40 countries of interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01259</id><created>2017-01-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Yesilyurt</keyname><forenames>Can</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Seng Ghee</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Gengchiau</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jalil</keyname><forenames>Mansoor B. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conductance modulation in Weyl semimetals with tilted energy dispersion
  without a band gap</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 121, 244303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4989993</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the tunneling conductance of Weyl semimetal with tilted energy
dispersion by considering electron transmission through a p-n-p junction with
one-dimensional electric and magnetic barrier. In the presence of both electric
and magnetic barriers, we found that a large conductance gap can be produced by
the aid of tilted energy dispersion without a band gap. The origin of this
effect is the shift of the electrons wave-vector at barrier boundaries caused
by i) the pseudo-magnetic field induced by electrical potential, i.e., a newly
discovered feature that is only possible in the materials possessing tilted
energy dispersion, ii) the real magnetic field induced by ferromagnetic layer
deposited on the top of the system. We use realistic barrier structure
applicable in current nanotechnology and analyze the temperature dependence of
the tunneling conductance. The new approach presented here may resolve a major
problem of possible transistor applications in topological semimetals, i.e.,
the absence of normal backscattering and gapless band structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01758</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01758</id><created>2017-01-06</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Quinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabo</keyname><forenames>Ismaila</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-continuum calculation of the surface states and electrical
  response of silicon in solution</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 205308 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.205308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A wide range of electrochemical reactions of practical importance occur at
the interface between a semiconductor and an electrolyte. We present an
embedded density-functional theory method using the recently released
self-consistent continuum solvation (SCCS) approach to study these interfaces.
In this model, a quantum description of the surface is incorporated into a
continuum representation of the bending of the bands within the electrode. The
model is applied to understand the electrical response of silicon electrodes in
solution, providing microscopic insights into the low-voltage region, where
surface states determine the electrification of the semiconductor electrode.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.01846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.01846</id><created>2017-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Bao-Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margine</keyname><forenames>Elena R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the topologically protected surface states in
  superconductor $\beta$-Bi$_{2}$Pd from the three-dimensional to the
  two-dimensional limit</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter, 29, 325501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-648X/aa7a4b</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent discovery of topologically protected surface states in the
noncentrosymmetric $\alpha$-BiPd and the centrosymmetric $\beta$-Bi$_{2}$Pd has
renewed the interest in the Bi-Pd family of superconductors. Here, we employ
first-principles calculations to investigate the structure, electronic, and
topological features of $\beta$-Bi$_{2}$Pd, in bulk and in thin films of
various thicknesses. We find that the Van der Waals dispersion corrections are
important for reproducing the experimental structural parameters, while the
spin-orbit interaction is critical for properly describing the appearance of
topological electronic states. By increasing the thickness of the slab, the
Dirac-cone surface states and the Rashba-type surface states gradually emerge
at 9 and 11 triple-layers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02311</id><created>2017-01-09</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bahr</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinhaus</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Hypercuboidal renormalization in spin foam quantum gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>14 + 4 pages, 18 figures, v2: matching published version, minor
  improvements and updated references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 95, 126006 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.95.126006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we apply background-independent renormalization group methods
to spin foam quantum gravity. It is aimed at extending and elucidating the
analysis of a companion letter, in which the existence of a fixed point in the
truncated RG flow for the model was reported. Here we repeat the analysis with
various modifications, and find that both qualitative and quantitative features
of the fixed point are robust in this setting. We also go into details about
the various approximation schemes employed in the analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.03622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.03622</id><created>2017-01-13</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakajima</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delbecq</keyname><forenames>Matthieu R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otsuka</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stano</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaha</keyname><forenames>Shinichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoneda</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noiri</keyname><forenames>Akito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Kento</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>Kenta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allison</keyname><forenames>Giles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludwig</keyname><forenames>Arne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieck</keyname><forenames>Andreas D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loss</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarucha</keyname><forenames>Seigo</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust Single-Shot Spin Measurement with 99.5% Fidelity in a Quantum Dot
  Array</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 119, 017701 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.017701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a new method for projective single-shot measurement of two
electron spin states (singlet versus triplet) in an array of gate-defined
lateral quantum dots in GaAs. The measurement has very high fidelity and is
robust with respect to electric and magnetic fluctuations in the environment.
It exploits a long-lived metastable charge state, which increases both the
contrast and the duration of the charge signal distinguishing the two
measurement outcomes. This method allows us to evaluate the charge measurement
error and the spin-to-charge conversion error separately. We specify conditions
under which this method can be used, and project its general applicability to
scalable quantum dot arrays in GaAs or silicon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.04141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.04141</id><created>2017-01-15</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of Chirality-odd Twist-3 Fragmentation Functions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>representation improved, published version</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.07.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the complete set of evolutions of chirality-odd twist-3
fragmentation functions at one-loop level. There are totally nine real twist-3
fragmentation functions, among which seven are independent. The
renormalization-scale dependence of the nine functions has an important
implication for studies of single transverse-spin asymmetries. We find that the
evolutions of the three complex fragmentation functions defined by
quark-gluon-quark operator are mixed with themselves. There is no mixing with
the fragmentation functions defined only with bilinear quark field operators.
In the large-$N_c$ limit the evolutions of the three complex fragmentation
functions are simplified and reduced to six homogenous equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.05579</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.05579</id><created>2017-01-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yen-Jung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cain</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanev</keyname><forenames>Teodor K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dravid</keyname><forenames>Vinayak P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Valley-Polarized Exciton-Polaritons in a Monolayer Semiconductor</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, and Supplementary Information</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics, 11, 431-435 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2017.86</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single layers of transition metal dichalcogenides are two-dimensional direct
bandgap semiconductors with degenerate, but inequivalent, `valleys' in the
electronic structure that can be selectively excited by polarized light.
Coherent superpositions of light and matter, exciton-polaritons, have been
observed when these materials are strongly coupled to photons, but these hybrid
quasiparticles do not harness the valley-sensitive excitations of monolayer
transition metal dichalcogenides. Here, we demonstrate evidence for valley
polarized exciton-polaritons in monolayers of MoS$_2$ embedded in a dielectric
microcavity. Unlike traditional microcavity exciton-polaritons, these
light-matter quasiparticles emit polarized light with spectral Rabi splitting.
The interplay of cavity-modified exciton dynamics and intervalley relaxation in
the high-cooperativity regime causes valley polarized exciton-polaritons to
persist to room temperature, distinct from the vanishing polarization in bare
monolayers. Achieving polarization-sensitive polaritonic devices operating at
room temperature presents a pathway for manipulating novel valley degrees of
freedom in coherent states of light and matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00586</id><created>2017-02-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Godreche</keyname><forenames>Claude</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Satya N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schehr</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author></authors><title>Record statistics of a strongly correlated time series: random walks and
  L\'evy flights</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn math.PR physics.data-an q-fin.ST</categories><comments>64 pages, 14 figures. Topical review, submitted for publication in J.
  Phys. A</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 50, 333001 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa71c1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review recent advances on the record statistics of strongly correlated
time series, whose entries denote the positions of a random walk or a L\'evy
flight on a line. After a brief survey of the theory of records for independent
and identically distributed random variables, we focus on random walks. During
the last few years, it was indeed realized that random walks are a very useful
&quot;laboratory&quot; to test the effects of correlations on the record statistics. We
start with the simple one-dimensional random walk with symmetric jumps (both
continuous and discrete) and discuss in detail the statistics of the number of
records, as well as of the ages of the records, i.e., the lapses of time
between two successive record breaking events. Then we review the results that
were obtained for a wide variety of random walk models, including random walks
with a linear drift, continuous time random walks, constrained random walks
(like the random walk bridge) and the case of multiple independent random
walkers. Finally, we discuss further observables related to records, like the
record increments, as well as some questions raised by physical applications of
record statistics, like the effects of measurement error and noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.02082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.02082</id><created>2017-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ra</keyname><forenames>Young-Sik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacquard</keyname><forenames>Cl&#xe9;ment</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Adrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabre</keyname><forenames>Claude</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treps</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Tomography of a Mode-Tunable Coherent Single-Photon Subtractor</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 7, 031012 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.7.031012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-photon subtraction plays important roles in optical quantum
information processing as it provides a non-Gaussian characteristic in
continuous-variable quantum information. While the conventional way of
implementing single-photon subtraction based on a low-reflectance beam splitter
works properly for a single-mode quantum state, it is unsuitable for a
multimode quantum state because a single photon is subtracted from all multiple
modes without maintaining their mode coherence. Here we experimentally
implement and characterize a mode-tunable coherent single-photon subtractor
based on sum frequency generation. It can subtract a single photon exclusively
from one desired time-frequency mode of light or from a coherent superposition
of multiple time-frequency modes. To fully characterize the implemented
single-photon subtractions, we employ quantum process tomography based on
coherent states. The mode-tunable coherent single-photon subtractor will be an
essential element for realizing non-Gaussian quantum networks necessary to get
a quantum advantage in information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03251</id><created>2017-02-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Iff</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Yu-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lundt</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoll</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumann</keyname><forenames>Vasilij</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Substrate engineering for high quality emission of free and localized
  excitons from atomic monolayers in hybrid architectures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.000669</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Atomic monolayers represent a novel class of materials to study localized and
free excitons in two dimensions and to engineer optoelectronic devices based on
their significant optical response. Here, we investigate the role of the
substrate on the photoluminescense response of MoSe$_2$ and WSe$_2$ monolayers
exfoliated either on SiO$_2$ or epitaxially grown InGaP substrates. In the case
of MoSe$_2$, we observe a significant qualitative modification of the emission
spectrum, which is widely dominated by the trion resonance on InGaP substrates.
However, the effects of inhomogeneous broadening of the emission features are
strongly reduced. Even more strikingly, in sheets of WSe$_2$, we could
routinely observe emission lines from localized excitons with linewidths down
to the resolution limit of 70\,$\mu$ eV. This is in stark contrast to reference
samples featuring WSe$_2$ monolayers on SiO$_2$ surfaces, where the emission
spectra from localized defects are widely dominated by spectral diffusion and
blinking behaviour. Our experiment outlines the enormous potential of
III-V-monolayer hybrid architectures to obtain high quality emission signals
from atomic monolayers, which are straight forward to integrate into
nanophotonic and integrated optoelectronic devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03460</id><created>2017-02-11</created><updated>2017-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nili</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kheyri</keyname><forenames>Masoud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abazari</keyname><forenames>Javad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fahimniya</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naji</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Population splitting of rodlike swimmers in Couette flow</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 13, 4494 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a quantitative analysis on the response of a dilute active
suspension of self-propelled rods (swimmers) in a planar channel subjected to
an imposed shear flow. To best capture the salient features of shear-induced
effects, we consider the case of an imposed Couette flow, providing a constant
shear rate across the channel. We argue that the steady-state behavior of
swimmers can be understood in the light of a population splitting phenomenon,
occurring as the shear rate exceeds a certain threshold, initiating the
reversal of swimming direction for a finite fraction of swimmers from down- to
upstream or vice versa, depending on swimmer position within the channel.
Swimmers thus split into two distinct, statistically significant and oppositely
swimming majority and minority populations. The onset of population splitting
translates into a transition from a self-propulsion-dominated regime to a
shear-dominated regime, corresponding to a unimodal-to-bimodal change in the
probability distribution function of the swimmer orientation. We present a
phase diagram in terms of the swim and flow Peclet numbers showing the
separation of these two regimes by a discontinuous transition line. Our results
shed further light on the behavior of swimmers in a shear flow and provide an
explanation for the previously reported non-monotonic behavior of the mean,
near-wall, parallel-to-flow orientation of swimmers with increasing shear
strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.04950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.04950</id><created>2017-02-16</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deshpande</keyname><forenames>Abhishek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gopalkrishnan</keyname><forenames>Manoj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouldridge</keyname><forenames>Thomas E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Nick S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Designing the Optimal Bit: Balancing Energetic Cost, Speed and
  Reliability</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>37 pages, 22 figures, Section 4 shortened by moving proofs to the
  Supplementary Information, Section A.2 added to the Supplementary Information
  to introduce accuracy of erasure, small clarifications added throughout, To
  appear in the Proceedings of the Royal Society A: Mathematical, Physical and
  Engineering Sciences</comments><doi>10.1098/rspa.2017.0117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the technologically relevant costs of operating a reliable bit
that can be erased rapidly. We find that both erasing and reliability times are
non-monotonic in the underlying friction, leading to a trade-off between
erasing speed and bit reliability. Fast erasure is possible at the expense of
low reliability at moderate friction, and high reliability comes at the expense
of slow erasure in the underdamped and overdamped limits. Within a given class
of bit parameters and control strategies, we define &quot;optimal&quot; designs of bits
that meet the desired reliability and erasing time requirements with the lowest
operational work cost. We find that optimal designs always saturate the bound
on the erasing time requirement, but can exceed the required reliability time
if critically damped. The non-trivial geometry of the reliability and erasing
time-scales allows us to exclude large regions of parameter space as
sub-optimal. We find that optimal designs are either critically damped or close
to critical damping under the erasing procedure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.05271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.05271</id><created>2017-02-17</created><updated>2017-06-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Kruining</keyname><forenames>Koen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayrapetyan</keyname><forenames>Armen G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;tte</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rg B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonuniform currents and spins of relativistic electron vortices in a
  magnetic field</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages + supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 030401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.030401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a relativistic description of electron vortex beams in a
homogeneous magnetic field. Including spin from the beginning reveals that
spin-polarized electron vortex beams have a complicated azimuthal current
structure, containing small rings of counterrotating current between rings of
stronger corotating current. Contrary to many other problems in relativistic
quantum mechanics, there exists a set of vortex beams with exactly zero
spin-orbit mixing in the highly relativistic and nonparaxial regime. The well
defined phase structure of these beams is analogous to simpler scalar vortex
beams, owing to the protection by the Zeeman effect. For states that do show
spin-orbit mixing, the spin polarization across the beam is nonuniform
rendering the spin and orbital degrees of freedom inherently inseparable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.06717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.06717</id><created>2017-02-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Dheeraj Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-orbital model for CeB$_6$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>EPL 118 (2017) 47003</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/47003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a two-orbital tight-binding model with bases belonging to the
$\Gamma_8$ quartet. The model captures several characteristics of the
Fermiology unravelled by the recent angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopic
(ARPES) measurements on cerium hexaboride CeB$_6$ samples cleaved along
different high-symmetry crystallographic directions, which includes the
ellipsoid-like Fermi surfaces (FSs) with major axes directed along $\Gamma$-X.
We calculate various multipolar susceptibilities within the model and identify
the susceptibility that shows the strongest divergence in the presence of
standard onsite Coulomb interactions and discuss it's possible implication and
relevance with regard to the signature of strong ferromagnetic correlations
existent in various phases as shown by the recent experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.01750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.01750</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Choudhury</keyname><forenames>Sayantan</forenames></author></authors><title>COSMOS-$e'$- soft Higgsotic attractors</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>106 pages, 33 figures, 6 tables, Accepted for publication in European
  Physical Journal C</comments><report-no>TIFR/TH/16-50</report-no><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C77 (2017) no.7, 469</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-017-5001-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we have developed an elegant algorithm to study the
cosmological consequences from a huge class of quantum field theories (i.e.
superstring theory, supergravity, extra dimensional theory, modified gravity
etc.), which are equivalently described by soft attractors in the effective
field theory framework. In this description we have restricted our analysis for
two scalar fields - dilaton and Higgsotic fields minimally coupled with
Einstein gravity, which can be generalized for any arbitrary number of scalar
field contents with generalized non-canonical and non-minimal interactions. We
have explicitly used $R^2$ gravity, from which we have studied the attractor
and non-attractor phase by exactly computing two point, three point and four
point correlation functions from scalar fluctuations using In-In
(Schwinger-Keldysh) and $\delta {\cal N}$ formalism. We have also presented
theoretical bounds on the amplitude, tilt and running of the primordial power
spectrum, various shapes (equilateral, squeezed, folded kite or counter
collinear) of the amplitude as obtained from three and four point scalar
functions, which are consistent with observed data. Also the results from two
point tensor fluctuations and field excursion formula are explicitly presented
for attractor and non-attractor phase. Further, reheating constraints, scale
dependent behaviour of the couplings and the dynamical solution for the dilaton
and Higgsotic fields are also presented. New sets of consistency relations
between two, three and four point observables are also presented, which shows
significant deviation from canonical slow roll models. Additionally, three
possible theoretical proposals have presented to overcome the tachyonic
instability at the time of late time acceleration. Finally, we have also
provided the bulk interpretation from the three and four point scalar
correlation functions for completeness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02050</id><created>2017-03-06</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bradlyn</keyname><forenames>Barry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elcoro</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cano</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergniory</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aroyo</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernevig</keyname><forenames>B. Andrei</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological quantum chemistry</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>v1: 8 pages + 40 pages supplemenetary material. Previously submitted
  v2: ~ Published version. 11 pages + 79 pages supplementary material.
  Descriptions of the data used in this paper can be found in arXiv:1706.08529
  and arXiv:1706.09272. All data can be accessed via the Bilbao
  Crystallographic Server (http://cryst.ehu.es). Two additional papers
  elaborating on the general theory currently in prep</comments><journal-ref>Nature 547, 298--305 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nature23268</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The past decade's apparent success in predicting and experimentally
discovering distinct classes of topological insulators (TIs) and semimetals
masks a fundamental shortcoming: out of 200,000 stoichiometric compounds extant
in material databases, only several hundred of them are topologically
nontrivial. Are TIs that esoteric, or does this reflect a fundamental problem
with the current piecemeal approach to finding them? To address this, we
propose a new and complete electronic band theory that highlights the link
between topology and local chemical bonding, and combines this with the
conventional band theory of electrons. Topological Quantum Chemistry is a
description of the universal global properties of all possible band structures
and materials, comprised of a graph theoretical description of momentum space
and a dual group theoretical description in real space. We classify the
possible band structures for all 230 crystal symmetry groups that arise from
local atomic orbitals, and show which are topologically nontrivial. We show how
our topological band theory sheds new light on known TIs, and demonstrate the
power of our method to predict a plethora of new TIs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02858</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jun-Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Da-Chuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Li-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Zhuo-Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Polygamy relation for the R\'enyi-$\alpha$ entanglement of assistance in
  multi-qubit systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a new polygamy relation of multi-party quantum entanglement in terms
of R\'{e}nyi-$\alpha$ entanglement of assistance for $\left( {\sqrt 7 - 1}
\right)/2\leq\alpha \leq \left( {\sqrt 13 - 1} \right)/2$. This class of
polygamy inequality reduces to the polygamy inequality based on entanglement of
assistance since R\'{e}nyi-$\alpha$ entanglement is a generalization of
entanglement of formation. We further show that the polygamy inequality also
holds for the $\mu$th power of R\'{e}nyi-$\alpha$ entanglement of assistance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07398</id><created>2017-03-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Bischer</keyname><forenames>Ingolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grandou</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive loops in thermal SU(2) Yang-Mills theory: Radiative corrections
  to the pressure beyond two loops</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>39 pages, 22 figures, 8 tables</comments><msc-class>81T13, 81T28</msc-class><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A 32, 1750118 (2017) [39 pages]</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X17501184</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We device an efficient book-keeping of excluded energy-sign and
scattering-channel combinations for the loop four-momenta associated with
massive quasi-particles, circulating in (connected) bubble diagrams subject to
vertex constraints inherited from the thermal ground state. The according
radiative corrections modify the free thermal-quasiparticle pressure at one
loop. Increasing the loop order in two-particle irreducible (2PI) bubble
diagrams, we exemplarily demonstrate a suppressing effect of the vertex
constraints on the number of valid combinations. This increasingly strong
suppression gave rise to the conjecture in hep-th/0609033 that the loop
expansion would terminate at a finite order. Albeit the low-temperature
dependence of the 2PI 3-loop diagram complies with this behaviour, a thorough
analysis of the high-temperature situation reveals that the leading power in
temperature is thirteen such that this diagram dominates all lower loop orders
for sufficiently high temperatures. An all-loop-order resummation of 2PI
diagrams with dihedral symmetry is thus required, defining an extremely
well-bounded analytical continuation of the low-temperatures result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.07634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.07634</id><created>2017-03-22</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ozawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amo</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloch</keyname><forenames>Jacqueline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carusotto</keyname><forenames>Iacopo</forenames></author></authors><title>Klein tunneling in driven-dissipative photonic graphene</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 013813 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.013813</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate Klein tunneling processes in photonic artificial
graphene. Klein tunneling is a phenomenon in which a particle with Dirac
dispersion going through a potential step shows a characteristic angle- and
energy-dependent transmission. We consider a generic photonic system consisting
of a honeycomb-shaped array of sites with losses, illuminated by coherent
monochromatic light. We show how the transmission and reflection coefficients
can be obtained from the steady-state field profile of the driven-dissipative
system. Despite the presence of photonic losses, we recover the main scattering
features predicted by the general theory of Klein tunneling. Signatures of
negative refraction and the orientation dependence of the intervalley
scattering are also highlighted. Our results will stimulate the experimental
study of intricate transport phenomena using driven-dissipative photonic
simulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08669</id><created>2017-03-25</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Taniya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marrani</keyname><forenames>Alessio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tripathy</keyname><forenames>Prasanta K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric Black Holes and Freudenthal Duality</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>1+13 pages; v2 : two Refs. added, typo fixed</comments><report-no>DFPD/2017/TH/02</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of Freudenthal duality on supersymmetric extremal black
hole attractors in N = 2, D = 4 ungauged supergravity. Freudenthal duality acts
on the dyonic black hole charges as an anti-involution which keeps the black
hole entropy and the critical points of the effective black hole potential
invariant. We analyze its effect on the recently discovered distinct, mutually
exclusive phases of axionic supersymmetric black holes, related to the
existence of non-trivial involutory constant matrices. In particular, we
consider a supersymmetric D0-D4-D6 black hole and we explicitly Freudenthal-map
it to a supersymmetric D0-D2-D4-D6 black hole. We thus show that the charge
representation space of a supersymmetric D0-D2-D4-D6 black hole also contains
mutually exclusive domains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09099</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kureel</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malik</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>(Anti-)BRST and (Anti-)co-BRST Symmetries in 2D non-Abelian Gauge
  Theory: Some Novel Observations</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX file, 21 pages v2: LaTeX file, 27 pages, Sec. 5 and 6 expanded,
  A new Appendix added, typos fixed</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss about the Becchi-Rouet-Stora-Tyutin (BRST), anti-BRST and
(anti-)co-BRST symmetry transformations and derive their corresponding
conserved charges in the case of a two (1+1)-dimensional (2D) self-interacting
non-Abelian gauge theory (without any interaction with matter fields). We point
out a set of novel features that emerge out in the BRST and co-BRST analysis of
the above 2D gauge theory. The algebraic structures of the symmetry operators
(and corresponding conserved charges) and their relationship with the
cohomological operators of differential geometry are established, too. To be
more precise, we demonstrate the existence of a single Lagrangian density that
respects the continuous symmetries which obey proper algebraic structure of the
cohomological operators of differential geometry. We lay emphasis on the
existence and properties of the Curci-Ferrari (CF) type restrictions in the
context of (anti-)BRST and (anti-)co-BRST symmetry transformations and pinpoint
their differences and similarities. All the observations, connected with the
(anti-)co-BRST symmetries, are completely novel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10077</id><created>2017-03-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Libisch</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsman</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgd&#xf6;rfer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kresse</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Embedding for bulk systems using localized atomic orbitals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 147, 034110 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4993795</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an embedding approach for semiconductors and insulators based on
or- bital rotations in the space of occupied Kohn-Sham orbitals. We have
implemented our approach in the popular VASP software package. We demonstrate
its power for defect structures in silicon and polaron formation in titania,
two challenging cases for conventional Kohn-Sham density functional theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00895</id><created>2017-04-04</created><updated>2017-07-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aram</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Hasan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khorasani</keyname><forenames>Sina</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical wave evolution due to interaction with elastic wave in a
  phoxonic crystal slab waveguide</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. B (2017) 123:218</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-017-6792-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phoxonic crystal as a means of guiding and confining electromagnetic and
elastic waves has already attracted attentions. Lack of exact knowledge on how
these two types of waves interact inside this crystal and how electromagnetic
wave evolves through this interaction has increased this field complexity. Here
we explain how an elastic wave affects an electromagnetic wave through
photo-elasticity and interface displacement mechanisms in a phoxonic crystal
slab waveguide. We obtain a master equation which can describe electromagnetic
wave evolution. In this equation we define a coupling parameter and calculate
its value for different modes of electromagnetic and elastic waves and show it
vanishes for some types of modes . Finally we solve the master equation for a
typical phoxonic crystal slab waveguide and illustrate the electromagnetic wave
evolution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03565</id><created>2017-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>S. Amor dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiolhais</keyname><forenames>M. C. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frederix</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gon&#xe7;alo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gouveia</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onofre</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pease</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peixoto</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reigoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the CP nature of the Higgs coupling in $t{\bar t}h$ events at
  the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 013004 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.013004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The determination of the CP nature of the Higgs coupling to top quarks is
addressed in this paper, using $t{\bar t} h$ events produced in $\sqrt{s} = 13$
TeV proton-proton collisions at the LHC. Dileptonic final states are employed,
with two oppositely charged leptons and four jets, corresponding to the decays
$t\rightarrow bW^+ \rightarrow b \ell^+\nu_\ell$, $\bar{t}\rightarrow
\bar{b}W^- \rightarrow \bar{b} \ell^-\bar{\nu}_\ell$ and $h\rightarrow
b\bar{b}$. Pure scalar ($h=H$), pure pseudo-scalar ($h=A$) and CP-violating
Higgs boson signal events, generated with MadGraph5_aMC@NLO, are fully
reconstructed through a kinematic fit. We furthermore generate samples that
have both a CP-even and a CP-odd component in the $t \bar t h$ coupling in
order to probe the ratio of the two components. New angular distributions of
the decay products, as well as CP angular asymmetries, are explored in order to
separate the scalar from the pseudo-scalar components of the Higgs boson and
reduce the contribution from the dominant irreducible background, $t{\bar
t}b{\bar b}$. Significant differences between the angular distributions and
asymmetries are observed, even after the full kinematic fit reconstruction of
the events, allowing to define the best observables for a global fit of the
Higgs couplings parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03962</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03962</id><created>2017-04-12</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamada</keyname><forenames>Ken-ji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Mikoto</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical Cosmological Constant in Asymptotically Background Free Quantum
  Gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 2 figures, typo corrected, version appeared in PRD</comments><report-no>KEK-TH-1972</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 026010 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.026010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effective potential in renormalizable quantum gravity with a
single dimensionless conformal coupling without a Landau pole. In order to
describe a background-free dynamics at the Planck scale and beyond, the
conformal-factor field is quantized exactly in a nonperturbative manner. Since
this field does not receive renormalization, the field-independent constant in
the effective potential becomes itself invariant under the renormalization
group flow. That is to say, it gives the physical cosmological constant. We
explicitly calculate the physical cosmological constant at the one-loop level
in the Landau gauge. We find that it is given by a function of renormalized
quantities of the cosmological constant, the Planck mass and the coupling
constant, and it should be the observed value. It will give a new perspective
on the cosmological constant problem free from an ultraviolet cutoff.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03989</id><created>2017-04-13</created><updated>2017-06-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Rong-Gen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Xiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai-Qing</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of inhomogeneities on holographic mutual information and
  butterfly effect</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>a footnote is added and some typos are revised</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1707 (2017) 082</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)082</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of inhomogeneity, which is induced by the graviton mass
in massive gravity, on the mutual information and the chaotic behavior of a
2+1-dimensional field theory from the gauge/gravity duality. When the system is
near-homogeneous, the mutual information increases as the graviton mass grows.
However, when the system is far from homogeneity, the mutual information
decreases as the graviton mass increases. By adding the perturbations of energy
into the system, we investigate the dynamical mutual information in the shock
wave geometry. We find that the greater perturbations disrupt the mutual
information more rapidly, which resembles the butterfly effect in chaos theory.
Besides, the greater inhomogeneity reduces the dynamical mutual information
more quickly just as in the static case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06634</id><created>2017-04-21</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schmittfull</keyname><forenames>Marcel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldauf</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaldarriaga</keyname><forenames>Matias</forenames></author></authors><title>Iterative initial condition reconstruction</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>26 pages, 14 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 023505 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.023505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent developments in perturbative calculations of the
nonlinear evolution of large-scale structure, we present an iterative algorithm
to reconstruct the initial conditions in a given volume starting from the dark
matter distribution in real space. In our algorithm, objects are first moved
back iteratively along estimated potential gradients, with a progressively
reduced smoothing scale, until a nearly uniform catalog is obtained. The linear
initial density is then estimated as the divergence of the cumulative
displacement, with an optional second-order correction. This algorithm should
undo nonlinear effects up to one-loop order, including the higher-order
infrared resummation piece. We test the method using dark matter simulations in
real space. At redshift $z=0$, we find that after eight iterations the
reconstructed density is more than $95\%$ correlated with the initial density
at $k\le 0.35\; h\mathrm{Mpc}^{-1}$. The reconstruction also reduces the power
in the difference between reconstructed and initial fields by more than 2
orders of magnitude at $k\le 0.2\; h\mathrm{Mpc}^{-1}$, and it extends the
range of scales where the full broadband shape of the power spectrum matches
linear theory by a factor of 2-3. As a specific application, we consider
measurements of the baryonic acoustic oscillation (BAO) scale that can be
improved by reducing the degradation effects of large-scale flows. In our
idealized dark matter simulations, the method improves the BAO signal-to-noise
ratio by a factor of 2.7 at $z=0$ and by a factor of 2.5 at $z=0.6$, improving
standard BAO reconstruction by $70\%$ at $z=0$ and $30\%$ at $z=0.6$, and
matching the optimal BAO signal and signal-to-noise ratio of the linear density
in the same volume. For BAO, the iterative nature of the reconstruction is the
most important aspect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00292</id><created>2017-04-30</created><updated>2017-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bobev</keyname><forenames>Nikolay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bueno</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vreys</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments on Squashed-sphere Partition Functions</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>40 pages, 7 figures, 1 table; v2: additional comments and
  clarifications added, updated bibliography</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1707 (2017) 093</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the partition function of odd-dimensional conformal field theories
placed on spheres with a squashed metric. We establish that the round sphere
provides a local extremum for the free energy which, in general, is not a
global extremum. In addition, we show that the leading quadratic correction to
the free energy around this extremum is proportional to the coefficient, $C_T$,
determining the two-point function of the energy-momentum tensor in the CFT.
For three-dimensional CFTs, we compute explicitly this proportionality constant
for a class of squashing deformations which preserve an $SU(2)\times U(1)$
isometry group on the sphere. In addition, we evaluate the free energy as a
function of the squashing parameter for theories of free bosons, free fermions,
as well as CFTs holographically dual to Einstein gravity with a negative
cosmological constant. We observe that, after suitable normalization, the
dependence of the free energy on the squashing parameter for all these theories
is nearly universal for a large region of parameter space and is well
approximated by a simple quadratic function arising from holography. We
generalize our results to five-dimensional CFTs and, in this context, we also
study theories holographically dual to six-dimensional Gauss-Bonnet gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06777</id><created>2017-05-18</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Crowther</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Linnemann</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalizability, fundamentality and a final theory: The role of
  UV-completion in the search for quantum gravity</title><categories>physics.hist-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>Correction made to section 2.1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Principles are central to physical reasoning, particularly in the search for
a theory of quantum gravity (QG), where novel empirical data is lacking. One
principle widely adopted in the search for QG is UV completion: the idea that a
theory should (formally) hold up to all possible high energies. We
argue---\textit{contra} standard scientific practice---that UV-completion is
poorly-motivated as a guiding principle in theory-construction, and cannot be
used as a criterion of theory-justification in the search for QG. For this, we
explore the reasons for expecting, or desiring, a UV-complete theory, as well
as analyse how UV completion is used, and how it should be used, in various
specific approaches to QG.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.08315</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.08315</id><created>2017-05-22</created><updated>2017-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET and UNMdP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Origin of time before inflation from a topological phase transition</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Version accepted in Physics of the Dark Universe. arXiv admin note:
  substantial text overlap with arXiv:1610.07979</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the origin of the universe (or pre-inflation) by suggesting that the
primordial space-time in the universe suffered a global topological phase
transition, from a 4D Euclidean manifold to an asymptotic 4D hyperbolic one. We
introduce a complex time, $\tau$, such that its real part becomes dominant
after started the topological phase transition. Before the big bang, $\tau$ is
a space-like coordinate, so that can be considered as a reversal variable.
After the phase transition is converted in a causal variable. The formalism
solves in a natural manner the quantum to classical transition of the
geometrical relativistic quantum fluctuations: $\sigma$, which has a geometric
origin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00049</id><created>2017-05-31</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Cong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Qian</forenames></author></authors><title>Rashba torque beyond the Boltzmann regime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035423 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035423</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study spin torques induced by Rashba spin-orbit coupling in
two-dimensional ferromagnets under the good-metal condition
$\epsilon_{F}\tau/\hbar\gg1$ ($\epsilon_{F}$ the Fermi energy, $\tau$ the
electron lifetime) by employing the Kubo formula. We find that, in the presence
of spin-dependent disorder the Rashba torque changes greatly as the system
evolves out of the weak disorder limit where $\hbar/\tau$ is much smaller than
any intrinsic energy scale characterizing the multiband structure. The
antidamping-like component of Rashba torque can be comparable to and larger
than the field-like one out of the weak disorder limit. The semiclassical
Boltzmann theory produces the same results as microscopic linear response
calculations only in the weak disorder limit. Our analysis indicates that rich
behaviors of various nonequilibrium phenomena beyond the Boltzmann theory may
also be present even when $\epsilon_{F}\tau/\hbar\gg1$ in multiband systems
where $\epsilon_{F}$ is not the unique intrinsic energy scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02339</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02339</id><created>2017-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>J. -Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sales</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Susner</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Flux growth in a horizontal configuration: an analogue to vapor
  transport growth</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Materials 1, 023402 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.023402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Flux growth of single crystals is normally performed in a vertical
configuration with an upright refractory container holding the flux melt. At
high temperatures, flux dissolves the charge forming a homogeneous solution
before nucleation and growth of crystals take place under proper
supersaturation generated by cooling or evaporating the flux. In this work, we
report flux growth in a horizontal configuration with a temperature gradient
along the horizontal axis: a liquid transport growth analogous to the vapor
transport technique. In a typical liquid transport growth, the charge is kept
at the hot end of the refractory container and the flux melt dissolves the
charge and transfers it to the cold end. Once the concentration of charge is
above the solubility limit at the cold end, the thermodynamically stable phase
nucleates and grows. Compared to the vertical flux growth, the liquid transport
growth can provide a large quantity of crystals in a single growth since the
charge/flux ratio is not limited by the solubility limit at the growth
temperature. This technique is complementary to the vertical flux growth and
can be considered when a large amount of crystals are needed but the yield from
the conventional vertical flux growth is limited. We applied this technique to
the growth of IrSb$_3$, Mo$_3$Sb$_7$, MnBi from self flux, and the growth of
FeSe, CrTe$_3$, NiPSe$_3$, FePSe$_3$, and InCuP$_2$S$_6$ from a halide flux.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.04625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.04625</id><created>2017-06-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Sanjib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grundland</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of soliton surfaces associated with integrable
  $\mathbb{C}P^{N-1}$ sigma models</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Math. Theor. 50 (2017) 335201</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/aa7953</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate certain properties of $\mathfrak{su}(N)$-valued
two-dimensional soliton surfaces associated with the integrable
$\mathbb{C}P^{N-1}$ sigma models constructed by the orthogonal rank-one
Hermitian projectors, which are defined on the two-dimensional Riemann sphere
with finite action functional. Several new properties of the projectors mapping
onto one-dimensional subspaces as well as their relations with three mutually
different immersion formulas, namely, the generalized Weierstrass, Sym-Tafel
and Fokas-Gel'fand have been discussed in detail. Explicit connections among
these three surfaces are also established by purely analytical descriptions
and, it is demonstrated that the three immersion formulas actually correspond
to the single surface parametrized by some specific conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.06227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.06227</id><created>2017-06-19</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;raud</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nonaka</keyname><forenames>Andy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>John B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donev</keyname><forenames>Aleksandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>Alejandro L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fluctuation-enhanced electric conductivity in electrolyte solutions</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter we analyze the effects of an externally applied electric field
on thermal fluctuations for a fluid containing charged species. We show in
particular that the fluctuating Poisson-Nernst-Planck equations for charged
multispecies diffusion coupled with the fluctuating fluid momentum equation,
result in enhanced charge transport. Although this transport is advective in
nature, it can macroscopically be represented as electrodiffusion with
renormalized electric conductivity. We calculate the renormalized electric
conductivity by deriving and integrating the structure factor coefficients of
the fluctuating quantities and show that the renormalized electric conductivity
and diffusion coefficients are consistent although they originate from
different noise terms. In addition, the fluctuating hydrodynamics approach
recovers the electrophoretic and relaxation corrections obtained by
Debye-Huckel-Onsager theory, and provides a quantitative theory that predicts a
non-zero cross-diffusion Maxwell-Stefan coefficient that agrees well with
experimental measurements. Finally, we show that strong applied electric fields
result in anisotropically enhanced velocity fluctuations and reduced
fluctuations of salt concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07100</id><created>2017-06-21</created><updated>2017-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kravchenko</keyname><forenames>Igor V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kravchenko</keyname><forenames>Vladislav V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torba</keyname><forenames>Sergii M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solution of parabolic free boundary problems using transmuted heat
  polynomials</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.NA</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, contact details updated</comments><msc-class>34A25, 34L40, 35A22, 35A35, 35K05, 35K10, 35R35, 65M70, 65M80, 65N35</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A numerical method for free boundary problems for the equation \[
u_{xx}-q(x)u=u_t \] is proposed. The method is based on recent results from
transmutation operators theory allowing one to construct efficiently a complete
system of solutions for this equation generalizing the system of heat
polynomials. The corresponding implementation algorithm is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.07455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.07455</id><created>2017-06-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Panotopoulos</keyname><forenames>Grigoris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rincon</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author></authors><title>Greybody factors for a minimally coupled massless scalar field in
  Einstein-Born-Infeld dilaton spacetime</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 8 figures. Version accepted for publication in PRD</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.025009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analyzed in detail the propagation of a minimally coupled massless
scalar field in the gravitational background of a four-dimensional
Einstein-Born-Infeld dilaton charged black hole. We have obtained analytical
expressions for the absorption cross section as well as for the decay rate for
the scalar field in the aforementioned spacetime, and we have shown graphically
its behavior for different values of the free parameters of the theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00673</id><created>2017-07-03</created><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Loureiro</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrede</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liddick</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowe</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chipps</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McNeice</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naqvi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pain</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokop</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quinn</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakstrup</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santia</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwartz</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shanab</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spyrou</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiagalingam</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Confirmation of the isomeric state in 26P</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review C 96, 014306 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.96.014306</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the independent experimental confirmation of an isomeric state in
the proton drip-line nucleus $^{26}$P. The ${\gamma}$-ray energy and half-life
determined are 164.4 $\pm$ 0.3 (sys) $\pm$ 0.2 (stat) keV and 104 $\pm$ 14 ns,
respectively, which are in agreement with the previously reported values. These
values are used to set a semi-empirical limit on the proton separation energy
of $^{26}$P, with the conclusion that it can be bound or unbound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.01345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.01345</id><created>2017-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bufalo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Upadhyay</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion Mass Bound in Very Special Relativity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages; to appear in PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 772, 420 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.06.070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we propose a very special relativity (VSR)-inspired description
of the axion electrodynamics. This proposal is based upon the construction of a
proper study of the SIM$(2)$--VSR gauge-symmetry. It is shown that the VSR
nonlocal effects give a health departure from the usual axion field theory. The
axionic classical dynamics is analysed in full detail, first by a discussion of
its solution in the presence of an external magnetic field. Next, we compute
photon-axion transition in VSR scenario by means of Primakoff interaction,
showing the change of a linearly polarized light to a circular one. Afterwards,
duality symmetry is discussed in the VSR framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03121</id><created>2017-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xiaolong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mi</keyname><forenames>Ligong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Lang</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Luis C.</forenames></author></authors><title>VLBA 24 and 43 GHz observations of massive binary black hole candidate
  PKS 1155+251</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, accepted by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1743</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  PKS 1155+251 is a radio-loud quasar source at z=0.203. Observations using
very long baseline interferometry (VLBI) at ~2, 5, 8 and 15 GHz show that the
structure of the radio source is quite complicated on parsec scales and that
the outer hot spots are apparently undergoing a significant contraction.
Because these results cannot be fully explained based on the compact symmetric
object (CSO) scenario with a radio core located between the northern and
southern complexes, we made observations with the Very Long Baseline Array
(VLBA) at 24 and 43 GHz to search for compact substructures and alternative
interpretations. The results show that the radio core revealed in the previous
VLBI observations remains compact with a flat spectrum in our
sub-milli-arcsecond--resolution images; the northern lobe emission becomes
faint at 24 GHz and is mostly resolving out at 43 GHz; the southern complex is
more bright but has been resolved into the brightest southern-end (S1) and jet
or tail alike components westwards. Explaining the southern components aligned
westward with a standard CSO scenario alone remains a challenge. As for the
flatter spectral index of the southern-end component S1 between 24 and 43 GHz
in our observations and the significant 15 GHz VLBA flux variability of S1, an
alternative scenario is that the southern complex may be powered by a secondary
black hole residing at S1. But more sensitive and high-resolution VLBI
monitoring is required to discriminate the CSO and the binary black hole
scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03209</id><created>2017-07-11</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shandilya</keyname><forenames>Prasoon K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>Prasanta K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A general inseparability criterion for non-Gaussian states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>3 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have derived a general separability criterion for a class of two mode
non-Gaussian continuous variable systems, obtained earlier using PPT, violation
of which provides sufficient condition for entanglement. It has been obtained
by utilizing the Cauchy-Schwarz inequality and from the basic definition of
separable states. This criterion coincides with the work of Agarwal and Biswas
[4] which involved inequality involving higher order correlation, for testing
entanglement in non-Gaussian states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04249</id><created>2017-07-13</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>Eric P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Nilanjana</forenames></author></authors><title>Tight uniform continuity bound for a family of entropies</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math-ph math.IT math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures. v2: added missing definition of Tsallis entropy,
  corrected minor typos</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a tight uniform continuity bound for a family of entropies which
includes the von Neumann entropy, the Tsallis entropy and the $\alpha$-R\'enyi
entropy, $S_\alpha$, for $\alpha\in (0,1)$. We establish necessary and
sufficient conditions for equality in the continuity bound and prove that these
conditions are the same for every member of the family. Our result builds on
recent work in which we constructed a state which was majorized by every state
in a neighbourhood ($\varepsilon$-ball) of a given state, and thus was the
minimal state in majorization order in the $\varepsilon$-ball. This minimal
state satisfies a particular semigroup property, which we exploit to prove our
bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04975</id><created>2017-07-16</created><updated>2017-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baraglia</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Zhenxi</forenames></author></authors><title>Special K\&quot;ahler geometry of the Hitchin system and topological
  recursion</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages</comments><msc-class>Primary 53C26, 14H15, Secondary 14H60, 14H81</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the special K\&quot;ahler geometry of the base of the Hitchin
integrable system in terms of spectral curves and topological recursion. The
Taylor expansion of the special K\&quot;ahler metric about any point in the base may
be computed by integrating the $g = 0$ Eynard-Orantin invariants of the
corresponding spectral curve over cycles. In particular, we show that the
Donagi-Markman cubic is computed by the invariant $W^{(0)}_3$. We use
topological recursion to go one step beyond this and compute the symmetric
quartic of second derivatives of the period matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05515</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Grosjean</keyname><forenames>Galien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandewalle</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetocapillary self-assemblies: locomotion and micromanipulation along
  a liquid interface</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft nlin.AO</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures review paper</comments><doi>10.1016/j.cis.2017.07.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents an overview and discussion of magnetocapillary
self-assemblies. New results are presented, in particular concerning the
possible development of future applications. These self-organizing structures
possess the notable ability to move along an interface when powered by an
oscillatory, uniform magnetic field. The system is constructed as follows. Soft
magnetic particles are placed on a liquid interface, and submitted to a
magnetic induction field. An attractive force due to the curvature of the
interface around the particles competes with an interaction between magnetic
dipoles. Ordered structures can spontaneously emerge from these conditions.
Furthermore, time-dependent magnetic fields can produce a wide range of dynamic
behaviours, including non-time-reversible deformation sequences that produce
translational motion at low Reynolds number. In other words, due to a
spontaneous breaking of time-reversal symmetry, the assembly can turn into a
surface microswimmer. Trajectories have been shown to be precisely
controllable. As a consequence, this system offers a way to produce microrobots
able to perform different tasks. This is illustrated in this paper by the
capture, transport and release of a floating cargo, and the controlled mixing
of fluids at low Reynolds number.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05686</id><created>2017-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ilhan</keyname><forenames>Onur Alp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bulut</keyname><forenames>Hasan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sulaiman</keyname><forenames>Tukur A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baskonus</keyname><forenames>Haci Mehmet</forenames></author></authors><title>On the new wave behavior to the longitudinal wave quation in a
  magneto-electro-elastic circular rod</title><categories>nlin.SI hep-th math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>18 figures,13 pages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  With the aid of the symbolic computations software; Wolfram Mathematica 9,
the powerful sine-Gordon expansion method is used in examining the analytical
solution of the longitudinal wave equation in a magneto-electro-elastic
circular rod. Sine-Gordon expansion method is based on the well-known
sine-Gordon equation and a wave transformation. The longitudinal wave equation
is an equation that arises in mathematical physics with dispersion caused by
the transverse Poisson's effect in a magneto-electro-elastic circular rod. We
successfully get some solutions with the complex, trigonometric and hyperbolic
function structure. We present the numerical simulations of all the obtained
solutions by choosing appropriate values of the parameters. We give the
physical meanings of some of the obtained analytical solutions which
significantly explain some practical physical problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06229</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Nasrollahebrahim</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Ebrahim Haji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abareshi</keyname><forenames>Bagher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghotbi</keyname><forenames>Cyrus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taghikhani</keyname><forenames>Vahid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amir</keyname><forenames>Hossein</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of Six Imidazolium-Based Ionic Liquids as Thermo-Kinetic
  Inhibitors for Methane Hydrate by Molecular Dynamics Simulation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>National Iranian Conference on Gas Hydrate (NICGH) Jul 2013, Tehran,
  Iran. 2 (2013)</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thermo-kinetic inhibition mechanism of six imidazolium-based ionic
liquids (ILs) on methane clathrate hydrate formation and growth is studied in
this work using classical molecular dynamics (MD) simulation. The ionic liquids
investigated include
1-(2,3-dihydroxypropyl)-3-methylimidazoliumbis(fluorosulfonyl)imide
([C3(OH)2mim][f2N]), 1-(2-hydroxyethyl)-3-methylimidazolium
bis(fluorosulfonyl)imide ([C2OHmim][f2N]), 1-ethyl-3-methylimidazolium
tetrafluoroborate ([C2mim][BF4]), 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium tetrafluoroborate
([C4mim][BF4]), 1-butyl-3-methylimidazolium acetate ([C4mim][OAc]) and
1-ethyl-3-methylimidazolium ethylsulfate ([C2mim][EtSO4]). Simulations showed
that [C2OHmim][f2N] and [C3(OH)2mim][f2N] are strongly hydrated compared to
other ILs because of hydrogen bonding between OH groups of the cation and water
molecules. They also exhibit high diffusion rates towards crystal surface and
bond to it through strong intermolecular interactions. As a result, these two
ILs are stronger thermo-kinetic inhibitors for formation and growth of methane
hydrates compared to other ILs studied in this work as well as conventional
inhibitors like methanol and NaCl. The simulations also revealed that cations
of [C3(OH)2mim][f2N] and [C2OHmim][f2N] show that the presence of ions near the
hydrate crystal causes hindrance for water and guest molecules adsorbing on the
hydrate surface, which inhibits the growth of hydrate crystals. In addition, it
is shown that [C3(OH)2mim][f2N] and [C2OHmim][f2N] are more likely to inhibit
hydrate formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06232</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Daddi-Moussa-Ider</keyname><forenames>Abdallah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisicki</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gekle</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Slow rotation of a spherical particle inside an elastic tube</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures and 107 references. Revised manuscript
  resubmitted to Acta Mech</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present an analytical calculation of the rotational
mobility functions of a particle rotating on the centerline of an elastic
cylindrical tube whose membrane exhibits resistance towards shearing and
bending. We find that the correction to the particle rotational mobility about
the cylinder axis depends solely on membrane shearing properties while both
shearing and bending manifest themselves for the rotational mobility about an
axis perpendicular to the cylinder axis. In the quasi-steady limit of vanishing
frequency, the particle rotational mobility nearby a no-slip rigid cylinder is
recovered only if the membrane possesses a non-vanishing resistance towards
shearing. We further show that for the asymmetric rotation along the cylinder
radial axis, a coupling between shearing and bending exists. Our analytical
predictions are compared and validated with corresponding boundary integral
simulations where a very good agreement is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06251</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Cardona</keyname><forenames>Jorge E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapitanski</keyname><forenames>Lev</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurable process selection theorem and non-autonomous inclusions</title><categories>math.DS math.AP math.CA nlin.CD</categories><msc-class>28B20, 54C60, 60J25, 35A02</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A semi-process is an analog of the semi-flow for non-autonomous differential
equations or inclusions. We prove an abstract result on the existence of
measurable semi-processes in the situations where there is no uniqueness. Also,
we allow solutions to blow up in finite time and then obtain local
semi-processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06256</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Rybin</keyname><forenames>Mikhail V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zherzdev</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feoktistov</keyname><forenames>Nikolay A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pevtsov</keyname><forenames>Alexander B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of photonic crystal stop-band on photoluminescence of
  $a$-Si$_{1-x}$C$_x$:H</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B. 95, 165118 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.165118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Effects associated with the change in the local density of photonic states in
a periodic structure based on alternating \textit{a}-Si$_{1-x}$C$_x$:H and
\textit{a}-SiO$_2$ amorphous layers forming a one-dimensional (1D) photonic
crystal have been analyzed. The use of \textit{a}-Si$_{1-x}$C$_x$:H as the
emitting material made it possible to examine the transformation of the
photoluminescence spectrum contour that is comparable in width with the
photonic stop-band. It was experimentally demonstrated that the emission is
enhanced and suppressed in the vicinity of the stop-band. The relative
intensities of the luminescence peaks at different edges of the stop-band vary
with the detuning of the stop-band position and photoluminescence peak of a
single \textit{a}-Si$_{1-x}$C$_x$:H film. The Purcell effect in the system
under consideration was theoretically described by the method in which the
local density of photonic states is calculated in terms of a 1D model. %A good
agreement was obtained between the experimentally measured and calculated
spectra. It was shown that the specific part of local density of states
substantially increases at the long-wavelength (low-frequency) edge of the
stop-band of a 1D photonic crystal as a result of the predominant localization
of the electric field of the light wave in the spatial regions of
\textit{a}-Si$_{1-x}$C$_x$:H which have a higher relative permittivity as
compared with \textit{a}-SiO$_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06258</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Arteaga-Sierra</keyname><forenames>Francisco R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antikainen</keyname><forenames>Aku</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Govind P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lossless Suppression and Enhancement of Soliton Self-Frequency Shifts</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Soliton self-frequency shifts (SSFS) can be suppressed in optical fibers
through spectral recoil, but this process leads to losses through continuous
transfer of energy to a dispersive wave. We demonstrate a novel way to alter
the strength of SSFS in photonic crystal fibers through a frequency-dependent
nonlinear parameter $\gamma(\omega)$. Our numerical simulations show both
suppression and enhancement of SSFS depending on the sign of nonlinear slope. A
large enough positive value of this slope can lead to total suppression of
SSFS, without spectral recoil and without energy transfer to a resonant
dispersive wave. Numerical simulations are supported by mathematical
predictions based on the moment method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06259</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Harnad</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortmann</keyname><forenames>Janosch</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero-temperature limit of quantum weighted Hurwitz numbers</title><categories>math-ph math.CO math.MP math.PR nlin.SI</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><report-no>CRM-3361 (2017)</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The partition function for quantum weighted double Hurwitz numbers can be
interpreted in terms of the energy distribution of a quantum Bose gas with
vanishing fugacity. We compute the leading term of the partition function and
the quantum weighted Hurwitz numbers in the zero temperature limit $T
\rightarrow 0$, as well as the next order corrections. The leading term is
shown to reproduce the case of uniformly weighted Hurwitz numbers of Belyi
curves. In particular, the KP or Toda $\tau$-function serving as generating
function for the quantum Hurwitz numbers is shown in the limit to give the one
for Belyi curves and, with suitable scaling, the same holds true for the
partition function, the weights and the expectations of Hurwitz numbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06280</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yangyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dostart</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Milo&#x161; A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Toward Microphononic Circuits on Chip: An Evaluation of Components based
  on High-Contrast Evanescent Confinement of Acoustic Waves</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the prospects for micron-scale acoustic wave components and
circuits on chip in solid planar structures that do not require suspension. We
leverage evanescent guiding of acoustic waves by high slowness contrast
materials readily available in silicon complementary metal-oxide semiconductor
(CMOS) processes. High slowness contrast provides strong confinement of GHz
frequency acoustic fields in micron-scale structures. We address the
fundamental implications of intrinsic material and radiation losses on
operating frequency, bandwidth, device size and as a result practicality of
multi-element microphononic circuits based on solid embedded waveguides. We
show that a family of acoustic components based on evanescently guided acoustic
waves, including waveguide bends, evanescent couplers, Y-splitters, and
acoustic-wave microring resonators, can be realized in compact, micron-scale
structures, and provide basic scaling and performance arguments for these
components based on material properties and simulations. We further find that
wave propagation losses are expected to permit high quality factor (Q),
narrowband resonators and propagation lengths allowing delay lines and the
coupling or cascading of multiple components to form functional circuits, of
potential utility in guided acoustic signal processing on chip. We also address
and simulate bends and radiation loss, providing insight into routing and
resonators. Such circuits could be monolithically integrated with electronic
and photonic circuits on a single chip with expanded capabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06290</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ugol'kova</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Artamonov</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimanovskaya</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruevich</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burhonov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egamberdiev</keyname><forenames>Sh.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metlova</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of the Nuclear Activity of the Seyfert Galaxy NGC 7469 over the
  Period of Observations 2008-2014</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>14 pages,6 figures; updated version of the paper published in
  Astronomy Letters, April 2017 issue; colored figures</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, v.43, no.4, pp.233-240, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773717040089</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results of multicolor UBVRI observations of the type 1 Seyfert
galaxy (SyG 1) NGC 7469 carried out at the 1.5-meter telescope of the Maidanak
Observatory (Uzbekistan) in 2008-2014. Analysis of the light curves indicates
the presence of another slow flare of a long-term variability in 2009-2014 with
a maximum in 2011-2012. We investigate properties of the long-term variability
in 2009-2014, present (U-B)-(B-V) color diagrams for maxima and minima of NGC
7469 nuclear variability using various apertures and compare them with the
black-body gas radiation which models the accretion disk radiation. Color-index
measurements shows that the color becomes bluer at maximum brightness,
indicating a higher temperature of the accretion disk. We have analysed the
relation of X-ray and optical variability of NGC 7469 in 2008 and 2009 in
comparison with the activity minimum in 2003. In 2008 the correlation
coefficient between the X-ray and optical radiation is close to 0.5. Such poor
correlation can be explained by the influence of an SN 1a explosion in close
proximity to the nucleus of NGC 7469. The SN manifests itself in the optical
band but does not affect the X-ray variability pattern. Comparison of the
variability data in 2009 reveals a good correlation between the optical (U
band) and the X-ray (7-10 keV) variability with the correlation coefficient of
about 0.93. The correlation coefficient and the lag depend on the wavelength in
the optical and X-ray bands. The lag between the X-ray and optical fluxes in
2009 is 2-4 days. In 2003 the lag is almost zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06305</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Cisneros</keyname><forenames>Cecilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>Travis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baluyot</keyname><forenames>Noel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tapavicza</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of tachysterol in vitamin D photosynthesis - A non-adiabatic
  molecular dynamics study</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physical Chemistry Chemical Physics 19 (8), 5763-5777 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP08064B</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To investigate the role of tachysterol in the photophysical/chemical
regulation of vitamin D photosynthesis, we studied its electronic absorption
properties and excited state dynamics using time-dependent density functional
theory (TDDFT), coupled cluster theory (CC2), and non-adiabatic molecular
dynamics. In excellent agreement with experiments, the simulated electronic
spectrum shows a broad absorption band covering the spectra of the other
vitamin D photoisomers. The broad band stems from the spectral overlap of four
different ground state rotamers. After photoexcitation, the first excited
singlet state (S1) decays within 882 fs. The S1 dynamics is characterized by a
strong twisting of the central double bond. 96% of all trajectories relax
without chemical transformation to the ground state. In 2.3 % of the
trajectories we observed [1,5]-sigmatropic hydrogen shift forming the partly
deconjugated toxisterol D1. 1.4 % previtamin D formation is observed via
hula-twist double bond isomerization. We find a strong dependence between
photoreactivity and dihedral angle conformation: hydrogen shift only occurs in
cEc and cEt rotamers and double bond isomerization occurs mainly in cEc
rotamers. Our study confirms the hypothesis that cEc rotamers are more prone to
previtamin D formation than other isomers. We also observe the formation of a
cyclobutene-toxisterol in the hot ground state (0.7 %). Due to its strong
absorption and unreactive behavior, tachysterol acts mainly as a sun shield
suppressing previtamin D formation. Tachysterol shows stronger toxisterol
formation than previtamin D. Absorption of low energy UV light by the cEc
rotamer can lead to previtamin D formation. Our study reinforces a recent
hypothesis that tachysterol can act as a previtamin D source when only low
energy ultraviolet light is available, as it is the case in winter or in the
morning and evening hours of the day.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06338</id><created>2017-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>H&#xe4;se</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreisbeck</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Al&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Machine Learning for Quantum Dynamics: Deep Learning of Excitation
  Energy Transfer Properties</title><categories>physics.chem-ph stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding the relationship between the structure of light-harvesting
systems and their excitation energy transfer properties is of fundamental
importance in many applications including the development of next generation
photovoltaics. Natural light harvesting in photosynthesis shows remarkable
excitation energy transfer properties, which suggests that pigment-protein
complexes could serve as blueprints for the design of nature inspired devices.
Mechanistic insights into energy transport dynamics can be gained by leveraging
numerically involved propagation schemes such as the hierarchical equations of
motion (HEOM). Solving these equations, however, is computationally costly due
to the adverse scaling with the number of pigments. Therefore virtual
high-throughput screening, which has become a powerful tool in material
discovery, is less readily applicable for the search of novel excitonic
devices. We propose the use of artificial neural networks to bypass the
computational limitations of established techniques for exploring the
structure-dynamics relation in excitonic systems. Once trained, our neural
networks reduce computational costs by several orders of magnitudes. Our
predicted transfer times and transfer efficiencies exhibit similar or even
higher accuracies than frequently used approximate methods such as secular
Redfield theory
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06392</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Maamache</keyname><forenames>Mustapha</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Unitary evolution of quantum time-dependent non-Hermitian systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>09pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a new perspective on non-Hermitian evolution in quantum mechanics
by emphasizing the same method as in the Hermitian quantum evolution. We first
give a precise description of the non unitary evolution, and collecting the
basic results around it and postulating the norm preserving. This cautionary
postulate imposing that the time evolution of a non Hermitian quantum system
preserves the inner products between the associated states must not be read
naively. We also give an example showing that the solutions of time-dependent
non Hermitian Hamiltonian systems given by a linear combination of SU(1,1) and
SU(2) are obtained thanks to time-dependent non-unitary transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06453</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruijl</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vermaseren</keyname><forenames>Jos</forenames></author></authors><title>FORM version 4.2</title><categories>hep-ph cs.SC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce FORM 4.2, a new minor release of the symbolic manipulation
toolkit. We demonstrate several new features, such as a new pattern matching
option, new output optimization, and automatic expansion of rational functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06481</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wie&#x15b;niak</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author></authors><title>The entire history of a photon</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the most basic mathematical tools, I present the full analysis of the
experiment decribed in [A. Danan, D. Farfurnik, S. Bar-Ad, and L. Vaidman, {\em
Phys. Rev. Lett.} {\bf 111}, 240402 (2013)]. First, I confirm that the data
presented therein are in full agreement with the standard quantum mechanics. I
then show other symptoms of presence of photons at all mirrors in the setup. I
then analytically explain both the absence of peaks a Readers of [A. Danan, D.
Farfurnik, S. Bar-Ad, and L. Vaidman, {\em Phys. Rev. Lett.} {\bf 111}, 240402
(2013)] are made to expect and presence of those not discussed in the
Reference.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06492</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Fujino</keyname><forenames>Toru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Network Structure on the Performance of a Modeled Traffic
  Network under Drivers' Bounded Rationality</title><categories>cs.MA nlin.AO</categories><comments>Submitted to Physica A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a minority route choice game to investigate the effect of the
network structure on traffic network performance under the assumption of
drivers' bounded rationality. We investigate ring-and-hub topologies to capture
the nature of traffic networks in cities, and employ a minority game-based
inductive learning process to model the characteristic behavior under the route
choice scenario. Through numerical experiments, we find that topological
changes in traffic networks induce a phase transition from an uncongested phase
to a congested phase. Understanding this phase transition is helpful in
planning new traffic networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06501</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Vardi</keyname><forenames>Roni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldental</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheinin</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardi</keyname><forenames>Shira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanter</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author></authors><title>Fast Reversible Learning based on Neurons functioning as Anisotropic
  Multiplex Hubs</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL 118 (2017) 46002</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/46002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neural networks are composed of neurons and synapses, which are responsible
for learning in a slow adaptive dynamical process. Here we experimentally show
that neurons act like independent anisotropic multiplex hubs, which relay and
mute incoming signals following their input directions. Theoretically, the
observed information routing enriches the computational capabilities of neurons
by allowing, for instance, equalization among different information routes in
the network, as well as high-frequency transmission of complex time-dependent
signals constructed via several parallel routes. In addition, this kind of hubs
adaptively eliminate very noisy neurons from the dynamics of the network,
preventing masking of information transmission. The timescales for these
features are several seconds at most, as opposed to the imprint of information
by the synaptic plasticity, a process which exceeds minutes. Results open the
horizon to the understanding of fast and adaptive learning realities in higher
cognitive functionalities of the brain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06515</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06515</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Tapsanit</keyname><forenames>Piyawath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruttanapun</keyname><forenames>Chesta</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-analytical solutions of wide-angle and broadband insulator-metal
  grating-metal metamaterial absorber in visible to near-infrared bands</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A metamaterial absorber converts solar radiation into heat for applications
in thermoelectric generators and solar thermophotovoltaics. A metamaterial
absorber typically consists of metallic parts separated by an insulator layer
which does not allow the total heat extraction via direct heat conduction.
Here, we propose wide-angle and broadband metamaterial absorber comprising an
insulator layer, metal grating, and metal back plane (IMM) that allows the
total heat extraction via direct heat conduction. We have formulated the
quasi-analytical solution (QANS) of the IMM-absorber by applying the
coupled-mode analysis with new technique for taking finite dielectric constant
of a metal into account. The QANS are consistent with finite difference time
domain (FDTD) simulation. We fine that the IMM-absorbers made by tungsten and
silver metals give the best and worse average absorbance over the wavelength
range 400-1,200 nm, respectively. The best IMM-absorber shows the optimized
average absorbance 96.2%. The broadband absorption results from the excitations
of insulator-metal waveguide resonance and slit waveguide resonance that are
insensitive to incident angles. The averaged absorbance is above 90.0% for the
incident angles 0-66 degree. The IMM-absorber performance may be enhanced by
using metal rod array with engineered supperlattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06538</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Mogull</keyname><forenames>Gustav</forenames></author></authors><title>A Tale of Two Loops: Simplifying All-Plus Yang-Mills Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>PhD thesis, University of Edinburgh, July 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pure Yang-Mills amplitudes with all external gluons carrying positive
helicity, known as all-plus amplitudes, have an especially simple structure.
The tree amplitudes vanish and, up to at least two loops, the loop-level
amplitudes are related to those of $\mathcal{N}=4$ super-Yang-Mills (SYM)
theory. This makes all-plus amplitudes a useful testing ground for new methods
of simplifying more general classes of amplitudes. In this thesis we consider
three new approaches, focusing on the structure before integration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06539</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sardi</keyname><forenames>Shira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldental</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amir</keyname><forenames>Hamutal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vardi</keyname><forenames>Roni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanter</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author></authors><title>Vitality of Neural Networks under Reoccurring Catastrophic Failures</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 31674 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep31674</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Catastrophic failures are complete and sudden collapses in the activity of
large networks such as economics, electrical power grids and computer networks,
which typically require a manual recovery process. Here we experimentally show
that excitatory neural networks are governed by a non-Poissonian reoccurrence
of catastrophic failures, where their repetition time follows a multimodal
distribution characterized by a few tenths of a second and tens of seconds
timescales. The mechanism underlying the termination and reappearance of
network activity is quantitatively shown here to be associated with nodal
time-dependent features, neuronal plasticity, where hyperactive nodes damage
the response capability of their neighbors. It presents a complementary
mechanism for the emergence of Poissonian catastrophic failures from damage
conductivity. The effect that hyperactive nodes degenerate their neighbors
represents a type of local competition which is a common feature in the
dynamics of real-world complex networks, whereas their spontaneous recoveries
represent a vitality which enhances reliable functionality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06549</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06549</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Vardi</keyname><forenames>Roni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldental</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardi</keyname><forenames>Shira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheinin</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanter</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author></authors><title>Simultaneous multi-patch-clamp and extracellular-array recordings:
  Single neuron reflects network activity</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.dis-nn physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 36228 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep36228</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The increasing number of recording electrodes enhances the capability of
capturing the network's cooperative activity, however, using too many monitors
might alter the properties of the measured neural network and induce noise.
Using a technique that merges simultaneous multi-patch-clamp and
multi-electrode array recordings of neural networks in-vitro, we show that the
membrane potential of a single neuron is a reliable and super-sensitive probe
for monitoring such cooperative activities and their detailed rhythms.
Specifically, the membrane potential and the spiking activity of a single
neuron are either highly correlated or highly anti-correlated with the
time-dependent macroscopic activity of the entire network. This surprising
observation also sheds light on the cooperative origin of neuronal burst in
cultured networks. Our findings present an alternative flexible approach to the
technique based on a massive tiling of networks by large-scale arrays of
electrodes to monitor their activity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06554</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Collins</keyname><forenames>Laura C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witte</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silverman</keyname><forenames>Rochelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>David B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomes</keyname><forenames>Kenjiro K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging Quasi-Periodic Electronic States in a Synthetic Penrose Tiling</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Main text: 14 pages, 4 figures; Supplement: 5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 8, 15961 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms15961</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Quasicrystals possess long-range order but lack the translational symmetry of
crystalline solids. In solid state physics, periodicity is one of the
fundamental properties that prescribes the electronic band structure in
crystals. In the absence of periodicity and the presence of quasicrystalline
order, the ways that electronic states change remain a mystery. Scanning
tunneling microscopy and atomic manipulation can be used to assemble a
two-dimensional quasicrystalline structure mapped upon the Penrose tiling.
Here, carbon monoxide molecules are arranged on the surface of Cu(111) one at a
time to form the potential landscape that mimics the ionic potential of atoms
in natural materials by constraining the electrons in the two-dimensional
surface state of Cu(111). The real-space images reveal the presence of the
quasiperiodic order in the electronic wave functions and the Fourier analysis
of our results links the energy of the resonant states to the local vertex
structure of the quasicrystal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06572</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Shiri</keyname><forenames>Daryoush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isacsson</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic in situ Control of Heat Rectification in Graphene Nano Ribbons
  using Electric Field-induced Strain</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An increasing number of papers propose routes to implement thermal
counterparts of electronic rectification. These schemes are mainly based on
combinations of crystal anharmonicity and broken mirror symmetry. With respect
to graphene, proposals pivot around shape asymmetry induced by using
hetero-structures of nano-patterned or defected sections of pristine graphene.
Using Molecular Dynamics (MD) we show that it suffices to split a graphene
nano-ribbon into two unequal strained sections using external force which leads
to large asymmetry in the forward and reverse heat fluxes. We find that the
corresponding rectification ratio is enhanced by up to 60 %. Also, and more
importantly, the polarity is controllable on-the-fly, i.e. by changing the
position where force is applied. Based upon our results we propose a
thermo-electric device which obviates the complex nano-patterning and
lithography required to pattern graphene every time a new rectification value
or sign is sought for, opening a route to simpler fabrication and
characterization of phononic phenomena in 2D materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06594</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Plaza-Rivera</keyname><forenames>Christian O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Hong T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoy</keyname><forenames>Robert S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Isostaticity and the solidification of semiflexible polymer melts</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using molecular dynamics simulations of a tangent-soft-sphere bead-spring
polymer model, we examine the degree to which semiflexible polymer melts
solidify at isostaticity. Flexible and stiff chains crystallize when they are
isostatic as defined by appropriate degree-of-freedom-counting arguments.
Semiflexible chains also solidify when isostatic if a generalized isostaticity
criterion that accounts for the slow freezing out of configurational freedom as
chain stiffness increases is employed. The dependence of the average
coordination number at solidification $Z(T_s)$ on chains' characteristic ratio
$C_\infty$ has the same functional form [$Z \simeq a - b\ln(C_\infty)$] as the
dependence of the average coordination number at jamming $Z(\phi_J)$ on
$C_\infty$ in athermal systems, suggesting that jamming-related phenomena play
a significant role in thermal polymer solidification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.06604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.06604</id><created>2017-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Giombi</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the Boson/Fermion Duality on the Three-Sphere</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>33 pages</comments><report-no>PUPT-2530</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the duality between theories of a fundamental scalar or fermion
coupled to $U(N)$ Chern-Simons gauge theory at the level of the three-sphere
partition function, or equivalently entanglement entropy across a circle. The
duality relation between the sphere free energies of the large $N$ bosonic and
fermionic conformal theories is sensitive to certain shifts in the Chern-Simons
level already at order $N$. We first study a similar duality in a ${\cal N}=2$
supersymmetric Chern-Simons matter theory, where it can be checked exactly
using localization. At large $N$, the free energies of supersymmetric and
non-supersymmetric theories are related in a simple way, and we use this fact
to obtain an explicit solution for the scalar and fermion free energies which
obey the duality map and have the expected weak and strong coupling behaviors.
We also suggest that a worldline representation of the free energy allows to
relate its calculation to a sum of Wilson loops in pure Chern-Simons theory. In
the supersymmetric case, we find that this approach precisely reproduces the
localization prediction. In the non-supersymmetric case, we observe that a
result consistent with the boson/fermion duality can be obtained using a
certain framing prescription, which remains to be understood. We also briefly
discuss the case of massive theories, and compare the small mass expansion of
the free energy to previously known results for the correlation functions of
bilinear operators in flat space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
