<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:34:24Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-07-28" from="2017-07-28" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1007.4670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1007.4670</id><created>2010-07-27</created><updated>2010-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bruschi</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Louko</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Martinez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dragan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuentes</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Unruh effect in quantum information beyond the single-mode
  approximation</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>revtex4, 3 figures, I.F. previously published as Fuentes-Guridi and
  Fuentes-Schuller. Minor changes and Journal reference added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 82:042332 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.82.042332</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the validity of the single-mode approximation that is commonly
invoked in the analysis of entanglement in non-inertial frames and in other
relativistic quantum information scenarios. We show that the single-mode
approximation is not valid for arbitrary states, finding corrections to
previous studies beyond such approximation in the bosonic and fermionic cases.
We also exhibit a class of wave packets for which the single-mode approximation
is justified subject to the peaking constraints set by an appropriate Fourier
transform.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.3394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.3394</id><created>2011-08-17</created><updated>2011-11-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galajinsky</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nersessian</keyname><forenames>Armen</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal mechanics inspired by extremal black holes in d=4</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>V2: presentation improved, new material and references added; the
  version to appear in JHEP</comments><report-no>LMP-TPU-9/11</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1111 (2011) 135</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2011)135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A canonical transformation which relates the model of a massive relativistic
particle moving near the horizon of an extremal black hole in four dimensions
and the conventional conformal mechanics is constructed in two different ways.
The first approach makes use of the action-angle variables in the angular
sector. The second scheme relies upon integrability of the system in the sense
of Liouville.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.3489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.3489</id><created>2012-05-14</created><updated>2013-07-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gover</keyname><forenames>A. Rod</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latini</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waldron</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Poincare-Einstein Holography for Forms via Conformal Geometry in the
  Bulk</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc hep-th math.AP</categories><comments>85 pages, LaTeX, typos corrected, references added, to appear in
  Memoirs of the AMS</comments><msc-class>53A30, 53B50, 53A55, 53B15, 22E46</msc-class><journal-ref>Memoir of the AMS 1106, Volume 235 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study higher form Proca equations on Einstein manifolds with boundary data
along conformal infinity. We solve these Laplace-type boundary problems
formally, and to all orders, by constructing an operator which projects
arbitrary forms to solutions. We also develop a product formula for solving
these asymptotic problems in general. The central tools of our approach are (i)
the conformal geometry of differential forms and the associated exterior
tractor calculus, and (ii) a generalised notion of scale which encodes the
connection between the underlying geometry and its boundary. The latter also
controls the breaking of conformal invariance in a very strict way by coupling
conformally invariant equations to the scale tractor associated with the
generalised scale. From this, we obtain a map from existing solutions to new
ones that exchanges Dirichlet and Neumann boundary conditions. Together, the
scale tractor and exterior structure extend the solution generating algebra of
[31] to a conformally invariant, Poincare--Einstein calculus on (tractor)
differential forms. This calculus leads to explicit holographic formulae for
all the higher order conformal operators on weighted differential forms,
differential complexes, and Q-operators of [9]. This complements the results of
Aubry and Guillarmou [3] where associated conformal harmonic spaces parametrise
smooth solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.6130</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.6130</id><created>2012-06-26</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Kent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunes</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Takahiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Slowly Rotating Black Holes in Dynamical Chern-Simons Gravity:
  Deformation Quadratic in the Spin</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 2 figures; Typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 86, 044037 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.86.044037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive a stationary and axisymmetric black hole solution to quadratic
order in the spin angular momentum. The previously found, linear-in-spin terms
modify the odd-parity sector of the metric, while the new corrections appear in
the even-parity sector. These corrections modify the quadrupole moment, as well
as the (coordinate-dependent) location of the event horizon and the ergoregion.
Although the linear-in-spin metric is of Petrov type D, the quadratic order
terms render it of type I. The metric does not possess a second-order Killing
tensor or a Carter-like constant. The new metric does not possess closed
timelike curves or spacetime regions that violate causality outside of the
event horizon. The new, even-parity modifications to the Kerr metric decay less
rapidly at spatial infinity than the leading-order in spin, odd-parity ones,
and thus, the former are more important when considering black holes that are
rotating moderately fast. We calculate the modifications to the Hamiltonian,
binding energy and Kepler's third law. These modifications are crucial for the
construction of gravitational wave templates for black hole binaries, which
will enter at second post-Newtonian order, just like dissipative modifications
found previously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.4901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.4901</id><created>2013-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Galajinsky</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nersessian</keyname><forenames>Armen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saghatelian</keyname><forenames>Armen</forenames></author></authors><title>Superintegrable models related to near horizon extremal Myers-Perry
  black hole in arbitrary dimension</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1306 (2013) 002</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2013)002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a systematic account of integrability of the spherical mechanics
associated with the near horizon extremal Myers-Perry black hole in arbitrary
dimension for the special case that all rotation parameters are equal. The
integrability is established both in the original coordinates and in
action-angle variables. It is demonstrated that the spherical mechanics
associated with the black hole in d=2n+1 is maximally superintegrable, while
its counterpart related to the black hole in d=2n lacks for only one integral
of motion to be maximally superintegrable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.1724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.1724</id><created>2014-05-07</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pedraza</keyname><forenames>Juan F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of nonlocal observables in an expanding boost-invariant plasma</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>v4: matches published version. v5: typo corrected, conclusions
  unchanged</comments><report-no>UTTG-14-14, TCC-014-14</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 90, 046010 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.90.046010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the AdS/CFT correspondence, we compute analytically the late-time
behavior of two-point functions, Wilson loops and entanglement entropy in a
strongly coupled $\mathcal{N}=4$ super-Yang-Mills plasma undergoing a
boost-invariant expansion. We take into account the effects of first order
dissipative hydrodynamics and investigate the effects of the (time-dependent)
shear viscosity on the various observables. The two-point functions decay
exponentially at late times and are unaffected by the viscosity if the points
are separated along the transverse directions. For longitudinal separation we
find a much richer structure. In this case the exponential is modulated by a
nonmonotonic function of the rapidities and a dimensionless combination of the
shear viscosity and proper time. We show that this peculiar behavior constrains
the regime of validity of the hydrodynamical expansion. In addition, similar
results are found for certain Wilson loops and entanglement entropies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.8513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.8513</id><created>2014-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>Byungjoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sangchul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Kyu-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goh</keyname><forenames>K. -I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Link overlap, viability, and mutual percolation in multiplex networks</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cs.SI</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaos, Solitons &amp; Fractals 72, 49-58 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chaos.2014.12.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many real-world complex systems are best modeled by multiplex networks. The
multiplexity has proved to have broad impact on the system's structure and
function. Most theoretical studies on multiplex networks to date, however, have
largely ignored the effect of link overlap across layers despite strong
empirical evidences for its significance. In this article, we investigate the
effect of link overlap in the viability of multiplex networks, both
analytically and numerically. Distinctive role of overlapping links in
viability and mutual connectivity is emphasized and exploited for setting up
proper analytic framework. A rich phase diagram for viability is obtained and
greatly diversified patterns of hysteretic behavior in viability are observed
in the presence of link overlap. Mutual percolation with link overlap is
revisited as a limit of multiplex viability problem, and controversy between
existing results is clarified. The distinctive role of overlapping links is
further demonstrated by the different responses of networks under random
removals of overlapping and non-overlapping links, respectively, as well as
under several removal strategies. Our results show that the link overlap
strongly facilitates viability and mutual percolation; at the same time, the
presence of link overlap poses challenge in analytical approach to the problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03094</id><created>2015-02-10</created><updated>2015-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hegg</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>Philip W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Strongly Coupled Fixed Point in $g\varphi^4$ Theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>revised version of previous paper with a proof of the irrelevance of
  \varphi^6 and higher terms at fixed point</comments><journal-ref>Euro. Phys. Lett. 115, 27005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/27005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show explicitly how a strongly coupled fixed point can be constructed in
scalar $g\varphi^4$ theory from the solutions to a non-linear eigenvalue
problem. The fixed point exists only for $d&lt; 4$, is unstable and characterized
by $\nu=2/d$ (correlation length exponent), $\eta=1/2-d/8$ (anomalous
dimension). For $d=2$, these exponents reproduce to those of the Ising model
which can be understood from the codimension of the critical point. At this
fixed point, $\varphi^{2i}$ terms with $i&gt;2$ are all irrelevant. The testable
prediction of this fixed point is that the specific heat exponent vanishes. 2d
critical Mott systems are well described by this new fixed point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02967</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02967</id><created>2015-04-12</created><updated>2015-08-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>Kosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumagai</keyname><forenames>Wataru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashi</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic Compatibility between LOCC Conversion and Recovery</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 052308 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.052308</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, entanglement concentration was explicitly shown to be irreversible.
However, it is still not clear what kind of states can be reversibly converted
in the asymptotic setting by LOCC when neither the initial nor the target state
is maximally entangled. We derive the necessary and sufficient condition for
the reversibility of LOCC conversions between two bipartite pure entangled
states in the asymptotic setting. In addition, we show that conversion can be
achieved perfectly with only local unitary operation under such condition
except for special cases. Interestingly, our result implies that an error-free
reversible conversion is asymptotically possible even between states whose
copies can never be locally unitarily equivalent with any finite numbers of
copies, although such a conversion is impossible in the finite setting. In
fact, we show such an example. Moreover, we establish how to overcome the
irreversibility of LOCC conversion in two ways. As for the first method, we
evaluate how many copies of the initial state is to be lost to overcome the
irreversibility of LOCC conversion. The second method is to add a supplementary
state appropriately, which also works for LU conversion unlike the first
method. Especially, for the qubit system, any non-maximally pure entangled
state can be a universal resource for the asymptotic reversibility when copies
of the state is sufficiently many. More interestingly, our analysis implies
that far-from-maximally entangled states can be better than nearly maximally
entangled states as this type of resource. This fact brings new insight to the
resource theory of state conversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04214</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nordsiek</keyname><forenames>Freja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lathrop</keyname><forenames>Daniel P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective phenomena in granular and atmospheric electrification</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 1 table, submitted to Phys. Rev. Fluids</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In clouds of suspended particles (grains, droplets, spheres, crystals, etc.),
collisions electrify the particles and the clouds, producing large electric
potential differences over large scales. This is seen most spectacularly in the
atmosphere as lighting in thunderstorms, thundersnow, dust storms, and volcanic
ash plumes where multi-million-volt potential differences over scales of
kilometers can be produced, but it is a general phenomenon in granular systems
as a whole. The electrification process is not well understood, especially for
electrification of insulating particles of the same material. To investigate
the relative importances of particle properties (material, size, etc.) and
collective phenomena (behaviors of systems at large scales not easily predicted
from local dynamics) in granular and atmospheric electrification, we used a
table-top experiment that mechanically shakes particles inside a cell where we
measure the macroscopic electric field between the electrically conducting end
plates. The measured electric fields are a result of capacitive coupling and
direct charge transfer between the particles and the plates. Using a diverse
range of mono-material particle sets (plastics, ceramic, glass, and metals), we
found that all our particle materials electrify and show similar dynamics with
long time-scale temporal variation and an electric field amplitude that depends
on the particle quantity in a complex way. These results suggest that while
particle properties do matter like previous investigations have shown,
macroscopic electrification of solids is relatively material agnostic and large
scale collective phenomena play a major role.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07698</id><created>2015-10-26</created><updated>2016-06-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Witten</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author></authors><title>Three Lectures On Topological Phases Of Matter</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el hep-th</categories><comments>60 pp, minor corrections in this version</comments><journal-ref>La Rivista del Nuovo Cimento, 39 (2016) 313-370</journal-ref><doi>10.1393/ncr/i2016-10125-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  These notes are based on lectures at the PSSCMP/PiTP summer school that was
held at Princeton University and the Institute for Advanced Study in July,
2015. They are devoted largely to topological phases of matter that can be
understood in terms of free fermions and band theory. They also contain an
introduction to the fractional quantum Hall effect from the point of view of
effective field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01234</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-02-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Szombati</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nadj-Perge</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Car</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plissard</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakkers</keyname><forenames>E. P. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kouwenhoven</keyname><forenames>L. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson $\varphi_{0}$-junction in nanowire quantum dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nat. Phys. 12 (2016) 568</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3742</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Josephson effect describes supercurrent flowing through a junction
connecting two superconducting leads by a thin barrier [1]. This current is
driven by a superconducting phase difference $\phi$ between the leads. In the
presence of chiral and time reversal symmetry of the Cooper pair tunneling
process [2] the current is strictly zero when $\phi$ vanishes. Only if these
underlying symmetries are broken the supercurrent for $\phi=0$ may be finite
[3-5]. This corresponds to a ground state of the junction being offset by a
phase $\phi_{0}$, different from 0 or $\pi$. Here, we report such a Josephson
$\phi_{0}$-junction based on a nanowire quantum dot. We use a quantum
interferometer device in order to investigate phase offsets and demonstrate
that $\phi_{0}$ can be controlled by electrostatic gating. Our results have
possible far reaching implications for superconducting flux and phase defined
quantum bits as well as for exploring topological superconductivity in quantum
dot systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00869</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00869</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yi-Jen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pabst</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective resonances of atomic xenon from the linear to the nonlinear
  regime</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  XUV nonlinear spectroscopy has recently discovered that there is more than
one collective dipole resonance state in the energy range of the giant dipole
resonance (GDR) of atomic Xe. This resonance-state substructure, hidden in the
linear regime, raises imminent questions regarding our understanding of the
collective electronic behavior of Xe, which has been largely founded on linear
spectroscopic studies. Here, we approach the collective response of Xe from a
new perspective: we study directly the resonance eigenstates, and then analyze
their spectroscopic manifestations. We find that linear spectroscopy captures
only partial information on the resonance substructure as a result of quantum
interferences. Moreover, we show that the resonance state dominating the GDR in
linear spectroscopy has no adiabatic connection to the resonance state
governing the corresponding cross section when multielectron interactions are
neglected. Going beyond the dipole-allowed correlated electronic structure, we
predict the existence of collective multipole resonances of Xe. Unlike any
known collective feature in atoms, these resonances live exceptionally long
(more than 100 attoseconds), thus providing a new playground for studying the
collective nonlinear response of Xe using advanced light sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04365</id><created>2016-01-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Etxarri</keyname><forenames>Aitzol</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization singularities on high index nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>ACS Photonics 4 (5), 1159-1164 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.7b00002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we study the emergence of polarization singularities in the
scattered fields of optical resonators excited by linearly polarized plane
waves. First, we prove analytically that combinations of isotropic electric and
magnetic dipoles can sustain L surfaces, and C lines that propagate from the
near-field to the far field. Moreover, based on these analytical results, we
derive anomalous scattering Kerker conditions trough singular optics arguments.
Secondly, through exact full-field calculations, we demonstrate that high
refractive index spherical resonators present such topologically protected
features. Furthermore, we calculate the polarization structure of light around
the generated C lines, unveiling a M\&quot;obius strip structure in the main axis of
the polarization ellipse. These results prove that high-index nanoparticles are
excellent candidates for the generation and control of polarization
singularities and that they may lead to new platforms for the experimental
study of the topology of light fields around optical antennas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08159</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Yenni P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stegmann</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Douglas J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seligman</keyname><forenames>Thomas H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chains of benzenes with lithium-atom adsorption: Vibrations and
  spontaneous symmetry breaking</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chemical Physics Letters 684:86 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cplett.2017.06.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study effects of different configurations of adsorbates on the vibrational
modes as well as symmetries of polyacenes and poly-p-phenylenes focusing on
lithium atom adsorption. We found that the spectra of the vibrational modes
distinguish the different configurations. For more regular adsorption schemes
the lowest states are bending and torsion modes of the skeleton, which are
essentially followed by the adsorbate. On poly-p-phenylenes we found that
lithium adsorption reduces and often eliminates the torsion between rings thus
increasing symmetry. There is spontaneous symmetry breaking in
poly-p-phenylenes due to double adsorption of lithium atoms on alternating
rings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05751</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05751</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sabass</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>Howard A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of the membrane for mechanosensing by tethered channels</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 258101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.258101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biologically important membrane channels are gated by force at attached
tethers. Here, we generically characterize the non-trivial interplay of force,
membrane tension, and channel deformations that can affect gating. A central
finding is that minute conical channel deformation under force leads to
significant energy release during opening. We also calculate channel-channel
interactions and show that they can amplify force sensitivity of tethered
channels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08104</id><created>2016-03-26</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhanja</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinivas</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malik</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Superspace Unitary Operator and Nilpotent (Anti-)dual BRST
  Symmetries: Superfield Formalism</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX file, 25 pages, journal reference is given</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics Vol. 2016 Article ID 2764245, 17
  pages (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/2764245</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We exploit the key concepts of the augmented version of superfield approach
to Becchi-Rouet-Stora-Tyutin (BRST) formalism to derive the superspace (SUSP)
dual unitary operator (and its Hermitian conjugate) and demonstrate their
utility in the derivation of the nilpotent and absolutely anticommuting
(anti-)dual BRST symmetry transformations for a set of interesting models of
the Abelian 1-form gauge theories. These models are the one (0+1)-dimensional
(1D) rigid rotor, modified versions of the two (1+1)-dimensional (2D) Proca as
well as anomalous gauge theories and 2D model of a self-dual bosonic field
theory. We show the universality of the SUSP dual unitary operator and its
Hermitian conjugate in the cases of all the Abelian models under consideration.
These SUSP dual unitary operators, besides maintaining the explicit group
structure, provide the alternatives to the dual-horizontality condition (DHC)
and dual-gauge invariant restrictions (DGIRs) of the superfield formalism. The
derivation of the dual unitary operators and corresponding (anti-)dual BRST
symmetries are completely novel results in our present investigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06325</id><created>2016-04-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Aslam</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gayen</keyname><forenames>Sirshendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Avtar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamaki</keyname><forenames>Takuma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takano</keyname><forenames>Yoshihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheet</keyname><forenames>Goutam</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic superconductivity in La(O,F)BiSeS crystals revealed by
  field-angle dependent Andreev reflection spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4 figures, references included</comments><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2017.07.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  From field-angle dependent Andreev reflection spectroscopy on single crystals
of La(O,F)BiSeS, which belongs to the recently discovered BiCh 2 (Ch = S, Se)
based layered superconductors, we found that the superconductivity in
La(O,F)BiSeS is highly anisotropic. We measured a superconducting energy gap of
0.61 meV for current injected along c-axis at 1.5 K. Detailed temperature and
magnetic field dependent studies of the gap also reveal the presence of
unconventional pairing in La(O,F)BiSeS. We show that the observed anisotropic
superconducting properties can be attributed to the anisotropy in the
superconducting order parameter with a complex symmetry in superconducting
La(O,F)BiSeS.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05312</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akashi</keyname><forenames>Ryosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iida</keyname><forenames>Yo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshizawa</keyname><forenames>Kanako</forenames></author></authors><title>Interference of the Bloch phase in layered materials with stacking
  shifts</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>30 pages, 30 figures. v2: Figures added and Reference list corrected.
  v3: Upon publication, data on black phosphorene added, title changed,
  derivation of some formulae refined, etc</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 95, 245401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.95.245401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In periodic systems, electronic wave functions of the eigenstates exhibit the
periodically modulated Bloch phases and are characterized by their wave numbers
${\bf k}$. We theoretically address the effects of the Bloch phase in general
layered materials with stacking shift. When the interlayer shift and the Bloch
wave vector ${\bf k}$ satisfy certain conditions, interlayer transitions of
electrons are prohibited by the interference of the Bloch phase. We specify the
manifolds in the ${\bf k}$ space where the hybridization of the Bloch states
between the layers is suppressed in accord with the stacking shift. These
manifolds, named stacking-adapted interference manifolds (SAIM), are obviously
applicable to general layered materials regardless of detailed atomic
configuration within the unit cell. We demonstrate the robustness and
usefulness of the SAIM with first-principles calculations for layered boron
nitride, transition-metal dichalcogenide, graphite, and black phosphorus. We
also apply the SAIM to general three-dimensional crystals to derive special
${\bf k}$-point paths for the respective Bravais lattices, along which the
Bloch-phase interference strongly suppresses the band dispersion. Our theory
provides a general and novel view on the anisotropic electronic kinetics
intrinsic to the periodic-lattice structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09386</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenting</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham</affiliation><affiliation>Kavli IPMU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jiaxin</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham</affiliation><affiliation>Kavli IPMU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Shaun</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frenk</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sawala</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham</affiliation></author></authors><title>What to expect from dynamical modelling of galactic haloes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures, published by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1334</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many dynamical models of the Milky Way halo require assumptions that the
distribution function of a tracer population should be independent of time
(i.e., a steady state distribution function) and that the underlying potential
is spherical. We study the limitations of such modelling by applying a general
dynamical model with minimal assumptions to a large sample of galactic haloes
from cosmological $N$-body and hydrodynamical simulations. Using dark matter
particles as dynamical tracers, we find that the systematic uncertainties in
the measured mass and concentration parameters typically have an amplitude of
25% to 40%. When stars are used as tracers, however, the systematic
uncertainties can be as large as a factor of $2-3$. The systematic
uncertainties are not reduced by increasing the tracer sample size and vary
stochastically from halo to halo. These systematic uncertainties are mostly
driven by underestimated statistical noise caused by correlated phase-space
structures that violate the steady state assumption. The number of independent
phase-space structures inferred from the uncertainty level sets a limiting
sample size beyond which a further increase no longer significantly improves
the accuracy of dynamical inferences. The systematic uncertainty level is
determined by the halo merger history, the shape and environment of the halo.
Our conclusions apply generally to any spherical steady-state model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09394</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Habouzit</keyname><forenames>Melanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volonteri</keyname><forenames>Marta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dubois</keyname><forenames>Yohan</forenames></author></authors><title>Blossoms from black hole seeds: properties and early growth regulated by
  supernova feedback</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures, matched the published version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx666</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive black holes (BHs) inhabit local galaxies, including the Milky Way and
some dwarf galaxies. BH formation, occurring at early cosmic times, must
account for the properties of BHs in today's galaxies, notably why some
galaxies host a BH, and others do not. We investigate the formation,
distribution and growth of BH `seeds' by using the adaptive mesh refinement
code Ramses. We develop an implementation of BH formation in dense,
low-metallicity environments, as advocated by models invoking the collapse of
the first generation of stars, or of dense nuclear star clusters. The seed
masses are computed one-by-one on-the-fly, based on the star formation rate and
the stellar initial mass function. This self-consistent method to seed BHs
allows us to study the distribution of BHs in a cosmological context and their
evolution over cosmic time. We find that all high-mass galaxies tend to a host
a BH, whereas low-mass counterparts have a lower probability of hosting a BH.
After the end of the epoch of BH formation, this probability is modulated by
the growth of the galaxy. The simulated BHs connect to low-redshift
observational samples, and span a similar range in accretion properties as
Lyman-Break Analogs. The growth of BHs in low-mass galaxies is stunted by
strong supernova feedback. The properties of BHs in dwarf galaxies thus remain
a testbed for BH formation. Simulations with strong supernova feedback, which
is able to quench BH accretion in shallow potential wells, produce galaxies and
BHs in better agreement with observational constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05760</id><created>2016-06-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Weimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Haoshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarmoff</keyname><forenames>Jory A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Termination of Single Crystal Bi2Se3 Surfaces Prepared by Various
  Methods</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>31 pages, 10 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94 (2016) 195408</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.195408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bismuth Selenide (Bi2Se3) is a topological insulator with a two-dimensional
layered structure that enables clean and well-ordered surfaces to be prepared
by cleaving. Although some studies have demonstrated that the cleaved surface
is terminated with Se, as expected from the bulk crystal structure, other
reports have indicated either a Bi- or mixed-termination. Low energy ion
scattering (LEIS), low energy electron diffraction (LEED) and x-ray
photoelectron spectroscopy (XPS) are used here to compare surfaces prepared by
ex situ cleaving, in situ cleaving, and ion bombardment and annealing (IBA) in
ultra-high vacuum (UHV). Surfaces prepared by in situ cleaving and IBA are well
ordered and Se-terminated. Ex situ cleaved samples could be either
Se-terminated or Bi-rich, are less well ordered and have adsorbed contaminants.
This suggests that a chemical reaction involving atmospheric contaminants,
which may preferentially adsorb at surface defects, could contribute to the
non-reproducibility of the termination.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05808</id><created>2016-06-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Weimin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Haoshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarmoff</keyname><forenames>Jory A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Structure of In Situ Cleaved Single Crystal Bi2Se3 Measured by
  Low Energy Ion Scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 6 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Vacuum Science &amp; Technology B 34 (2016) 04J108</journal-ref><doi>10.1116/1.4955134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bismuth Selenide is a two-dimensional topological insulator material composed
of stacked quintuple layers (QL). The layers are held together by a weak van
der Waals force that enables surface preparation by cleaving. Low energy ion
scattering experiments (LEIS) show that Bi2Se3 cleaved under ultra-high vacuum
(UHV) has a Se-terminated structure that is consistent with cleaving between
QLs. Comparison of experimental data to molecular dynamics simulations confirms
the Se-termination and provides an estimate of the surface relaxation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07962</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07962</id><created>2016-06-25</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pappas</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bannenberg</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lelievre-Berna</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dewhurst</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalgliesh</keyname><forenames>R. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlagel</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longrasso</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falus</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Fluctuations, Precursor Phenomena and Phase Transition in MnSi
  under Magnetic Field</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 047203 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.047203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The reference chiral helimagnet MnSi is the first system where skyrmion
lattice correlations have been reported. At zero magnetic field the transition
at $T_C$ to the helimagnetic state is of first order. Above $T_C$, in a region
dominated by precursor phenomena, neutron scattering shows the build up of
strong chiral fluctuating correlations over the surface of a sphere with radius
$2\pi/\ell$, where $\ell$ is the pitch of the helix. It has been suggested that
these fluctuating correlations drive the helical transition to first order
following a scenario proposed by Brazovskii for liquid crystals. We present a
comprehensive neutron scattering study under magnetic fields, which provides
evidence that this is not the case. The sharp first order transition persists
for magnetic fields up to 0.4 T whereas the fluctuating correlations weaken and
start to concentrate along the field direction already above 0.2 T. Our results
thus disconnect the first order nature of the transition from the precursor
fluctuating correlations. They also show no indication for a tricritical point,
where the first order transition crosses over to second order with increasing
magnetic field. In this light, the nature of the first order helical transition
and the precursor phenomena above $T_C$, both of general relevance to chiral
magnetism, remain an open question.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02178</id><created>2016-07-07</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Regnault</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maciejko</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kivelson</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sondhi</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of a fractional quantum Hall nematic phase in a microscopic
  model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>v2: 15 pages, 9 figures (includes new Appendix with additional
  numerical results); published version [Editors' Suggestion]</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035150 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035150</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At small momenta, the Girvin-MacDonald-Platzman (GMP) mode in the fractional
quantum Hall (FQH) effect can be identified with gapped nematic fluctuations in
the isotropic FQH liquid. This correspondence would be exact as the GMP mode
softens upon approach to the putative point of a quantum phase transition to a
FQH nematic. Motivated by these considerations as well as by suggestive
evidence of an FQH nematic in tilted field experiments, we have sought evidence
of such a nematic FQHE in a microscopic model of interacting electrons in the
lowest Landau level at filling factor 1/3. Using a family of anisotropic
Laughlin states as trial wave functions, we find a continuous quantum phase
transition between the isotropic Laughlin liquid and the FQH nematic. Results
of numerical exact diagonalization also suggest that rotational symmetry is
spontaneously broken, and that the phase diagram of the model contains both a
nematic and a stripe phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05483</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2017-05-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Yifei</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape evolutions of $^{72,74}$Kr with temperature in the covariant
  density functional theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. C, 41(9), 094102 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/41/9/094102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rich phenomena of deformations in neutron-deficient krypton isotopes such
as the shape evolution with neutron number and the shape coexistence attract
the interests of nuclear physicists for decades. It will be interesting to
study such shape phenomena using a novel way, i.e., by thermally exciting the
nucleus. So in this work, we develop the finite temperature covariant density
functional theory for axially deformed nuclei with the treatment of pairing
correlations by BCS approach, and apply this approach for the study of shape
evolutions in $^{72,74}$Kr with increasing temperatures. For $^{72}$Kr, with
temperature increasing, the nucleus firstly experiences a relatively quick
weakening in oblate deformation at temperature $T \sim0.9$ MeV, and then
changes from oblate to spherical at $T \sim2.1$ MeV. For $^{74}$Kr, its global
minimum locates at quadroupole deformation $\beta_2 \sim -0.14$ and abruptly
changes to spherical at $T\sim 1.7$ MeV. The proton pairing transition occurs
at critical temperature 0.6 MeV following the rule $T_c =0.6 \Delta_p (0)$
where $\Delta_p(0)$ is the proton pairing gap at zero temperature. The
signatures of the above pairing transition and shape changes can be found in
the curve of the specific heat. The single-particle level evolutions with the
temperature are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.08996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.08996</id><created>2016-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Ayoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarzynski</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical and quantum shortcuts to adiabaticity in a tilted piston</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Chem. B, 121 , 3403-3411 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcb.6b08769</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adiabatic quantum state evolution can be accelerated through a variety of
shortcuts to adiabaticity. In one approach, a counterdiabatic quantum
Hamiltonian $\hat H_{CD}$ is constructed to suppress nonadiabatic excitations.
In the analogous classical problem, a counterdiabatic classical Hamiltonian
$H_{CD}$ ensures that the classical action remains constant even under rapid
driving. Both the quantum and classical versions of this problem have been
solved for the special case of scale-invariant driving, characterized by linear
expansions, contractions or translations of the system. Here we investigate an
example of a non-scale-invariant system -- a tilted piston. We solve exactly
for the classical counterdiabatic Hamiltonian $H_{CD}(q,p,t)$, which we then
quantize to obtain a Hermitian operator $\hat H_{CD}(t)$. Using numerical
simulations, we find that $\hat H_{CD}$ effectively suppresses non-adiabatic
excitations under rapid driving. These results offer a proof of principle --
beyond the special case of scale-invariant driving -- that quantum shortcuts to
adiabaticity can successfully be constructed from their classical counterparts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.04818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.04818</id><created>2016-09-15</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gopalakrishnan</keyname><forenames>Sarang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Islam</keyname><forenames>K. Ranjibul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knap</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise-induced subdiffusion in strongly localized quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures + Supplemental Material, v2: additional data on
  noise-induced dynamics in many-body localized systems</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 046601 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.046601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the dynamics of strongly localized systems subject to dephasing
noise with arbitrary correlation time. Although noise inevitably induces
delocalization, transport in the noise-induced delocalized phase is
subdiffusive in a parametrically large intermediate-time window. We argue for
this intermediate-time subdiffusive regime both analytically and using
numerical simulations on single-particle localized systems. Furthermore, we
show that normal diffusion is restored in the long-time limit, through
processes analogous to variable-range hopping. With numerical simulations based
on Lanczos exact diagonalization, we demonstrate that our qualitative
conclusions are also valid for interacting systems in the many-body localized
phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07104</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2017-06-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the production of high-$p_{\rm T}$ electrons from
  heavy-flavour hadron decays in Pb-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}$ = 2.76
  TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>28 pages, 7 captioned figures, 2 tables, authors from page 23,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/3162</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-235</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 771 (2017) 467-481</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2017.05.060</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Electrons from heavy-flavour hadron decays (charm and beauty) were measured
with the ALICE detector in Pb-Pb collisions at a centre-of-mass of energy
$\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}=2.76$ TeV. The transverse momentum ($p_{\rm T}$)
differential production yields at mid-rapidity were used to calculate the
nuclear modification factor $R_{\rm AA}$ in the interval $3&lt;p_{\rm T}&lt; 18$
GeV/$c$. The $R_{\rm AA}$ shows a strong suppression compared to binary scaling
of pp collisions at the same energy (up to a factor of 4) in the 10% most
central Pb-Pb collisions. There is a centrality trend of suppression, and a
weaker suppression (down to a factor of 2) in semi-peripheral (50-80%)
collisions is observed. The suppression of electrons in this broad $p_{\rm T}$
interval indicates that both charm and beauty quarks lose energy when they
traverse the hot medium formed in Pb-Pb collisions at LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.08421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.08421</id><created>2016-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Markauskas</keyname><forenames>Darius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruggel-Emden</keyname><forenames>Harald</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical analysis of wet separation of particles by density differences</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>This manuscript was accepted for the publication in the conference
  proceedings of ICNAAM 2016 conference</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conference Proceedings 1863, 180005 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4992365</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wet particle separation is widely used in mineral processing and plastic
recycling to separate mixtures of particulate materials into further usable
fractions due to density differences. This work presents efforts aiming to
numerically analyze the wet separation of particles with different densities.
In the current study the discrete element method (DEM) is used for the solid
phase while the smoothed particle hydrodynamics (SPH) is used for modeling of
the liquid phase. The two phases are coupled by the use of a volume averaging
technique. In the current study, simulations of spherical particle separation
were performed. In these simulations, a set of generated particles with two
different densities is dropped into a rectangular container filled with liquid.
The results of simulations with two different mixtures of particles
demonstrated how separation depends on the densities of particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09187</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09187</id><created>2016-09-28</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Shi-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissociation of large transverse-momentum prompt J/psi produced in Pb-Pb
  collisions at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>30 pages, LaTex; 1 added figure and table</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Phys. A966 (2017) 224</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysa.2017.07.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A collision of a light meson and a charmonium produces quarks and antiquarks
first, then the charm quark fragments into a charmed hadron, and finally three
or more mesons are produced. This is the mechanism that we consider and propose
to understand the prompt-J/psi nuclear modification factor in the range of
J/psi transverse momentum from 10 GeV/c to 18 GeV/c, as measured by the CMS
Collaboration and the ATLAS Collaboration. Unpolarized cross sections are
derived and calculated for the reactions pion+charmonium -&gt;H_c+X with H_c being
a charmed meson. Numerical cross sections are parametrized and used to
calculate the dissociation rate of charmonium in the interaction with pions in
hadronic matter. The momentum dependence of the rate obtained is so as to lead
to a decreasing charmonium nuclear modification factor with increasing
transverse momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00851</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00851</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2017-03-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jhu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pochung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Ming-Chiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Relaxation of the entanglement spectrum in quench dynamics of
  topological systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>26 pages, 14 figures</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/aa79b3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study how the entanglement spectrum relaxes to its steady state in
one-dimensional quadratic systems after a quantum quench. In particular we
apply the saddle point expansion to the dimerized chains and 1-D p-wave
superconductors. We find that the entanglement spectrum always exhibits a
power-law relaxation superimposed with oscillations at certain characteristic
angular frequencies. For the dimerized chains, we find that the exponent $\nu$
of the power-law decay is always $3/2$. For 1-D p-wave superconductors,
however, we find that depending on the initial and final Hamiltonian, the
exponent $\nu$ can take value from a limited list of values. The smallest
possible value is $\nu=1/2$, which leads to a very slow convergence to its
steady state value.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02499</id><created>2016-10-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Krivonos</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nersessian</keyname><forenames>Armen</forenames></author></authors><title>SU(1,2) invariance in two-dimensional oscillator</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1702 (2017) 006</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2017)006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Performing the Hamiltonian analysis we explicitly established the canonical
equivalence of the deformed oscillator, constructed in
arXiv:1607.03756[hep-th], with the ordinary one. As an immediate consequence,
we proved that the SU(1,2) symmetry is the dynamical symmetry of the ordinary
two-dimensional oscillator. The characteristic feature of this SU(1,2) symmetry
is a non-polynomial structure of its generators written it terms of the
oscillator variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.05767</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.05767</id><created>2016-10-18</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Huan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>Sangeeta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rhoads</keyname><forenames>James E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leitherer</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wofford</keyname><forenames>Aida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Tianxing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Junxian</forenames></author></authors><title>Ly$\alpha$ and UV Sizes of Green Pea Galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures. ApJ accepted</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa6337</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Green Peas are nearby analogs of high-redshift Ly$\alpha$-emitting galaxies.
To probe their Ly$\alpha$ escape, we study the spatial profiles of Ly$\alpha$
and UV continuum emission of 24 Green Pea galaxies using the Cosmic Origins
Spectrograph (COS) on Hubble Space Telescope (HST). We extract the spatial
profiles of Ly$\alpha$ emission from their 2D COS spectra, and of UV continuum
from both the 2D spectra and NUV images. The Ly$\alpha$ emission shows more
extended spatial profiles than the UV continuum in most Green Peas. The
deconvolved Full Width Half Maximum (FWHM) of the Ly$\alpha$ spatial profile is
about 2 to 4 times that of the UV continuum in most cases. Since Green Peas are
analogs of high-z LAEs, it suggests that most high-z LAEs likely have larger
Ly$\alpha$ sizes than UV sizes. We also compare the spatial profiles of
Ly$\alpha$ photons at blueshifted and redshifted velocities in eight Green Peas
with sufficient data quality, and find the blue wing of the Ly$\alpha$ line has
a larger spatial extent than the red wing in four Green Peas with comparatively
weak blue Ly$\alpha$ line wings. We show that Green Peas and MUSE $z=3-6$ LAEs
have similar Ly$\alpha$ and UV continuum sizes, which probably suggests
starbursts in both low-z and high-z LAEs drive similar gas outflows illuminated
by Ly$\alpha$ light. Five Lyman continuum (LyC) leakers in this sample have
similar Ly$\alpha$ to UV continuum size ratios (~1.4-4.3) to the other Green
Peas, indicating their LyC emission escape through ionized holes in the
interstellar medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08564</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08564</id><created>2016-10-26</created><updated>2016-11-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Radin</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author></authors><title>Wulff shape for equilibrium phases</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>future versions can be obtained at
  http://www.ma.utexas.edu/users/radin/papers.html</comments><journal-ref>Notices Amer. Math. Soc. 64 (2017) 551-556</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use surface tension to distinguish between phases with isotropic internal
structure from phases which are microscopically anisotropic. There are many
interesting open problems, especially in two dimensions, and in phase
coexistence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00887</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Safranski</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barsukov</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Han Kyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jara</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Houchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lenz</keyname><forenames>Kilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>Juergen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tserkovnyak</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Mingzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krivorotov</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin caloritronic nano-oscillator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nat Commun 8, 117 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-00184-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Energy loss due to ohmic heating is a major bottleneck limiting down-scaling
and speed of nano-electronic devices, and harvesting ohmic heat for signal
processing is a major challenge in modern electronics. Here we demonstrate that
thermal gradients arising from ohmic heating can be utilized for excitation of
coherent auto-oscillations of magnetization and for generation of tunable
microwave signals. The heat-driven dynamics is observed in
$\mathrm{Y_{3}Fe_{5}O_{12}/Pt}$ bilayer nanowires where ohmic heating of the Pt
layer results in injection of pure spin current into the
$\mathrm{Y_{3}Fe_{5}O_{12}}$ layer. This leads to excitation of
auto-oscillations of the $\mathrm{Y_{3}Fe_{5}O_{12}}$ magnetization and
generation of coherent microwave radiation. Our work paves the way towards spin
caloritronic devices for microwave and magnonic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.02238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.02238</id><created>2016-11-07</created><updated>2017-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence of Szegedy's and Coined Quantum Walks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf. Process. 16(9), 215 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-017-1667-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Szegedy's quantum walk is a quantization of a classical random walk or Markov
chain, where the walk occurs on the edges of the bipartite double cover of the
original graph. To search, one can simply quantize a Markov chain with
absorbing vertices. Recently, Santos proposed two alternative search algorithms
that instead utilize the sign-flip oracle in Grover's algorithm rather than
absorbing vertices. In this paper, we show that these two algorithms are
exactly equivalent to two algorithms involving coined quantum walks, which are
walks on the vertices of the original graph with an internal degree of freedom.
The first scheme is equivalent to a coined quantum walk with one walk-step per
query of Grover's oracle, and the second is equivalent to a coined quantum walk
with two walk-steps per query of Grover's oracle. These equivalences lie
outside the previously known equivalence of Szegedy's quantum walk with
absorbing vertices and the coined quantum walk with the negative identity
operator as the coin for marked vertices, whose precise relationships we also
investigate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05829</id><created>2016-11-17</created><updated>2017-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datt</keyname><forenames>Charu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natale</keyname><forenames>Giovanniantonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatzikiriakos</keyname><forenames>Savvas G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elfring</keyname><forenames>Gwynn J.</forenames></author></authors><title>An active particle in a complex fluid</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 823, 675-688 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.353</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study active particles with prescribed surface velocities in
non-Newtonian fluids. We employ the reciprocal theorem to obtain the velocity
of an active spherical particle with an arbitrary axisymmetric slip-velocity in
an otherwise quiescent second-order fluid. We then determine how the motion of
a diffusiophoretic Janus particle is affected by complex fluid rheology, namely
viscoelasticity and shear-thinning viscosity, compared to a Newtonian fluid,
assuming a fixed slip-velocity. We find that a Janus particle may go faster or
slower in a viscoelastic fluid, but is always slower in a shear-thinning fluid
as compared to a Newtonian fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.08192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.08192</id><created>2016-11-24</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Polettini</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author></authors><title>Carnot efficiency at divergent power output</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters, Volume 118, Number 4 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/118/40003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The widely debated feasibility of thermodynamic machines achieving Carnot
efficiency at finite power has been convincingly dismissed. Yet, the common
wisdom that efficiency can only be optimal in the limit of infinitely-slow
processes overlooks the dual scenario of infinitely-fast processes. We
corroborate that efficient engines at divergent power output are not
theoretically impossible, framing our claims within the theory of Stochastic
Thermodynamics. We inspect the case of an electronic quantum dot coupled to
three particle reservoirs to illustrate the physical rationale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.09751</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.09751</id><created>2016-11-29</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Doyle</keyname><forenames>Casey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanski</keyname><forenames>Boleslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korniss</keyname><forenames>Gyorgy</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effects of Communication Burstiness on Consensus Formation and
  Tipping Points in Social Dynamics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 95, 062303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.95.062303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current models for opinion dynamics typically utilize a Poisson process for
speaker selection, making the waiting time between events exponentially
distributed. Human interaction tends to be bursty, though, having higher
probabilities of either extremely short waiting times or long periods of
silence. To quantify the burstiness effects on the dynamics of social models,
we place in competition two groups exhibiting different speakers' waiting-time
distributions. These competitions are implemented in the binary Naming Game,
and show that the relevant aspect of the waiting-time distribution is the
density of the head rather than that of the tail. We show that even with
identical mean waiting times, a group with a higher density of short waiting
times is favored in competition over the other group. This effect remains in
the presence of nodes holding a single opinion that never changes, as the
fraction of such committed individuals necessary for achieving consensus
decreases dramatically when they have a higher head density than the holders of
the competing opinion. Finally, to quantify differences in burstiness, we
introduce the expected number of small-time activations and use it to
characterize the early-time regime of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02697</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lester</keyname><forenames>Christopher Gorham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunt</keyname><forenames>Benjamin Hylton</forenames></author></authors><title>Difference between two species of emu hides a test for lepton flavour
  violation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 page, 7 figs; v2: reference added; v3: clarified statement about
  W+jet bias; v4: changes from referee comments, inc addition of quantitative
  bias estimate. Replaced ptmiss with mt(mu); v5: fixes error introduced in v4
  (ptmiss should have been replaced by mT(e)+mT(mu) not by mT(mu)). An erratum
  is also submitted to JHEP. Error is not present in arXiv v1, v2, v3 or v5</comments><report-no>CAV-HEP-16/20</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP03(2017)149</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2017)149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that an LHC measurement of some simple quantities related to the
ratio of rates of e+mu- to e-mu+ events is surprisingly sensitive to as-yet
unexcluded R-parity violating supersymmetric models with non-zero lambda-prime
231 couplings. The search relies upon the approximate lepton universality in
the Standard Model, the sign of the charge of the proton, and a collection of
favourable detector biases. The proposed search is unusual because: it does not
require any of the displaced vertices, hadronic neutralino decay products, or
squark/gluino production relied upon by existing LHC RPV searches; it could
work in cases in which the only light sparticles were smuons and neutralinos;
and it could make a discovery (though not necessarily with optimal
significance) without requiring the computation of a leading-order Monte Carlo
estimate of any background rate. The LHC has shown no strong hints of
post-Higgs physics and so precision Standard Model measurements are becoming
ever more important. We argue that in this environment growing profits are to
be made from searches that place detector biases and symmetries of the Standard
Model at their core - searches based around `controls' rather than around
signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03212</id><created>2016-12-09</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lovorn</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarker</keyname><forenames>Sanjoy K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex Quasi-Two-Dimensional Crystalline Order Embedded in VO$_2$ and
  Other Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 045501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.045501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Metal oxides such as VO$_2$ undergo structural transitions to low-symmetry
phases characterized by intricate crystalline order, accompanied by rich
electronic behavior. We derive a minimal ionic Hamiltonian based on symmetry
and local energetics which describes structural transitions involving all four
observed phases, in the correct order. An exact analysis shows that complexity
results from the symmetry-induced constraints of the parent phase which forces
ionic displacements to form multiple interpenetrating groups using
low-dimensional pathways and distant neighbors. Displacements within each group
exhibit independent, quasi two-dimensional order, which is frustrated and
fragile. This selective ordering mechanism is not restricted to VO$_2$: it
applies to other oxides which show similar complex order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.02436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.02436</id><created>2017-01-09</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sukhinin</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aceves</keyname><forenames>Alejandro B</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diels</keyname><forenames>Jean-Claude</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arissian</keyname><forenames>Ladan</forenames></author></authors><title>Collapse events of two-color optical beams</title><categories>physics.optics nlin.PS physics.plasm-ph</categories><msc-class>78A60, 78A40</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 95, 031801 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.95.031801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study optical self-focusing that leads to collapse events
for the time-independent model of co-propagating beams with different
wavelengths. We show that collapse events depend on the combined critical power
of two beams for both fundamental, vortex and mixed configurations as well as
on the ratio of their individual powers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1701.06932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1701.06932</id><created>2017-01-24</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Denizli</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senol</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yilmaz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>I. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karadeniz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Top quark FCNC couplings at future circular hadron electron colliders</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 Figures, 4 Tables, to appear in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 015024 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.015024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A study of single top quark production via flavor changing neutral current
interactions at $tq\gamma$ vertices is performed at future circular hadron
electron collider. The signal cross sections for the processes $e^{-}p\to
e^{-}W^{\pm}q+X$ and $e^{-}p\to e^{-}W^{\pm}bq+X$ in the collision of electron
beam with energy $E_e=$ 60 GeV and proton beam with energy $E_p=$ 50 TeV are
calculated. In the analysis, the invariant mass distributions of three jets
reconstructing top quark mass, requiring one b-tagged jet and other two jets
reconstructing the $W$ mass are used to count signal and background events
after all selection cuts. The upper limits on the anomalous flavor changing
neutral current $tq\gamma$ couplings are found to be $\lambda_q &lt; $ 0.01 at
future circular hadron electron collider for $L_{int}=100$ fb$^{-1}$ with the
fast simulation of detector effects. Signal significance depending on the
couplings $\lambda_q$ is analyzed and an enhanced sensitivity is found to the
branching ratio BR($t\to q\gamma$) at the future circular hadron electron
collider when compared to the current experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02270</id><created>2017-03-07</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eliashvili</keyname><forenames>Merab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsitsishvili</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Boundary Conditions and Formation of Pure Spin Currents in Magnetic
  Field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 93 (2017) 196</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2017.06.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Schr\&quot;odinger equation for an electron confined to a two-dimensional strip is
considered in the presence of homogeneous orthogonal magnetic field. Since the
system has edges, the eigenvalue problem is supplied by the boundary conditions
(BC) aimed in preventing the leakage of matter away across the edges. In the
case of spinless electrons the Dirichlet and Neumann BC are considered. The
Dirichlet BC result in the existence of charge carrying edge states. For the
Neumann BC each separate edge comprises two counterflow sub-currents which
precisely cancel out each other provided the system is populated by electrons
up to certain Fermi level. Cancelation of electric current is a good starting
point for developing the spin-effects. In this scope we reconsider the problem
for a spinning electron with Rashba coupling. The Neumann BC are replaced by
Robin BC. Again, the two counterflow electric sub-currents cancel out each
other for a separate edge, while the spin current survives thus modeling what
is known as pure spin current -- spin flow without charge flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02483</id><created>2017-03-07</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kirilin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadofyev</keyname><forenames>Andrey V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Transport and Generalized Axial Charge</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>19 pages, version accepted in PRD</comments><report-no>PUPT-2518, MIT-CTP/4888</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 016019 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.016019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we continue studying the modification of the axial charge in
chiral media by macroscopic helicities. Recently it was shown that magnetic
reconnections result in a persistent current of zero mode along flux tubes.
Here we argue that in general a change in the helical part of the generalized
axial charge results in the same phenomenon. Thus one may say that there is a
novel realization of chiral effects requiring no initial chiral asymmetry. The
transfer of flow helicity to zero modes is analyzed in a toy model based on a
vortex reconnection in a chiral superfluid. Then, we discuss the balance
between the two competing processes effect of reconnections and the chiral
instability on the example of magnetic helicity. We argue that in the general
case there is a possibility for the distribution of the axial charge between
the magnetic and fermionic forms at the end of the instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.03589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.03589</id><created>2017-03-10</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Arata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soda</keyname><forenames>Jiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear resonant oscillation of gravitational potential induced by
  ultralight axion in $f(R)$ gravity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, published version</comments><report-no>KOBE-COSMO-17-03</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 023534 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.023534</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ultralight axion dark matter with mass around $10^{-22}$ eV in
$f(R)$ gravity which might resolve the dark energy problem. In particular, we
focus on the fact that the pressure of the axion field oscillating in time
produces oscillations of gravitational potentials. We show that the oscillation
of the gravitational potential is sensitive to the model of gravity.
Remarkably, we find that the detectability of the oscillation through the
gravitational wave detectors can be significantly enhanced due to the nonlinear
resonance between the ultralight axion and the scalaron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10201</id><created>2017-03-29</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Muthukrishnan</keyname><forenames>Siddharth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lidar</keyname><forenames>Daniel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-adiabatic Grover search via the WKB approximation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 13 figures; updated to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 012329 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.012329</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In various applications one is interested in quantum dynamics at intermediate
evolution times, for which the adiabatic approximation is inadequate. Here we
develop a quasi-adiabatic approximation based on the WKB method, designed to
work for such intermediate evolution times. We apply it to the problem of a
single qubit in a time-varying magnetic field, and to the Hamiltonian Grover
search problem, and show that already at first order, the quasi-adiabatic WKB
captures subtle features of the dynamics that are missed by the adiabatic
approximation. However, we also find that the method is sensitive to the type
of interpolation schedule used in the Grover problem, and can give rise to
nonsensical results for the wrong schedule, due to loss of normalization.
Conversely, it reproduces the quadratic Grover speedup when the well-known
optimal schedule is used.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.10313</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.10313</id><created>2017-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>Siddarth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Zhiyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahadevan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wrinkling instability of an inhomogeneously stretched viscous sheet</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Fluids 2, 074103 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.2.074103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the redrawing of hot glass into thin sheets, we investigate the
shape and stability of a thin viscous sheet that is inhomogeneously stretched
in an imposed non-uniform temperature field. We first determine the associated
base flow by solving the long-timescale stretching flow of a flat sheet as a
function of two dimensionless parameters: the normalized stretching velocity
$\alpha$, and a dimensionless width of the heating zone $\beta$. This allows us
to determine the conditions for the onset of an out-of-plane wrinkling
instability stated in terms of an eigenvalue problem for a linear partial
differential equation governing the displacement of the midsurface of the
sheet. We show the sheet can become unstable in two regions that are upstream
and downstream of the heating zone where the minimum in-plane stress is
negative. This yields the shape and growth rates of the most unstable buckling
mode in both regions for various values of the stretching velocity and heating
zone width. A transition from stationary to oscillatory unstable modes is found
in the upstream region with increasing $\beta$ while the downstream region is
always stationary. We show that the wrinkling instability can be entirely
suppressed when the surface tension is large enough relative to the magnitude
of the in-plane stress. Finally, we present an operating diagram that indicates
regions of the parameter space that result in a required outlet sheet thickness
upon stretching, while simultaneously minimizing or suppressing the
out-of-plane buckling; a result that is relevant for the glass redraw method
used to create ultrathin glass sheets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00640</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-06-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dettmann</keyname><forenames>Carl P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>Georgie</forenames></author></authors><title>Symmetric motifs in random geometric graphs</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><msc-class>90B15, 47A10, 05C50, 05C80</msc-class><doi>10.1093/comnet/cnx022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study symmetric motifs in random geometric graphs. Symmetric motifs are
subsets of nodes which have the same adjacencies. These subgraphs are
particularly prevalent in random geometric graphs and appear in the Laplacian
and adjacency spectrum as sharp, distinct peaks, a feature often found in
real-world networks. We look at the probabilities of their appearance and
compare these across parameter space and dimension. We then use the Chen-Stein
method to derive the minimum separation distance in random geometric graphs
which we apply to study symmetric motifs in both the intensive and
thermodynamic limits. In the thermodynamic limit the probability that the
closest nodes are symmetric approaches one, whilst in the intensive limit this
probability depends upon the dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.01996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.01996</id><created>2017-04-06</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goodrich</keyname><forenames>Timothy D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Humble</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>Blair D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimizing Adiabatic Quantum Program Compilation using a Graph-Theoretic
  Framework</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adiabatic quantum computing has evolved in recent years from a theoretical
field into an immensely practical area, a change partially sparked by D-Wave
System's quantum annealing hardware. These multimillion-dollar quantum
annealers offer the potential to solve optimization problems millions of times
faster than classical heuristics, prompting researchers at Google, NASA and
Lockheed Martin to study how these computers can be applied to complex
real-world problems such as NASA rover missions. Unfortunately, compiling
(embedding) an optimization problem into the annealing hardware is itself a
difficult optimization problem and a major bottleneck currently preventing
widespread adoption. Additionally, while finding a single embedding is
difficult, no generalized method is known for tuning embeddings to use minimal
hardware resources. To address these barriers, we introduce a graph-theoretic
framework for developing structured embedding algorithms. Using this framework,
we introduce a biclique virtual hardware layer to provide a simplified
interface to the physical hardware. Additionally, we exploit bipartite
structure in quantum programs using odd cycle transversal (OCT) decompositions.
By coupling an OCT-based embedding algorithm with new, generalized reduction
methods, we develop a new baseline for embedding a wide range of optimization
problems into fault-free D-Wave annealing hardware. To encourage the reuse and
extension of these techniques, we provide an implementation of the framework
and embedding algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02838</id><created>2017-04-10</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bovenzi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breitkreiz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baireuther</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>T. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tworzydlo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adagideli</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beenakker</keyname><forenames>C. W. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chirality blockade of Andreev reflection in a magnetic Weyl semimetal</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures. V2: added investigation of the dependence of the
  chirality blockade on the direction of the magnetization and (Appendix C)
  calculations of the Fermi-arc mediated Josephson effect</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 035437 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.035437</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Weyl semimetal with broken time-reversal symmetry has a minimum of two
species of Weyl fermions, distinguished by their opposite chirality, in a pair
of Weyl cones at opposite momenta $\pm K$ that are displaced in the direction
of the magnetization. Andreev reflection at the interface between a Weyl
semimetal in the normal state (N) and a superconductor (S) that pairs $\pm K$
must involve a switch of chirality, otherwise it is blocked. We show that this
&quot;chirality blockade&quot; suppresses the superconducting proximity effect when the
magnetization lies in the plane of the NS interface. A Zeeman field at the
interface can provide the necessary chirality switch and activate Andreev
reflection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.03227</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.03227</id><created>2017-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Gopinath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Subrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polaki</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathews</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamruddin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transfer of Vertical Graphene Nanosheets onto Flexible Substrates
  towards Supercapacitor Application</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1088/1361-6528/aa8252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Vertical graphene nanosheets (VGNs) are the material of choice for
next-generation electronic device applications. The growing demand for flexible
devices in electronic industry brings in restriction on growth temperature of
the material of interest. However, VGNs with better structural quality is
usually achieved at high growth temperatures. The difficulty associated with
the direct growth on flexible substrates can overcome by adopting an effective
strategy of transferring the well grown VGNs onto arbitrary flexible substrates
through soft chemistry route. Hence, we demonstrated a simple, inexpensive and
scalable technique for the transfer of VGNs onto arbitrary substrates without
disrupting its morphology and structural properties. After transfer, the
morphology, chemical structure and electronic properties are analyzed by
scanning electron microscopy, Raman spectroscopy and four probe resistive
methods, respectively. Associated characterization investigation indicates the
retention of morphological, structural and electrical properties of transferred
VGNs compared to as-grown one. Furthermore the storage capacity of the VGNs
transferred onto flexible substrates is also examined. A very lower sheet
resistance of 0.67 kOhm/sq. and excellent supercapacitance of 158
micro-Farrad/cm2 with 91.4% retention after 2000 cycles confirms the great
prospective of this damage-free transfer approach of VGNs for flexible
nanoelectronic device applications
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.06968</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.06968</id><created>2017-04-23</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maris</keyname><forenames>Pieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vary</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quarkonium as relativistic bound state on the light front</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>28 pages, 17 figures, 5 tables. Supplemental Materials are provided
  in the source file under &quot;Other formats&quot; (see also &quot;Ancillary files&quot;)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 016022 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.016022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study charmonium and bottomonium as relativistic bound states in a
light-front quantized Hamiltonian formalism. The effective Hamiltonian is based
on light-front holography. We use a recently proposed longitudinal confinement
to complete the soft-wall holographic potential for the heavy flavors. The spin
structure is generated from the one-gluon exchange interaction with a running
coupling. The adoption of asymptotic freedom improves the spectroscopy compared
with previous light-front results. Within this model, we compute the mass
spectroscopy, decay constants and the r.m.s. radii. We also present a detailed
study of the obtained light-front wave functions and use the wave functions to
compute the light-cone distributions, specifically the distribution amplitudes
and parton distribution functions. Overall, our model provides a reasonable
description of the heavy quarkonia.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.00592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.00592</id><created>2017-05-01</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Shu-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toma</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsumura</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>A Radiative Neutrino Mass Model with SIMP Dark Matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables, expanded, new appendix added, new
  references added, updated plots, fixed minor typos, matches journal version</comments><report-no>KUNS-2675, TUM-HEP/1082/17</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1707 (2017) 101</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2017)101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the first viable radiative seesaw model, in which the neutrino
masses are induced radiatively via the two-loop Feynman diagram involving
Strongly Interacting Massive Particles (SIMP). The stability of SIMP dark
matter (DM) is ensured by a $\mathbb{Z}_5$ discrete symmetry, through which the
DM annihilation rate is dominated by the $3 \to 2$ self-annihilating processes.
The right amount of thermal relic abundance can be obtained with perturbative
couplings in the resonant SIMP scenario, while the astrophysical bounds
inferred from the Bullet cluster and spherical halo shapes can be satisfied. We
show that SIMP DM is able to maintain kinetic equilibrium with thermal plasma
until the freeze-out temperature via the Yukawa interactions associated with
neutrino mass generation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01105</id><created>2017-05-02</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>Nicole F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dent</keyname><forenames>James B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leane</keyname><forenames>Rebecca K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiler</keyname><forenames>Thomas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing Dark Matter Annihilation Rates with Dark Bremsstrahlung</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables. v2: minor changes, matches version
  published in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 023011 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.023011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many dark matter interaction types lead to annihilation processes which
suffer from p-wave suppression or helicity suppression, rendering them
subdominant to unsuppressed s-wave processes. We demonstrate that the natural
inclusion of dark initial state radiation can open an unsuppressed s-wave
annihilation channel, and thus provide the dominant dark matter annihilation
process for particular interaction types. We illustrate this effect with the
bremsstrahlung of a dark spin-0 or dark spin-1 particle from fermionic dark
matter, $\overline{\chi}\chi\rightarrow \overline{f}f\phi$ or
$\overline{f}fZ'$. The dark initial state radiation process, despite having a
3-body final state, proceeds at the same order in the new physics scale
$\Lambda$ as the annihilation to the 2-body final state
$\overline{\chi}\chi\rightarrow \overline{f}f$. This is lower order in
$\Lambda$ than the well-studied lifting of helicity suppression via Standard
Model final state radiation, or virtual internal bremsstrahlung. This dark
bremsstrahlung process should influence LHC and indirect detection searches for
dark matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.04154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.04154</id><created>2017-05-11</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lopez-Eiguren</keyname><forenames>Asier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizarraga</keyname><forenames>Joanes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hindmarsh</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urrestilla</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Microwave Background constraints for global strings and global
  monopoles</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>Minor changes, matches published version; 24 pages, 9 figures</comments><report-no>HIP-2017-07/TH</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP 1707 (2017) no.07, 026</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2017/07/026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the first CMB power spectra from numerical simulations of the
global O(N) linear $\sigma$-model with N = 2,3, which have global strings and
monopoles as topological defects. In order to compute the CMB power spectra we
compute the unequal time correlators (UETCs) of the energy-momentum tensor,
showing that they fall off at high wave number faster than naive estimates
based on the geometry of the defects, indicating non-trivial
(anti-)correlations between the defects and the surrounding Goldstone boson
field. We obtain source functions for Einstein-Boltzmann solvers from the
UETCs, using a recent method that improves the modelling at the radiation-
matter transition. We show that the interpolation function that mimics the
transition is similar to other defect models, but not identical, confirming the
non-universality of the interpolation function. The CMB power spectra for
global strings and monopoles have the same overall shape as those obtained
using the non-linear $\sigma$-model approximation, which is well captured by a
large-N calculation. However, the amplitudes are larger than the large-N
calculation predict, and in the case of global strings much larger: a factor of
20 at the peak. Finally we compare the CMB power spectra with the latest CMB
data to put limits on the allowed contribution to the temperature power
spectrum at multipole $\ell$ = 10 of 1.7% for global strings and 2.4% for
global monopoles. These limits correspond to symmetry-breaking scales of
2.9x1015 GeV (6.3x1014 GeV with the expected logarithmic scaling of the
effective string tension between the simulation time and decoupling) and
6.4x1015 GeV respectively. The bound on global strings is a significant one for
the ultra-light axion scenario with axion masses ma 10-28 eV. These upper
limits indicate that gravitational wave from global topological defects will
not be observable at the GW observatory LISA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.05294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.05294</id><created>2017-05-15</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duclut</keyname><forenames>Charlie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delamotte</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-universality in the erosion of tilted landscapes</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.AO physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 012149 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.012149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The anisotropic model for landscapes erosion proposed by Pastor-Satorras and
Rothman in [R. Pastor-Satorras and D. H. Rothman, Phys. Rev. Lett. 80, 4349
(1998)] is believed to capture the physics of erosion at intermediate length
scale ($\lesssim3$ km), and to account for the large value of the roughness
exponent $\alpha$ observed in real data at this scale. Our study of this model
-- conducted using the nonperturbative renormalization group (NPRG) --
concludes on the nonuniversality of this exponent because of the existence of a
line of fixed points. Thus the roughness exponent depends (weakly) on the
details of the soil and the erosion mechanisms. We conjecture that this
feature, while preserving the generic scaling observed in real data, could
explain the wide spectrum of values of $\alpha$ measured for natural
landscapes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07166</id><created>2017-05-19</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dupont</keyname><forenames>Maxime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capponi</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horvati&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Mladen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laflorencie</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing Bose-Glass physics with disorder-induced Bose-Einstein
  condensation in the doped $S=1$ antiferromagnet
  Ni(Cl$_{1-x}$Br$_x$)$_2$-4SC(NH$_2$)$_2$ at high magnetic fields</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>16 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024442 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024442</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interplay between disorder and interactions for emergent bosonic
degrees of freedom induced by an external magnetic field in the Br-doped
spin-gapped antiferromagnetic material Ni(Cl$_{1-x}$Br$_x$)$_2$-4SC(NH$_2$)$_2$
(DTNX). Building on nuclear magnetic resonance experiments at high magnetic
field [A. Orlova et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 067203 (2017)], we describe the
localization of isolated impurity states, providing a realistic theoretical
modeling for DTNX. Going beyond single impurity localization we use quantum
Monte Carlo simulations to explore many-body effects from which pairwise
effective interactions lead to a (impurity-induced) BEC revival [M. Dupont, S.
Capponi, and N. Laflorencie, Phys. Rev. Lett. 118, 067204 (2017)]. We further
address the question of the existence of a many-body localized Bose-glass (BG)
phase in DTNX, which is found to compete with a series of a new kind of BEC
regimes made out of the multi-impurity states. The global magnetic
field-temperature phase diagram of DTNX reveals a very rich structure for low
impurity concentration, with consecutive disorder-induced BEC mini-domes
separated by intervening many-body localized BG regimes. Upon increasing the
impurity level, multiple mini-BEC phases start to overlap, while intermediate
BG regions vanish.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09030</id><created>2017-05-24</created><updated>2017-07-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Muxin</forenames></author></authors><title>Einstein Equation from Covariant Loop Quantum Gravity in Semiclassical
  Continuum Limit</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>12+3 pages, no figure, presentation improved</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 024047 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.024047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we explain how 4-dimensional general relativity and in
particular, the Einstein equation, emerge from the spinfoam amplitude in loop
quantum gravity. We propose a new limit which couples both the semiclassical
limit and continuum limit of spinfoam amplitudes. The continuum Einstein
equation emerges in this limit. Solutions of Einstein equation can be
approached by dominant configurations in spinfoam amplitudes. A running scale
is naturally associated to the sequence of refined triangulations. The
continuum limit corresponds to the infrared limit of the running scale. An
important ingredient in the derivation is a regularization for the sum over
spins, which is necessary for the semiclassical continuum limit. We also
explain in this paper the role played by the so-called flatness in spinfoam
formulation, and how to take advantage of it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.09191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.09191</id><created>2017-05-25</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lamb</keyname><forenames>Gavin P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Shiho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pian</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author></authors><title>Extending the &quot;Energetic Scaling of Relativistic Jets From Black Hole
  Systems&quot; to Include $\gamma$-ray-loud X-ray Binaries</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures. Accepted 26 Jul 2017 by MNRAS, text and title
  updated to match accepted version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1933</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the jet power $P_j$ and geometrically corrected $\gamma$-ray
luminosity $L_\gamma$ for the X-ray binaries (XRBs) Cygnus X-1, Cygnus X-3, and
V404 Cygni, and $\gamma$-ray upper limits for GRS 1915+105 and GX339-4, follow
the universal scaling for the energetics of relativistic jets from black hole
(BH) systems found by Nemmen et al. (2012) for blazars and GRBs. The observed
peak $\gamma$-ray luminosity for XRBs is geometrically corrected; and the
minimum jet power is estimated from the peak flux density of radio flares and
the flare rise time. The $L_\gamma-P_j$ correlation holds across $\sim 17$
orders of magnitude. The correlation suggests a jet origin for the high energy
emission from X-ray binaries, and indicates a common mechanism or efficiency
for the high energy emission 0.1-100 GeV from all relativistic BH systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03209</id><created>2017-06-10</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jana</keyname><forenames>Soumya</forenames><affiliation>IIT Kharagpur, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kar</keyname><forenames>Sayan</forenames><affiliation>IIT Kharagpur, India</affiliation></author></authors><title>Born-Infeld gravity with a Brans-Dicke scalar</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures. Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 024050 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.024050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently proposed Born-Infeld (BI) theories of gravity assume a constant BI
parameter ($\kappa$). However, no clear consensus exists on the sign and value
of $\kappa$. Recalling the Brans-Dicke (BD) approach, where a scalar field was
used to generate the gravitational constant $G$, we suggest an extension of
Born-Infeld gravity with a similar Brans-Dicke flavor. Thus, a new action, with
$\kappa$ elevated to a spacetime dependent real scalar field, is proposed. We
illustrate this new theory in a cosmological setting with pressureless dust and
radiation as matter. Assuming a functional form of $\kappa(t)$, we numerically
obtain the scale factor evolution and other details of the background
cosmology. It is known that BI gravity differs from general relativity (GR) in
the strong-field regime but reduces to GR for intermediate and weak fields. Our
studies in cosmology demonstrate how, with this new, scalar-tensor BI gravity,
deviations from GR as well as usual BI gravity, may arise in the weak-field
regime too. For example, we note a late-time acceleration without any dark
energy contribution. Apart from such qualitative differences, we note that
fixing the sign and value of $\kappa$ is no longer a necessity in this theory,
though the origin of the BD scalar does remain an open question.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03859</id><created>2017-06-12</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Laciana</keyname><forenames>Carlos E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereyra</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovere</keyname><forenames>Santiago L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Size invariance sector for an agent-based innovation diffusion model</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.CY cs.SI</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that under certain conditions it is possible to model a complex
system in a way that leads to results that do not depend on system size. As an
example of complex system an innovation diffusion model is considered. In that
model a set of individuals (the agents), which are interconnected, must decide
if adopt or not an innovation. The agents are connected in a member of the
networks family known as small worlds networks (SWN). It is found that for a
subfamily of the SWN the saturation time and the form of the adoption curve are
invariants respect to the change in the size of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05270</id><created>2017-06-16</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yasin</keyname><forenames>Alhassan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Nianqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musho</keyname><forenames>Terence</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio Screening of a Sulfur Desorbed MoS$_2$ Photocatalyst for
  Nitrogen Fixation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The following study investigates the thermodynamic reaction barriers during
nitrogen fixation for an inorganic sulfur desorbed photocatalyst Molybdenum
disulfide surface. The design space is investigated using an density functional
theory (DFT) method within a space bound by MMoS$_2$ M=Mo,Fe,Co. The discussion
focuses on Heyrovsky type reactions along both the associative and dissociative
pathway. A key insight into the roles of the inorganic and the balance between
nitrogen and hydrogen affinity, providing evidence for an optimal material that
minimizes the required over-potential. It is found that phases with a higher
concentration of Mo face high reaction barrier involving nitrogen, where phases
with higher concentrations of Fe and Co face high reaction barriers involving
hydrogen species. In the absence of kinetic considerations, the best phase was
predicted to be the 1T phase with a Mo$_{0.75}$Fe$_{0.25}$S$_{2}$ composition.
This phase proved to have a balance of hydrogen and nitrogen affinity and
follows the dissociative pathway, which can be evolved through non-thermal
methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.05332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.05332</id><created>2017-06-16</created><updated>2017-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zazunov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egger</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarado</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yeyati</keyname><forenames>A. Levy</forenames></author></authors><title>Josephson effect in multiterminal topological junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures, final version (minor changes) to appear in PRB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 024516 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.024516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Josephson effect in a trijunction formed by two topological
superconductor (TS) wires and a conventional $s$-wave superconductor. Using a
boundary Green's function formalism, analytical results for the current-phase
relation are obtained in various limiting cases by modeling the TS wires via
the low-energy limit of a Kitaev chain. We show that Josephson transport
critically depends on the spin canting angle $\theta$ between the boundary spin
polarizations of the TS wires, which in turn suggests that the spin structure
of Majorana states can be accessed through supercurrent measurements. We also
extend the boundary Green's function approach to a more microscopic spinful
wire model and thereby compute the dependence of $\theta$ on experimentally
accessible parameters such as the Zeeman field and/or the chemical potential.
Furthermore, we show that the equilibrium current-phase relation between both
TS wires exhibits a robust $4\pi$-periodicity since the conventional
superconducting lead effectively locks the fermion parity of the trijunction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09686</id><created>2017-06-29</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Klerk</keyname><forenames>Niek J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasileiadis</keyname><forenames>Alexandros</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Raymond B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazant</keyname><forenames>Martin Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagemaker</keyname><forenames>Marnix</forenames></author></authors><title>Explaining key properties of lithiation in TiO$_2$-anatase Li-ion
  battery electrodes using phase-field modelling</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures, Supplementary Information available. Changes
  with respect to the previous version: Corrected typography in certain
  formulas, and a couple of small corrections to the text</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Materials 1 (2017) 025404</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.025404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The improvement of Li-ion battery performance requires development of models
that capture the essential physics and chemistry in Li-ion battery electrode
materials. In this paper a novel electrochemical phase-field model is presented
that captures the thermodynamic and kinetic properties of lithium-insertion in
TiO$_2$-anatase, a well-known and intensively studied Li-ion battery electrode
material. Previous experimental work on lithiated anatase TiO$_2$ provided all
parameters necessary for the phase-field simulations, giving the opportunity to
gain fundamental insight in the lithiation of anatase and validate this
phase-field model. The phase-field model captures the essential experimentally
observed phenomena, rationalising the impact of C-rate, particle size, surface
area, and the memory effect on the performance of anatase as a Li-ion battery
electrode. Thereby a comprehensive physical picture of the lithiation of
anatase TiO$_2$ is provided. The results of the simulations demonstrate that
the performance of anatase is limited by the formation of the poor Li-ion
diffusion in the Li$_1$TiO$_2$ phase at the surface of the particles. Unlike
other electrode materials, the kinetic limitations of individual anatase
particles limit the performance of full electrodes. Hence, rather than
improving the ionic and electronic network in electrodes, improving the
performance of anatase TiO$_2$ electrodes requires preventing the formation of
a blocking Li$_1$TiO$_2$ phase at the surface of particles. Additionally, the
qualitative agreement of the phase-field model, containing only parameters from
literature, with a broad spectrum of experiments demonstrates the capabilities
of phase-field models for understanding Li-ion electrode materials, and its
promise for guiding the design of electrodes through a thorough understanding
of material properties and their interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.09781</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.09781</id><created>2017-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Somanchi</keyname><forenames>Sowmya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terr&#xe9;s</keyname><forenames>Bernat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peiro</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staggenborg</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beschoten</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampfer</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>From diffusive to ballistic transport in etched graphene constrictions
  and nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>32 pages, 6 figures. Will appear in Annalen der Physik</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 529, 1700082 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201700082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene nanoribbons and constrictions are envisaged as fundamental
components of future carbon-based nanoelectronic and spintronic devices. At
nanoscale, electronic effects in these devices depend heavily on the dimensions
of the active channel and the nature of edges. Hence, controlling both these
parameters is crucial to understand the physics in such systems. This review is
about the recent progress in the fabrication of graphene nanoribbons and
constrictions in terms of low temperature quantum transport. In particular,
recent advancements using encapsulated graphene allowing for quantized
conductance and future experiments towards exploring spin effects in these
devices are presented. The influence of charge carrier inhomogeneity and the
important length scales which play a crucial role for transport in high quality
samples are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.10015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.10015</id><created>2017-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Man</keyname><forenames>Xingkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>Masao</forenames></author></authors><title>Vapor-Induced Motion of Liquid Droplets on an Inert Substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>11pages,4figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 044502 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.044502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Evaporating droplets are known to show complex motion that has conventionally
been explained by the Marangoni effect (flow induced by the gradient of surface
tension). Here, we show that the droplet motion can be induced even in the
absence of the Marangoni effect due to the gradient of evaporation rate. We
derive an equation for the velocity of a droplet subject to non-uniform
evaporation rate and non-uniform surface tension placed on an inert substrate
where the wettability is uniform and unchanged. The equation explains the
previously observed attraction-repulsion- chasing behaviors of evaporating
droplets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.02872</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.02872</id><created>2017-07-07</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez-Pastora</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical properties of a source of the Kerr metric: Bound on the surface
  gravitational potential and conditions for the fragmentation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Some typos corrected. Published in PRD. arXiv
  admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1701.02098</comments><journal-ref>PRD 96, 024048 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.024048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate some important physical aspects of a recently presented
interior solution for the Kerr metric. It is shown that, as in the spherically
symmetric case, there is a specific limit for the maximal value of the surface
potential (degree of compactness), beyond which, unacceptable physical
anomalies appear. Such a bound is related to the appearance of negative
(repulsive) gravitational acceleration, that is accompanied by the appearance
of negative values of the pressure. A detailed discussion on this effect is
presented. We also study the possibility of a fragmentation scenario, assuming
that the source leaves the equilibrium, and we bring out the differences with
the spherically symmetric case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.03691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.03691</id><created>2017-07-12</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Qin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author></authors><title>Charmless $B_{c} \to VV$ decays in the QCD factorization approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><doi>10.1088/1361-6471/aa7bca</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we studied the charmless $B_{c}\to VV$ ($V$ denotes the light
ground $\rm SU(3)$ vector meson) decays within the framework of QCD
factorization. In the evaluation, two different schemes for regulating the
end-point divergence are adopted. One (scheme I) is to use parameterization
model, which is usually employed in the QCD factorization approach; the other
(scheme II) is based on the infrared finite gluon propagator of Cornwall
prescription. It is found that, in the annihilation amplitudes, the end-point
divergence appears only in the power-suppressed corrections related to the
twist-3 distribution amplitudes of $V$-meson. The strength of annihilation
amplitudes evaluated in scheme II is generally larger than the one in scheme I.
Numerically, in the decay modes considered in this paper, the CKM-favored
$B_{c} \to \rho^{-}\omega, K^{*-}K^{*0} $ decays have the relatively large
branching fractions, $\sim {\cal{O}}(10^{-7})$, and hence are likely to be the
first observed by the future experiments. In addition, all of the decay modes
are dominated by the longitudinal polarization state; numerically, $f_{L}(B_{c}
\to VV) \gtrsim 99\%$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.04429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.04429</id><created>2017-07-14</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Limei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Xiaoxiong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhonghua</forenames></author></authors><title>AdS Black Hole with Phantom Scalar Field</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present an AdS black hole solution with Ricci flat horizon
in Einstein-phantom scalar theory. The phantom scalar fields just depend on the
transverse coordinates $x$ and $y$, and which are parameterized by the
parameter $\alpha$. We study the thermodynamics of the AdS phantom black hole.
Although its horizon is a Ricci flat Euclidean space, we find that the
thermodynamical properties of the black hole solution are qualitatively same as
those of AdS Schwarzschild black hole. Namely there exists a minimal
temperature, the large black hole is thermodynamically stable , while the
smaller one is unstable, so there is a so-called Hawking-Page phase transition
between the large black hole and the thermal gas solution in the AdS spacetime
in Poincare coordinates. We also calculate the entanglement entropy for a strip
geometry dual to the AdS phantom black holes and find that the behavior of the
entanglement entropy is qualitatively the same as that of the black hole
thermodynamical entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.07599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.07599</id><created>2017-07-24</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cabras</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Movchan</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piccolroaz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet-Bloch waves in periodic networks of the Rayleigh beams:
  honeycomb systems, dispersion degeneracies and structured interfaces</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper addresses novel dispersion properties of elastic flexural waves in
periodic structures which possess rotational inertia. The structure is
represented as a lattice, whose elementary links are formally defined as the
Rayleigh beams. Although in the quasi-static regime such beams respond
similarly to the classical Euler-Bernoulli beams, as the frequency increases
the dispersion of flexural waves possesses new interesting features. For a
doubly periodic lattice, we give a special attention to degeneracies associated
with so-called Dirac cones on the dispersion surfaces as well as directional
anisotropy. Comparative analysis for Floquet-Bloch waves in periodic flexural
lattices of different geometries is presented and accompanied by numerical
simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08565</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Celik</keyname><forenames>Halise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kannan</keyname><forenames>Harsha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mellnik</keyname><forenames>Alex R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xinran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ralph</keyname><forenames>Daniel C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doty</keyname><forenames>Matthew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorenz</keyname><forenames>Virginia O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>John Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>3D MOKE spin-orbit torque magnetometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate simultaneous detection of current driven antidamping-like and
field-like spin-orbit torques in heavy metal/ferromagnetic metal bilayers by
measuring all three magnetization components m_(x,) m_y, and m_z using the
vector magneto-optic Kerr effect. We have also implemented a self-calibration
method to accurately determine the effective fields of spin-orbit torques. With
this technique, we investigate the magnitude and direction of spin-orbit
torques in a series of platinum/permalloy samples. The values found are in
excellent agreement with results obtained via quadratic magneto-optic Kerr
effect, planar Hall effect, and spin transfer ferromagnetic resonance
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08566</id><created>2017-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Gizon</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fournier</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hohage</keyname><forenames>Thorsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Problems in computational helioseismology</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Oberwolfach Report, Computational Inverse Problems for Partial
  Differential Equations, 14 May - 20 May 2017.
  https://www.mfo.de/occasion/1720/www_view</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss current advances in forward and inverse modeling for local
helioseismology. We report theoretical uniqueness results, in particular the
Novikov-Agaltsov reconstruction algorithm, which is relevant to solving the
non-linear inverse problem of time-distance helioseismology (finite amplitude
pertubations to the medium). Numerical experiments were conducted to determine
the number of frequencies required to reconstruct density and sound speed in
the solar interior.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08572</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08572</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Heringer</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Kerkwijk</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sim</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kerzendorf</keyname><forenames>W. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral sequences of Type Ia supernovae. I. Connecting normal and
  sub-luminous SN Ia and the presence of unburned carbon</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Type Ia supernovae are generally agreed to arise from thermonuclear
explosions of carbon-oxygen white dwarfs. The actual path to explosion,
however, remains elusive, with numerous plausible parent systems and explosion
mechanisms suggested. Observationally, type Ia supernovae have multiple
subclasses, distinguished by their lightcurves and spectra. This raises the
question whether these reflect that multiple mechanisms occur in nature, or
instead that explosions have a large but continuous range of physical
properties. We revisit the idea that normal and 91bg-like supernovae can be
understood as part of a spectral sequence, in which changes in temperature
dominate. Specifically, we find that a single ejecta structure is sufficient to
provide reasonable fits of both the normal type Ia supernova SN~2011fe and the
91bg-like SN~2005bl, provided that the luminosity and thus temperature of the
ejecta are adjusted appropriately. This suggests that the outer layers of the
ejecta are similar, thus providing some support of a common explosion
mechanism. Our spectral sequence also helps to shed light on the conditions
under which carbon can be detected in pre-maximum SN~Ia spectra -- we find that
emission from iron can &quot;fill in&quot; the carbon trough in cool SN~Ia. This may
indicate that the outer layers of the ejecta of events in which carbon is
detected are relatively metal poor compared to events where carbon is not
detected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08574</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08574</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Decataldo</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pallottini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallerani</keyname><forenames>Simona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallini</keyname><forenames>Livia</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular clumps photoevaporation in ionized regions</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1879</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the photoevaporation of molecular clumps exposed to a UV radiation
field including hydrogen-ionizing photons ($h\nu &gt; 13.6$ eV) produced by
massive stars or quasars. We follow the propagation and collision of shock
waves inside clumps and take into account self-shielding effects, determining
the evolution of clump size and density with time. The structure of the
ionization-photodissociation region (iPDR) is obtained for different initial
clump masses ($M=0.01 - 10^4\,{\rm M}_\odot$) and impinging fluxes ($G_0=10^2 -
10^5$ in units of the Habing flux). The cases of molecular clumps engulfed in
the HII region of an OB star and clumps carried within quasar outflows are
treated separately. We find that the clump undergoes in both cases an initial
shock-contraction phase and a following expansion phase, which lets the
radiation penetrate in until the clump is completely evaporated. Typical
evaporation time-scales are $\simeq 0.01$ Myr in the stellar case and 0.1 Myr
in the quasar case, where the clump mass is 0.1 ${\rm M}_\odot$ and $10^3\,{\rm
M}_\odot$ respectively. We find that clump lifetimes in quasar outflows are
compatible with their observed extension, suggesting that photoevaporation is
the main mechanism regulating the size of molecular outflows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08601</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kariyado</keyname><forenames>Toshikaze</forenames></author></authors><title>Counting Pseudo Landau Levels in Spatially Modulated Dirac Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a system with Dirac cones, spatial modulation in material parameters
induces a pseudo magnetic field, which acts like an external magnetic field.
Here, we derive a concise formula to count the pseudo Landau levels in the
simplest setup for having a pseudo magnetic field. The formula is so concise
that it is helpful in seeing the essence of the phenomenon, and in considering
the experimental design for the pseudo magnetic field. Furthermore, it is
revealed that anisotropic Dirac cones are advantageous in pseudo Landau level
formation in general. The proposed setup is relatively easy to be realized by
spatial modulation in the chemical composition, and we perform an estimation of
the pseudo magnetic field in an existing material (an antiperovskite material),
by following the composition dependence with the help of the ab-initio method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08607</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmad</keyname><forenames>Rehan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Kevin S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of Contact Network Models on Stochastic Epidemic Simulations</title><categories>cs.SI cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>To appear at International Conference on Social Informatics (SocInfo)
  2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The importance of modeling the spread of epidemics through a population has
led to the development of mathematical models for infectious disease
propagation. A number of empirical studies have collected and analyzed data on
contacts between individuals using a variety of sensors. Typically one uses
such data to fit a probabilistic model of network contacts over which a disease
may propagate. In this paper, we investigate the effects of different contact
network models with varying levels of complexity on the outcomes of simulated
epidemics using a stochastic Susceptible-Infectious-Recovered (SIR) model. We
evaluate these network models on six datasets of contacts between people in a
variety of settings. Our results demonstrate that the choice of network model
can have a significant effect on how closely the outcomes of an epidemic
simulation on a simulated network match the outcomes on the actual network
constructed from the sensor data. In particular, preserving degrees of nodes
appears to be much more important than preserving cluster structure for
accurate epidemic simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08628</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gaudenzi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesci</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sclavi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gigoyan</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mickaelian</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral Properties and Variability of BIS objects</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>28 pages, 3 figures, accepted by Revista Mexicana de Astronomia y
  Astrofisica</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Through the analysis and interpretation of newly obtained and of literature
data we have clarified the nature of poorly investigated IRAS point sources
classified as late type stars, belonging to the Byurakan IRAS ~Stars catalog.
From medium resolution spectroscopyof 95 stars we have strongly revised 47
spectral types and newly classified 31 sources. Nine stars are of G or K types,
four are N carbon stars in the Asymptotic Giant Branch, the others being M type
stars. From literature and new photometric observations we have studied their
variability behaviour. For the regular variables we determined distances,
absolute magnitudes and mass loss rates. For the other stars we estimated the
distances, ranging between 1.3 and 10~kpc with a median of 2.8~kpc from the
galactic plane, indicating that BIS stars mostly belong to the halo population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08637</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Iurov</keyname><forenames>Andrii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gumbs</keyname><forenames>Godfrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Danhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balakrishnan</keyname><forenames>Ganesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-temperature Coulomb Excitations in Extrinsic Dirac Structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>22 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have derived algebraic, analytic expressions for the chemical potential
without any restriction on temperature for all types of doped, or extrinsic,
gapped Dirac cone materials including gapped graphene, silicene, germanene and
single-layer transition metal dichalcogenides. As an important intermediate
step of our derivations, we have established a reliable piecewise-linear model
for cal- culating the density-of-states in molybdenum disulfide, showing good
agreement with previously obtained numerical results. For the spin- and
valley-resolved band structure, we obtain an additional decrease of the
chemical potential due to thermally induced doping of the upper subband at
finite temperature. It has been demonstrated that since the symmetry between
the electron and hole states in $MoS_2$ is broken, the chemical potential could
cross the zero-energy level at sufficiently high temperature. These results
allow us to investigate the collective properties, polarizability, plasmons and
their damping. Emphasis is placed on low temperatures, when initial electron
doping plays a crucial role. We clearly demonstrated the contribution of the
initial doping to the finite-temperature collective properties of the
considered materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08639</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08639</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gleason</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manton</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheung</keyname><forenames>Janet</forenames></author><author><keyname>Byrum</keyname><forenames>Taylor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jensen</keyname><forenames>Cody</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Lingyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dvorak</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarrige</keyname><forenames>Ignace</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbamonte</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic resolving power of XUV diffraction gratings measured with
  Fizeau interferometry</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a method for using Fizeau interferometry to measure the
intrinsic resolving power of a diffraction grating. This method is more
accurate than traditional techniques based on a long-trace profiler (LTP),
since it is sensitive to long-distance phase errors not revealed by a d-spacing
map. We demonstrate 50,400 resolving power for a mechanically ruled XUV grating
from Inprentus, Inc.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08641</id><created>2017-07-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Maudlin</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author></authors><title>Time Symmetric Quantum Theory Without Retrocausality</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In their recent paper &quot;Is a Time Symmetric Interpretation of Quantum Theory
Possible Without Retrocausality?&quot;, Matthew Leifer and Matthew Pusey argue that
the answer to their title question is &quot;no&quot;. Unfortunately, the central proof
offered in the paper contains a fatal error, and the conclusion cannot be
established. Interpretations of quantum theory without retrocausalty can be
time symmetric not only in the traditional sense but also in Leifer and Pusey's
supposedly stricter sense. There appear to be no prospects for proving any
analogous theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08642</id><created>2017-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Spirichev</keyname><forenames>Yurii A.</forenames></author></authors><title>About the Abraham force in a conducting medium</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The article is devoted to the Abraham force in a conducting medium. From the
energy-momentum tensor of the electromagnetic field interaction with moving
charges the equation for the Abraham force is obtained. It is shown that the
Abraham force in a conducting medium, as well as in a dielectric medium, has
vortical character. Current density vectors and vector potential must be
non-collinear
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08648</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Storey</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Incoherent superconductivity well above $T_c$ in high-$T_c$ cuprates -
  harmonizing the spectroscopic and thermodynamic data</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 19, 073026 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa79bf</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cuprate superconductors have long been known to exhibit an energy gap that
persists high above the superconducting transition temperature ($T_c$). Debate
has continued now for decades as to whether it is a precursor superconducting
gap or a pseudogap arising from some competing correlation. Failure to resolve
this has arguably delayed explaining the origins of superconductivity in these
highly complex materials. Here we effectively settle the question by
calculating a variety of thermodynamic and spectroscopic properties, exploring
the effect of a temperature-dependent pair-breaking term in the self-energy in
the presence of pairing interactions that persist well above $T_c$. We start by
fitting the detailed temperature-dependence of the electronic specific heat and
immediately can explain its hitherto puzzling field dependence. Taking this
same combination of pairing temperature and pair-breaking scattering we are
then able to simultaneously describe in detail the unusual temperature and
field dependence of the superfluid density, tunneling, Raman and optical
spectra, which otherwise defy explanation in terms a superconducting gap that
closes conventionally at $T_c$. These findings demonstrate that the gap above
$T_c$ in the overdoped regime likely originates from incoherent superconducting
correlations, and is distinct from the competing-order &quot;pseudogap&quot; that appears
at lower doping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08657</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Ye-Heng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Zhen-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xin-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Qian-Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Da-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Shao-Chun</forenames></author></authors><title>High-buckled R3 stanene with topologically nontrivial energy gap</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stanene has been predicted to be a two-dimensional topological insulator
(2DTI). Its low-buckled atomic geometry and the enhanced spin-orbit coupling
are expected to cause a prominent quantum spin hall (QSH) effect. However, most
of the experimentally grown stanene to date displays a metallic state without a
real gap, possibly due to the chemical coupling with the substrate and the
stress applied by the substrate. Here,we demonstrate an efficient way of tuning
the atomic buckling in stanene to open a topologically nontrivial energy gap.
Via tuning the growth kinetics, we obtain not only the low-buckled 1x1 stanene
but also an unexpected high-buckled R3xR3 stanene on the Bi(111) substrate.
Scanning tunneling microscopy (STM) study combined with density functional
theory (DFT) calculation confirms that the R3xR3 stanene is a distorted 1x1
structure with a high-buckled Sn in every three 1x1 unit cells. The
high-buckled R3xR3 stanene favors a large band inversion at the {\Gamma} point,
and the spin orbital coupling open a topologically nontrivial energy gap. The
existence of edge states as verified in both STM measurement and DFT
calculation further confirms the topology of the R3xR3 stanene. This study
provides an alternate way to tune the topology of monolayer 2DTI materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08663</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaverri-Miranda</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frutos-Alfaro</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez-Ovarez</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva-Mercado</keyname><forenames>Andree</forenames></author></authors><title>Innermost stable circular orbits of a Kerr-like Metric with Quadrupole</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The innermost stable circular orbit equation of a test particle is obtained
for an approximate Kerr-like spacetime with quadrupole moment. We derived the
effective potential for the radial coordinate by the Euler-Lagrange method.
This equation can be employed to measure the mass quadrupole by observational
means, because from this equation a quadratic polynomial for the quadrupole
moment can be found. As expected, the limiting cases of this equation are found
to be the known cases of Kerr and Schwarzschild.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08670</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mizukami</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konczykowski</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuura</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watashige</keyname><forenames>Tatsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasahara</keyname><forenames>Shigeru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibauchi</keyname><forenames>Takasada</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Disorder on the Superconducting Phase Diagram in
  BaFe$_2$(As$_{1-x}$P$_x$)$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 86, 083706 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.86.083706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In many classes of unconventional superconductors, the question of whether
the superconductivity is enhanced by the quantum-critical fluctuations on the
verge of an ordered phase remains elusive. One of the most direct ways of
addressing this issue is to investigate how the superconducting dome traces a
shift of the ordered phase. Here, we study how the phase diagram of the
iron-based superconductor BaFe$_2$(As$_{1-x}$P$_x$)$_2$ changes with disorder
via electron irradiation, which keeps the carrier concentrations intact. With
increasing disorder, we find that the magneto-structural transition is
suppressed, indicating that the critical concentration is shifted to the lower
side. Although the superconducting transition temperature $T_c$ is depressed at
high concentrations ($x\gtrsim$0.28), it shows an initial increase at lower
$x$. This implies that the superconducting dome tracks the shift of the
antiferromagnetic phase, supporting the view of the crucial role played by
quantum-critical fluctuations in enhancing superconductivity in this iron-based
high-$T_c$ family.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08679</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jaksch</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engels</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemmerling</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gheorghe</keyname><forenames>Codin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pahlsson</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xe9;sert</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ott</keyname><forenames>Frederic</forenames></author></authors><title>Cumulative Reports of the SoNDe Project July 2017</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This are the cumulated reports of the SoNDe detector Project as of July 2017.
The contained reports are: - Report on the 1x1 module technical demonstrator -
Report on used materials - Report on radiation hardness of components - Report
on potential additional applications - Report on the 2x2 module technical
demonstrator - Report on test results of the 2x2 technical demonstrator
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08716</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Po-Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Meng-Chi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>I-Ta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tseng</keyname><forenames>Pin-Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Guo-Jie Jason</forenames></author></authors><title>A vehicle with a two-wheel steering system mobile in shallow dense
  granular media</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cs.RO</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We design a vehicle with a steering system made of two independently
rotatable wheels on the front. We quantify the effectiveness of the steering
system in the mobility and maneuverability of the vehicle running in a box
containing a layer ping-pong balls with a packing density 0.8, below the random
close packing value 0.84 in 2D. The steering system can reduce the resistance
exerted by the jammed balls formed ahead of the fast-moving vehicle. Moreover,
if only one of the two steering wheels rotates, the vehicle can turn into the
direction opposite to the rotating wheel. The steering system performs more
efficiently if the wheels engage the ping-pong balls better by increasing the
contact area between the wheels and the balls. We advocate applying our design
to machines moving in granular materials with a moderate packing density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08724</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Grytsay</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural Instability of a Biochemical Process</title><categories>nlin.CD q-bio.CB</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ukr. J. Phys., Vol. 55, N 5, p.599-606 (2010)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By the example of a mathematical model of a biochemical process, the
structural instability of dynamical systems is studied by calculating the full
spectrum of Lyapunov indices with the use of the generalized Benettin
algorithm. For the reliability of the results obtained, the higher Lyapunov
index determined with the orthogonalization of perturbation vectors by the
Gram-Schmidt method is compared with that determined with the overdetermination
of only the norm of a perturbation vector. Specific features of these methods
and the comparison of their efficiencies for a multidimensional phase space are
presented. A scenario of the formation of strange attractors at a change of the
dissipation parameter is studied. The main regularities and the mechanism of
formation of a deterministic chaos due to the appearance of a fold or a funnel,
which leads to the uncertainty of the evolution of a biosystem, are determined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08727</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Visser</keyname><forenames>Matt</forenames><affiliation>Victoria University of Wellington</affiliation></author></authors><title>From mindless mathematics to thinking meat?</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>7 pages. Essay written for the FQXi 2017 essay contest: &quot;Wandering
  towards a goal: How can mindless mathematical laws give rise to aims and
  intention?&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deconstruction of the theme of the 2017 FQXi essay contest is already an
interesting exercise in its own right: Teleology is rarely useful in physics
--- the only known mainstream physics example (black hole event horizons) has a
very mixed score-card --- so the &quot;goals&quot; and &quot;aims and intentions&quot; alluded to
in the theme of the 2017 FQXi essay contest are already somewhat pushing the
limits. Furthermore, &quot;aims and intentions&quot; certainly carries the implication of
consciousness, and opens up a whole can of worms related to the mind-body
problem. As for &quot;mindless mathematical laws&quot;, that allusion is certainly in
tension with at least some versions of the &quot;mathematical universe hypothesis&quot;.
Finally &quot;wandering towards a goal&quot; again carries the implication of
consciousness, with all its attendant problems.
  In this essay I will argue, simply because we do not yet have any really good
mathematical or physical theory of consciousness, that the theme of this essay
contest is premature, and unlikely to lead to any resolution that would be
widely accepted in the mathematics or physics communities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08731</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Kota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagao</keyname><forenames>Tohru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toba</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terao</keyname><forenames>Koki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuoka</keyname><forenames>Kenta</forenames></author></authors><title>Active Galactic Nuclei with a Low-Metallicity Narrow-Line Region</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages including 14 figures, published in The Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 842 (2017) 44-57</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa70e1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-metallicity active galactic nuclei (AGNs) are interesting to study the
early phase of the AGN evolution. However most AGNs are chemically matured and
accordingly low-metallicity AGNs are extremely rare. One approach to search for
low-metallicity AGNs systematically is utilizing the so-called BPT diagram that
consists of the [O III]$\lambda$5007/H$\beta$$\lambda4861$ and [N
II]$\lambda6584$/H$\alpha$$\lambda6563$ flux ratios. Specifically,
photoionization models predict that low-metallicity AGNs show a high [O
III]$\lambda$5007/H$\beta$$\lambda$4861 ratio and a relatively low [N
II]$\lambda$6584/H$\alpha$$\lambda$6563 ratio, that corresponds to the location
between the sequence of star-forming galaxies and that of usual AGNs on the BPT
diagram (hereafter &quot;the BPT valley&quot;). However, other populations of galaxies
such as star-forming galaxies and AGNs with a high electron density or a high
ionization parameter could be also located in the BPT valley, not only
low-metallicity AGNs. In this paper, we examine whether most of emission-line
galaxies at the BPT valley are low-metallicity AGNs or not. We select 70
BPT-valley objects from 212,866 emission line galaxies obtained by the Sloan
Digital Sky Survey. Among the 70 BPT-valley objects, 43 objects show firm
evidence of the AGN activity; i.e., the He II$\lambda$4686 emission and/or weak
but significant broad H$\alpha$ emission. Our analysis shows that those 43
BPT-valley AGNs are not characterized by a very high gas density nor ionization
parameter, inferring that at least 43 among 70 BPT-valley objects (i.e., $&gt;60$
%) are low-metallicity AGNs. This suggests that the BPT diagram is an efficient
tool to search for low-metallicity AGNs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08733</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Combes</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames><affiliation>LERMA-Obs-Paris</affiliation></author></authors><title>Secular evolution of Milky Way-type galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, SF2A 2017, C. Reyle, P. Di Matteo, F. Herpin, E.
  Lagadec, A. Lancon F. Royer (eds)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The internal evolution of disk galaxies like the Milky Way are driven by
non-axisymmetries (bars) and the implied angular momentum transfer of the
matter; baryons are essentially driven inwards to build a more concentrated
disk. This mass concentration may lead to the decoupling of a secondary bar,
since the orbit precessing frequency is then much enhanced. Vertical resonances
with the bar will form a box/peanut bulge in a Gyr time-scale. Gas flows due to
gravity torques can lead to a young nuclear disk forming stars, revealed by a
sigma-drop in velocity dispersion. These gas flows moderated by feedback
produce intermittent accretion of the super-massive black hole, and cycles of
AGN activity. The fountain effect due to nuclear star formation may lead to
inclined, and even polar nuclear disks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08745</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Changsu</forenames><affiliation>Center for the Exploration of the Origin of the Universe, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Seoul National University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Im</keyname><forenames>Myungshin</forenames><affiliation>Center for the Exploration of the Origin of the Universe, Department of Physics and Astronomy, Seoul National University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Seoul National University Camera II (SNUCAM-II): The New SED Camera for
  the Lee Sang Gak Telescope (LSGT)</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>8 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables, published in 2017 June issue of JKAS</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the Korean Astronomical Society (2017), 50, 71-78</journal-ref><doi>10.5303/JKAS.2017.50.3.71</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the characteristics and the performance of the new CCD camera
system, SNUCAM-II (Seoul National University CAMera system II) that was
installed on the Lee Sang Gak Telescope (LSGT) at the Siding Spring Observatory
in 2016. SNUCAM-II consists of a deep depletion chip covering a wide wavelength
from 0.3 {\mu}m to 1.1 {\mu}m with high sensitivity (QE at &gt; 80% over 0.4 to
0.9 {\mu}m). It is equipped with the SDSS ugriz filters and 13 medium band
width (50 nm) filters, enabling us to study spectral energy distributions
(SEDs) of diverse objects from extragalactic sources to solar system objects.
On LSGT, SNUCAM-II offers 15.7 {\times} 15.7 arcmin field-of-view (FOV) at a
pixel scale of 0.92 arcsec and a limiting magnitude of g = 19.91 AB mag and
z=18.20 AB mag at 5{\sigma} with 180 sec exposure time for point source
detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08797</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Croitoru</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of magnetic drifts on ion transport in turbulent tokamak plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stochastic advection of low energy deuterium ions is studied in a three
dimensional realistic turbulence model in conditions relevant for current
tokamak fusion experiments. The diffusion coefficients are calculated starting
from the test particles trajectories in the framework of the semi-analitical
statistical model called the Decorrelation Trajectory Method. We show that
trajectory trapping determined by the space correlation of the velocity field
is the main cause for anomalous diffusion and we obtain the transport regimes
corresponding to different values of the parameters of the turbulence model and
a trapping condition in the limit of frozen turbulence. Depending on the value
of the parameters of the model, the interaction between turbulence and magnetic
drifts leads to both an increase (with transport in the poloidal direction
increasing up to an order of magnitude) and a decrease of the particle
transport.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08805</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Margueritte</keyname><forenames>Laure</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markov</keyname><forenames>Petar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiron</keyname><forenames>Lionel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Starck</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vonthron-S&#xe9;n&#xe9;cheau</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourjot</keyname><forenames>M&#xe9;lanie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delsuc</keyname><forenames>Marc-Andr&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Automatic differential analysis of NMR experiments in complex samples</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>35 pages, 36 figures, 26 references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Liquid state NMR is a powerful tool for the analysis of complex mixtures of
unknown molecules. This capacity has been used in many analytical approaches:
metabolomics, identification of active compounds in natural extracts,
characterization of species, and such studies require the acquisition of many
diverse NMR measurements on series of samples.
  While acquisition can easily be performed automatically, the number of NMR
experiments involved in these studies increases very rapidly and this data
avalanche requires to resort to automatic processing and analysis.
  We present here a program that allows the autonomous, unsupervised processing
of a large corpus of 1D, 2D and DOSY experiments from a series of samples
acquired in different conditions. The program provides all the signal
processing steps, as well as peak-picking and bucketing of 1D and 2D spectra,
the program and its components are fully available. In an experiment mimicking
the search of an active species in natural extract, we use it for the automatic
detection of small amounts of artemisin added to a series of plant extracts,
and for the generation of the spectral fingerprint of this molecules.
  This program called Plasmodesma is a novel tool which should be useful to
decipher complex mixtures, particularly in the discovery of biologically active
natural products from plants extracts, but can also in drug discovery or
metabolomics studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08828</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorobtsov</keyname><forenames>O. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukharamova</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarev</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chollet</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurta</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meijer</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikorski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dzhigaev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serkez</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singer</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petukhov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vartanyants</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffraction based Hanbury Brown and Twiss interferometry performed at a
  hard x-ray free-electron laser</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>32 pages, 10 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate experimentally Hanbury Brown and Twiss (HBT) interferometry at
a hard X-ray Free Electron Laser (XFEL) on a sample diffraction patterns. This
is different from the traditional approach when HBT interferometry requires
direct beam measurements in absence of the sample. HBT analysis was carried out
on the Bragg peaks from the colloidal crystals measured at Linac Coherent Light
Source (LCLS). We observed high degree (80%) spatial coherence of the full beam
and the pulse duration of the monochromatized beam on the order of 11 fs that
is significantly shorter than expected from the electron bunch measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08838</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08838</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;ffer</keyname><forenames>Alexander F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D&#xfc;rr</keyname><forenames>Hermann A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berakdar</keyname><forenames>Jamal</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast nanoscale magnetic switching via intense picosecond electron
  bunches</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures, SPIE proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetic field associated with a picosecond intense electron pulse is
shown to switch locally the magnetization of extended films and nanostructures
and to ignite locally spin waves excitations. Also, topologically protected
magnetic textures such as skyrmions can be imprinted swiftly in a sample with a
residual Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya spin-orbital coupling. Characteristics of the
created excitations such as the topological charge or the width of the magnon
spectrum can be steered via the duration and the strength of the electron
pulses. The study points to a possible way for a spatiotemporally controlled
generation of magnetic and skyrmionic excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08843</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Ciattoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizza</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase-matching-free parametric oscillators based on two dimensional
  semiconductors</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>22 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical parametric oscillators are widely-used pulsed and continuous-wave
tunable sources for innumerable applications, as in quantum technologies,
imaging and biophysics. A key drawback is material dispersion imposing the
phase-matching condition that generally entails a complex setup design, thus
hindering tunability and miniaturization. Here we show that the burden of
phase-matching is surprisingly absent in parametric micro-resonators adopting
monolayer transition-metal dichalcogenides as quadratic nonlinear materials. By
the exact solution of nonlinear Maxwell equations and first-principle
calculation of the semiconductor nonlinear response, we devise a novel kind of
phase-matching-free miniaturized parametric oscillator operating at
conventional pump intensities. We find that different two-dimensional
semiconductors yield degenerate and non-degenerate emission at various spectral
regions thanks to doubly-resonant mode excitation, which can be tuned through
the incidence angle of the external pump laser. In addition we show that
high-frequency electrical modulation can be achieved by doping through
electrical gating that efficiently shifts the parametric oscillation threshold.
Our results pave the way for new ultra-fast tunable micron-sized sources of
entangled photons, a key device underpinning any quantum protocol.
Highly-miniaturized optical parametric oscillators may also be employed in
lab-on-chip technologies for biophysics, environmental pollution detection and
security.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08847</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Suarjaya</keyname><forenames>I Made Agus Dwi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasahara</keyname><forenames>Yoshiya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goto</keyname><forenames>Yoshitaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical study on propagation characteristics of Omega signals (VLF)
  in magnetosphere detected by the Akebono satellite</title><categories>physics.space-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Earth, Planets and Space (2017) 69:100</journal-ref><doi>10.1186/s40623-017-0684-5</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  This paper shows a statistical analysis of 10.2 kHz Omega broadcasts of an
artificial signal broadcast from ground stations, propagated in the
plasmasphere, and detected using an automatic detection method we developed. We
study the propagation patterns of the Omega signals to understand the
propagation characteristics that are strongly affected by plasmaspheric
electron density and the ambient magnetic field. We show the unique propagation
patterns of the Omega 10.2 kHz signal when it was broadcast from two
high-middle-latitude stations. We use about eight years of data captured by the
Poynting flux analyzer subsystem on board the Akebono satellite from October
1989 to September 1997. We demonstrate that the signals broadcast from almost
the same latitude (in geomagnetic coordinates) propagated differently depending
on the geographic latitude. We also study propagation characteristics as a
function of local time, season, and solar activity. The Omega signal tended to
propagate farther on the nightside than on the dayside and was more widely
distributed during winter than during summer. When solar activity was at
maximum, the Omega signal propagated at a lower intensity level. In contrast,
when solar activity was at minimum, the Omega signal propagated at a higher
intensity and farther from the transmitter station.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08853</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08853</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kurazhkovskii</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurazhkovskaya</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klain</keyname><forenames>B. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Peculiarities of geomagnetic field behavior near boundary of the
  mesozoic - cenozoic</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The results of paleointensity determinations of the geomagnetic field, which
are obtained by sedimentary rocks in the Middle Jurassic - Neogene (167-12) Ma,
are summarized. It was found that in the interval (167-67) Ma (Middle Jurassic
- Cretaceous) mean values and amplitudes of paleointensity variations
increased. Mean values of paleointensity reached a maximum in front of the
Cretaceous-Paleogene boundary. During the Paleogene the mean values and
amplitudes of paleointensity variations decreased. In the Cretaceous - the
beginning of the Paleogene cyclic changes in the amplitudes of paleointensity
variations with characteristic times of several million years have been
observed. It is shown that the duration of cycles of the paleointensity changes
coincided with transgressive-regressive cycles (T-R cycles). This can be
considered as a confirmation of the hypothesis on a relation between processes
in the Earth's core and tectonic processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08880</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Dharma-wardana</keyname><forenames>M. W. C.</forenames><affiliation>NRC-Canada</affiliation></author></authors><title>A calculation of the Deuterium Hugoniot using the classical-map
  hypernetted-chain (CHNC) approach</title><categories>physics.chem-ph astro-ph.EP cond-mat.stat-mech physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>This paper contains some of the material submitted to the DOE/NNSA
  EOS workshop, May-31, Rochester, USA, 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Hugoniot for Deuterium is calculated using the classical-map
hyper-netted-chain (CHNC) approach using several models of the effective
temperature that may be assigned to the electron-ion interaction. This
effective temperature embodies the exchange-correlation and kinetic energy
functional that is assigned to the electron-ion interaction. Deuterium pair
distribution functions (calculated using the neutral-pseudo atom method)
showing the formation of molecular pre-peaks are displayed to clarify the
soft-turning over of the hugoniot in the pressure range of 0.2-0.6 Megabars.
This contribution updates a previous CHNC calculation of the deuterium hugoniot
given in Phys. Rev. B, 66, 014110 (2002).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08900</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Pekkil&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames><affiliation>ReSoLVE Center of Excellence, Aalto</affiliation></author><author><keyname>V&#xe4;is&#xe4;l&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>Miikka S.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, University of Helsinki</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;pyl&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>Maarit J.</forenames><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Sonnensystemforschung</affiliation><affiliation>ReSoLVE Center of Excellence, Aalto</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K&#xe4;pyl&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>Petri J.</forenames><affiliation>AIP</affiliation><affiliation>ReSoLVE Center of Excellence, Aalto</affiliation><affiliation>Max-Planck-Institut f&#xfc;r Sonnensystemforschung</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Anjum</keyname><forenames>Omer</forenames><affiliation>Nokia Solutions and Networks, Finland</affiliation><affiliation>ReSoLVE Center of Excellence, Aalto</affiliation></author></authors><title>Methods for compressible fluid simulation on GPUs using high-order
  finite differences</title><categories>physics.comp-ph astro-ph.IM cs.DC physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Computer Physics Communications, Volume 217, August 2017, Pages
  11-22</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2017.03.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We focus on implementing and optimizing a sixth-order finite-difference
solver for simulating compressible fluids on a GPU using third-order
Runge-Kutta integration. Since graphics processing units perform well in
data-parallel tasks, this makes them an attractive platform for fluid
simulation. However, high-order stencil computation is memory-intensive with
respect to both main memory and the caches of the GPU. We present two
approaches for simulating compressible fluids using 55-point and 19-point
stencils. We seek to reduce the requirements for memory bandwidth and cache
size in our methods by using cache blocking and decomposing a latency-bound
kernel into several bandwidth-bound kernels. Our fastest implementation is
bandwidth-bound and integrates $343$ million grid points per second on a Tesla
K40t GPU, achieving a $3.6 \times$ speedup over a comparable hydrodynamics
solver benchmarked on two Intel Xeon E5-2690v3 processors. Our alternative GPU
implementation is latency-bound and achieves the rate of $168$ million updates
per second.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08914</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhokhin</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gachok</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Transition to Chaos in the Kinetic Model of Cellulose Hydrolysis Under
  Enzyme Biosynthesis Control</title><categories>q-bio.CB nlin.AO</categories><comments>3 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Studia Biophysica vol. 123 (1988) No. 1, p.59-62</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the paper the kinetic model of the biochemical process of cellulose
hydrolysis with cell application is presented. The model includes enzyme
biosynthesis control and is open conditions it represents the dynamical system
in the preturbulent regime. The limit cycle and its five consequence
bifurcations of the doubling-period type are found. Also the limit regime of
the system - the strange attractor - is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08916</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Biasutti</keyname><forenames>Michela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voigt</keyname><forenames>Aiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavon</keyname><forenames>Benjamin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scheff</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>Sources of inter-model scatter in TRACMIP, the Tropical Rain belts with
  an Annual cycle and a Continent Model Intercomparison Project</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>Extended abstract for AMS AOFD 2017 conference; 4 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the source of inter-model scatter in the surface temperature
response to quadrupling CO2 in two sets of GCM simulations from the Tropical
Rain Belts with an Annual cycle and a Continent Model Intercomparison Project
(TRACMIP; Voigt et al, 2016). TRACMIP provides simulations of idealized
climates that allow for studying the fundamental dynamics of tropical rainfall
and its response to climate change. One configuration is an aquaplanet
atmosphere (i.e., with zonally-symmetric boundary conditions) coupled to a slab
ocean (AquaCTL and Aqua4x). The other includes an equatorial continent
represented by a thin slab ocean with increased surface albedo and decreased
evaporation (LandCTL and Land4x).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08921</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>de Vries</keyname><forenames>E. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pezzini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meijer</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koirala</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salehi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moon</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oh</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coexistence of bulk and surface states probed by Shubnikov-de Haas
  oscillations in Bi$_2$Se$_3$ with high charge-carrier density</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Manuscript including supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 96, 045433 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.045433</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological insulators are ideally represented as having an insulating bulk
with topologically protected, spin-textured surface states. However, it is
increasingly becoming clear that these surface transport channels can be
accompanied by a finite conducting bulk, as well as additional topologically
trivial surface states. To investigate these parallel conduction transport
channels, we studied Shubnikov-de Haas oscillations in Bi$_2$Se$_3$ thin films,
in high magnetic fields up to 30 T so as to access channels with a lower
mobility. We identify a clear Zeeman-split bulk contribution to the
oscillations from a comparison between the charge-carrier densities extracted
from the magnetoresistance and the oscillations. Furthermore, our analyses
indicate the presence of a two-dimensional state and signatures of additional
states the origin of which cannot be conclusively determined. Our findings
underpin the necessity of theoretical studies on the origin of and the
interplay between these parallel conduction channels for a careful analysis of
the material's performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08923</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gr&#xe4;ff</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenhauer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feuchtgruber</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex spectral line profiles resulting from cryogenic deformation of
  the SINFONI/SPIFFI diffraction gratings</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>26 page, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Astron. Telesc. Instrum. Syst. 3(3), 035002 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.3.3.035002</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The integral field spectrograph, SPIFFI, has complex line profile shapes that
vary with wavelength and pixel scale, the origins of which have been sought
since the instrument construction. SPIFFI is currently operational as part of
SINFONI at the VLT, and will be upgraded and incorporated into the new VLT
instrument ERIS. We conducted an investigation of the line profiles based on
measurements we could take with the instrument calibration unit, as well as
laboratory measurements of spare SPIFFI optical components. Cryogenic
measurements of a spare SPIFFI diffraction grating showed significant periodic
deformation. These measurements match the cryogenic deformation expected from
bimetallic bending stress based on a finite element analysis of the
lightweighted grating blank. The periodic deformation of the grating surface
gives rise to satellite peaks in the diffraction pattern of the grating. An
optical simulation including the cryogenic grating deformation reproduces the
behavior of the SPIFFI line profiles with both wavelength and pixel scale as
measured with the instrument calibration unit. The conclusion is that cryogenic
deformation of the diffraction gratings is responsible for the non-ideal line
profiles, and that the diffraction gratings should be replaced during the
upgrade for optimal instrument performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08930</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08930</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>Rui Carlos Andrade</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marques</keyname><forenames>Anselmo Miguel Magalh&#xe3;es</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>Ricardo Assis Guimar&#xe3;es</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on the Kitaev \leftrightarrow Tight-binding correspondence</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>34 pages, 31 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this project, we study the properties of a non-trivial topological system
which exhibits localized edge states. In our study, we adress the Kitaev chain,
a one-dimensional chain of atoms deposited on top of a p-wave superconductor
that induces superconductivity in the chain by proximity effect. We establish a
correspondence between the Kitaev chain and a tight-binding lattice with a
particular geometry for a particular case of the system parameters. This
correspondence allows one to find the exact energy levels and eigenstates of
the Kitaev chain when t=|\Delta| and \mu=0 for an arbitrary chain size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08937</id><created>2017-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahl&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>Olof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gustafsson</keyname><forenames>Henrik P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleinschmidt</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Baiying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Persson</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Fourier coefficients attached to small automorphic representations of
  ${\mathrm{SL}}_n(\mathbb{A})$</title><categories>math.RT hep-th math.NT</categories><comments>55 pages</comments><msc-class>11F70, 22E55, 11F30</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that Fourier coefficients of automorphic forms attached to minimal or
next-to-minimal automorphic representations of ${\mathrm{SL}}_n(\mathbb{A})$
are completely determined by certain highly degenerate Whittaker coefficients.
We give an explicit formula for the Fourier expansion, analogously to the
Piatetski-Shapiro-Shalika formula. In addition, we derive expressions for
Fourier coefficients associated to all maximal parabolic subgroups. These
results have potential applications for scattering amplitudes in string theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0611021</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0611021</id><created>2006-11-08</created><updated>2017-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bialas</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bzdak</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Wounded quarks and diquarks in heavy ion collisions</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, added references; corrected typo in Eq. (15)</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett.B 649: 263-268 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2007.04.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model in which the soft collisions of the nucleon are described in terms of
interactions of its two constituents (a quark and a diquark) is proposed. When
adjusted to describe precisely the elastic proton-proton scattering data and
supplemented with the idea of wounded constituents, the model accounts rather
well for the centrality dependence of particle production in the central
rapidity region at RHIC energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:solv-int/9910011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>solv-int/9910011</id><created>1999-10-28</created><updated>2017-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maltsev</keyname><forenames>Andrei Ya.</forenames></author></authors><title>The averaging of non-local Hamiltonian structures in Whitham's method</title><categories>solv-int nlin.SI</categories><comments>Latex, 40 Pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Intern. Journ. of Math. and Math. Sci. 30:7 (2002) 399-434</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the $m$-phase Whitham's averaging method and propose a procedure
of &quot;averaging&quot; of non-local Hamiltonian structures. The procedure is based on
the existence of a sufficient number of local commuting integrals of a system
and gives a Poisson bracket of Ferapontov type for the Whitham's system. The
method can be considered as a generalization of the Dubrovin-Novikov procedure
for the local field-theoretical brackets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
