<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:05:07Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-26" from="2016-08-26" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0903.1983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0903.1983</id><created>2009-03-11</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shu-Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermions Tunneling from Higher-Dimensional Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om Black
  Hole: Semiclassical and Beyond Semiclassical Approximation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  4647069</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/4647069</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on semiclassical tunneling method, we focus on charged fermions
tunneling from higher-dimensional Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m black hole. We first
simplify the Dirac equation by semiclassical approximation, and then a
semiclassical Hamilton-Jacobi equation is obtained. Using the Hamilton-Jacobi
equation, we study the Hawking temperature and fermions tunneling rate at the
event horizon of the higher-dimensional Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m black hole
spacetime. Finally, the correct entropy is calculation by the method beyond
semiclassical approximation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.0234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.0234</id><created>2010-12-01</created><updated>2011-02-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Harvey B.</forenames></author></authors><title>The errant life of a heavy quark in the quark-gluon plasma</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures, part of New Journal of Physics focus issue
  &quot;Strongly Correlated Quantum Fluids: From Ultracold Quantum Gases to QCD
  Plasmas&quot;. Corrected the factors of pi in Eq. (22) and Eq.(25), resulting in a
  larger $\Delta\kappa$ by a factor pi</comments><report-no>MKPH-T-10-39</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the high-temperature phase of QCD, the heavy quark momentum diffusion
constant determines, via a fluctuation-dissipation relation, how fast a heavy
quark kinetically equilibrates. This transport coefficient can be extracted
from thermal correlators via a Kubo formula. We present a lattice calculation
of the relevant Euclidean correlators in the gluon plasma, based on a recent
formulation of the problem in heavy-quark effective field theory (HQET). We
find a $\approx20%$ enhancement of the Euclidean correlator at maximal time
separation as the temperature is lowered from $6T_c$ to $2T_c$, pointing to
stronger interactions at lower temperatures. At the same time, the correlator
becomes flatter from $6T_c$ down to $2T_c$, indicating a relative shift of the
spectral weight to lower frequencies. A recent next-to-leading order
perturbative calculation of the correlator agrees with the time dependence of
the lattice data at the few-percent level. We estimate how much additional
contribution from the $\omega\lesssim T$ region of the perturbative spectral
function would be required to bring it in agreement with the lattice data at
$3.1T_c$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1102.3042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1102.3042</id><created>2011-02-15</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kuzenko</keyname><forenames>Sergei M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyler</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex linear superfield as a model for Goldstino</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages; V2: references and comments added; V3: typos in eq. (4)
  corrected</comments><msc-class>81Q60</msc-class><journal-ref>JHEP 1104:057, 2011</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2011)057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a Goldstino model formulated in terms of a constrained complex
linear superfield. Its comparison to other Goldstino models is given. Couplings
to supersymmetric matter and supergravity are briefly described.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.0135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.0135</id><created>2013-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Ganichev</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarasenko</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karch</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kvon</keyname><forenames>Z. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic quantum ratchet effect in Si-MOSFETs</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 26, 255802 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/26/25/255802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the observation of magnetic quantum ratchet effect in
metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect-transistors on silicon surface
(Si-MOSFETs). We show that the excitation of an unbiased transistor by ac
electric field of terahertz radiation at normal incidence leads to a direct
electric current between the source and drain contacts if the transistor is
subjected to an in-plane magnetic field. The current rises linearly with the
magnetic field strength and quadratically with the ac electric field amplitude.
It depends on the polarization state of the ac field and can be induced by both
linearly and circularly polarized radiation. We present the quasi-classical and
quantum theories of the observed effect and show that the current originates
from the Lorentz force acting upon carriers in asymmetric inversion channels of
the transistors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1910</id><created>2014-11-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tarasenko</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durnev</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nestoklon</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivchenko</keyname><forenames>E. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Jun-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zunger</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author></authors><title>Split Dirac cones in HgTe/CdTe quantum wells due to symmetry-enforced
  level anticrossing at interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 081302(R) (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.081302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the fine structure of Dirac states in HgTe/CdHgTe quantum wells
of critical and close-to-critical thickness and demonstrate the formation of an
anticrossing gap between the tips of the Dirac cones driven by interface
inversion asymmetry. By combining symmetry analysis, atomistic calculations,
and k-p theory with interface terms, we obtain a quantitative description of
the energy spectrum and extract the interface mixing coefficient. The
zero-magnetic-field splitting of Dirac cones can be experimentally revealed in
studying magnetotransport phenomena, cyclotron resonance, Raman scattering, or
THz radiation absorption.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.4273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.4273</id><created>2014-11-16</created><updated>2016-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hakio&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;nay</keyname><forenames>Mehmet</forenames></author></authors><title>Unconventional Pairings and Radial Line Nodes in Inversion Symmetry
  Broken Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>[8 pages, 6 figures, 1 table (main)]</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physc.2016.07.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Noncentrosymmetric superconductors (NCSs) with broken inversion symmetry can
have spin-dependent order parameters (OPs) with mixed parity which can also
have nodes in the pair potential as well as the energy spectra. These nodes are
distinct features that are not present in conventional superconductors. They
appear as points or lines in the momentum space where the latter can have
angular or radial geometries dictated by the dimensionality, the lattice
structure and the pairing interaction.
  In this work we study the nodes in time reversal symmetry (TRS) preserving
NCSs at the OP, the pair potential, and the energy spectrum levels. Nodes are
examined by using spin independent pairing interactions respecting the
rotational $C_{\infty v}$ symmetry in the presence of spin-orbit coupling
(SOC). The pairing symmetries and the nodal topology are affected by the
relative strength of the pairing channels which is studied for the mixed
singlet-triplet, pure singlet, and pure triplet. Complementary to the angular
line nodes widely present in the literature, the $C_{\infty v}$ symmetry here
allows radial line nodes (RLNs) due to the nonlinear momentum dependence in the
OPs. The topology of the RLNs in the mixed case shows a distinctly different
characterization than the half-spin quantum vortex at the Dirac point. We apply
this NCS physics to the inversion symmetry broken exciton condensates (ECs) in
double quantum wells where the point and the RLNs can be found. On the other
hand, for a pure triplet condensate, two fully gapped and topologically
distinct regimes exist, separated by a QSHI-like zero energy superconducting
state with even number of Majorana modes. We also remark on how the point and
the RLNs can be manipulated, enabling an external control on the
topology.tions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04653</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Croon</keyname><forenames>Djuna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>Veronica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarrant</keyname><forenames>Ewan R. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reheating with a Composite Higgs</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>33 pages, 5 figures. Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 045010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.045010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The flatness of the inflaton potential and lightness of the Higgs could have
the common origin of the breaking of a global symmetry. This scenario provides
a unified framework of Goldstone Inflation and Composite Higgs, where the
inflaton and the Higgs both have a pseudo--Goldstone boson nature. The inflaton
reheats the Universe via decays to the Higgs and subsequent secondary
production of other SM particles via the top and massive vector bosons. We find
that inflationary predictions and perturbative reheating conditions are
consistent with CMB data for sub--Planckian values of the fields, as well as
opening up the possibility of inflation at the TeV scale. We explore this
exciting possibility, leading to an interplay between collider data and
cosmological constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01247</id><created>2015-08-05</created><updated>2016-04-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campanelli</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic magnetization out from the vacuum</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, abstract changed, minor revisions, reference added</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 28 (2016) 1650165</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501650</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The large-scale magnetic fields we observe today in galaxies and galaxy
clusters could be the result of a pure quantum effect taking place during
inflation, to wit, the creation of particles (photons) out from the vacuum in a
curved spacetime. We show that, whenever the conformal invariance of
electromagnetism is broken during inflation, the actual magnetic field
spectrum, in the classical limit, is given by $B_k \simeq k^2
\sqrt{n_{\mathbf{k}} }$, where $n_{\mathbf{k}} \gg 1$ is the number of created
photons with wavenumber $k$. In particular, a scale-invariant magnetic field of
order of $10^{12}$G can emerge in the simplest model of cosmic magnetogenesis,
the one where the inflaton is kinetically coupled to the photon. Moreover, and
contrarily to the general belief, we show that such a model is free from the
so-called strong-coupling and backreaction problems. This conclusion follows,
indirectly, from the observation that post-inflationary electric currents,
which in the literature are incorrectly supposed to freeze superhorizon
magnetic fields after inflation, are indeed vanishing on superhorizon scales
due to causality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07777</id><created>2015-08-31</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tarasenko</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burkard</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author></authors><title>Limitation of electron mobility from hyperfine interaction in
  ultra-clean quantum wells and topological insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045309 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of electron transport and scattering processes limiting electron
mobility in high-quality semiconductor structures is central to solid-state
electronics. Here, we uncover an unavoidable source of electron scattering
which is caused by fluctuations of nuclear spins. We calculate the momentum
relaxation time of electrons in quantum wells governed by the hyperfine
interaction between electrons and nuclei and show that this time drastically
depends on the spatial correlation of nuclear spins. Moreover, the scattering
processes accompanied by a spin flip are a source of the backscattering of
Dirac fermions at conducting surfaces of topological insulators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05816</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lockhart</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paternostro</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete-time quantum walks as generators of multipartite entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Minor revisions, 9 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the idea of a discrete-time quantum walk on a graph by placing a
qubit on each vertex, and allowing the walker to interact with the qubit at its
current position. We show that allowing for a controlled-Z interaction at each
time step between the walker and the vertex qubits generates multipartite
entanglement between the qubits. We demonstrate that for particular coin
operators the system generates a highly entangled cluster state, of use in
measurement based quantum computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08438</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>M. G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rcio M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parisio</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author></authors><title>Remote preparation of $W$ states from imperfect bipartite sources</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Published in Quantum Information Processing 8 pages, 2 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1358-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Several proposals to produce {\it tripartite} $W$-type entanglement are
probabilistic even if no imperfections are considered in the processes. We
provide a deterministic way to remotely create $W$ states out of an EPR source.
The proposal is made viable through measurements (which can be demolitive) in
an appropriate three-qubit basis. The protocol becomes probabilistic only when
source flaws are considered. It turns out that, even in this situation, it is
robust against imperfections in two senses: (i) It is possible, after
postselection, to create a pure ensemble of $W$ states out of an EPR source
containing a systematic error; (ii) If no postselection is done, the resulting
mixed state has a fidelity, with respect to a pure $|W\rangle$, which is higher
than that of the imperfect source in comparison to an ideal EPR source. This
simultaneously amounts to entanglement concentration and {\it lifting}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01183</id><created>2015-10-05</created><updated>2016-06-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tahamtan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svitek</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Robinson--Trautman solution with nonlinear electrodynamics</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 figures, to appear in EPJC</comments><msc-class>83C15, 83C22, 83C50, 83C57</msc-class><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 335</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4175-9</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Explicit Robinson--Trautman solutions with electromagnetic field satisfying
nonlinear field equations are derived and analyzed. The solutions are generated
from the spherically symmetric ones. In all cases the electromagnetic field
singularity is removed while the gravitational one persists. The models
resolving curvature singularity were not possible to generalize to
Robinson--Trautman geometry indicating that the removal of singularity in
associated spherically symmetric case is just a consequence of high symmetry.
We show that the solutions are generally of algebraic type II but reduce to
type D in spherical symmetry. Asymptotically they tend to the spherically
symmetric case as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01320</id><created>2015-10-05</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>McAlpine</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Helly</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schaller</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Trayford</keyname><forenames>James W.</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Furlong</keyname><forenames>Michelle</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bower</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Crain</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames><affiliation>Liverpool John Moores</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schaye</keyname><forenames>Joop</forenames><affiliation>Leiden Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Theuns</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vecchia</keyname><forenames>Claudio Dalla</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de Astrofisica de Canaria</affiliation><affiliation>Universidad de La Laguna</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frenk</keyname><forenames>Carlos S.</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>Ian G.</forenames><affiliation>Liverpool John Moores</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jenkins</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames><affiliation>ICC, Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rosas-Guevara</keyname><forenames>Yetli</forenames><affiliation>Santiago</affiliation></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Simon D. M.</forenames><affiliation>MPA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Baes</keyname><forenames>Maarten</forenames><affiliation>Gent</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Camps</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames><affiliation>Gent</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lemson</keyname><forenames>Gerard</forenames><affiliation>Johns Hopkins University</affiliation></author></authors><title>The EAGLE simulations of galaxy formation: public release of halo and
  galaxy catalogues</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures + appendices. The simulation data is available at
  http://www.eaglesim.org/database.php (comments welcome). Paper accepted to
  AstronomyComputing. Note there is a typo in the published version, Section
  4.1, replace 3/2 with 2/3 for velocity dispersion</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy and Computing (2016), pp. 72-89</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2016.02.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the public data release of halo and galaxy catalogues extracted
from the EAGLE suite of cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of galaxy
formation. These simulations were performed with an enhanced version of the
GADGET code that includes a modified hydrodynamics solver, time-step limiter
and subgrid treatments of baryonic physics, such as stellar mass loss,
element-by-element radiative cooling, star formation and feedback from star
formation and black hole accretion. The simulation suite includes runs
performed in volumes ranging from 25 to 100 comoving megaparsecs per side, with
numerical resolution chosen to marginally resolve the Jeans mass of the gas at
the star formation threshold. The free parameters of the subgrid models for
feedback are calibrated to the redshift z=0 galaxy stellar mass function,
galaxy sizes and black hole mass - stellar mass relation. The simulations have
been shown to match a wide range of observations for present-day and
higher-redshift galaxies. The raw particle data have been used to link galaxies
across redshifts by creating merger trees. The indexing of the tree produces a
simple way to connect a galaxy at one redshift to its progenitors at higher
redshift and to identify its descendants at lower redshift. In this paper we
present a relational database which we are making available for general use. A
large number of properties of haloes and galaxies and their merger trees are
stored in the database, including stellar masses, star formation rates,
metallicities, photometric measurements and mock gri images. Complex queries
can be created to explore the evolution of more than 10^5 galaxies, examples of
which are provided in appendix. (abridged)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06664</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2015-10-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saade</keyname><forenames>Alaa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caltagirone</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carron</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daudet</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dr&#xe9;meau</keyname><forenames>Ang&#xe9;lique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gigan</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krzakala</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Projections through multiple optical scattering: Approximating
  kernels at the speed of light</title><categories>cs.ET cs.LG physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE International Conference on
  Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing (ICASSP) pages: 6215 - 6219</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ICASSP.2016.7472872</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random projections have proven extremely useful in many signal processing and
machine learning applications. However, they often require either to store a
very large random matrix, or to use a different, structured matrix to reduce
the computational and memory costs. Here, we overcome this difficulty by
proposing an analog, optical device, that performs the random projections
literally at the speed of light without having to store any matrix in memory.
This is achieved using the physical properties of multiple coherent scattering
of coherent light in random media. We use this device on a simple task of
classification with a kernel machine, and we show that, on the MNIST database,
the experimental results closely match the theoretical performance of the
corresponding kernel. This framework can help make kernel methods practical for
applications that have large training sets and/or require real-time prediction.
We discuss possible extensions of the method in terms of a class of kernels,
speed, memory consumption and different problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01902</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Radicevic</keyname><forenames>Djordje</forenames></author></authors><title>Disorder Operators in Chern-Simons-Fermion Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, one figure, v2: added a few comments and references</comments><report-no>SU-ITP-15/16</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Building on the recent progress in solving Chern-Simons-matter theories in
the planar limit, we compute the scaling dimensions of a large class of
disorder (&quot;monopole&quot;) operators in $U(N)_k$ Chern-Simons-fermion theories at
all 't Hooft couplings $\lambda = N/k$. We find that the lowest-dimension
operator of this sort has dimension $\frac23 k^{3/2}$. We comment on the
implications of these results to analyzing maps of fermionic disorder operators
under 3D bosonization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07458</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fraser</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ernest</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakeri</keyname><forenames>Mohammadreza</forenames></author></authors><title>Verifiable Associated Processes from Radiative Lepton Masses with Dark
  Matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures. Discussion of rare lepton decays expanded.
  Details about dark matter added to match the published PRD version</comments><report-no>UCRHEP-T558</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 115019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.115019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If leptons do not couple directly to the one Higgs doublet of the standard
model of particle interactions, they must still do so somehow indirectly to
acquire mass, as proposed recently in several models where it happens in one
loop through dark matter. We analyze the important consequences of this
scenario in a specific model, including Higgs decay, muon anomalous magnetic
moment, $\mu \to e \gamma$, $\mu \to eee$, and the proposed dark sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00249</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nosaka</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Kazuma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terashima</keyname><forenames>Seiji</forenames></author></authors><title>Large N behavior of mass deformed ABJM theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages,3 figures; v2: typos corrected, a comment on solution II
  added, footnotes added, references added</comments><report-no>YITP-15-106</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, using the localization technique we analyze the large N limit
of the mass deformed Aharony-Bergman-Jafferis-Maldacena (ABJM) theory on the
three sphere with a finite mass parameter and finite Chern-Simons levels. We
find two different solutions of the saddle point equations in the large N
limit. With these solutions we compute the free energy and find that there is a
first order phase transition. Our results may predict a phase transition in the
dual gravity theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00436</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jingdi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Xuelian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Mengkun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teitelbaum</keyname><forenames>Samuel W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Post</keyname><forenames>Kirk W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basov</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Wenbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Averitt</keyname><forenames>Richard D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooperative photoinduced metastable phase control in strained manganite
  films</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nature Materials, Vol. 15, 956 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nmat4695</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major challenge in condensed matter physics is active control of quantum
phases. Dynamic control with pulsed electromagnetic fields can overcome
energetic barriers enabling access to transient or metastable states that are
not thermally accessible. Here we demonstrate strain-engineered tuning of
La2/3Ca1/3MnO3 into an emergent charge-ordered insulating phase with extreme
photo-susceptibility where even a single optical pulse can initiate a
transition to a long-lived metastable hidden metallic phase. Comprehensive
single-shot pulsed excitation measurements demonstrate that the transition is
cooperative and ultrafast, requiring a critical absorbed photon density to
activate local charge excitations that mediate magnetic-lattice coupling that,
in turn, stabilize the metallic phase. These results reveal that strain
engineering can tune emergent functionality towards proximal macroscopic states
to enable dynamic ultrafast optical phase switching and control.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01376</id><created>2015-12-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Zeyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author></authors><title>Gap plasmon resonator arrays for unidirectional launching and shaping of
  surface plasmon polaritons</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 108, 161105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4947431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the design and experimental realization of a kind of miniaturized
devices for efficient unidirectional launching and shaping of surface plasmon
polaritons (SPPs). Each device consists of an array of evenly spaced gap
plasmon resonators with varying dimensions. Particle swarm optimization is used
to achieve a theoretical two dimensional launching efficiency of about 51%,
under the normal illumination of a 5-{\mu}m waist Gaussian beam at 780 nm. By
modifying the wavefront of the SPPs, unidirectional SPPs with focused, Bessel
and Airy profiles are launched and imaged with leakage radiation microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02022</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Xiaolong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic Crystal Cavity on Single-Mode Optical Fiber End Facet for
  Label-Free Biosensing</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>18pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 108, 231105 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  All surface plasmon resonance (SPR) devices on single-mode optical fibers'
(SMF) end facets, as reported up to date, are limited by severely broad and
shallow resonance spectra. The consequent poor performance when they are used
as refractive index sensors, together with the challenge of nanofabrication on
fiber end facets, has prohibited the development of such devices for label-free
biosensing. Meanwhile, the planewave coupled, multimode fiber and fiber
sidewall SPR counterparts are extensively employed for label-free biosensing.
In this paper, we report the design, fabrication and characterization of a
plasmonic crystal cavity on a SMF end facet, which shows high performance
label-free sensing capability that comes from a steep cavity resonance near the
plasmonic bandedge. The experimental figure-of-merit is 68 RIU^-1, which is
over twenty times improvement to previous reports. The refractive index
detection limit is 3.5*10^-6 RIU at 1 s integration time. We also describe a
novel glue-and-strip process to transfer gold nano structures onto fiber end
facets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02249</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Espath</keyname><forenames>LFR</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarmiento</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignal</keyname><forenames>P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varga</keyname><forenames>BON</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cortes</keyname><forenames>AMA</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalcin</keyname><forenames>L</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calo</keyname><forenames>VM</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy Exchange Analysis in Droplet Dynamics via the
  Navier-Stokes-Cahn-Hilliard Model</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><doi>10.1017/jfm.2016.277</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop the energy budget equation of the coupled
Navier-Stokes-Cahn-Hilliard (NSCH) system. We use the NSCH equations to model
the dynamics of liquid droplets in a liquid continuum. Buoyancy effects are
accounted for through the Boussinesq assumption. We physically interpret each
quantity involved in the energy exchange to further insight into the model.
Highly resolved simulations involving density-driven flows and merging of
droplets allow us to analyze these energy budgets. In particular, we focus on
the energy exchanges when droplets merge, and describe flow features relevant
to this phenomenon. By comparing our numerical simulations to analytical
predictions and experimental results available in the literature, we conclude
that modeling droplet dynamics within the framework of NSCH equations is a
sensible approach worth further research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06852</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06852</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Potter</keyname><forenames>Andrew C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serbyn</keyname><forenames>Maksym</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishwanath</keyname><forenames>Ashvin</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric transport signatures of Dirac composite fermions in the
  half-filled Landau level</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5+4 pages, 2 figures; v2: minor changes, close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 031026 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.031026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The half filled Landau level is expected to be approximately particle-hole
symmetric, which requires an extension of the Halperin-Lee-Read (HLR) theory of
the compressible state observed at this filling. Recent work indicates that,
when particle-hole symmetry is preserved, the composite Fermions experience a
quantized $\pi$-Berry phase upon winding around the composite Fermi-surface,
analogous to Dirac fermions at the surface of a 3D topological insulator. In
contrast, the effective low energy theory of the composite fermion liquid
originally proposed by HLR lacks particle-hole symmetry and has vanishing Berry
phase. In this paper, we explain how thermoelectric transport measurements can
be used to test the Dirac nature of the composite Fermions by quantitatively
extracting this Berry phase. First we point out that longitudinal thermopower
(Seebeck effect) is non-vanishing due to the unusual nature of particle hole
symmetry in this context and is not sensitive to the Berry phase. In contrast,
we find that off-diagonal thermopower (Nernst effect) is directly related to
the topological structure of the composite Fermi surface, vanishing for zero
Berry phase and taking its maximal value for $\pi$ Berry phase. In contrast, in
purely electrical transport signatures the Berry phase contributions appear as
small corrections to a large background signal, making the Nernst effect a
promising diagnostic of the Dirac nature of composite fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02353</id><created>2016-01-11</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dedkov</keyname><forenames>G. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kyasov</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation and Heating of Rotating Neutral Particle in Close Vicinity to
  the Surface of Transparent Dielectric</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Several formulas and typos were corrected; submitted to Physica
  Scripta; 13 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated the intensity of electromagnetic radiation from particles
rotating in close vicinity to a transparent dielectric plate. The radiation is
a result of quantum and thermal friction occurring during particle rotation,
while the driving factor of radiation is a decrease in the kinetic energy of
particle. The characteristic frequency of radiation is determined by the
angular velocity and the temperature of the plate and surrounding vacuum
background. These results are challenging for experimental verification in
future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04927</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04927</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Valentinis</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Marel</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berthod</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rise and fall of shape resonances in thin films of BCS superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 054516 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.054516</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The confinement of a superconductor in a thin film changes its Fermi-level
density of states and is expected to change its critical temperature $T_c$.
Previous calculations have reported large discontinuities of $T_c$ when the
chemical potential coincides with a subband edge. By solving the BCS gap
equation exactly, we show that such discontinuities are artifacts and that
$T_c$ is a continuous function of the film thickness. We also find that $T_c$
is reduced in thin films compared with the bulk if the confinement potential is
lower than a critical value, while for stronger confinement $T_c$ increases
with decreasing film thickness, reaches a maximum, and eventually drops to
zero. Our numerical results are supported by several exact solutions. We
finally interpret experimental data for ultrathin lead thin films in terms of a
thickness-dependent effective mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06683</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saade</keyname><forenames>Alaa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lelarge</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krzakala</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zdeborov&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>Lenka</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering from Sparse Pairwise Measurements</title><categories>cs.SI cond-mat.dis-nn cs.LG</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the 2016 IEEE International Symposium on
  Information Theory (ISIT) Pages: 780 - 784</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ISIT.2016.7541405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of grouping items into clusters based on few random
pairwise comparisons between the items. We introduce three closely related
algorithms for this task: a belief propagation algorithm approximating the
Bayes optimal solution, and two spectral algorithms based on the
non-backtracking and Bethe Hessian operators. For the case of two symmetric
clusters, we conjecture that these algorithms are asymptotically optimal in
that they detect the clusters as soon as it is information theoretically
possible to do so. We substantiate this claim for one of the spectral
approaches we introduce.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07219</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>Zheng-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Yao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonadiabatic holonomic quantum computation with all-resonant control</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>v2: thoroughly rewritten version with major revission; v3: Accepted
  by PRA; V4: Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 022331 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.022331</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The implementation of holonomic quantum computation on superconducting
quantum circuits is challenging due to the general requirement of controllable
complicated coupling between multilevel systems. Here we solve this problem by
proposing a scalable circuit QED lattice with simple realization of a universal
set of nonadiabatic holonomic quantum gates. Compared with the existing
proposals, we can achieve both the single and two logical qubit gates in an
tunable and all-resonant way through a hybrid transmon-transmission-line
encoding of the logical qubits in the decoherence-free subspaces. This distinct
advantage thus leads to quantum gates with very fast speeds and consequently
very high fidelities. Therefore, our scheme paves a promising way towards the
practical realization of high-fidelity nonadiabatic holonomic quantum
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07261</id><created>2016-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rueda</keyname><forenames>Alfredo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedlmeir</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collodo</keyname><forenames>Michele C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stiller</keyname><forenames>Birgit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schunk</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strekalov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquardt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Johannes M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Painter</keyname><forenames>Oskar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwefel</keyname><forenames>Harald G. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient single sideband microwave to optical conversion using an
  electro-optical whispering gallery mode resonator</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures; comments welcome!</comments><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.000597</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Linking classical microwave electrical circuits to the optical
telecommunication band is at the core of modern communication. Future quantum
information networks will require coherent microwave-to-optical conversion to
link electronic quantum processors and memories via low-loss optical
telecommunication networks. Efficient conversion can be achieved with
electro-optical modulators operating at the single microwave photon level. In
the standard electro-optic modulation scheme this is impossible because both,
up- and downconverted, sidebands are necessarily present. Here we demonstrate
true single sideband up- or downconversion in a triply resonant whispering
gallery mode resonator by explicitly addressing modes with asymmetric free
spectral range. Compared to previous experiments, we show a three orders of
magnitude improvement of the electro-optical conversion efficiency reaching
0.1% photon number conversion for a 10GHz microwave tone at 0.42mW of optical
pump power. The presented scheme is fully compatible with existing
superconducting 3D circuit quantum electrodynamics technology and can be used
for non-classical state conversion and communication. Our conversion bandwidth
is larger than 1MHz and not fundamentally limited.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02025</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yaouanc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Reotier</keyname><forenames>P. Dalmas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roessli</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forget</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A novel type of splayed ferromagnetic order observed in Yb2Ti2O7</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Revised version accepted for publication. To appear shortly in J.
  Phys.: Condens. Matter</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 426002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/42/426002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pyrochlore insulator Yb2Ti2O7 has attracted the attention of
experimentalists and theoreticians alike for about 15 years. Conflicting
neutron diffraction data on the possible existence of magnetic Bragg
reflections at low temperature have been published. Here we report the
observation of magnetic Bragg reflections by neutron powder diffraction at 60
mK. The magnetic diffraction pattern is analyzed using representation theory.
We find Yb2Ti2O7 to be a splayed ferromagnet as reported for Yb2Sn2O7, a
sibling compound with also dominating ferromagnetic interactions as inferred
from the positive Curie-Weiss temperature. However, the configuration of the
magnetic moment components perpendicular to the easy axis is of the
all-in--all-out type in Yb2Ti2O7 while it is two-in--two-out in Yb2Sn2O7. An
overall experimental picture of the magnetic properties emerges.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02974</id><created>2016-02-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zwicker</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murugan</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brenner</keyname><forenames>Michael P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Receptor arrays optimized for natural odor statistics</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.NC</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1073/pnas.1600357113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Natural odors typically consist of many molecules at different
concentrations. It is unclear how the numerous odorant molecules and their
possible mixtures are discriminated by relatively few olfactory receptors.
Using an information-theoretic model, we show that a receptor array is optimal
for this task if it achieves two possibly conflicting goals: (i) each receptor
should respond to half of all odors and (ii) the response of different
receptors should be uncorrelated when averaged over odors presented with
natural statistics. We use these design principles to predict statistics of the
affinities between receptors and odorant molecules for a broad class of odor
statistics. We also show that optimal receptor arrays can be tuned to either
resolve concentrations well or distinguish mixtures reliably. Finally, we use
our results to predict properties of experimentally measured receptor arrays.
Our work can thus be used to better understand natural olfaction and it also
suggests ways to improve artificial sensor arrays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05933</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tram</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fidler</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crittenden</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koyama</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettinari</keyname><forenames>Guido W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wands</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>The Intrinsic Matter Bispectrum in $\Lambda$CDM</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in JCAP. 17 pages + appendices, 6 figures.
  Code available at GitHub: http://github.com/coccoinomane/song</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/05/058</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a fully relativistic calculation of the matter bispectrum at
second order in cosmological perturbation theory assuming a Gaussian primordial
curvature perturbation. For the first time we perform a full numerical
integration of the bispectrum for both baryons and cold dark matter using the
second-order Einstein-Boltzmann code, SONG. We review previous analytical
results and provide an improved analytic approximation for the second-order
kernel in Poisson gauge which incorporates Newtonian nonlinear evolution,
relativistic initial conditions, the effect of radiation at early times and the
cosmological constant at late times. Our improved kernel provides a percent
level fit to the full numerical result at late times for most configurations,
including both equilateral shapes and the squeezed limit. We show that baryon
acoustic oscillations leave an imprint in the matter bispectrum, making a
significant impact on squeezed shapes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06034</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for single production of a vector-like quark via a heavy gluon in
  the $4b$ final state with the ATLAS detector in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt{s}
  = 8$ TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>36 pages, 5 figures, 5 tables. All figures including auxiliary
  figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/EXOT-2014-19</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-321</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B758 (2016) 249</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.04.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is performed for the process $pp \to G^* \to B_H\bar b/\bar B_H b
\to H b \bar b \to b\bar bb\bar b$, predicted in composite Higgs scenarios,
where $G^*$ is a heavy colour octet vector resonance and $B_H$ a vector-like
quark of charge $-1/3$. The data were obtained from $pp$ collisions at a
centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV corresponding to an integrated luminosity of
19.5 fb$^{-1}$, recorded by the ATLAS detector at the LHC. The largest
background, multijet production, is estimated using a data-driven method. No
significant excess of events with respect to Standard Model predictions is
observed, and upper limits on the production cross section times branching
ratio are set. Comparisons to the predictions from a specific benchmark model
are made, resulting in lower mass limits in the two-dimensional mass plane of
$m_{G^*}$ vs. $m_{B_H}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06278</id><created>2016-02-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Liew</keyname><forenames>Seng Fatt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redding</keyname><forenames>Brandon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choma</keyname><forenames>Michael A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagare</keyname><forenames>Hemant D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author></authors><title>Broadband multimode fiber spectrometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, in submission</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters Vol. 41, pp. 2029-2032 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.002029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general-purpose all-fiber spectrometer is demonstrated to overcome the
trade-off between spectral resolution and bandwidth. By integrating a
wavelength division multiplexer with five multimode optical fibers, we have
achieved 100 nm bandwidth with 0.03 nm resolution at wavelength 1500 nm. An
efficient algorithm is developed to reconstruct the spectrum from the speckle
pattern produced by interference of guided modes in the multimode fibers. Such
algorithm enables a rapid, accurate reconstruction of both sparse and dense
spectra in the presence of noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01612</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Redding</keyname><forenames>Brandon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liew</keyname><forenames>Seng Fatt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bromberg</keyname><forenames>Yaron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Raktim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author></authors><title>Evanescently coupled multimode spiral spectrometer</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, in submission</comments><journal-ref>Optica Vol. 3, pp. 956-962 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.3.000956</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We designed a high-resolution compact spectrometer based on an
evanescently-coupled multimode spiral waveguide. Interference between the modes
in the waveguide forms a wavelength-dependent speckle pattern which is used as
a fingerprint to identify the input wavelength after calibration. Evanescent
coupling between neighboring arms of the spiral results in a non-resonant
broad-band enhancement of the spectral resolution. Experimentally, we
demonstrated a resolution of 0.01 nm at a wavelength of 1520 nm using a 250
{\mu}m radius spiral structure. Spectra containing 40 independent spectral
channels are recovered simultaneously and the operation bandwidth is
significantly increased by applying compressive sensing to sparse spectra
reconstruction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02439</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Charged-particle distributions in $pp$ interactions at $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV
  measured with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>30 pages plus author list and cover page (47 pages total), 13
  figures, 1 table. Final version published in EPJC. All figures including
  auxiliary figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2014-19/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-020</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:403</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4203-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents measurements of distributions of charged particles which
are produced in proton--proton collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of
$\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV and recorded by the ATLAS detector at the LHC. A special
dataset recorded in 2012 with a small number of interactions per beam crossing
(below 0.004) and corresponding to an integrated luminosity of $160 \mathrm{\mu
b^{-1}}$ was used. A minimum-bias trigger was utilised to select a data sample
of more than 9 million collision events. The multiplicity, pseudorapidity, and
transverse momentum distributions of charged particles are shown in different
regions of kinematics and charged-particle multiplicity, including measurements
of final states at high multiplicity. The results are corrected for detector
effects and are compared to the predictions of various Monte Carlo event
generator models which simulate the full hadronic final state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02817</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02817</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Qichen</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Meng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiandong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Zhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zang</keyname><forenames>Jianfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Nuo</forenames></author></authors><title>The adjustable thermal resistor by reversibly folding a graphene sheet</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanoscale, 2016,8, 14943-14949</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6NR01992G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phononic (thermal) devices are studied such as thermal diode, thermal
transistors, thermal logic gates, and thermal memories. However, the thermal
resistor has not been demonstrated yet. Here, we propose an instantaneously
adjustable thermal resistor by folded graphene. Through theoretical analysis
and molecular dynamics simulations, we studied the phonon folding effect and
the dependent of thermal resistivity on the length between two folds and the
overall length. Further, we discuss on the possibility to realize the
instantaneously adjustable thermal resistor in experiment. Our studies bring
insights in designing thermal resistor and understanding thermal modulation of
2D materials by adjusting its basic structure parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02991</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for neutral resonances decaying into a Z boson and a pair of b
  jets or tau leptons</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/HIG-15-001/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-HIG-15-001, CERN-EP-2016-039</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 759 (2016) 369</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.05.087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is performed for a new resonance decaying into a lighter resonance
and a Z boson. Two channels are studied, targeting the decay of the lighter
resonance into either a pair of oppositely charged tau leptons or a b b-bar
pair. The Z boson is identified via its decays to electrons or muons. The
search exploits data collected by the CMS experiment at a centre-of-mass energy
of 8 TeV, corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 19.8 inverse femtobarns.
No significant deviations are observed from the standard model expectation and
limits are set on production cross sections and parameters of two-Higgs-doublet
models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03439</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Chien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muechler</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Car</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neupert</keyname><forenames>Titus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maciejko</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermionic Symmetry-Protected Topological Phase in a Two-Dimensional
  Hubbard Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Original: 5+3 pages, 4+2 figures, including the supplemental
  material. Revised: updated title, content, and references in version 2</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 096405 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.096405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the two-dimensional (2D) Hubbard model using exact diagonalization
for spin-1/2 fermions on the triangular and honeycomb lattices decorated with a
single hexagon per site. In certain parameter ranges, the Hubbard model maps to
a quantum compass model on those lattices. On the triangular lattice, the
compass model exhibits collinear stripe antiferromagnetism, implying
$d$-density wave charge order in the original Hubbard model. On the honeycomb
lattice, the compass model has a unique, quantum disordered ground state that
transforms nontrivially under lattice reflection. The ground state of the
Hubbard model on the decorated honeycomb lattice is thus a 2D fermionic
symmetry-protected topological phase. This state -- protected by time-reversal
and reflection symmetries -- cannot be connected adiabatically to a
free-fermion topological phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05566</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>Jean-Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xe9;bert-Dufresne</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allard</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dub&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Louis J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Growing networks of overlapping communities with internal structure</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>14 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables</comments><msc-class>37N99</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 022317 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an intuitive model that describes both the emergence of
community structure and the evolution of the internal structure of communities
in growing social networks. The model comprises two complementary mechanisms:
One mechanism accounts for the evolution of the internal link structure of a
single community, and the second mechanism coordinates the growth of multiple
overlapping communities. The first mechanism is based on the assumption that
each node establishes links with its neighbors and introduces new nodes to the
community at different rates. We demonstrate that this simple mechanism gives
rise to an effective maximal degree within communities. This observation is
related to the anthropological theory known as Dunbar's number, i.e., the
empirical observation of a maximal number of ties which an average individual
can sustain within its social groups. The second mechanism is based on a
recently proposed generalization of preferential attachment to community
structure, appropriately called structural preferential attachment (SPA). The
combination of these two mechanisms into a single model (SPA+) allows us to
reproduce a number of the global statistics of real networks: The distribution
of community sizes, of node memberships and of degrees. The SPA+ model also
predicts (a) three qualitative regimes for the degree distribution within
overlapping communities and (b) strong correlations between the number of
communities to which a node belongs and its number of connections within each
community. We present empirical evidence that support our findings in real
complex networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05646</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Haruki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Po</keyname><forenames>Hoi Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaletel</keyname><forenames>Michael P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vishwanath</keyname><forenames>Ashvin</forenames></author></authors><title>Filling-Enforced Gaplessness in Band Structures of the 230 Space Groups</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 page main text plus 9 page supplemental materials, 1 figure, 7
  tables; v2: minor changes throughout the paper; the version to appear in PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 096404 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.096404</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonsymmorphic symmetries like screws and glides produce electron band
touchings, obstructing the formation of a band insulator and leading, instead,
to metals or nodal semimetals even when the number of electrons in the unit
cell is an even integer. Here, we calculate the electron fillings compatible
with being a band insulator for all 230 space groups, for noninteracting
electrons with time-reversal symmetry. Our bounds are tight - that is, we can
rigorously eliminate band insulators at any forbidden filling and produce
explicit models for all allowed fillings - and stronger than those recently
established for interacting systems. These results provide simple criteria that
should help guide the search for topological semimetals and, also, have
implications for both the nature and stability of the resulting nodal Fermi
surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07445</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07445</id><created>2016-03-24</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fire</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guestrin</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Time Is of the Essence: Analyzing the Effect of Vertex-Joining Time on
  Complex Network Evolution</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Complex networks have non-trivial characteristics and appear in many
real-world systems. Such networks are vitally important, but their full
underlying dynamics are not completely understood. Utilizing new data sources,
however, can unveil the evolution process of these networks.
  This study uses the recently published Reddit dataset, containing over 1.65
billion comments, to construct the largest publicly available social network
corpus to date. We used this dataset to deeply examine the network evolution
process, which resulted in two key observations: First, links are more likely
to be created among users who join a network at a similar time. Second, the
rate in which new users join a network is a central factor in molding a
network's topology; i.e., different user-join patterns create different
topological properties.
  Based on these observations, we developed the \textit{Temporal Preferential
Attachment} random network generation model. This model produces not only
scale-free networks that have relative high clustering coefficients, but also
networks that are sensitive to both the rate and the time in which users join
the network. This results in a more accurate and flexible model of how complex
networks evolve, one which more closely represents real-world data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08545</id><created>2016-03-28</created><updated>2016-08-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>Pramod</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting the two formulations of Bianchi identities and their
  implications on moduli stabilization</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>version 3: 46 pages; improved presentation with some clarifications
  added on page 18; to appear in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP08(2016)146</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)146</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of non-geometric type II orientifold compactifications, there
have been two formulations for representing the various NS-NS
Bianchi-identities. In the first formulation, the standard three-form flux
($H_3$), the geometric flux ($\omega$) and the non-geometric fluxes ($Q$ and
$R$) are expressed by using the real six-dimensional indices (e.g. $H_{ijk},
\omega_{ij}{}^k, Q_i{}^{jk}$ and $R^{ijk}$), and this formulation has been
heavily utilized for simplifying the scalar potentials in
toroidal-orientifolds. On the other hand, relevant for the studies beyond
toroidal backgrounds, a second formulation is utilized in which all flux
components are written in terms of various involutively even/odd $(2,1)$- and
$(1,1)$-cohomologies of the complex threefold. In the lights of recent model
building interests and some observations made in arXiv:0705.3410 and
arXiv:0709.2186, in this article, we revisit two most commonly studied toroidal
examples in detail to illustrate that the present forms of these two
formulations are not completely equivalent. To demonstrate the same, we
translate all the identities of the first formulation into cohomology
ingredients, and after a tedious reshuffling of the subsequent constraints,
interestingly we find that all the identities of the second formulation are
embedded into the first formulation which has some additional constraints. In
addition, we look for the possible solutions of these Bianchi identities in a
detailed analysis, and we find that some solutions can reduce the size of
scalar potential very significantly, and in some cases are too strong to break
the no-scale structure completely. Finally, we also comment on the influence of
imposing some of the solutions of Bianchi identities in studying moduli
stabilization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00683</id><created>2016-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Barkeshli</keyname><forenames>Maissam</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge $2e/3$ superconductivity and topological degeneracies without
  localized zero modes in bilayer fractional quantum Hall states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages + 4 pages appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 096803 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.096803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been recently shown that non-Abelian defects with localized
parafermion zero modes can arise in conventional Abelian fractional quantum
Hall (FQH) states. Here we propose an alternate route to creating,
manipulating, and measuring topologically protected degeneracies in bilayer FQH
states coupled to superconductors, without the creation of localized
parafermion zero modes. We focus mainly on electron-hole bilayers, with a $\pm
1/3$ Laughlin FQH state in each layer, with boundaries that are
proximity-coupled to a superconductor. We show that the superconductor induces
charge $2e/3$ quasiparticle-pair condensation at each boundary of the FQH
state, and that this leads to (1) topologically protected degeneracies that can
be measured through charge sensing experiments and (2) a fractional charge
$2e/3$ AC Josephson effect. We demonstrate that an analog of non-Abelian
braiding is possible, despite the absence of a localized zero mode. We discuss
several practical advantages of this proposal over previous work, and also
extensions to electron-electron bilayers at $\nu = 2/3 + 1/3$ coupled to
superconductivity, and to electron-hole bilayers with only interlayer
tunneling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04201</id><created>2016-04-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Elze</keyname><forenames>Hans-Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipartite Cellular Automata and the Superposition Principle</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP nlin.CG</categories><comments>12 pages; accepted for publication - Int. J. Qu. Info</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Quant. Info. (IJQI) Vol. 14, No. 4 (2016) 1640001</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749916400013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cellular automata can show well known features of quantum mechanics, such as
a linear updating rule that resembles a discretized form of the Schr\&quot;odinger
equation together with its conservation laws. Surprisingly, a whole class of
&quot;natural&quot; Hamiltonian cellular automata, which are based entirely on
integer-valued variables and couplings and derived from an Action Principle,
can be mapped reversibly to continuum models with the help of Sampling Theory.
This results in &quot;deformed&quot; quantum mechanical models with a finite discreteness
scale $l$, which for $l\rightarrow 0$ reproduce the familiar continuum limit.
Presently, we show, in particular, how such automata can form &quot;multipartite&quot;
systems consistently with the tensor product structures of nonrelativistic
many-body quantum mechanics, while maintaining the linearity of dynamics.
Consequently, the Superposition Principle is fully operative already on the
level of these primordial discrete deterministic automata, including the
essential quantum effects of interference and entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05136</id><created>2016-04-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hofmann</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>SU(2) Yang-Mills Theory: Waves, Particles, and Quantum Thermodynamics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, no figs</comments><journal-ref>Entropy 2016, 18, 310</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e18090310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We elucidate how Quantum Thermodynamics at temperature $T$ emerges from pure
and classical SU(2) Yang-Mills theory on a four-dimensional Euclidean spacetime
slice $S_1\times {\bf R}^3$. The concept of a (deconfining) thermal ground
state, composed of certain solutions to the fundamental, classical Yang-Mills
equation, allows for a unified addressation of both (classical) wave- and
(quantum) particle-like excitations thereof.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05849</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fejos</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsuda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fixed point structure of the Abelian Higgs model</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, title changed, typos corrected, gauge fixing
  condition refined (results unchanged)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 121701 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.121701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The order of the superconducting phase transition is analyzed via the
functional renormalization group approach. For the first time, we derive fully
analytic expressions for the $\beta$ functions of the charge and the
self-coupling in the Abelian Higgs model with one complex scalar field in $d=3$
dimensions that support the existence of two charged fixed points: an infrared
(IR) stable fixed point describing a second-order phase transition and a
tritical fixed point controlling the region of the parameter space that is
attracted by the former one. It is found that the region separating first- and
second-order transitions can be uniquely characterized by the Ginzburg-Landau
parameter $\kappa$, and the system undergoes a second order transition, only if
$\kappa&gt;\kappa_c \approx 0.62/\sqrt2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06099</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Batell</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pospelov</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shuve</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Shedding Light on Neutrino Masses with Dark Forces</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 12 figures. v2: final version published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1608 (2016) 052</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Heavy right-handed neutrinos (RHNs) provide the simplest explanation for the
origin of light neutrino masses and mixings. If the RHN masses are at or below
the weak scale, direct experimental discovery of these states is possible at
accelerator experiments such as the LHC or new dedicated beam dump experiments;
in such experiments, the RHN decays after traversing a macroscopic distance
from the collision point. The experimental sensitivity to RHNs is significantly
enhanced if there is a new &quot;dark&quot; gauge force connecting them to the Standard
Model (SM), and detection of RHNs can be the primary discovery mode for the new
dark force itself. We take the well-motivated example of a B-L gauge symmetry
and analyze the sensitivity to displaced decays of the RHNs produced via the
new gauge interaction in two experiments: the LHC and the proposed SHiP beam
dump experiment. In the most favorable case in which the mediator can be
produced on-shell and decays to RHNs, the sensitivity reach is controlled by
the square of the B-L gauge coupling. We demonstrate that these experiments
could access neutrino parameters responsible for the observed SM neutrino
masses and mixings in the most straightforward implementation of the see-saw
mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06956</id><created>2016-04-23</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>Panayotis G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuevas-Maraver</keyname><forenames>Jes&#xfa;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelinovsky</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy criterion for the spectral stability of discrete breathers</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures. Includes Supplementary Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 094101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.094101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discrete breathers are ubiquitous structures in nonlinear anharmonic models
ranging from the prototypical example of the Fermi-Pasta-Ulam model to
Klein-Gordon nonlinear lattices, among many others. We propose a general
criterion for the emergence of instabilities of discrete breathers analogous to
the well-established Vakhitov-Kolokolov criterion for solitary waves. The
criterion involves the change of monotonicity of the discrete breather's energy
as a function of the breather frequency. Our analysis suggests and numerical
results corroborate that breathers with increasing (decreasing)
energy-frequency dependence are generically unstable in soft (hard) nonlinear
potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00670</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Simone</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Aspects of Spontaneous Baryogenesis</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>31 pages, 4 figures, v2: published in JCAP</comments><report-no>SISSA 24/2016/FISI</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)052</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate cosmological aspects of spontaneous baryogenesis driven by a
scalar field, and present general constraints that are independent of the
particle physics model. The relevant constraints are obtained by studying the
backreaction of the produced baryons on the scalar field, the cosmological
expansion history after baryogenesis, and the baryon isocurvature
perturbations. We show that cosmological considerations alone provide powerful
constraints, especially for the minimal scenario with a quadratic scalar
potential. Intriguingly, we find that for a given inflation scale, the other
parameters including the reheat temperature, decoupling temperature of the
baryon violating interactions, and the mass and decay constant of the scalar
are restricted to lie within ranges of at most a few orders of magnitude. We
also discuss possible extensions to the minimal setup, and propose two ideas
for evading constraints on isocurvature perturbations: one is to suppress the
baryon isocurvature with nonquadratic scalar potentials, another is to
compensate the baryon isocurvature with cold dark matter isocurvature by making
the scalar survive until the present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01416</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hedri</keyname><forenames>Sonia El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirschauer</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Nhan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitbeck</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissecting Jets and Missing Energy Searches Using $n$-body Extended
  Simplified Models</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>31 + 28 pages, 11 + 10 figures; v2 references added, journal version</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-122-E, NSF-KITP-16-063</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simplified Models are a useful way to characterize new physics scenarios for
the LHC. Particle decays are often represented using non-renormalizable
operators that involve the minimal number of fields required by symmetries.
Generalizing to a wider class of decay operators allows one to model a variety
of final states. This approach, which we dub the $n$-body extension of
Simplified Models, provides a unifying treatment of the signal phase space
resulting from a variety of signals. In this paper, we present the first
application of this framework in the context of multijet plus missing energy
searches. The main result of this work is a global performance study with the
goal of identifying which set of observables yields the best discriminating
power against the largest Standard Model backgrounds for a wide range of signal
jet multiplicities. Our analysis compares combinations of one, two and three
variables, placing emphasis on the enhanced sensitivity gain resulting from
non-trivial correlations. Utilizing boosted decision trees, we compare and
classify the performance of missing energy, energy scale and energy structure
observables. We demonstrate that including an observable from each of these
three classes is required to achieve optimal performance. This work
additionally serves to establish the utility of $n$-body extended Simplified
Models as a diagnostic for unpacking the relative merits of different search
strategies, thereby motivating their application to new physics signatures
beyond jets and missing energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04617</id><created>2016-05-15</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xc1;lvarez-Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ariznabarreta</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Ardila</keyname><forenames>Juan C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcell&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation theory and Christoffel formulas for matrix biorthogonal
  polynomials on the real line</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP math.RA math.SP nlin.SI</categories><comments>103 pages, 1 table</comments><msc-class>42C05, 15A23</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper transformations for matrix orthogonal polynomials in the real
line are studied. The orthogonality is understood in a broad sense, and is
given in terms of a nondegenerate continuous sesquilinear form, which in turn
is determined by a quasidefinite matrix of bivariate generalized functions with
a well defined support. The discussion of the orthogonality for such a
sesquilinear form includes, among others, matrix Hankel cases with linear
functionals, general matrix Sobolev orthogonality and discrete orthogonal
polynomials with an infinite support. The first transformation considered is
that of Geronimus type, two different methods are developed. A spectral one,
based on the spectral properties of the perturbing polynomial, and constructed
in terms of the second kind functions. Then, using spectral techniques and
spectral jets, Christoffel-Geronimus formulas for the transformed polynomials
and norms are presented. For this type of transformations, the paper also
proposes an alternative method, which does not require of spectral techniques.
A discussion on matrix spectral linear transformations is presented, as well.
These transformations can be understood as rational perturbations of the matrix
of bivariate generalized functions together with an addition of appropriate
masses, determined these last ones by the spectral properties of the polynomial
denominator. As for the Geronimus case, two techniques are applied, spectral
and mixed spectral/nonspectral. Christoffel--Geronimus--Uvarov formulas are
found with both approaches and some applications are given. The transformation
theory is finally discussed in the context of the 2D non-Abelian Toda lattice
and noncommutative KP hierarchies, understood as the theory of continuous
transformations of quasidefinite sesquilinear forms. This approach allows for
the finding of perturbed quasitau and Baker matrices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04917</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>D'Eramo</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavanagh</keyname><forenames>Bradley J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panci</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>You can hide but you have to run: direct detection with vector mediators</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>26 pages + appendices, 9 + 2 figures. The runDM code is available at
  https://github.com/bradkav/runDM/. v2: references added, version published in
  JHEP</comments><report-no>SCIPP 16/07</report-no><journal-ref>J. High Energ. Phys. (2016) 2016: 111</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study direct detection in simplified models of Dark Matter (DM) in which
interactions with Standard Model (SM) fermions are mediated by a heavy vector
boson. We consider fully general, gauge-invariant couplings between the SM, the
mediator and both scalar and fermion DM. We account for the evolution of the
couplings between the energy scale of the mediator mass and the nuclear energy
scale. This running arises from virtual effects of SM particles and its
inclusion is not optional. We compare bounds on the mediator mass from direct
detection experiments with and without accounting for the running. In some
cases the inclusion of these effects changes the bounds by several orders of
magnitude, as a consequence of operator mixing which generates new interactions
at low energy. We also highlight the importance of these effects when
translating LHC limits on the mediator mass into bounds on the direct detection
cross section. For an axial-vector mediator, the running can alter the derived
bounds on the spin-dependent DM-nucleon cross section by a factor of two or
more. Finally, we provide tools to facilitate the inclusion of these effects in
future studies: general approximate expressions for the low energy couplings
and a public code runDM to evolve the couplings between arbitrary energy
scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07118</id><created>2016-05-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Planat</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames><affiliation>Institut FEMTO-ST, CNRS, Besan&#xe7;on, France</affiliation></author></authors><title>Two-letter words and a fundamental homomorphism ruling geometric
  contextuality</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.GR math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 11 figures, 2 tables to appear in &quot;Symmetry: Culture and
  Science&quot;</comments><msc-class>81P13, 11G32, 43A22, 81P45</msc-class><journal-ref>Symmetry, Culture and Science: Vol. 28, No 3, 255-270, 2017</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has recently been recognized by the author that the quantum contextuality
paradigm may be formulated in terms of the properties of some subgroups of the
two-letter free group $G$ and their corresponding point-line incidence geometry
$\mathcal{G}$. I introduce a fundamental homomorphism $f$ mapping the
(infinitely many) words of G to the permutations ruling the symmetries of
$\mathcal{G}$. The substructure of $f$ is revealing the essence of geometric
contextuality in a straightforward way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08430</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Contrera</keyname><forenames>Gustavo A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grunfeld</keyname><forenames>A. Gabriela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaschke</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Supporting the search for the CEP location with nonlocal PNJL models
  constrained by Lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 Figures. Version accepted by Eur. Phys. J. A as part of
  the topical collection: Exploring strongly interacting matter at high
  densities - NICA White Paper</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 231</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16231-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possible location of the critical endpoint in the QCD
phase diagram based on nonlocal covariant PNJL models including a vector
interaction channel. The form factors of the covariant interaction are
constrained by lattice QCD data for the quark propagator. The comparison of our
results for the pressure including the pion contribution and the scaled
pressure shift $\Delta P / T^4$ vs $T/T_c$ with lattice QCD results shows a
better agreement when Lorentzian formfactors for the nonlocal interactions and
the wave function renormalization are considered. The strength of the vector
coupling is used as a free parameter which influences results at finite
baryochemical potential. It is used to adjust the slope of the pseudocritical
temperature of the chiral phase transition at low baryochemical potential and
the scaled pressure shift accessible in lattice QCD simulations. Our study,
albeit presently performed at the meanfield level, supports the very existence
of a critical point and favors its location within a region that is accessible
in experiments at the NICA accelerator complex.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09396</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Radicevic</keyname><forenames>Djordje</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement Entropy and Duality</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages; v2: typos corrected, minimal edits for clarity</comments><report-no>SU-ITP-16/11</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the algebraic approach to entanglement entropy, we study several dual
pairs of lattice theories and show how the entropy is completely preserved
across each duality. Our main result is that a maximal algebra of observables
in a region typically dualizes to a non-maximal algebra in a dual region. In
particular, we show how the usual notion of tracing out external degrees of
freedom dualizes to a tracing out coupled to an additional summation over
superselection sectors. We briefly comment on possible extensions of our
results to more intricate dualities, including holographic ones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09580</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barenghi</keyname><forenames>Carlo F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parker</keyname><forenames>Nick G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A primer on quantum fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>132 pages. Published as SpringerBriefs in Physics book. Typos
  corrected in this version</comments><journal-ref>A Primer in Quantum Fluids (Springer, Berlin 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-42476-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This book introduces the theoretical description and properties of quantum
fluids. The focus is on gaseous atomic Bose-Einstein condensates and, to a
minor extent, superfluid helium, but the underlying concepts are relevant to
other forms of quantum fluids such as polariton and photonic condensates. The
book is pitched at the level of advanced undergraduates and early postgraduate
students, aiming to provide the reader with the knowledge and skills to develop
their own research project on quantum fluids. Indeed, the content for this book
grew from introductory notes provided to our own research students. It is
assumed that the reader has prior knowledge of undergraduate mathematics and/or
physics; otherwise, the concepts are introduced from scratch, often with
references for directed further reading.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00859</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Prabhu</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schiffrin</keyname><forenames>Joshua S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wald</keyname><forenames>Robert M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Variational Principle for the Axisymmetric Stability of Rotating
  Relativistic Stars</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>v2: updated some text and references; published in CQG v1: 36 pages</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. (2016) 33 185007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/18/185007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well known that all rotating perfect fluid stars in general relativity
are unstable to certain non-axisymmetric perturbations via the
Chandrasekhar-Friedman-Schutz (CFS) instability. However, the mechanism of the
CFS instability requires, in an essential way, the loss of angular momentum by
gravitational radiation and, in many instances, it acts on too long a timescale
to be physically/astrophysically relevant. It is therefore of interest to
examine the stability of rotating, relativistic stars to axisymmetric
perturbations, where the CFS instability does not occur. In this paper, we
provide a Rayleigh-Ritz type variational principle for testing the stability of
perfect fluid stars to axisymmetric perturbations, which generalizes to
axisymmetric perturbations of rotating stars a variational principle given by
Chandrasekhar for spherical perturbations of static, spherical stars. Our
variational principle provides a lower bound to the rate of exponential growth
in the case of instability. The derivation closely parallels the derivation of
a recently obtained variational principle for analyzing the axisymmetric
stability of black holes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06632</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mertens</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verschelde</keyname><forenames>Henri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakharov</keyname><forenames>Valentin I.</forenames></author></authors><title>String Theory in Polar Coordinates and the Vanishing of the One-Loop
  Rindler Entropy</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>58 pages + appendices, v2: typos corrected, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1608 (2016) 113</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the string spectrum of flat space in polar coordinates, following
the small curvature limit of the $SL(2,\mathbb{R})/U(1)$ cigar CFT. We first
analyze the partition function of the cigar itself, making some clarifications
of the structure of the spectrum that have escaped attention up to this point.
The superstring spectrum (type 0 and type II) is shown to exhibit an involution
symmetry, that survives the small curvature limit. We classify all marginal
states in polar coordinates for type II superstrings, with emphasis on their
links and their superconformal structure. This classification is confirmed by
an explicit large $\tau_2$ analysis of the partition function. Next we compare
three approaches towards the type II genus one entropy in Rindler space: using
a sum-over-fields strategy, using a Melvin model approach and finally using a
saddle point method on the cigar partition function. In each case we highlight
possible obstructions and motivate that the correct procedures yield a
vanishing result: $S=0$. We finally discuss how the QFT UV divergences of the
fields in the spectrum disappear when computing the free energy and entropy
using Euclidean techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08356</id><created>2016-06-27</created><updated>2016-08-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hollik</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang Gregor</forenames></author></authors><title>A new view on vacuum stability in the MSSM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 10 figures; v3: typos corrected, matches version to be
  published in JHEP</comments><report-no>DESY 16-114</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 08 (2016) 126</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)126</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  A consistent theoretical description of physics at high energies requires an
assessment of vacuum stability in either the Standard Model or any extension of
it. Especially supersymmetric extensions allow for several vacua and the choice
of the desired electroweak one gives strong constraints on the parameter space.
As the general parameter space in the Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model is
huge, any severe constraint on it unrelated to direct phenomenological
observations enhances the predictability of the model. We perform an updated
analysis of possible charge and color breaking minima without relying on fixed
directions in field space that minimize certain terms in the potential (known
as &quot;D-flat&quot; directions). Concerning the cosmological stability of false vacua,
we argue that there are always directions in configuration space which lead to
very short-lived vacua and therefore such exclusions are strict. In addition to
existing strong constraints on the parameter space, we find even stronger
constraints extending the field space compared to previous analyses and combine
those constraints with predictions for the light CP-even Higgs mass in the
Minimal Supersymmetric Standard Model. Low masses for supersymmetric partners
are excluded from vacuum stability in combination with the 125 GeV Higgs and
the allowed parameter space opens at a few TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00406</id><created>2016-07-01</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baker</keyname><forenames>Mark Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>On the analytical formulation of classical electromagnetic fields</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Three objections to the canonical analytical treatment of covariant
electromagnetic theory are presented: (i) only half of Maxwell's equations are
present upon variation of the fundamental Lagrangian; (ii) the trace of the
canonical energy-momentum tensor is not equivalent to the trace of the observed
energy-momentum tensor; (iii) the Belinfante symmetrization procedure exists
separate from the analytical approach in order to obtain the known observed
result. It is shown that the analytical construction from Noether's theorem is
based on manipulations that were developed to obtain the compact forms of the
theory presented by Minkowski and Einstein; presentations which were developed
before the existence of Noether's theorem. By reformulating the fundamental
Lagrangian, all of the objections are simultaneously relieved. Variation of the
proposed Lagrangian yields the complete set of Maxwell's equations in the
Euler-Lagrange equation of motion, and the observed energy-momentum tensor
directly follows from Noether's theorem. Previously unavailable symmetries and
identities that follow naturally from this procedure are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02498</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>Torben R</forenames><affiliation>European Spallation Source ERIC, Denmark</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Markvardsen</keyname><forenames>Anders J</forenames><affiliation>ISIS Facility, Rutherford Appleton Laboratory, UK</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Willendrup</keyname><forenames>Peter K</forenames><affiliation>European Spallation Source ERIC, Denmark</affiliation><affiliation>Physics Department, Technical University of Denmark</affiliation></author></authors><title>McStas and Mantid integration</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>17 pages, 12 figures, POSTPRINT with proofs of article submitted to
  Journal of Neutron Research</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  McStas and Mantid are two well established software frameworks within the
neutron scattering community. McStas has been primarily used for simulating the
neutron transport of instruments, while Mantid has been primarily used for data
reduction. We report here the status of our work done on the interoperability
between the instrument simulation software McStas and the data reduction
software Mantid. This provides a demonstration of how to successfully link
together two software that otherwise have been developed independently, and in
particular here show how this has been achieved for an instrument simulation
software and a data reduction software. This paper will also provide examples
of some of the expected future enhanced analysis that can be achieved from
combining accurate instrument and sample simulations with software for
correcting raw data. In the case of this work for raw data collected at large
scale neutron facilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07953</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohashi</keyname><forenames>Koki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawamata</keyname><forenames>Takayuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takamatsu</keyname><forenames>Tomohisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adachi</keyname><forenames>Tadashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kato</keyname><forenames>Masatsune</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koike</keyname><forenames>Yoji</forenames></author></authors><title>Pairing Symmetry Studied from Impurity Effects in the Undoped
  Superconductor T'-La$_{1.8}$Eu$_{0.2}$CuO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, accepted for publication in Journal of the
  Physical Society of Japan</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 093703 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.093703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have investigated the effects of magnetic Ni and nonmagnetic Zn impurities
on the superconductivity in undoped T'-La$_{1.8}$Eu$_{0.2}$CuO$_4$ (T'-LECO)
with the Nd$_2$CuO$_4$-type structure, using the polycrystalline bulk samples,
to clarify the pairing symmetry. It has been found that both suppression rates
of the superconducting transition temperature $T_\mathrm{c}$ by Ni and Zn
impurities are nearly the same and are very similar to those in the optimally
doped and overdoped regimes of hole-doped T-La$_{2-x}$Sr$_{x}$CuO$_4$ with the
K$_2$NiF$_4$-type structure. These results strongly suggest that the
superconductivity in undoped T'-LECO is of the $d$-wave symmetry and is
mediated by the spin fluctuation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08680</id><created>2016-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Otaka</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mashiko</keyname><forenames>Hiroaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Yusei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tenya</keyname><forenames>Kenichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueta</keyname><forenames>Daichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshizawa</keyname><forenames>Hideki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakakibara</keyname><forenames>Toshiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity and non-Fermi-liquid behavior in the heavy-fermion
  compound CeCo$_{1-x}$Ni$_x$In$_5$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, to appear in J. Phys. Soc. Jpn</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 094713 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.094713</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effect of off-plane impurity on superconductivity and non-Fermi-liquid
(NFL) behavior in the layered heavy-fermion compound CeCo$_{1-x}$Ni$_x$In$_5$
is investigated by specific heat, magnetization, and electrical resistivity
measurements. These measurements reveal that the superconducting (SC)
transition temperature T$_c$ monotonically decreases from 2.3 K (x=0) to 0.8 K
(x=0.20) with increasing x, and then the SC order disappears above x=0.25. At
the same time, the Ni substitution yields the NFL behavior at zero field for
x=0.25, characterized by the -ln T divergence in specific heat divided by
temperature, C$_p$/T, and magnetic susceptibility, M/B. The NFL behavior in
magnetic fields for x=0.25 is quite similar to that seen at around the SC upper
critical field in pure CeCoIn$_5$, suggesting that both compounds are governed
by the same antiferromagnetic quantum criticality. The resemblance of the
doping effect on the SC order among Ni- , Sn-, and Pt-substituted CeCoIn5
supports the argument that the doped carriers are primarily responsible for the
breakdown of the SC order. The present investigation further reveals the
quantitative differences in the trends of the suppression of superconductivity
between Ce(Co,Ni)In$_5$ and the other alloys, such as the rates of decrease in
T$_c$, dT$_c$/dx, and specific heat jump at T$_c$, d($\Delta$C$_p$/T$_c$)/dx.
We suggest that the occupied positions of the doped ions play an important role
in the origin of these differences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00467</id><created>2016-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Koley</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transition in IrTe$_2$ induced by spin-orbit coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Solid State Communications 247, 40,2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2016.08.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  IrTe$_2$ has been renewed as an interesting system showing competing
phenomenon between a questionable density-wave transition near 270 K followed
by superconductivity with doping of high atomic number materials. Higher atomic
numbers of Te and Ir supports strong spin-orbital coupling in this system.
Using dynamical mean field theory with LDA band structure I have introduced
Rashba spin orbit coupling in this system to get the interpretation for
anomalous resistivity and related transition in this system. While no
considerable changes are observed in DMFT results of Ir-5d band other than
orbital selective pseudogap pinned to Fermi level, Te-p band shows a van Hove
singularity at the Fermi level except low temperature. Finally I discuss the
implications of these results in theoretical understanding of ordering in
IrTe$_2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02627</id><created>2016-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Borzi</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albarrac&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>F. A. G&#xf3;mez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosales</keyname><forenames>H. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rossini</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steppke</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prabhakaran</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackenzie</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabra</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigera</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Intermediate magnetisation state and competing orders in
  Dy$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ and Ho$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>27 pages, 8 figures, including supplementary information, accepted
  for publication in Nature Communications</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12592 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12592</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Among the frustrated magnetic materials, spin-ice stands out as a
particularly interesting system. Residual entropy, freezing and glassiness,
Kasteleyn transitions and fractionalisation of excitations in three dimensions
all stem from a simple classical Hamiltonian. But is the usual spin-ice
Hamiltonian a correct description of the experimental systems? Here we address
this issue by measuring magnetic susceptibility in the two most studied
spin-ice compounds, Dy$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$ and Ho$_2$Ti$_2$O$_7$, using a vector
magnet. Using these results, and guided by a theoretical analysis of possible
distortions to the pyrochlore lattice, we construct an effective Hamiltonian
and explore it using Monte Carlo simulations. We show how this Hamiltonian
reproduces the experimental results, including the formation of a phase of
intermediate polarisation, and gives important information about the possible
ground-state of real spin-ice systems. Our work suggests an unusual situation
in which distortions might contribute to the preservation rather than relief of
the effects of frustration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03283</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Fuchs</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunlap</keyname><forenames>Bart H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennihy</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Donoghue</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clemens</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichart</keyname><forenames>D. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>LaCluyze</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haislip</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivarsen</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Magnetic Cataclysmic Variable LSQ1725-64</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted to MNRAS, 16 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 2016, 462: 2382-2395</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new photometry and spectroscopy of the 94m eclipsing binary
LSQ1725-64 that provide insight into the fundamental parameters and
evolutionary state of this system. We confirm that LSQ1725-64 is a magnetic
cataclysmic variable whose white dwarf has a surface-averaged magnetic field
strength of $12.5 \pm 0.5$ MG measured from Zeeman splitting. The spectral type
and colour of the secondary, as well as the eclipse length, are consistent with
other secondaries that have not yet evolved through the period minimum expected
for cataclysmic variables. We observe two different states of mass transfer and
measure the transition between the two to occur over about 45 orbital cycles.
In the low state, we observe photometric variations that we hypothesize to
arise predominantly from two previously heated magnetic poles of the white
dwarf. Our precise eclipse measurements allow us to determine binary parameters
of LSQ1725-64 and we find it contains a high mass ($0.97 \pm 0.03\ M_{\odot}$)
white dwarf if we assume a typical mass-radius relationship for a CO core white
dwarf. We also measure an eclipse of the accretion stream after the white dwarf
eclipse, and use it to estimate an upper limit of the mass transfer rate. This
derived limit is consistent with that expected from angular momentum loss via
gravitational radiation alone.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03982</id><created>2016-08-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Vijande</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valcarce</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for doubly-heavy dibaryons in a quark model</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages. To be published in Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 034038 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.034038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the stability of hexaquark systems containing two heavy quarks and
four light quarks within a simple quark model. No bound or metastable state is
found. The reason stems on a delicate interplay between chromoelectric and
chromomagnetic effects. Our calculation provides also information about
anticharmed pentaquarks that are seemingly unbound in simple quark models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05264</id><created>2016-08-10</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>Katsutaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational energy of a Schwarzschild black hole</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous paper, we proposed a new gravitational energy momentum tensor.
Here we use this tensor to evaluate the gravitational energies both inside and
outside the horizon of a Schwarzschild black hole. Our results show that all of
the gravitational energy exists outside the horizon, and that there is no
gravitational energy inside the horizon. We comment on a relation with our
gravitational energy momentum tensor and another one which is proposed in a
teleparallel gravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05673</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Najimuddin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyaya</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakshit</keyname><forenames>Subhendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>Avirup</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring the extended scalar sector with resonances in vector boson
  scattering</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, minor corrections</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the study of scalar resonances at various vector boson
scattering processes at the Large Hadron Collider can serve as a useful tool to
distinguish between different extensions of the scalar sector of the Standard
Model. The recent measurement of the Higgs boson properties leaves enough room
for the extended scalar sectors to be relevant for such studies. The shape of
the resonances, being model dependent, can shed light on the viable parameter
space of a number of theoretical models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06795</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Pursiainen</keyname><forenames>Sampsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaasalainen</keyname><forenames>Mikko</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnetic 3D subsurface imaging with source sparsity for a
  synthetic object</title><categories>astro-ph.IM math-ph math.MP physics.med-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures. This is an author-created, un-copyedited version
  of an article accepted for publication/published in Inverse Problems. IOP
  Publishing Ltd is not responsible for any errors or omissions in this version
  of the manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version of Record is
  available online at http://doi.org/10.1088/0266-5611/31/12/125004</comments><msc-class>65R32, 85A99</msc-class><journal-ref>Inverse Problems 31 (2015) 125004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0266-5611/31/12/125004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper concerns electromagnetic 3D subsurface imaging in connection with
sparsity of signal sources. We explored an imaging approach that can be
implemented in situations that allow obtaining a large amount of data over a
surface or a set of orbits but at the same time require sparsity of the signal
sources. Characteristic to such a tomography scenario is that it necessitates
the inversion technique to be genuinely three-dimensional: For example, slicing
is not possible due to the low number of sources. Here, we primarily focused on
astrophysical subsurface exploration purposes. As an example target of our
numerical experiments we used a synthetic small planetary object containing
three inclusions, e.g. voids, of the size of the wavelength. A tetrahedral
arrangement of source positions was used, it being the simplest symmetric point
configuration in 3D. Our results suggest that somewhat reliable inversion
results can be produced within the present a priori assumptions, if the data
can be recorded at a specific resolution. This is valuable early-stage
knowledge especially for design of future planetary missions in which the
payload needs to be minimized, and potentially also for the development of
other lightweight subsurface inspection systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06936</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tianye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>Yefeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Chuangang</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple setup to measure muon lifetime and electron energy spectrum of
  muon decay and its Monte Carlo simulation</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We designed a simple setup to measure the muon lifetime and the electron
energy spectra of muon decay. A low cost coincidental circuit was designed to
select the signals of muon decay events detected by a plastic scintillator
detector. It triggered a digital oscilloscope to record the signals of muon
decay events for measuring the muon lifetime and electron energy spectrum. A
Landau-distribution energy loss method was introduced to conduct the energy
calibration of the system. The experimental results were well reproduced by the
Monte Carlo simulation. The software and hardware of the system are completely
open to students, thus more helpful for instruction and motivation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06937</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Grosvenor</keyname><forenames>Kevin T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horava</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mogni</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Ziqi</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonrelativistic Short-Distance Completions of a Naturally Light Higgs</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonrelativistic scalar field theories can exhibit a natural cascading
hierarchy of scales, protected by a hierarchy of polynomial shift symmetries.
Using a simple model, we argue that a high-energy cross-over to such
nonrelativistic behavior naturally leads to light scalars, and thus represents
a useful ingredient for technically natural resolutions of scalar mass
hierarchies, perhaps even the Higgs mass hierarchy puzzle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06939</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06939</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Markson</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rittenhouse</keyname><forenames>Seth T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaffer</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadeghpour</keyname><forenames>H. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin mixing in Cs ultralong-range Rydberg molecules: a case study</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate vibrational spectra of ultralong-range Cs(32p) Rydberg molecules
which form in an ultracold gas of Cs atoms. We account for the partial-wave
scattering of the Rydberg electrons from the ground Cs perturber atoms by
including the full set of spin-resolved ${}^{1,3}S_J$ and ${}^{1,3}P_J$
scattering phase shifts, and allow for the mixing of singlet (S=0) and triplet
(S=1) spin states through Rydberg electron spin-orbit and ground electron
hyperfine interactions. Excellent agreement with observed data in
Sa{\ss}mannshausen et al. [Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 133201(2015)] in line
positions and profiles is obtained. We also determine the spin-dependent
permanent electric dipole moments for these molecules. This is the first such
calculation of ultralong-range Rydberg molecules in which all of the
relativistic contributions are accounted for.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06940</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Hardy</keyname><forenames>Lucien</forenames></author></authors><title>Operational General Relativity: Possibilistic, Probabilistic, and
  Quantum</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>235 pages. Many figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we develop an operational formulation of General Relativity
similar in spirit to existing operational formulations of Quantum Theory. To do
this we introduce an operational space (or op-space) built out of scalar
fields. A point in op-space corresponds to some nominated set of scalar fields
taking some given values in coincidence. We assert that op-space is the space
in which we observe the world. We introduce also a notion of agency (this
corresponds to the ability to set knob settings just like in Operational
Quantum Theory). The effects of agents' actions should only be felt to the
future so we introduce also a time direction field. Agency and time direction
can be understood as effective notions. We show how to formulate General
Relativity as a possibilistic theory and as a probabilistic theory. In the
possibilistic case we provide a compositional framework for calculating whether
some operationally described situation is possible or not. In the probabilistic
version we introduce probabilities and provide a compositional framework for
calculating the probability of some operationally described situation. Finally
we look at the quantum case. We review the operator tensor formulation of
Quantum Theory and use it to set up an approach to Quantum Field Theory that is
both operational and compositional. Then we consider strategies for solving the
problem of Quantum Gravity. By referring only to operational quantities we are
able to provide formulations for the possibilistic, probabilistic, and (the
nascent) quantum cases that are manifestly invariant under diffeomorphisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06970</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Akhoury</keyname><forenames>Ratindranath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garfinkle</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Nishant</forenames></author></authors><title>White holes in Einstein-aether theory</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>25 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform numerical simulations of gravitational collapse in Einstein-aether
theory. We find that under certain conditions, the collapse results in the
temporary formation of a white hole horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07007</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Ji-Hyung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muralidhar</keyname><forenames>Ramachandran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waser</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazant</keyname><forenames>Martin Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resistive Switching in Aqueous Nanopores by Shock Electrodeposition</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solid-state programmable metallization cells have attracted considerable
attention as memristive elements for Redox-based Resistive Random Access Memory
(ReRAM) for low-power and low-voltage applications. In principle, liquid-state
metallization cells could offer the same advantages for aqueous systems, such
as biomedical lab-on-a-chip devices, but robust resistive switching has not yet
been achieved in liquid electrolytes, where electrodeposition is notoriously
unstable to the formation of fractal dendrites. Here, the recently discovered
physics of shock electrodeposition are harnessed to stabilize aqueous copper
growth in polycarbonate nanopores, whose surfaces are modified with charged
polymers. Stable bipolar resistive switching is demonstrated for 500 cycles
with &lt;10s retention times, prior to any optimization of the geometry or
materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07033</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Munir</keyname><forenames>Asif</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Masood</forenames></author></authors><title>Convective heat transfer to Sisko fluid over a rotating disk</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article deals with study of the steady flow and heat transfer
characteristics of Sisko fluid over a rotating infinite disk. The flow and heat
transfer aspects are thoroughly investigated encompassing highly shear
thinning/thickening Sisko fluids. The modeled boundary layer equations are
reduced to a system of nonlinear ordinary differential equations using the
appropriate transformation. The resulting equations are then solved numerically
by shooting method in the domain . The numerical data for the velocity and
temperature fields are graphically sketched and effects of the relevant
parameters are discussed in detail. In addition, the velocity gradients at the
disk surface and the local Nusselt number for different values of the
pertaining parameters are given in tabulated form. Further, the flow and
temperature fields of power-law and Newtonian fluids are also compared with
those Sisko fluid. Moreover, a comparison with previously published work, as a
special case of the problem, has been provided and the results are found to be
in excellent agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07040</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Lhotka</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourdin</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narita</keyname><forenames>Yasuhito</forenames></author></authors><title>Charged dust grain dynamics subject to solar wind, Poynting-Robertson
  drag, and the interplanetary magnetic field</title><categories>astro-ph.EP math.DS</categories><comments>32 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 828, Number 1, p.10 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/828/1/10</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the combined effect of solar wind, Poynting-Robertson drag,
and the frozen-in interplanetary magnetic field on the motion of charged dust
grains in our solar system. For this reason we derive a secular theory of
motion by the means of averaging method and validate it with numerical
simulations of the un-averaged equations of motions. The theory predicts that
the secular motion of charged particles is mainly affected by the z-component
of the solar magnetic axis, or the normal component of the interplanetary
magnetic field. The normal component of the interplanetary magnetic field leads
to an increase or decrease of semi-major axis depending on its functional form
and sign of charge of the dust grain. It is generally accepted that the
combined effects of solar wind and photon absorption and re-emmision
(Poynting-Robertson drag) lead to a decrease in semi-major axis on secular time
scales. On the contrary, we demonstrate that the interplanetary magnetic field
may counteract these drag forces under certain circumstances. We derive a
simple relation between the parameters of the magnetic field, the physical
properties of the dust grain as well as the shape and orientation of the
orbital ellipse of the particle, which is a necessary conditions for the
stabilization in semi-major axis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07053</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07053</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nirmal</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sreejith</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathew</keyname><forenames>Joice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarpotdar</keyname><forenames>Mayuresh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suresh</keyname><forenames>Ambily</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>Ajin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Safonova</keyname><forenames>Margarita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murthy</keyname><forenames>Jayant</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise modeling and analysis of an IMU-based attitude sensor: improvement
  of performance by filtering and sensor fusion</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures, presented at SPIE Astronomical Telescopes +
  Instrumentation Symposium, 26 June-1 July 2016, Edinburgh, United Kingdom</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE. 9912, Advances in Optical and Mechanical Technologies
  for Telescopes and Instrumentation II, 99126W, July 22, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2234255</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe the characterization and removal of noise present in the Inertial
Measurement Unit (IMU) MPU-6050. This IMU was initially used in an attitude
sensor (AS) developed in-house, and subsequently implemented in a pointing and
stabilization platform developed for small balloon-borne astronomical payloads.
We found that the performance of the IMU degrades with time due to the
accumulation of different errors. Using the Allan variance analysis method, we
identified the different components of noise present in the IMU and verified
the results using a power spectral density analysis (PSD). We tried to remove
the high-frequency noise using smoothing filters, such as moving average filter
and Savitzky-Golay filter. Although we did manage to filter some of the
high-frequency noise, the performance of these filters was not satisfactory for
our application. We found the distribution of the random noise present in the
IMU using a probability density analysis, and identified the noise to be white
Gaussian in nature which we successfully removed by a Kalman filter in real
time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07069</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcantoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pasquarelli</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carbone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carabelli</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microelectrode arrays of diamond-insulated graphitic channels for real
  time detection of exocytotic events from cultured chromaffin cells and slices
  of adrenal glands</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.bio-ph</categories><journal-ref>Analytical Chemistry 88, 7493-7499 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.analchem.5b04449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A microstructured graphitic 4x4 multielectrode array was embedded in a single
crystal diamond substrate (4x4 {uG-SCD MEA) for real-time monitoring of
exocytotic events from cultured chromaffin cells and adrenal slices. The
current approach relies on the development of a parallel ion beam lithographic
technique, which assures the time effective fabrication of extended arrays with
reproducible electrode dimensions. The reported device is suitable for
performing amperometric and voltammetric recordings with high sensitivity and
temporal resolution, by simultaneously acquiring data from 16 rectangularly
shaped microelectrodes (20x3.5 um^2) separated by 200 um gaps. Taking advantage
of the array geometry we addressed the following specific issues: i) detect
both the spontaneous and KCl-evoked secretion simultaneously from several
chromaffin cells directly cultured on the device surface, ii) resolve the
waveform of different subsets of exocytotic events, iii) monitoring quantal
secretory events from thin slices of the adrenal gland. The frequency of
spontaneous release was low (0.12 Hz and 0.3 Hz respectively for adrenal slices
and cultured cells) and increased up to 0.9 Hz after stimulation with 30 mM KCl
in cultured cells. The spike amplitude as well as rise and decay time were
comparable with those measured by carbon fiber microelectrodes and allowed to
identify three different subsets of secretory events associated to &quot;full
fusion&quot; events, &quot;kiss and-run&quot; and &quot;kiss-and-stay&quot; exocytosis, confirming that
the device has adequate sensitivity and time resolution for real-time
recordings. The device offers the significant advantage of shortening the time
to collect data by allowing simultaneous recordings from cell populations
either in primary cell cultures or in intact tissues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07070</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Preda</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz-Hijar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tormo-Marquez</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>O. Pena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivares</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pugno</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sordini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez-Mir</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ocal</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Micro and nano-patterning of single-crystal diamond by swift heavy ion
  irradiation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 69, 1 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2016.06.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents experimental data and analysis of the structural damage
caused by swift-heavy ion irradiation of single-crystal diamond. The patterned
buried structural damage is shown to generate, via swelling, a mirror-pattern
on the sample surface, which remains largely damage-free. While extensive
results are available for light ion implantations, this effect is reported here
for the first time in the heavy ion regime, where a completely different range
of input parameters (in terms of ion species, energy, stopping power, etc.) is
available for customized irradiation. The chosen ion species are Au and Br, in
the energy range 10-40 MeV. The observed patterns, as characterized by
profilometry and atomic force microscopy, are reported in a series of model
experiments, which show swelling patterns ranging from a few nm to above 200
nm. Moreover, a systematic phenomenological modelling is presented, in which
surface swelling measurements are correlated to buried crystal damage. A
comparison is made with data for light ion implantations, showing good
compatibility with the proposed models. The modelling presented in this work
can be useful for the design and realization of micropatterned surfaces in
single crystal diamond, allowing to generate highly customized structures by
combining appropriately chosen irradiation parameters and masks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07074</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effects of surface roughness on lunar Askaryan pulses</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Presented at ARENA 2014: Acoustic and Radio EeV Neutrino Detection
  Activities, Annapolis, U.S.A 2014. Submitted to AIP Conference Proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effects of lunar surface roughness, on both small and large scales, on
Askaryan radio pulses generated by particle cascades beneath the lunar surface
has never been fully estimated. Surface roughness affects the chances of a
pulse escaping the lunar surface, its coherency, and the characteristic
detection geometry. It will affect the expected signal shape, the relative
utility of different frequency bands, the telescope pointing positions on the
lunar disk, and most fundamentally, the chances of detecting the known UHE
cosmic ray and any prospective UHE neutrino flux. Near-future radio-telescopes
such as FAST and the SKA promise to be able to detect the flux of cosmic rays,
and it is critical that surface roughness be treated appropriately in
simulations. of the lunar Askaryan technique. In this contribution, a facet
model for lunar surface roughness is combined with a method to propagate
coherent radio pulses through boundaries to estimate the full effects of lunar
surface roughness on neutrino-detection probabilities. The method is able to
produce pulses from parameterised particle cascades beneath the lunar surface
as would be viewed by an observer at Earth, including all polarisation and
coherency effects. Results from this calculation are presented for both
characteristic cosmic ray and neutrino cascades, and estimates of the effects
mentioned above - particularly signal shape, frequency-dependence, and
sensitivity - are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07075</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dan&#x10d;o</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hnatich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komarova</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krasnov</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu&#x10d;ivjansk&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mi&#x17e;i&#x161;in</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nalimov</keyname><forenames>M. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Hydrodynamic Fluctuations on the Phase Transition in Models
  E and F of Critical Dynamics</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>The authors thank the Organizers of the conference &quot;Models in Quantum
  Field Theory IV, MQFT-2012&quot; for the opportunity to present the results of the
  research summarised in the paper, 13 pages, 5 Tables</comments><journal-ref>Theor Math Phys 176(1), (2013) 888</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11232-013-0076-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the renormalization group method to study model E of critical dynamics
in the presence of velocity fluctuations arising in accordance with the
stochastic Navier-Stokes equation. Using Martin-Siggia-Rose theorem, we obtain
a field- theoretical model that allows a perturbative renormalization group
analysis. By direct power counting and an analysis of ultraviolet divergences,
we show that the model is multiplicatively renormalizable, and we use a
two-parameter expansion in $\varepsilon$ and $\delta$ to calculate
renormalization constants. Here, $\varepsilon$ is a deviation from the critical
dimension four, and $\delta$ is a deviation from the Kolmogorov regime. We
present the results of the one-loop approximation and part of the fixed-point
structure. We briefly discuss the possible effect of velocity fluctuations on
the large-scale behavior of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07078</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Antokhin</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>An efficient and flexible Abel-inversion method for noisy data</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2111</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an efficient and flexible method for solving Abel integral
equation of the first kind, frequently appearing in many fields of
astrophysics, physics, chemistry, and applied sciences. This equation
represents an ill-posed problem, thus solving it requires some kind of
regularization. Our method is based on solving the equation on a so-called
compact set of functions and/or using Tikhonov's regularization. A priori
constraints on the unknown function, defining a compact set, are very loose and
can be set using simple physical considerations. Tikhonov's regularization on
itself does not require any explicit a priori constraints on the unknown
function and can be used independently of such constraints or in combination
with them. Various target degrees of smoothness of the unknown function may be
set, as required by the problem at hand. The advantage of the method, apart
from its flexibility, is that it gives uniform convergence of the approximate
solution to the exact solution, as the errors of input data tend to zero. The
method is illustrated on several simulated models with known solutions. An
example of astrophysical application of the method is also given.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07087</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorusso</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ugues</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zelferino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baima</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pugno</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambrosio</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Softening the ultra-stiff: controlled variation of Young's modulus in
  single crystal diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>32 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Materialia 116, 95-103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2016.06.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A combined experimental and numerical study on the variation of the elastic
properties of defective single-crystal diamond is presented for the first time,
by comparing nano-indentation measurements on MeV-ion-implanted samples with
multi-scale modeling consisting of both ab initio atomistic calculations and
meso-scale Finite Element Method (FEM) simulations. It is found that by locally
introducing defects in the 2x10^18 - 5x10^21 cm-3 density range, a significant
reduction of, as well as of density, can be induced in the diamond crystal
structure without incurring in the graphitization of the material. Ab initio
atomistic simulations confirm the experimental findings with a good degree of
confidence. FEM simulations are further employed to verify the consistency of
measured deformations with a stiffness reduction, and to derive strain and
stress levels in the implanted region. Combining these experimental and
numerical results, we also provide insight into the mechanism responsible for
the depth dependence of the graphitization threshold in diamond. This work
prospects the possibility of achieving accurate tunability of the mechanical
properties of single-crystal diamond through defect engineering, with
significant technological applications, i.e. the fabrication and control of the
resonant frequency of diamond-based micromechanical resonators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07092</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07092</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bag</keyname><forenames>Saientan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mogurampelly</keyname><forenames>Santosh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goddard</keyname><forenames>William A</forenames><suffix>III</suffix></author><author><keyname>Maiti</keyname><forenames>Prabal K</forenames></author></authors><title>Dramatic changes in DNA Conductance with stretching: Structural
  Polymorphism at a critical extension</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><doi>10.1039/C6NR03418G</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to interpret recent experimental studies of the dependence of
conductance of ds-DNA as the DNA is pulled from the 3'end1-3'end2 ends, which
find a sharp conductance jump for a very short (4.5 %) stretching length, we
carried out multiscale modeling, to predict the conductance of dsDNA as it is
mechanically stretched to promote various structural polymorphisms. We
calculate the current along the stretched DNA using a combination of molecular
dynamics simulations, non-equilibrium pulling simulations, quantum mechanics
calculations, and kinetic Monte Carlo simulations. For 5'end1-5'end2
attachments we find an abrupt jump in the current within a very short
stretching length (6 $ \AA $ or 17 %) leading to a melted DNA state. In
contrast, for 3'end1-3'end2 pulling it takes almost 32$ \AA $ (84 %) of
stretching to cause a similar jump in the current. Thus, we demonstrate that
charge transport in DNA can occur over stretching lengths of several
nanometers. We find that this unexpected behaviour in the B to S conformational
DNA transition arises from highly inclined base pair geometries that result
from this pulling protocol. We find that the dramatically different conductance
behaviors for two different pulling protocols arise from the nature of how
hydrogen bonds of DNA base pairs break.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07093</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tengattini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enrico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boarino</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fecht</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterization of the recovery of mechanical properties of
  ion-implanted diamond after thermal annealing</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 63, 75-79 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2015.11.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to their outstanding mechanical properties, diamond and diamond-like
materials find significant technological applications ranging from
well-established industrial fields (cutting tools, coatings, etc.) to more
advanced mechanical devices as micro- and nano-electromechanical systems. The
use of energetic ions is a powerful and versatile tool to fabricate
three-dimensional micro-mechanical structures. In this context, it is of
paramount importance to have an accurate knowledge of the effects of
ion-induced structural damage on the mechanical properties of this material,
firstly to predict potential undesired side-effects of the ion implantation
process, and possibly to tailor the desired mechanical properties of the
fabricated devices. We present an Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM)
characterization of free-standing cantilevers in single-crystal diamond
obtained by a FIB-assisted lift-off technique, which allows a determination of
the Young's modulus of the diamond crystal after the MeV ion irradiation
process concurrent to the fabrication of the microstructures, and subsequent
thermal annealing. The AFM measurements were performed with the beam-bending
technique and show that the thermal annealing process allows for an effective
recovery of the mechanical properties of the pristine crystal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07098</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bag</keyname><forenames>Saientan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Manish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiti</keyname><forenames>Prabal K</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge Transport in Dendrimer Melt using Multiscale Modeling Simulation</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jpcb.6b04209</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a theoretical calculation of the charge carrier
mobility in two different dendrimeric melt system (Dendritic phenyl azomethine
with Triphenyl amine core and Dendritic Carbazole with Cyclic Phenylazomethine
as core), which have recently been reported1 to increase the efficiency of
Dye-Sensitized solar cells (DSSCs) by interface modification. Our mobility
calculation, which is a combination of molecular dynamics simulation, first
principles calculation and kinetic Monte Carlo simulation, leads to mobilities
that are in quantitative agreement with available experimental data. We also
show how the mobility depends on the dendrimer generation. Furthermore, we
examine the variation of mobility with external electric field and external
reorganization energy. Physical mechanisms behind observed electric field and
generation dependencies of mobility are also explored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07113</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubanov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomba</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enrico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrat-Mabilon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peaucelle</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thi</keyname><forenames>T. N. Tran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boarino</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gheeraert</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of high-power laser irradiation on sub-superficial graphitic
  layers in single crystal diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Materialia 103, 665-671 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actamat.2015.10.046</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the structural modifications induced by a lambda = 532 nm
ns-pulsed high-power laser on sub-superficial graphitic layers in
single-crystal diamond realized by means of MeV ion implantation. A systematic
characterization of the structures obtained under different laser irradiation
conditions (power density, number of pulses) and subsequent thermal annealing
was performed by different electron microscopy techniques. The main feature
observed after laser irradiation is the thickening of the pre-existing
graphitic layer. Cross sectional SEM imaging was performed to directly measure
the thickness of the modified layers, and subsequent selective etching of the
buried layers was employed to both assess their graphitic nature and enhance
the SEM imaging contrast. In particular, it was found that for optimal
irradiation parameters the laser processing induces a six-fold increase the
thickness of sub superficial graphitic layers without inducing mechanical
failures in the surrounding crystal. TEM microscopy and EELS spectroscopy
allowed a detailed analysis of the internal structure of the laser irradiated
layers, highlighting the presence of different nano graphitic and amorphous
layers. The obtained results demonstrate the effectiveness and versatility of
high-power laser irradiation for an accurate tuning of the geometrical and
structural features of graphitic structures embedded in single crystal diamond,
and open new opportunities in diamond fabrication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07119</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rubanov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fairchild</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suvorova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prawer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural transformation of implanted diamond layers during high
  temperature annealing</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research B 365A, 50-54
  (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nimb.2015.07.020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the recent years graphitization of ion-beam induced amorphous layers
became the basic tool for device fabrication in diamond. The etchable graphitic
layers can be removed to form free-standing membranes into which the desired
structures can be sculpted using FIB milling. The optical properties of the
devices fabricated using this method are assumed on the model of sharp
diamond-air interface. The real quality of this interface could depend on
degree of graphitization of the amorphous damage layers after annealing. In the
present work the graphitization process was studied using conventional and
analytical TEM. It was found that annealing at 550 {\deg}C results in a partial
graphitization of the implanted volume with formation of the nano-crystalline
graphitic phase sandwiched between layers of tetrahedral amorphous carbon.
Annealing at 1400 {\deg}C resulted in complete graphitization of the amorphous
layers. The average size of graphite nano-crystals did not exceed 5 nm with
predominant orientation of c-planes normal to the sample surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07122</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sciortino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corsi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czelusniak</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gelli</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorelli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagomarsino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mando</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parrini</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoro</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sordini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sytchkova</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taccetti</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Micro-beam and pulsed laser beam techniques for the micro-fabrication of
  diamond surface and bulk structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research B 348, 191 198
  (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nimb.2014.11.061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Micro-fabrication in diamond is involved in a wide set of emerging
technologies, exploiting the exceptional characteristics of diamond for
application in bio-physics, photonics, radiation detection. Micro ion-beam
irradiation and pulsed laser irradiation are complementary techniques, which
permit the implementation of complex geometries, by modification and
functionalization of surface and/or bulk material, modifying the optical,
electrical and mechanical characteristics of the material. In this article we
summarize the work done in Florence (Italy) concerning ion beam and pulsed
laser beam micro-fabrication in diamond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07126</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bernardi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kelvin probe characterization of buried graphitic microchannels in
  single-crystal diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 117, 024103 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4905425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present an investigation by Kelvin Probe Microscopy (KPM) of
buried graphitic microchannels fabricated in single-crystal diamond by direct
MeV ion microbeam writing. Metal deposition of variable-thickness masks was
adopted to implant channels with emerging endpoints and high temperature
annealing was performed in order to induce the graphitization of the
highly-damaged buried region. When an electrical current was flowing through
the biased buried channel, the structure was clearly evidenced by KPM maps of
the electrical potential of the surface region overlying the channel at
increasing distances from the grounded electrode. The KPM profiling shows
regions of opposite contrast located at different distances from the endpoints
of the channel. This effect is attributed to the different electrical
conduction properties of the surface and of the buried graphitic layer. The
model adopted to interpret these KPM maps and profiles proved to be suitable
for the electronic characterization of buried conductive channels, providing a
non-invasive method to measure the local resistivity with a micrometer
resolution. The results demonstrate the potential of the technique as a
powerful diagnostic tool to monitor the functionality of all-carbon
graphite/diamond devices to be fabricated by MeV ion beam lithography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07132</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07132</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Monticone</keyname><forenames>D. Gatto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Traina</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enrico</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brida</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degiovanni</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boarino</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-photon emitters based on NIR colour centres in diamond coupled
  with solid immersion lenses</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Quantum Information 12 (7-8), 1560011
  (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219749915600114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-photon sources represent a key enabling technology in quantum optics,
and single colour centres in diamond are a promising platform to serve this
purpose, due to their high quantum efficiency and photostability at room
temperature. The widely studied nitrogen vacancy centres are characterized by
several limitations, thus other defects have recently been considered, with a
specific focus of centres emitting in the Near Infra-Red. In the present work,
we report on the coupling of native near-infrared-emitting centres in
high-quality single crystal diamond with Solid Immersion Lens structures
fabricated by Focused Ion Beam lithography. The reported improvements in terms
of light collection efficiency make the proposed system an ideal platform for
the development of single-photon emitters with appealing photophysical and
spectral properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07134</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Forneris</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Re</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pompili</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verona</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rinati</keyname><forenames>G. Verona</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benetti</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cannata</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Pietrantonio</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>A 3-dimensional interdigitated electrode geometry for the enhancement of
  charge collection efficiency in diamond detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters 108, 18001 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/108/18001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, a single crystal CVD diamond film with a novel
three-dimensional (3D) interdigitated electrode geometry has been fabricated
with the Reactive Ion Etching (RIE) technique in order to increase the charge
collection efficiency (CCE) with respect to that obtained by standard
superficial electrodes. The geometrical arrangement of the electric field lines
due to the 3D patterning of the electrodes results in a shorter travel path for
the excess charge carriers, thus contributing to a more efficient charge
collection mech-anism. The CCE of the device was mapped by means of the Ion
Beam Induced Charge (IBIC) technique. A 1 MeV proton micro-beam was raster
scanned over the active area of the diamond detector under different bias
voltage conditions, enabling to probe the charge transport properties of the
detector up to a depth of 8 {\mu}m below the sample surface. The experimental
results, supported by the numerical simulations, show a significant improvement
in the 3D-detector performance (i.e. CCE, energy resolution, extension of the
active area) if compared with the results obtained by standard surface metallic
electrodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07136</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Abramowicz</keyname><forenames>Marek A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Velocity, acceleration and gravity in Einstein's relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Einstein's relativity theory demands that all meaningful physical objects
should be defined covariantly, i.e. in a coordinate independent way. Concepts
of relative velocity, acceleration, gravity acceleration and gravity potential
are fundamental in Newton's theory and they are imprinted in everyone's
physical intuition. Unfortunately, relativistic definitions of them are not
commonly known or appreciated. Every now and then some confused authors use
wrong, non-covariant, definitions of velocity, acceleration and gravity, based
on their vague Newtonian intuitions and hidden in a superficial, often purely
semantic, relativistic disguise. A recent example of such a confusion (Gorkavyi
&amp; Vasilkov, 2016) is discussed at the end of this Note.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07156</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Orwa</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newnham</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santori</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barclay</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>K. M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beausoleil</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharonovich</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fairchild</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greentree</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prawer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>An upper limit on the lateral vacancy diffusion length in diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 24, 6-10 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2012.02.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ion implantation is widely used to modify the structural, electrical and
optical properties of materials. By appropriate masking, this technique can be
used to define nano- and micro-structures. However, depending on the type of
mask used, experiments have shown that vacancy-related substrate modification
can be inferred tens of microns away from the edge of the mask used to define
the implanted region. This could be due to fast diffusion of vacancies from the
implanted area during annealing or to a geometric effect related to ion
scattering around the mask edges. For quantum and single-atom devices, stray
ion damage can be deleterious and must be minimized. In order to profile the
distribution of implantation-induced damage, we have used the nitrogen-vacancy
colour centre as a sensitive marker for vacancy concentration and distribution
following MeV He ion implantation into diamond and annealing. Results show that
helium atoms implanted through a mask clamped to the diamond surface are
scattered underneath the mask to distances in the range of tens of micrometers
from the mask edge. Implantation through a lithographically defined and
deposited mask, with no spacing between the mask and the substrate,
significantly reduces the scattering to &lt;5 m but does not eliminate it. These
scattering distances are much larger than the theoretically estimated vacancy
diffusion distance of 260 nm under similar conditions. This paper shows that
diffusion, upon annealing, of vacancies created by ion implantation in diamond
is limited and the appearance of vacancies many tens of micrometers from the
edge of the mask is due to scattering effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07171</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Thi</keyname><forenames>T. N. Tran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gheeraert</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartwig</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lafford</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perrat-Mabilon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peaucelle</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bustarret</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-smooth single crystal diamond surfaces resulting from implantation
  and lift-off processes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica Status Solidi A 208 (9), 2057-2061 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/pssa.201100038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method for obtaining a smooth, single crystal diamond surface is presented,
whereby a sacrificial defective layer is created by implantation and
graphitized by annealing before being selectively etched. We have used O+ at
240 keV, the main process variables being the ion fluence (ranging from 3x10^15
cm^-2 to 3x10^17 cm^-2) and the final etching process (wet etch, H2 plasma and
annealing in air). The substrates were characterized by atomic force
microscopy, optical profilometry and white beam X-ray topography. The influence
of the various process parameters on the resulting lift-off efficiency and
final surface roughness is discussed. An O+ fluence of 2x10^17 cm^-2 was found
to result in sub-nanometre roughness over tens of um^2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07175</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07175</id><created>2016-08-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Knill</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author></authors><title>On Particles and Primes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>39 pages, 14 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1606.05971</comments><msc-class>11R52, 20G20, 11A99, 11Z99, 17A35</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Primes in the two complete associative normed division algebras C and H have
affinities with structures seen in the standard model of particle physics. On
the integers in the two algebras, there are two equivalence relations: a strong
one, related to a U(1) and SU(3) symmetry allowing to permute and switch signs
of the coordinates of the integers, as well as a weak relation with origins
from units U(1),SU(2) in the algebra. Weak equivalence classes within the
strong equivalence classes of odd primes in C case relate to leptons, the inert
ones being neutrino like, and the split ones resembling electron-positron
pairs. In the H case, for odd primes, the equivalence classes come in groups of
two or three, leading to a caricature of hadrons featuring either mesons built
by a quark pair or then baryons obtained by quark triplets. We can now list for
every rational prime p all these particles and attach fractional charges to its
constituents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07176</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Argiolas</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazzan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sordini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modification of the structure of diamond with MeV ion implantation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 20, 774-778 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2011.03.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present experimental results and numerical simulations to investigate the
modification of structural-mechanical properties of ion-implanted
single-crystal diamond. A phenomenological model is used to derive an
analytical expression for the variation of mass density and elastic properties
as a function of damage density in the crystal. These relations are applied
together with SRIM Monte Carlo simulations to set up Finite Element simulations
for the determination of internal strains and surface deformation of
MeV-ion-implanted diamond samples. The results are validated through comparison
with high resolution X-ray diffraction and white-light interferometric
profilometry experiments. The former are carried out on 180 keV B implanted
diamond samples, to determine the induced structural variation, in terms of
lattice spacing and disorder, whilst the latter are performed on 1.8 MeV He
implanted diamond samples to measure surface swelling. The effect of thermal
processing on the evolution of the structural-mechanical properties of damaged
diamond is also evaluated by performing the same profilometric measurements
after annealing at 1000 {\deg}C, and modeling the obtained trends with a
suitably modified analytical model. The results allow the development of a
coherent model describing the effects of MeV-ion-induced damage on the
structural-mechanical properties of single-crystal diamond. In particular, we
suggest a more reliable method to determine the so-called diamond
&quot;graphitization threshold&quot; for the considered implantation type.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07181</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruch</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Marcos P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time resolved spectroscopy and photometry of three little known bright
  cataclysmic variables: LS IV -08$^{\rm o}$ 3, HQ Monocerotis and ST
  Chamaeleontis</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><journal-ref>New Astronomy, Vol. 50, p. 109 - 119 (January 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.newast.2016.07.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As part of a project to better characterize comparatively bright but so far
little studied cataclysmic variables in the southern hemisphere, we have
obtained spectroscopic and photometric data of the nova-like variables LS IV
-08$^{\rm o}$ 3 and HQ Mon, and of the Z Cam type dwarf nova ST Cha. The
spectra of all systems are as expected for their respective types. We derive
improved orbital ephemeris of LS IV -08$^{\rm o}$ 3 and map its accretion disk
in the light of the H$\alpha$ emission using Doppler tomography. We find that
the emission has a two component origin, arising in the outer parts of the
accretion disk and possibly on the illuminated face of the secondary star. The
light curve of LS IV -08$^{\rm o}$ 3 exhibits a low level of flickering and
indications for a modulation on the orbital period. Spectroscopy of HQ Mon
suggests an orbital period of $\approx$5.15 hours which is incompatible with
previous (uncertain) estimates. The light curves show the typical low scale
flickering of UX UMa type nova-like systems, superposed upon variations on
longer time scales. During one night a modulation with a period of $\approx$41
min is observed, visible for at least 4 hours. However, it does not repeat
itself in other nights. A spectroscopic orbital period of $\approx$5.5 hours is
derived for ST Cha. A previously suspected period of 6.8 hours (or
alternatively 9.6 hours), based on historical photographic photometry is
incompatible with the spectroscopic period. Moreover, we show that our new as
well as previous photometry does not contain evidence for the quoted
photometric period.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07190</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Manfredotti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Re</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Luminescence centers in proton irradiated single crystal CVD diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 19, 854-860 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2010.02.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diamond displays a large variety of luminescence centers which define its
optical properties and can be either created or modified by irradiation. The
main purpose of the present work is to study the radiation hardness of several
of such centers in homoepitaxial single crystal CVD diamond by following the
evolution of photoluminescence and ionoluminescence upon 2 MeV proton
irradiation. Luminescence decays were observed with values of the fluence at
half of the starting luminescence (F1/2) of the order of 1014 cm-2. The 3H
center displayed a non monotonic behavior, with a growing behavior and a
subsequent decay with a rather high F1/2 value (in the order of few 1016 cm-2),
maintaining at the highest fluences an intensity significantly higher than the
blue A-band. A simple model based on a double-exponential trend was defined to
fit with satisfactory accuracy the evolution of the 3H center. Several PL
centers (namely: 3H, TR12, 491 nm, 494 nm) exhibited clear correlations and
anti-correlations in their fluence dependences, which were considered in the
attempt to acquire some insight into their possible alternative attributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07195</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Bhaskar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mimura</keyname><forenames>Yukihiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Is Electroweak Symmetry Breaking Still Natural in the MSSM?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>MI-TH-1626</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The absence of any signal of supersymmetry (SUSY) at the LHC has raised the
SUSY particle mass scale compared to $Z$ boson mass $M_Z$. We investigate the
naturalness of the electroweak symmetry breaking after considering radiative
symmetry breaking along with 125 GeV Higgs mass. We find that the important
quantity to measure the naturalness of the hierarchy between the SUSY scale and
$M_Z$ is the separation between the radiative symmetry breaking scale, i.e.,
where $m_{H_u}^2+\mu^2$ turns negative for large $\tan\beta$ case ($\mu$ is the
Higgsino mass and $m_{H_u}$ is the SUSY breaking up-type Higgs boson mass) and
the average stop mass. Using this measure, one can show that the electroweak
symmetry breaking can be natural even if $\mu$ is large contrary to the
prevailing claim that $\mu$ is needed to be small to maintain the naturalness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07196</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rafelski</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Charting the future frontier(s) of particle production</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>Dedicated to Andrzej Bialas in honour of his 80th birthday, 16 pages
  with some contextual pictures and remarks</comments><journal-ref>Acta Physica Polonica B, Vol 47 (7) p1977 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolB.47.1977</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This short note describes the long collaborative effort between Arizona and
Krak\'ow, showing some of the key strangeness signatures of quark-gluon plasma.
It further presents an annotated catalog of foundational questions defining the
research frontiers which I believe can be addressed in the foreseeable future
in the context of relativistic heavy ion collision experiments. The list
includes topics that are specific to the field, and ventures towards the
known-to-be-unknown that may have a better chance with ions as compared to
elementary interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07203</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Soderlind</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>First-principles phase stability, bonding, and electronic structure of
  actinide metals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><report-no>LLNL-JRNL-626976</report-no><journal-ref>JOURNAL OF ELECTRON SPECTROSCOPY AND RELATED PHENOMENA Volume: 194
  Pages: 2-7 Special Issue: SI DOI: 10.1016/j.elspec.2013.11.009</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.elspec.2013.11.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The actinide elemental metals are scare, often toxic and radio active,
causing challenges for both experiments and theory while offering fascinating
physics. For practical purposes they are the prevalent building blocks for
materials where nuclear properties are of interest. Here, however, we are
focusing on fundamental properties of the actinides related to their electronic
structure and characteristic bonding in the condensed state. The series of
actinides is naturally divided into two segments. First, the set of lighter
actinides thorium through plutonium, often referred to as the early actinides,
display variations of their atomic volume reminiscent of transition metals
suggesting a gradual occupation of bonding 5f states. Second, the heavier (or
late) actinides, Am and onwards, demonstrate a volume behavior comparable to
the rare-earth metals thus implying nonbonding 5f states. Arguably, one can
distinguish plutonium metal as special case lying between these two subsets
because it shares some features from both. Therefore, we discuss the early
actinides, plutonium metal, and the late actinides separately applying
first-principles density-functional-theory (DFT) calculations. The analysis
includes successes and failures of the theory to describe primarily phase
stability, bonding, and electronic structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07205</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Poluektov</keyname><forenames>Yu. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soroka</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of the Fermi gas in a quantum well</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For the ideal Fermi gas that fills a quantum well confined by two parallel
planes, there are calculated the thermodynamic characteristics in general form
for arbitrary temperatures, namely: the thermodynamic potential, energy,
entropy, equations of state, heat capacities and compressibilities. The
distance between planes is considered as an additional thermodynamic variable.
Owing to the anisotropy, the pressure of the Fermi gas along and transverse to
the planes is different, so that the system is characterized by two equations
of state and a set of different heat capacities. Limiting cases of low and high
temperatures are considered. The temperature dependencies of the entropy and
heat capacities at low temperatures remain linear, just as in the volume case,
and their dependencies on the chemical potential and density undergo jumps at
the beginning of the filling of new discrete levels. It is shown that the
behavior of thermodynamic quantities with the distance between plates can be
either oscillating or monotonic, depending on what quantity is assumed to be
fixed: the volume or surface density. For high temperatures the corrections to
thermodynamic quantities are obtained, which are proportional to the ratio of
the thermal de Broglie wavelength to the distance between planes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07215</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Barun</forenames></author></authors><title>A Demonstration of Spectral Level Reconstruction of Intrinsic $B$-mode
  Power</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the prospects and consequences of the spectral level
reconstruction of primordial $B$-mode power by solving the systems of linear
equations assuming that the lensing potential together with the lensed
polarization spectra are already in hand. We find that this reconstruction
technique may be very useful to have an estimate of the amplitude of primordial
gravity waves or more specifically the value of tensor to scalar ratio. We also
see that one can have cosmic variance limited reconstruction of the intrinsic
$B$-mode power up to few hundred multipoles ($\ell\sim500$) which is more than
sufficient to have an estimate of the tensor to scalar ratio. Since the small
scale cosmic microwave background (CMB henceforth) anisotropies are not sourced
by the primordial gravity waves generated during inflation. We also find that
the impact of instrumental noise may be bypassed within this reconstruction
algorithm. A simple demonstration for the nullification of the instrumental
noise anticipating COrE like futuristic space mission complemented with Planck
2013 cosmology has been presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07221</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kondrin</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolaev</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boldyrev</keyname><forenames>K. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shulga</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zibrov</keyname><forenames>I. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brazhkin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk graphanes synthesized from benzene and pyridine</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a high-pressure high-temperature synthesis of several
millimeter-sized samples of bulk graphanes with the composition C-H(D) from
benzene and graphene-derivative C-H-N$_{0.2}$ from pyridine. X-ray diffraction,
transmission electron microscopy, and infrared spectroscopy of new materials
reveal relatively large (several nanometers in size) crystalline grains of an
sp3-bonded graphane lattice (3-cycle-4-step, the orthorhombic structure with
Pbca space group and parameters a = 9.5-9.8, b = 8.9-9.1, c = 17.1-17.3 $\AA$).
The main hydrogen groups in samples are C-H groups connected by aliphatic
bonds. The synthesized graphanes at atmospheric pressure are stable up to 500
C. The macroscopic density of CH samples is 1.5-1.57 g cm$^{-3} $ and the
refractive index is 1.78-1.80. The absorption spectra of samples with a high
degree of crystallization exhibits a weak absorption maximum at 2.8 eV, which
is responsible for the yellow-orange color, large absorption maximum at 4 eV
and an absorption edge associated with the width of the optical gap at 5.2 eV.
The bulk modulus (30-37 GPa) and shear modulus (15-18 GPa) of the fabricated
samples, as well as their hardness (1-1.5 GPa), are about twice as high as the
respective values for polycrystalline graphite. The solution of metalorganic
complexes in benzene and pyridine makes it possible to obtain doped graphanes,
which can have extraordinary electron transport and magnetic properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07230</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07230</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Trani</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mapelli</keyname><forenames>Michela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spera</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bressan</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of tidally captured planets in the Galactic Center</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures, 1 table, accepted for publication in The
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent observations suggest ongoing planet formation in the innermost parsec
of the Galactic center (GC). The super-massive black hole (SMBH) might strip
planets or planetary embryos from their parent star, bringing them close enough
to be tidally disrupted. Photoevaporation by the ultraviolet field of young
stars, combined with ongoing tidal disruption, could enhance the near-infrared
luminosity of such starless planets, making their detection possible even with
current facilities. In this paper, we investigate the chance of planet tidal
captures by means of high-accuracy N-body simulations exploiting Mikkola's
algorithmic regularization. We consider both planets lying in the clockwise
(CW) disk and planets initially bound to the S-stars. We show that tidally
captured planets remain on orbits close to those of their parent star.
Moreover, the semi-major axis of the planet orbit can be predicted by simple
analytic assumptions in the case of prograde orbits. We find that starless
planets that were initially bound to CW disk stars have mild eccentricities and
tend to remain in the CW disk. However, we speculate that angular momentum
diffusion and scattering with other young stars in the CW disk might bring
starless planets on low-angular momentum orbits. In contrast, planets initially
bound to S-stars are captured by the SMBH on highly eccentric orbits, matching
the orbital properties of the G1 and G2 clouds. Our predictions apply not only
to planets but also to low-mass stars initially bound to the S-stars and
tidally captured by the SMBH.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07245</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Chaudhary</keyname><forenames>Raghvendra P</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ummethala</keyname><forenames>Govind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaiswal</keyname><forenames>Arun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hawal</keyname><forenames>Suyog R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saxena</keyname><forenames>Sumit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shukla</keyname><forenames>Shobha</forenames></author></authors><title>One-step Patterning of Sub-wavelength Plasmonic Gratings in
  Metal-Polymer Composites</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  2D and 3D micro/nano fabrication based on two-photon polymerization (TPP) has
emerged as a strong contender for additive manufacturing for wide variety of
applications. In this manuscript we report one step patterning of structurally
stable, subwavelength 2D and 3D gold nanostructures using femto-second laser by
incorporating single photon photoinitiator only in pure and metal precursor
doped polymers. The metal polymer composite nanostructures are written directly
by in-situ reduction of gold precursor within the photoresist using
femto-second laser irradiation. The photo-initiator triggers the reduction of
gold precursor and induces simultaneous polymerization of the photoresist based
on two-photon absorption phenomenon. Diffraction gratings with varied loading
of gold precursors in photoresist have been fabricated and characterized by
measuring their diffraction efficiencies in the infrared region. Minimum line
width of 390 nm has been achieved for 5 wt% gold loaded polymers. Systematic
studies of the effect of laser power, metal precursor loading etc. on the
line-widths have also been performed. These investigations are expected to pave
way for exploration of new material combinations for development of simple
fabrication for fabrication of metal composite functional structures at
significantly low cost and with high-throughput.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07250</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Leitmann</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franosch</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Tube Concept for Entangled Stiff Fibers Predicts Their Dynamics in Space
  and Time</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, Physical Review Letters, includes Supplemental Material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 097801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.097801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study dynamically crowded solutions of stiff fibers deep in the semidilute
regime, where the motion of a single constituent becomes increasingly confined
to a narrow tube. The spatiotemporal dynamics for wave numbers resolving the
motion in the confining tube becomes accessible in Brownian dynamics
simulations upon employing a geometry-adapted neighbor list. We demonstrate
that in such crowded environments the intermediate scattering function,
characterizing the motion in space and time, can be predicted quantitatively by
simulating a single freely diffusing phantom needle only, yet with very unusual
diffusion coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07256</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jihn E.</forenames></author></authors><title>CP-Conservation in QCD and why only &quot;invisible&quot; Axions work</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages of LaTeX with 5 figures</comments><report-no>Talk presented at 12th PATRAS Workshop, Jeju, Korea, 20-24 June 2016</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Among solutions of the strong CP problem, the &quot;invisible&quot; axion in the narrow
axion window is argued to be the remaining possibility among natural solutions
on the smallness of $\bar{\theta}$. Related to the gravity spoil of global
symmetries, some prospective invisible axions from theory point of view are
discussed. In all these discussions, including the observational possibility,
cosmological constraints must be included.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07257</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Vassallo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esfeld</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Leibnizian relationalism for general relativistic physics</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, accepted for publication in Studies in History and
  Philosophy of Modern Physics</comments><doi>10.1016/j.shpsb.2016.08.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An ontology of Leibnizian relationalism, consisting in distance relations
among sparse matter points and their change only, is well recognized as a
serious option in the context of classical mechanics. In this paper, we
investigate how this ontology fares when it comes to general relativistic
physics. Using a Humean strategy, we regard the gravitational field as a means
to represent the overall change in the distance relations among point particles
in a way that achieves the best combination of being simple and being
informative.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07263</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldblatt</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author></authors><title>Tutorial models of the climate and habitability of Proxima Centauri b: a
  thin atmosphere is sufficient to distribute heat given low stellar flux</title><categories>astro-ph.EP physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to ApJ Lett</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Proxima Centauri b, an Earth-size planet in the habitable zone of our nearest
stellar neighbour, has just been discovered. A theoretical framework of
synchronously rotating planets, in which the risk of a runaway greenhouse on
the sunlight side and atmospheric collapse on the reverse side are mutually
ameliorated via heat transport is discussed. This is developed via simple
(tutorial) models of the climate. These show that lower incident stellar flux
means that less heat transport, so less atmospheric mass, is required. The
incident stellar flux at Proxima Centauri b is indeed low, which may help
enhance habitability if it has suffered some atmospheric loss or began with a
low volatile inventory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07272</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Nekrasov</keyname><forenames>Nikita</forenames></author></authors><title>BPS/CFT correspondence II: Instantons at crossroads, Moduli and
  Compactness Theorem</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.AG math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>63 pages, 16 figures, paper 2 out of 5</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gieseker-Nakajima moduli spaces $M_{k}(n)$ parametrize the charge $k$
noncommutative $U(n)$ instantons on ${\bf R}^{4}$ and framed rank $n$ torsion
free sheaves $\mathcal{E}$ on ${\bf C\bf P}^{2}$ with ${\rm
ch}_{2}({\mathcal{E}}) = k$. They also serve as local models of the moduli
spaces of instantons on general four-manifolds. We study the generalization of
gauge theory in which the four dimensional spacetime is a stratified space $X$
immersed into a Calabi-Yau fourfold $Z$. The local model ${\bf M}_{k}({\vec
n})$ of the corresponding instanton moduli space is the moduli space of charge
$k$ (noncommutative) instantons on origami spacetimes. There, $X$ is modelled
on a union of (up to six) coordinate complex planes ${\bf C}^{2}$ intersecting
in $Z$ modelled on ${\bf C}^{4}$. The instantons are shared by the collection
of four dimensional gauge theories sewn along two dimensional defect surfaces
and defect points. We also define several quiver versions ${\bf M}_{\bf
k}^{\gamma}({\vec{\bf n}})$ of ${\bf M}_{k}({\vec n})$, motivated by the
considerations of sewn gauge theories on orbifolds ${\bf C}^{4}/{\Gamma}$.
  The geometry of the spaces ${\bf M}_{\bf k}^{\gamma}({\vec{\bf n}})$, more
specifically the compactness of the set of torus-fixed points, for various
tori, underlies the non-perturbative Dyson-Schwinger identities recently found
to be satisfied by the correlation functions of $qq$-characters viewed as local
gauge invariant operators in the ${\mathcal{N}}=2$ quiver gauge theories.
  The cohomological and K-theoretic operations defined using ${\bf M}_{k}({\vec
n})$ and their quiver versions as correspondences provide the geometric
counterpart of the $qq$-characters, line and surface defects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07277</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ryu</keyname><forenames>Hyejin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abeykoon</keyname><forenames>Milinda</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bozin</keyname><forenames>Emil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsumoto</keyname><forenames>Yosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakatsuji</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrovic</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiband electronic transport in $\alpha$-Yb$_{1-x}$Sr$_{x}$AlB$_{4}$
  [x = 0, 0.19(3)] single crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Condens. Matter. 28, 425602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/42/425602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the evidence for the multiband electronic transport in
$\alpha$-YbAlB$_{4}$ and $\alpha$-Yb$_{0.81(2)}$Sr$_{0.19(3)}$AlB$_{4}$.
Multiband transport reveals itself below 10 K in both compounds via Hall effect
measurements, whereas anisotropic magnetic ground state sets in below 3 K in
$\alpha$-Yb$_{0.81(2)}$Sr$_{0.19(3)}$AlB$_{4}$. Our results show that Sr$^{2+}$
substitution enhances conductivity, but does not change the quasiparticle mass
of bands induced by heavy fermion hybridization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0410439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0410439</id><created>2004-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Audley</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames><affiliation>UK Astronomy Technology Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Holland</keyname><forenames>Wayne</forenames><affiliation>UK Astronomy Technology Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hodson</keyname><forenames>Trevor</forenames><affiliation>UK Astronomy Technology Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>MacIntosh</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames><affiliation>UK Astronomy Technology Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Robson</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames><affiliation>UK Astronomy Technology Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Kent</forenames><affiliation>NIST Boulder</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hilton</keyname><forenames>Gene</forenames><affiliation>NIST Boulder</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Duncan</keyname><forenames>William</forenames><affiliation>NIST Boulder</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Reintsema</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames><affiliation>NIST Boulder</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames><affiliation>Scottish Microelectronics Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Parkes</keyname><forenames>William</forenames><affiliation>Scottish Microelectronics Centre</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ade</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames><affiliation>Cardiff University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames><affiliation>Cardiff University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fich</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kycia</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Naylor</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>George</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bastien</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames><affiliation>Canadian SCUBA-2 Consortium</affiliation></author></authors><title>An update on the SCUBA-2 project</title><categories>astro-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 14 figures, Invited talk at SPIE Glasgow 21-25 June 2004,
  Conference 5498</comments><doi>10.1117/12.551259</doi><abstract>  SCUBA-2, which replaces SCUBA (the Submillimeter Common User Bolometer Array)
on the James Clerk Maxwell Telescope (JCMT) in 2006, is a large-format
bolometer array for submillimeter astronomy. Unlike previous detectors which
have used discrete bolometers, SCUBA-2 has two dc-coupled, monolithic, filled
arrays with a total of ~10,000 bolometers. It will offer simultaneous imaging
of a 50 sq-arcmin field of view at wavelengths of 850 and 450 microns. SCUBA-2
is expected to have a huge impact on the study of galaxy formation and
evolution in the early Universe as well as star and planet formation in our own
Galaxy. Mapping the sky to the same S/N up to 1000 times faster than SCUBA, it
will also act as a pathfinder for the new submillimeter interferometers such as
ALMA. SCUBA-2's absorber-coupled pixels use superconducting transition edge
sensors operating at 120 mK for performance limited by the sky background
photon noise. The monolithic silicon detector arrays are deep-etched by the
Bosch process to isolate the pixels on silicon nitride membranes. Electrical
connections are made through indium bump bonds to a SQUID time-domain
multiplexer (MUX). We give an overview of the SCUBA-2 system and an update on
its status, and describe some of the technological innovations that make this
unique instrument possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:astro-ph/0607067</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-26</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>astro-ph/0607067</id><created>2006-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Audley</keyname><forenames>Michael D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crane</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dace</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glowacka</keyname><forenames>Dorota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldie</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasenby</keyname><forenames>Anthony N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevenson</keyname><forenames>Howard M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsaneva</keyname><forenames>Vassilka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Withington</keyname><forenames>Stafford</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimes</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>Bradley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yassin</keyname><forenames>Ghassan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piccirillo</keyname><forenames>Lucio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisano</keyname><forenames>Giampaolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duncan</keyname><forenames>William D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilton</keyname><forenames>Gene C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irwin</keyname><forenames>Kent D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reintsema</keyname><forenames>Carl D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>TES imaging array technology for CLOVER</title><categories>astro-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures, SPIE Orlando 24-31 May 2006, Conference 6275</comments><doi>10.1117/12.670792</doi><abstract>  CLOVER is an experiment which aims to detect the signature of gravitational
waves from inflation by measuring the B-mode polarization of the cosmic
microwave background. CLOVER consists of three telescopes operating at 97, 150,
and 220 GHz. The 97-GHz telescope has 160 horns in its focal plane while the
150 and 220-GHz telescopes have 256 horns each. The horns are arranged in a
hexagonal array and feed a polarimeter which uses finline-coupled TES
bolometers as detectors. To detect the two polarizations the 97-GHz telescope
has 320 detectors while the 150 and 220-GHz telescopes have 512 detectors each.
To achieve the required NEPs the detectors are cooled to 100 mK for the 97 and
150-GHz polarimeters and 230 mK for the 220-GHz polarimeter. Each detector is
fabricated as a single chip to guarantee fully functioning focal planes. The
detectors are contained in linear modules made of copper which form split-block
waveguides. The detector modules contain 16 or 20 detectors each for
compatibility with the hexagonal arrays of horns in the telescopes' focal
planes. Each detector module contains a time-division SQUID multiplexer to read
out the detectors. Further amplification of the multiplexed signals is provided
by SQUID series arrays. The first prototype detectors for CLOVER operate with a
bath temperature of 230 mK and are used to validate the detector design as well
as the polarimeter technology. We describe the design of the CLOVER detectors,
detector blocks, and readout, and give an update on the detector development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
