<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:54:57Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-19" from="2016-08-19" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0907.3779</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0907.3779</id><created>2009-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Qifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Jinming</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced spin-orbit coupling in hydrogenated and fluorinated graphenes
  studied from first principles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures, and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Carbon 48, 1405 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.carbon.2009.12.031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin-orbit couplings (SOCs) of hydrogenated and fluorinated graphenes are
calculated from the first principles method. It is found that the SOC-induced
band splittings near their Fermi energies can be significantly enhanced to the
order of 10$^{-2}$ eV from the original about 10$^{-6}$ eV of the pure raphene,
which is comparable to those found in the diamond and even the archetypal
semiconductors. And two different mechanisms are proposed to explain the SOC
enhancements in these two systems. The huge SOC enhancements are found to come
not only from the sp$^3$ hybridization of carbon atoms, but also from the
larger intrinsic SOC of the fluorine atom than the carbon one. We hope many
interesting phenomena caused by the SOCs (e.g. the spin Hall effect) can be
observed experimentally in these systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.1704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.1704</id><created>2014-01-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Liebchen</keyname><forenames>Benno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelcher</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatiotemporal Oscillation Patterns in the Collective Relaxation
  Dynamics of Interacting Particles in Periodic Potentials</title><categories>nlin.AO cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 112 134102 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.112.134102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the emergence of self-organized structures in the course of
the relaxation of an initially excited, dissipative and finite chain of
interacting particles in a periodic potential towards its many particle
equilibrium configuration. Specifically we observe a transition from an in
phase correlated motion via phase randomized oscillations towards oscillations
with a phase difference $\pi$ between adjacent particles thereby yielding the
growth of long time transient spatiotemporal oscillation patterns. Parameter
modifications allow for designing these patterns, including steady states and
even states that combine in phase and correlated out of phase oscillations
along the chain. The complex relaxation dynamics is based on finite size
effects together with an evolution running from the nonlinear to the linear
regime thereby providing a highly unbalanced population of the center of mass
and relative motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.0571</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.0571</id><created>2014-07-02</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Healey</keyname><forenames>Timothy J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Shape of a M\&quot;obius Strip via Elastic Rod Theory Revisited</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Authors withdraw paper due to indications that Cosserat rod model
  developed is over constrained. New paper with improved model and additional
  results published at arXiv:1407.0571</comments><msc-class>74K10, 34B60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1993 Mahadevan and Keller used the Kirchhoff rod theory to predict the
shape of a M\&quot;obius band. Starting from the solution for a square cross-section
(isotropic), they employ numerical continuation in the cross-sectional aspect
ratio in order to approach the solution for a thin strip. Certain smoothly
varying configurations are obtained. More recently in 2007, Starostin and van
der Heijden pointed out that an actual M\&quot;obius band &quot;localizes&quot; into a nearly
flat triangular configuration as the ratio of the strip width to center-line
circumference is no longer small. Accordingly they return to the developable,
thin-plate model of Sadowsky and Wunderlich, obtaining such localized shapes.
In this work we strike a middle ground between these two approaches. We employ
the standard two-director (special) Cosserat model, and we also use the
cross-sectional aspect ratio as a numerical continuation parameter.
Nonetheless, we are able to capture both the smoothly varying shapes and the
localized, nearly triangular configurations. Our point of departure is that we
do not always employ the strength-of-materials formula for the torsional
stiffness - a standard feature of the Kirchhoff theory. Our key observation
comes from the usual Cosserat ansatz in light of developability, suggesting an
increasing torsional stiffness ratio (as well as one increasing bending
stiffness ratio) as the thickness becomes small. We demonstrate that the
closed-loop configurations we obtain are stable with respect to small
perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.0723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.0723</id><created>2014-11-03</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bigi</keyname><forenames>I. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>CP Asymmetries (\&amp; T Violation) in Known Matter -- and beyond</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>31 pages, 6 figures; more information, added Sect.3.1.1 with comments
  about LHCb data with evidence for {\bf T}-odd moment,
  UND-HEP-14-BIG07(/UND-HEP-16-BIG01)</comments><journal-ref>Open Physics Journal, 2016, 55-76</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Finding \cp~violation (\CPV ) in 1964 produced a real revolution in the
fundamental dynamics, although the community did not understand it right away.
The paper by Kobayashi \&amp; Maskawa \cite{KM} appeared in 1973 to describe
\CPV~in classes of three (or more) families of quarks, non-minimal Higgs'
dynamics and/or charged right-handed currents. The Standard Model is defined
now with three families of quarks. It can describe the measured \cp~ \&amp;
\ot~violation in kaon and $B$ mesons at least as the leading source. None has
been found in baryons, charm mesons, top quarks and EDMs -- except from `hot'
news from LHCb data about {\bf T}-odd moment in $\Lambda_b^0 \to p
\pi^-\pi^+\pi^-$ \cite{LHCbtalk}. We have failed the explain our matter vs.
anti-matter huge asymmetry. Even when there is no obvious connections with that
asymmetry, it makes sense to probe \CPV~for the signs of New Dynamics \&amp; their
features. Furthermore we have to measure regional \CPV~in many-body final
states with accuracy. I discuss EDMs, axion's impact on cosmology \&amp; its
connection with Dark Matter; finally I talk about \CPV~in leptonic dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.1529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.1529</id><created>2014-12-03</created><updated>2016-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mathews</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rose</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garnavich</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamazaki</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kajino</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detectability of Cosmic Dark Flow in the Type Ia Supernova
  Redshift-Distance Relation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures, resubmitted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>2016 ApJ 827 60</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/827/1/60</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We re-analyze the detectability of large scale dark flow (or local bulk flow)
with respect to the CMB background based upon the redshift-distance relation
for Type Ia supernovae (SN Ia). We made two independent analyses: one based
upon identifying the three Cartesian velocity components; and the other based
upon the cosine dependence of the deviation from Hubble flow on the sky. We
apply these analyses to the Union2.1 SN Ia data and to the SDSS-II supernova
survey. For both methods, results for low redshift, $z &lt; 0.05$, are consistent
with previous searches. We find a local bulk flow of $v_{\rm bf} \sim 300$ km
s$^{-1}$ in the direction of $(l,b) \sim (270, 35)^{\circ}$. However, the
search for a dark flow at $z&gt;0.05$ is inconclusive. Based upon simulated data
sets, we deduce that the difficulty in detecting a dark flow at high redshifts
arises mostly from the observational error in the distance modulus. Thus, even
if it exists, a dark flow is not detectable at large redshift with current SN
Ia data sets. We estimate that a detection would require both significant sky
coverage of SN Ia out to $z = 0.3$ and a reduction in the effective distance
modulus error from 0.2 mag to $\lesssim 0.02$ mag. We estimate that a greatly
expanded data sample of $\sim 10^4$ SN Ia might detect a dark flow as small as
300 km s$^{-1}$ out to $z = 0.3$ even with a distance modulus error of $0.2$
mag. This may be achievable in a next generation large survey like LSST.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4889</id><created>2014-12-16</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Restuccia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veiro</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Yang-Mills connections valued on the octonionic algebra</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Proceedings for the XIX Simposio Chileno de Fisica, SOCHIFI 2014
  Conference, 26-28 November 2014, held at Concepcion U., Chile</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 720 (2016) 012018</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/720/1/012018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a formulation of Yang-Mills theory where the gauge field is
valued on an octonionic algebra and the gauge transformation is the group of
automorphisms of it. We show, under mild assumptions, that the only possible
gauge formulations are the usual $\mathfrak{su}(2)$ or $\mathfrak{u}(1)$
Yang-Mills theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00596</id><created>2015-01-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Liebchen</keyname><forenames>Benno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmelcher</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction Induced Directed Transport in AC-Driven Periodic Potentials</title><categories>nlin.PS cond-mat.other cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17 083011 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/8/083011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that repulsive power law interactions can induce directed
transport of particles in dissipative, ac-driven periodic potentials, in
regimes where the underlying noninteracting system exhibits localized
oscillations. Contrasting the well-established single particle ratchet
mechanism, this interaction induced transport is based on the collective
behaviour of the interacting particles yielding a spatiotemporal nonequilibrium
pattern comprising persistent travelling excitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.04468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.04468</id><created>2015-02-16</created><updated>2016-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maltsev</keyname><forenames>A. Ya.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the canonical forms of the multi-dimensional averaged Poisson
  brackets</title><categories>math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>33 pages, Latex</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics 57 : 5 (2016), 053501</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4947529</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider here special Poisson brackets given by the &quot;averaging&quot; of local
multi-dimensional Poisson brackets in the Whitham method. For the brackets of
this kind it is natural to ask about their canonical forms, which can be
obtained after transformations preserving the &quot;physical meaning&quot; of the field
variables. We show here that the averaged bracket can always be written in the
canonical form after a transformation of &quot;Hydrodynamic Type&quot; in the case of
absence of annihilators of initial bracket. However, in general case the
situation is more complicated. As we show here, in more general case the
averaged bracket can be transformed to a &quot;pseudo-canonical&quot; form under some
special (&quot;physical&quot;) requirements on the initial bracket.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02715</id><created>2015-04-10</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Musto</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vicary</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Latin squares and unitary error bases</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce quantum Latin squares, combinatorial quantum
objects which generalize classical Latin squares, and investigate their
applications in quantum computer science. Our main results are on applications
to unitary error bases (UEBs), basic structures in quantum information which
lie at the heart of procedures such as teleportation, dense coding and error
correction. We present a new method for constructing a UEB from a quantum Latin
square equipped with extra data. Developing construction techniques for UEBs
has been a major activity in quantum computation, with three primary methods
proposed: shift-and-multiply, Hadamard, and algebraic. We show that our new
approach simultaneously generalizes the shift-and-multiply and Hadamard
methods. Furthermore, we explicitly construct a UEB using our technique which
we prove cannot be obtained from any of these existing methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00616</id><created>2015-05-04</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Telles</keyname><forenames>G. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tavares</keyname><forenames>P. E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritsch</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cidrim</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bagnato</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barenghi</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Twisted unwinding of multi-charged quantum vortex and generation of
  turbulence in atomic Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, supp. material attached</comments><report-no>LD15702</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the observation of the twisted decay of quadruply charged vortices
in an atomic Bose-Einstein condensate. Supporting numerical simulations show
that the singly-charged vortices, which result from the decay of a
multi-charged vortex, twist around intertwined in the shape of helical Kelvin
waves. Finally, we propose to apply this effect to generate an almost isotropic
state of turbulence which we characterize in terms of the velocity statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05656</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05656</id><created>2015-05-21</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gahramanov</keyname><forenames>Ilmar</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathematical structures behind supersymmetric dualities</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, v2: minor corrections, comments and refs. added</comments><report-no>HU-EP-15-14</report-no><msc-class>81T60, 33D60, 33E20, 33D90, 39A13</msc-class><journal-ref>Archivum Math. 51 (2015) 5, 273-286</journal-ref><doi>10.5817/AM2015-5-273</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of these notes is to give a short survey of an interesting
connection between partition functions of supersymmetric gauge theories and
hypergeometric functions and to present the recent progress in this direction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05031</id><created>2015-06-16</created><updated>2016-08-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Nieva</keyname><forenames>Joaquin F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dresselhaus</keyname><forenames>Mildred S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levitov</keyname><forenames>Leonid S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant Tunneling and Intrinsic Bistability in Twisted Graphene
  Structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 085412 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We predict that vertical transport in heterostructures formed by twisted
graphene layers can exhibit a unique bistability mechanism. Intrinsically
bistable $I$-$V$ characteristics arise from resonant tunneling and interlayer
charge coupling, enabling multiple stable states in the sequential tunneling
regime. We consider a simple trilayer architecture, with the outer layers
acting as the source and drain and the middle layer floating. Under bias, the
middle layer can be either resonant or non-resonant with the source and drain
layers. The bistability is controlled by geometric device parameters easily
tunable in experiments. The nanoscale architecture can enable uniquely fast
switching times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00740</id><created>2015-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Libal</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichhardt</keyname><forenames>C. J. Olson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reichhardt</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Doped Colloidal Artificial Ice</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 postscript figures</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics 17 (10), 103010 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/10/103010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine square and kagome artificial spin ice for colloids confined in
arrays of double-well traps. Unlike magnetic artificial spin ices, colloidal
and vortex artificial spin ice realizations allow creation of doping sites
through double occupation of individual traps. We find that doping square and
kagome ice geometries produces opposite effects. For square ice, doping creates
local excitations in the ground state configuration that produce a local
melting effect as the temperature is raised. In contrast, the kagome ice ground
state can absorb the doping charge without generating non-ground-state
excitations, while at elevated temperatures the hopping of individual colloids
is suppressed near the doping sites. These results indicate that in the square
ice, doping adds degeneracy to the ordered ground state and creates local weak
spots, while in the kagome ice, which has a highly degenerate ground state,
doping locally decreases the degeneracy and creates local hard regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03163</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03163</id><created>2015-07-11</created><updated>2016-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coquereaux</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuber</keyname><forenames>Jean-Bernard</forenames></author></authors><title>Maps, immersions and permutations</title><categories>math.CO hep-th math.GT</categories><comments>46 pages, 18 figures, 9 tables. Version 2: added precisions on the
  notion used for the equivalence of immersed curves, new references. Version
  3: Corrected typos, one array in Appendix B1 was duplicated by mistake, the
  position of tables and the order of the final sections have been modified,
  results unchanged. To be published in the Journal of Knot Theory and Its
  Ramifications</comments><msc-class>05C10, 05C30, 57M25, 83C47</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Knot Theory and Its Ramifications, Vol. 25 (2016)
  1650047 (58 pages), World Scientific Publishing Company</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218216516500474</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of counting and of listing topologically inequivalent
&quot;planar&quot; {4-valent} maps with a single component and a given number n of
vertices. This enables us to count and to tabulate immersions of a circle in a
sphere (spherical curves), extending results by Arnold and followers. Different
options where the circle and/or the sphere are/is oriented are considered in
turn, following Arnold's classification of the different types of symmetries.
We also consider the case of bicolourable and bicoloured maps or immersions,
where faces are bicoloured. Our method extends to immersions of a circle in a
higher genus Riemann surface. There the bicolourability is no longer automatic
and has to be assumed. We thus have two separate countings in non zero genus,
that of bicolourable maps and that of general maps. We use a classical method
of encoding maps in terms of permutations, on which the constraints of
&quot;one-componentness&quot; and of a given genus may be applied. Depending on the
orientation issue and on the bicolourability assumption, permutations for a map
with n vertices live in S(4n) or in S(2n). In a nutshell, our method reduces to
the counting (or listing) of orbits of certain subset of S(4n) (resp. S(2n))
under the action of the centralizer of a certain element of S(4n) (resp.
S(2n)). This is achieved either by appealing to a formula by Frobenius or by a
direct enumeration of these orbits. Applications to knot theory are briefly
mentioned.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04755</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mirbabayi</keyname><forenames>Mehrdad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective Theory of Squeezed Correlation Functions</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19+6 pages</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/03/056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Various inflationary scenarios can often be distinguished from one another by
looking at the squeezed limit behavior of correlation functions. Therefore, it
is useful to have a framework designed to study this limit in a more systematic
and efficient way. We propose using an expansion in terms of weakly coupled
super-horizon degrees of freedom, which is argued to generically exist in a
near de Sitter space-time. The modes have a simple factorized form which leads
to factorization of the squeezed-limit correlation functions with power-law
behavior in $k_{\rm long}/k_{\rm short}$. This approach reproduces the known
results in single-, quasi-single-, and multi-field inflationary models.
However, it is applicable even if, unlike the above examples, the additional
degrees of freedom are not weakly coupled at sub-horizon scales. Stronger
results are derived in two-field (or sufficiently symmetric multi-field)
inflationary models. We discuss the observability of the non-Gaussian 3-point
function in the large-scale structure surveys, and argue that the squeezed
limit behavior has a higher detectability chance than equilateral behavior when
it scales as $(k_{\rm long}/k_{\rm short})^\Delta$ with $\Delta&lt;1$ -- where
local non-Gaussianity corresponds to $\Delta=0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04673</id><created>2015-08-19</created><updated>2015-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liebchen</keyname><forenames>Benno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marenduzzo</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagonabarraga</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cates</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering and pattern formation in chemorepulsive active colloids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft nlin.PS</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 258301 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.258301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that migration away from self-produced chemicals
(chemorepulsion) generates a generic route to clustering and pattern formation
among self-propelled colloids. The clustering instability can be caused either
by anisotropic chemical production, or by a delayed orientational response to
changes of the chemical environment. In each case, chemorepulsion creates
clusters of a self-limiting area which grows linearly with self-propulsion
speed. This agrees with recent observations of dynamic clusters in Janus
colloids (albeit not yet known to be chemorepulsive). More generally, our
results could inform design principles for the self-assembly of chemorepulsive
synthetic swimmers and/or bacteria into nonequilibrium patterns.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00478</id><created>2015-10-01</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kezerashvili</keyname><forenames>Roman Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsiklauri</keyname><forenames>Shalva M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takibayev</keyname><forenames>Nurgali Zh.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lightest Kaonic Nuclear Clusters</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>Talk presented CIPANP2015. 8 pages, LaTeX</comments><report-no>CIPANP2015-Kezerashvili</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our study of kaonic three-body $\overset{\_}{K}NN$,
$\overset{\_}{K}\overset{\_}{K}N$ and $KK\overset{\_}{K}$ and four-body
$\overset{\_}{K}% NNN $, $\ $and $\overset{\_}{K}\overset{\_}{K}NN$ clusters
within the framework of a potential model using the method of hyperspherical
functions in momentum representation. To perform a numerical calculations for
the bound state energy of the light kaonic system, we use a set of different
potentials for the nucleon-nucleon and $\overset{\_}{K}N$ interactions, as well
as for the kaon-kaon interaction. The calculations show that a quasibound state
energy is not sensitive to the $NN$ interaction, and it shows very strong
dependence on the $\overset{\_}{K}N$ potential. We also compare our results
with those obtained using different theoretical approaches. The theoretical
discrepancies in the binding energy and width for the lightest kaonic system
related to the different $NN$ and $\overset{\_% }{K}N$ interactions are
addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07733</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07733</id><created>2015-10-26</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Deqin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porsezian</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jingsong</forenames></author></authors><title>On the evolution of a rogue wave along the orthogonal direction of the
  ($t,x$)-plane</title><categories>nlin.PS math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>17 pages, 13 figures. We have newly added the disucssion on the phase
  difference between the KE and the NLS. This version has been accepted by
  CNSNS(Aug.2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The localization characters of the first-order rogue wave (RW) solution $u$
of the Kundu-Eckhaus equation is studied in this paper.
  We discover a full process of the evolution for the contour line with height
$c^2+d$ along the orthogonal direction of the ($t,x$)-plane for a first-order
RW $|u|^2$: A point at height $9c^2$ generates a convex curve for $3c^2\leq
d&lt;8c^2$, whereas it becomes a concave curve for $0&lt;d&lt;3c^2$, next it reduces to
a hyperbola on asymptotic plane (i.e. equivalently $d=0$), and the two branches
of the hyperbola become two separate convex curves when $-c^2&lt;d&lt;0$, and finally
they reduce to two separate points at $d=-c^2$. Using the contour line method,
the length, width, and area of the RW at height $c^2+d (0&lt;d&lt;8c^2)$ , i.e. above
the asymptotic plane, are defined. We study the evolutions of three
above-mentioned localization characters on $d$ through analytical and visual
methods. The phase difference between the Kundu-Eckhaus and the nonlinear
Schrodinger equation is also given by an explicit formula.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08214</id><created>2015-10-28</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jerger</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macha</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamann</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s Rosario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reshitnyk</keyname><forenames>Yarema</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juliusson</keyname><forenames>Kristinn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>Arkady</forenames></author></authors><title>Realization of a binary-outcome projection measurement of a three-level
  superconducting quantum system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 6, 014014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.6.014014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Binary-outcome measurements allow to determine whether a multi-level quantum
system is in a certain state while preserving quantum coherence between all
orthogonal states. In this paper, we explore different regimes of the
dispersive readout of a three-level superconducting quantum system coupled to a
microwave cavity in order to implement binary-outcome measurements. By
designing identical cavity frequency shifts for the first and second excited
states of the system, we realize strong projective binary-outcome measurements
onto its ground state with a fidelity of $94.3\%$. Complemented with standard
microwave control and low-noise parametric amplification, this scheme enables
the quantum non-demolition detection of leakage errors and can be used to
create sets of compatible measurements to reveal the contextual nature of
superconducting circuits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00078</id><created>2015-10-31</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Soma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>Somenath</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical Trajectories in Rindler Space and Restricted Structure of
  Phase Space</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages REVTEX file with seven .eps figure, some parts are re-written</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nature of single particle classical phase space trajectories in Rindler
space have been studied. It has been shown that only a small portion of the
phase space is accessible to the particles, whereas the major part of the phase
space region is completely forbidden. It has also been noticed that the area /
volume of the forbidden region of phase space increases with the increase in
the strength of gravitational field. The physical significance of such
squeezing of phase space in strong gravitational field has been discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05165</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tanner</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cecil</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heitsch</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author></authors><title>Starburst Driven Galactic Superbubbles Radiating to 10 K</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 14 figures. Published in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 821, 7 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/821/1/7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Our three-dimensional hydro-dynamical simulations of starbursts examine the
formation of superbubbles over a range of driving luminosities and mass
loadings that determine superbubble growth and wind velocity. From this we
determine the relationship between the velocity of a galactic wind and the
power of the starburst. We find a threshold for the formation of a wind, above
which the speed of the wind is not affected by grid resolution or the
temperature floor of our radiative cooling. We investigate the effect two
different temperature floors in our radiative cooling prescription have on wind
kinematics and content. We find that cooling to $10$ K instead of to $10^4$ K
increases the mass fraction of cold neutral and hot X-ray gas in the galactic
wind while halving that in warm H$\alpha$. Our simulations show the mass of
cold gas transported into the lower halo does not depend on the starburst
strength. Optically bright filaments form at the edge of merging superbubbles,
or where a cold dense cloud has been disrupted by the wind. Filaments formed by
merging superbubbles will persist and grow to $&gt;400$ pc in length if anchored
to a star forming complex. Filaments embedded in the hot galactic wind contain
warm and cold gas that moves $300-1200$ km s$^{-1}$ slower than the surrounding
wind, with the coldest gas hardly moving with respect to the galaxy. Warm and
cold matter in the galactic wind show asymmetric absorption profiles consistent
with observations, with a thin tail up to the wind velocity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00562</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mutch</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geil</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poole</keyname><forenames>Gregory B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Angel</keyname><forenames>Paul W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duffy</keyname><forenames>Alan R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mesinger</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyithe</keyname><forenames>J. Stuart B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark-ages reionization and galaxy formation simulation - III. Modelling
  galaxy formation and the epoch of reionization</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>30 pages, 18 figures; published in MNRAS; Updated to match published
  version. Additional results and fitting formulae added from previous version.
  All other results and conclusions remain unchanged</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (October 11, 2016) 462 (1): 250-276</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce Meraxes, a new, purpose-built semi-analytic galaxy formation
model designed for studying galaxy growth during reionization. Meraxes is the
first model of its type to include a temporally and spatially coupled treatment
of reionization and is built upon a custom (100 Mpc)$^3$ N-body simulation with
high temporal and mass resolution, allowing us to resolve the galaxy and star
formation physics relevant to early galaxy formation. Our fiducial model with
supernova feedback reproduces the observed optical depth to electron scattering
and evolution of the galaxy stellar mass function between $z$=5 and 7,
predicting that a broad range of halo masses contribute to reionization. Using
a constant escape fraction and global recombination rate, our model is unable
to simultaneously match the observed ionizing emissivity at $z{\lesssim}6$.
However, the use of an evolving escape fraction of 0.05-0.1 at $z{\sim}6$,
increasing towards higher redshift, is able to satisfy these three constraints.
We also demonstrate that photoionization suppression of low mass galaxy
formation during reionization has only a small effect on the ionization history
of the inter-galactic medium. This lack of `self-regulation' arises due to the
already efficient quenching of star formation by supernova feedback. It is only
in models with gas supply-limited star formation that reionization feedback is
effective at regulating galaxy growth. We similarly find that reionization has
only a small effect on the stellar mass function, with no observationally
detectable imprint at $M_{\rm *}{&gt;}10^{7.5}\,{\rm M_{{\odot}}}$. However,
patchy reionization has significant effects on individual galaxy masses, with
variations of factors of 2-3 at $z$=5 that correlate with environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03921</id><created>2016-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ojambati</keyname><forenames>Oluwafemi S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mosk</keyname><forenames>Allard P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vellekoop</keyname><forenames>Ivo M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagendijk</keyname><forenames>Ad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vos</keyname><forenames>Willem L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy density distribution of shaped waves inside scattering media
  mapped onto a complete set of diffusion modes</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 18525-18540 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.018525</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the spatial distribution of the energy density of optimally
shaped waves inside a scattering medium can be described by considering only a
few of the lowest eigenfunctions of the diffusion equation. Taking into account
only the fundamental eigenfunction, the total internal energy inside the sample
is underestimated by only 2%. The spatial distribution of the shaped energy
density is very similar to the fundamental eigenfunction, up to a cosine
distance of about 0.01. We obtained the energy density inside a quasi-1D
disordered waveguide by numerical calculation of the joined scattering matrix.
Computing the transmission-averaged energy density over all transmission
channels yields the ensemble averaged energy density of shaped waves. From the
averaged energy density obtained, we reconstruct its spatial distribution using
the eigenfunctions of the diffusion equation. The results from our study have
exciting applications in controlled biomedical imaging, efficient light
harvesting in solar cells, enhanced energy conversion in solid-state lighting,
and low threshold random lasers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04430</id><created>2016-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Anil Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>A transitioning universe with anisotropic dark energy</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figure panels</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys. Space Sci 361, 276 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2862-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present a model of transitioning universe with minimal
interaction between perfect fluid and anisotropic dark energy in Bianchi I
space-time. The two sources are assumed to minimally interacted and therefore
their energy momentum tensors are conserved separately. The explicit expression
for average scale factor are considered in hybrid form that gives time varying
deceleration parameter which describes both the early and late time physical
features of universe. We also discuss the physical and geometrical properties
of the model derived in this paper. The solution is interesting physically as
it explain accelerating universe as well as singularity free universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07309</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07309</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>Vitor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franzin</keyname><forenames>Edgardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pani</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the gravitational-wave ringdown a probe of the event horizon?</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures. Version published as Editors' Suggestion in
  Physical Review Letters. v4: includes Erratum correcting the caption of
  Fig.4. All conclusions remain unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 171101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.171101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is commonly believed that the ringdown signal from a binary coalescence
provides a conclusive proof for the formation of an event horizon after the
merger. This expectation is based on the assumption that the ringdown waveform
at intermediate times is dominated by the quasinormal modes of the final
object. We point out that this assumption should be taken with great care, and
that very compact objects with a light ring will display a similar ringdown
stage, even when their quasinormal-mode spectrum is completely different from
that of a black hole. In other words, universal ringdown waveforms indicate the
presence of light rings, rather than of horizons. Only precision observations
of the late-time ringdown signal, where the differences in the quasinormal-mode
spectrum eventually show up, can be used to rule out exotic alternatives to
black holes and to test quantum effects at the horizon scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07684</id><created>2016-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Capolupo</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambiase</keyname><forenames>Gaetano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitiello</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal condensate structure and cosmological energy density of the
  Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, Volume 2016, 3127597 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this paper is the study of thermal vacuum condensate for scalar
and fermion fields. We analyze the thermal states at the temperature of the
cosmic microwave background (CMB) and we show that the vacuum expectation value
of the energy momentum tensor density of photon fields reproduces the energy
density and pressure of the CMB. We perform the computations in the formal
framework of the thermo field dynamics. We also consider the case of neutrinos
and thermal states at the temperature of the neutrino cosmic background.
Consistency with the estimated lower bound of the sum of the active neutrino
masses is verified. In the boson sector, non trivial contribution to the energy
of the universe is given by particles of masses of the order of $10^{-4}eV$
compatible with the ones of the axion-like particles. The fractal self-similar
structure of the thermal radiation is also discussed and related to the
coherent structure of the thermal vacuum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08104</id><created>2016-02-25</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gielen</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sindoni</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Cosmology from Group Field Theory Condensates: a Review</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><proxy>Sigma</proxy><report-no>IMPERIAL-TP-2016-SG-1</report-no><msc-class>83C45, 83C27, 83F05, 81T27</msc-class><journal-ref>SIGMA 12 (2016), 082</journal-ref><doi>10.3842/SIGMA.2016.082</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We give, in some detail, a critical overview over recent work towards
deriving a cosmological phenomenology from the fundamental quantum dynamics of
group field theory (GFT), based on the picture of a macroscopic universe as a
&quot;condensate&quot; of a large number of quanta of geometry which are given by
excitations of the GFT field over a &quot;no-space&quot; vacuum. We emphasise conceptual
foundations, relations to other research programmes in GFT and the wider
context of loop quantum gravity (LQG), and connections to the quantum physics
of real Bose-Einstein condensates. We show how to extract an effective dynamics
for GFT condensates from the microscopic GFT physics, and how to compare it
with predictions of more conventional quantum cosmology models, in particular
loop quantum cosmology (LQC). No detailed familiarity with the GFT formalism is
assumed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02530</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02530</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hyun</keyname><forenames>Seungjoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Sang-A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Sang-Heon</forenames></author></authors><title>Canonical energy and hairy AdS black holes</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>1+28 pages, plain LaTeX; v2: typos fixed; v3 version to appear in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 044014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.044014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the modified version of the canonical energy which was introduced
originally by Hollands and Wald. Our construction depends only on the
Euler-Lagrange expression of the system and thus is independent of the
ambiguity in the Lagrangian. After some comments on our construction, we
briefly mention on the relevance of our construction to the boundary
information metric in the context of the AdS/CFT correspondence. We also study
the stability of three-dimensional hairy extremal black holes by using our
construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08000</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08000</id><created>2016-03-25</created><updated>2016-08-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bonvini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marzani</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muselli</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rottoli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Higgs cross section at N$^3$LO+N$^3$LL and its uncertainty</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, 6 figures. Version to be published in JHEP</comments><report-no>OUTP-16-05P, TIF-UNIMI-2016-2</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 08 (2016) 105</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the inclusive production of a Higgs boson in gluon-fusion and we
study the impact of threshold resummation at next-to-next-to-next-to-leading
logarithmic accuracy (N$^3$LL) on the recently computed fixed-order prediction
at next-to-next-to-next-to-leading order (N$^3$LO). We propose a conservative,
yet robust way of estimating the perturbative uncertainty from missing higher
(fixed- or logarithmic-) orders. We compare our results with two other
different methods of estimating the uncertainty from missing higher orders: the
Cacciari-Houdeau Bayesian approach to theory errors, and the use of algorithms
to accelerate the convergence of the perturbative series. We confirm that the
best convergence happens at $\mu_R=\mu_F=m_H\,/\,2$, and we conclude that a
reliable estimate of the uncertainty from missing higher orders on the Higgs
cross section at 13 TeV is approximately $\pm4$%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01503</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>XMASS Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Takiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraide</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichimura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishimoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takachio</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasaka</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>N. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itow</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kegasa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fushimi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martens</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miuchi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishijima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A measurement of the time profile of scintillation induced by low energy
  gamma-rays in liquid xenon with the XMASS-I detector</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.CO hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in Nucl. Instrum. Meth.
  A</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Instrum. Meth. A 834 (2016) 192-196</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.08.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the measurement of the emission time profile of scintillation from
gamma-ray induced events in the XMASS-I 832 kg liquid xenon scintillation
detector. Decay time constant was derived from a comparison of scintillation
photon timing distributions between the observed data and simulated samples in
order to take into account optical processes such as absorption and scattering
in liquid xenon. Calibration data of radioactive sources, $^{55}$Fe,
$^{241}$Am, and $^{57}$Co were used to obtain the decay time constant. Assuming
two decay components, $\tau_1$ and $\tau_2$, the decay time constant $\tau_2$
increased from 27.9 ns to 37.0 ns as the gamma-ray energy increased from 5.9
keV to 122 keV. The accuracy of the measurement was better than 1.5 ns at all
energy levels. A fast decay component with $\tau_1 \sim 2$ ns was necessary to
reproduce data. Energy dependencies of $\tau_2$ and the fraction of the fast
decay component were studied as a function of the kinetic energy of electrons
induced by gamma-rays. The obtained data almost reproduced previously reported
results and extended them to the lower energy region relevant to direct dark
matter searches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01864</id><created>2016-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>Yang-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Bin-Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Shu-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shan-Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Ming-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yan-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Extremely large and significantly anisotropic magnetoresistance in ZrSiS
  single crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, 21 references</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 108, 244101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953772</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the extremely large magnetoresistance observed in transition metal
telluride, like WTe$_2$, attracted much attention because of the potential
applications in magnetic sensor. Here we report the observation of extremely
large magnetoresistance as 3.0$\times$10$^4$ % measured at 2 K and 9 T magnetic
field aligned along [001]-ZrSiS. The significant magnetoresistance change
(~1.4$\times$10$^4$ %) can be obtained when the magnetic field is titled from
[001] to [011]-ZrSiS. These abnormal magnetoresistance behaviors in ZrSiS can
be understood by electron-hole compensation and the open orbital of Fermi
surface. Because of these superior MR properties, ZrSiS may be used in the
novel magnetic sensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01924</id><created>2016-04-07</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>BESIII Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Ablikim</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achasov</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ai</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albayrak</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambrose</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amoroso</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferroli</keyname><forenames>R. Baldini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ban</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertani</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bettoni</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briere</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calcaterra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cetin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelkov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cibinetto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dbeyssi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedovich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denig</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denysenko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Destefanis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Mori</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>L. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>S. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eren</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fava</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feldbauer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felici</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>C. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fioravanti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritsch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garzia</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goetzen</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>W. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradl</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>A. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>L. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haddadi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Y. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantar-Nayestanaki</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavatsyuk</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiese</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kloss</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolcu</keyname><forenames>O. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopf</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornicer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupsc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leng</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Z. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>D. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhiqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loehner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>R. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>M. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lv</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Q. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>F. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggiora</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messchendorp</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>C. Morales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriya</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muchnoi</keyname><forenames>N. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muramatsu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nerling</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolaev</keyname><forenames>I. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouyang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pacetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patteri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelizaeus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettersson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poling</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>L. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashid</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redmer</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ren</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ripka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rong</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosner</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>X. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoro</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savri&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoenning</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>P. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spataro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>G. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tapan</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thorndike</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiemens</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ullrich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uman</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varner</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>S. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidenkaff</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedner</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>L. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiu</keyname><forenames>Q. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>H. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>C. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>W. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuncu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafar</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zallo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhemchugov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zotti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the leptonic decay width of $J/\psi$ using initial state
  radiation</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.08.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a data set of 2.93 fb$^{-1}$ taken at a center-of-mass energy of
$\sqrt{s}$ = 3.773 GeV with the BESIII detector at the BEPCII collider, we
measure the process $e^+e^-\rightarrow J/\psi\gamma\rightarrow
\mu^+\mu^-\gamma$ and determine the product of the branching fraction and the
electronic width $\mathcal B_{\mu\mu}\cdot \Gamma_{ee} = (333.4 \pm 2.5_{\rm
stat} \pm 4.4_{\rm sys})$~eV. Using the earlier-published BESIII result for
$\mathcal B_{\mu\mu}$ = (5.973 $\pm$ 0.007$_{\rm stat}$ $\pm$ 0.037$_{\rm
sys}$)\%, we derive the $J/\psi$ electronic width $\Gamma_{ee}$~= (5.58 $\pm$
0.05$_{\rm stat}$ $\pm$ 0.08$_{\rm sys}$) keV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08413</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08413</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ashcroft</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eto</keyname><forenames>Minoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haberichter</keyname><forenames>Mareike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nitta</keyname><forenames>Muneto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paranjape</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Head butting sheep: Kink Collisions in the Presence of False Vacua</title><categories>hep-th nlin.PS</categories><comments>Matches version published in J. Phys. A. 32 pages, 20 figures and 9
  kink scattering videos included as ancillary files</comments><report-no>UdeM-GPP-TH-16-251, YGHP-16-04</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 365203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/36/365203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate numerically kink collisions in a $1+1$ dimensional scalar
field theory with multiple vacua. The domain wall model we are interested in
involves two scalar fields and a potential term built from an asymmetric double
well and (double) sine-Gordon potential together with an interaction term.
Depending on the initial kink setup and impact velocities, the model allows for
a wide range of scattering behaviours. Kinks can repel each other, annihilate,
form true or false domain walls and reflect off each other.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08493</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Angloher</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bavykina</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bento</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bucci</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canonica</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciemniak</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Defay</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deuter</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erb</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feilitzsch</keyname><forenames>F. v.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iachellini</keyname><forenames>N. Ferreiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorla</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;tlein</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauff</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huff</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isaila</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jochum</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiefer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kimmerle</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kluck</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraus</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lanfranchi</keyname><forenames>J. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loebell</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;nster</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagliarone</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petricca</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfister</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potzel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pr&#xf6;bst</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reindl</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rottler</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sailer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;ffner</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schieck</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmaler</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nert</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seidel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sivers</keyname><forenames>M. v.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stodolsky</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strandhagen</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strauss</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanzke</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyak</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thi</keyname><forenames>H. H. Trinh</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xfc;rko&#x11f;lu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uffinger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulrich</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usherov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wawoczny</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Willers</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xfc;strich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Z&#xf6;ller</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>New Limits on Double Electron Capture of $^{40}$Ca and $^{180}$W</title><categories>nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physics G: Nuclear and Particle Physics, Volume 43,
  Number 9 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/9/095202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyzed low-background data from the CRESST-II experiment with a total
net exposure of 730 kg days to extract limits on double electron capture
processes. We established new limits for $^{40}$Ca with
$T_{1/2}^{2v2K}&gt;9.9\times10^{21}$ y and $T_{1/2}^{0v2EC}&gt;1.4\times10^{22}$ y
and for $^{180}$W with T$_{1/2}^{2v2K}&gt;3.1\times10^{19}$ y and
$T_{1/2}^{0v2EC}&gt;9.4\times10^{18}$ y at 90% CL. Depending on the process, these
values improve the currently best limits by a factor of $\sim$1.4-30.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08626</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiang</keyname><forenames>Chia-Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cackett</keyname><forenames>Edward M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Jon M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Sudip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strohmayer</keyname><forenames>Tod E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the evolution of the inner disk radius with flux in the neutron star
  low-mass X-ray binary Serpens X-1</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the latest \emph{Suzaku} observation of the bright neutron star
low-mass X-ray binary Serpens X-1 taken in 2013 October and 2014 April. The
observation was taken using the burst mode and only suffered mild pile-up
effects. A broad iron line is clearly detected in the X-ray spectrum. We test
different models and find that the iron line is asymmetric and best interpreted
by relativistic reflection. The relativistically broadened iron line is
generally believed to originate from the innermost regions of the accretion
disk, where strong gravity causes a series of special and general relativistic
effects. The iron line profile indicates an inner radius of $\sim8$ $R_{\rm
G}$, which gives an upper limit on the size of the neutron star. The asymmetric
iron line has been observed in a number of previous observations, which gives
several inner radius measurements at different flux states. We find that the
inner radius of Serpens X-1 does not evolve significantly over the range of
$L/L_{\rm Edd}\sim0.4-0.6$, and the lack of flux dependence of the inner radius
implies that the accretion disk may be truncated outside the innermost stable
circular orbit by the boundary layer rather than the stellar magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00747</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zu</keyname><forenames>Mengjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tong</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ning</forenames></author></authors><title>Density affects the nature of the hexatic-liquid transition in
  two-dimensional melting of core-softened systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 085702 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.085702</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find that both continuous and discontinuous hexatic-liquid transitions can
happen in the melting of two-dimensional solids of soft-core disks. For three
typical model systems, Hertzian, harmonic, and Gaussian-core models, we observe
the same scenarios. These systems exhibit reentrant crystallization (melting)
with a maximum melting temperature $T_m$ happening at a crossover density
$\rho_m$. The hexatic-liquid transition at a density smaller than $\rho_m$ is
discontinuous. Liquid and hexatic phases coexist in a density interval, which
becomes narrower with increasing temperature and tends to vanish approximately
at $T_m$. Above $\rho_m$, the transition is continuous, in agreement with the
Kosterlitz-Thouless-Halperin-Nelson-Young theory. For these soft-core systems,
the nature of the hexatic-liquid transition depends on density (pressure), with
the melting at $\rho_m$ being a plausible transition point from discontinuous
to continuous hexatic-liquid transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04404</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Zhongbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable Weyl Points in Periodically Driven Nodal Line Semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.quant-gas physics.optics</categories><comments>6+2 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 087402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.087402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Weyl semimetals and nodal line semimetals are characterized by linear band
touching at zero-dimensional points and one-dimensional lines, respectively. We
predict that a circularly polarized light drives nodal line semimetals into
Weyl semimetals. The Floquet Weyl points thus obtained are tunable by the
incident light, which enables investigations of them in a highly controllable
manner. The transition from nodal line semimetals to Weyl semimetals is
accompanied by the emergence of a large and tunable anomalous Hall
conductivity. Our predictions are experimentally testable by transport
measurement in film samples or by pump-probe angle-resolved photoemission
spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05982</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Liebchen</keyname><forenames>Benno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cates</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marenduzzo</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author></authors><title>Pattern Formation in Chemically Interacting Active Rotors with
  Self-Propulsion</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.PS</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter (Communication) 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01162D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that active rotations in chemically signalling particles, such
as autochemotactic {\it E. coli} close to walls, create a route for pattern
formation based on a nonlinear yet deterministic instability mechanism. For
slow rotations, we find a transient persistence of the uniform state, followed
by a sudden formation of clusters contingent on locking of the average
propulsion direction by chemotaxis. These clusters coarsen, which results in
phase separation into a dense and a dilute region. Faster rotations arrest
phase separation leading to a global travelling wave of rotors with
synchronized roto-translational motion. Our results elucidate the physics
resulting from the competition of two generic paradigms in active matter,
chemotaxis and active rotations, and show that the latter provides a tool to
design programmable self-assembly of active matter, for example to control
coarsening.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06121</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06121</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-08-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Preston</keyname><forenames>Anthony W. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological backreaction in higher-derivative gravity expansions</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>27 pages, 2 references added, minor clarifications made, comments
  added to introduction and discussion, some details moved to appendices</comments><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)038</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate a general effective stress-energy tensor induced by cosmological
inhomogeneity in effective theories of gravity where the action is
Taylor-expandable in the Riemann tensor and covariant derivatives of the
Riemann tensor. This is of interest as an effective fluid that might provide an
alternative to the cosmological constant, but it also applies to gravitational
waves. We use an adaptation of Green and Wald's weak-averaging framework, which
averages over perturbations in the field equation where the perturbation length
scales are small compared to the averaging scale. In this adaptation, the
length scale of the effective theory, $1/M$, is also taken to be small compared
with the averaging scale. This ensures that the perturbation length scales
remain in fixed proportion to the length scale of the effective theory as the
cosmological averaging scale is taken to be large. We find that backreaction
from higher-derivative terms in the effective action can continue to be
important in the late universe, given a source of sufficiently high-frequency
metric perturbations. This backreaction might also provide a window on exotic
particle physics in the far ultraviolet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07359</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pilat-Lohinger</keyname><forenames>Elke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazso</keyname><forenames>Akos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Funk</keyname><forenames>Barbara</forenames></author></authors><title>A quick method to identify secular resonances in multi-planet systems
  with a binary companion</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>28 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gravitational perturbations in multi-planet systems caused by an accompanying
star are the subject of this investigation. Our dynamical model is based on the
binary star HD41004 AB where a giant planet orbits HD41004 A. We modify the
orbital parameters of this system and analyze the motion of a hypothetical
test-planet surrounding HD41004 A on an interior orbit to the detected giant
planet. Our numerical computations indicate perturbations due to mean motion
and secular resonances. The locations of these resonances are usually connected
to high eccentricity and highly inclined motion depending strongly on the
binary-planet architecture.As the positions of mean motion resonances can
easily be determined, the main purpose of this study is to present a new
semi-analytical method to determine the location of a secular resonance without
huge computational effort.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08648</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zi-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batchelor</keyname><forenames>Murray T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Addendum to `Algebraic equations for the exceptional eigenspectrum of
  the generalized Rabi model'</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49, 369401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/36/369401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our recent paper (Li and Batchelor J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48, 454005
(2015)) we obtained exceptional points in the eigenspectrum of the generalized
Rabi model in terms of a set of algebraic equations. We also gave a proof for
the number of roots of the constraint polynomials defining these exceptional
solutions as a function of the system parameters and discussed the number of
crossing points in the eigenspectrum. This approach however, only covered a
subset of all exceptional points in the eigenspectrum. In this addendum, we
clarify the distinction between the exceptional parts of the eigenspectrum for
this model and discuss the subset of exceptional points not determined in our
paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00273</id><created>2016-06-01</created><updated>2016-08-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Van Cuyck</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jachowicz</keyname><forenames>Natalie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jim&#xe9;nez</keyname><forenames>Ra&#xfa;l Gonz&#xe1;lez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Vishvas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryckebusch</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dessel</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of short-range correlations in neutrino-nucleus scattering</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 10 figures. Version published in Physical Review C</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 024611 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024611</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: Nuclear short-range correlations (SRCs) are corrections to
mean-field wave functions connected with the short-distance behavior of the
nucleon-nucleon interaction. These SRCs provide corrections to lepton- nucleus
cross sections as computed in the impulse approximation (IA). Purpose: We want
to investigate the influence of SRCs on the one-nucleon (1N) and two-nucleon
(2N) knockout channel for muon-neutrino induced processes on a $^{12}$C target
at energies relevant for contemporary measurements. Method: The model adopted
in this work, corrects the impulse approximation for SRCs by shifting the com-
plexity induced by the SRCs from the wave functions to the operators. Due to
the local character of the SRCs, it is argued that the expansion of these
operators can be truncated at a low order. Results: The model is compared with
electron-scattering data, and two-particle two-hole responses are presented for
neutrino scattering. The contributions from the vector and axial-vector parts
of the nuclear current as well as the central, tensor and spin-isospin part of
the SRCs are studied. Conclusions: Nuclear SRCs affect the 1N knockout channel
and give rise to 2N knockout. The exclusive neutrino-induced 2N knockout cross
section of SRC pairs is shown and the 2N knockout contribution to the QE signal
is calculated. The strength occurs as a broad background which extends into the
dip region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00363</id><created>2016-06-01</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wicki</keyname><forenames>Flavio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longchamp</keyname><forenames>Jean-Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latychevskaia</keyname><forenames>Tatiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escher</keyname><forenames>Conrad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Hans-Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>Mapping Unoccupied Electronic States of Freestanding Graphene by
  Angle-Resolved Low-Energy Electron Transmission</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B, Volume 94, Issue 7, 075424 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075424</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report angle-resolved electron transmission measurements through
freestanding graphene sheets in the energy range of 18 to 30 eV above the Fermi
level. The measurements are carried out in a low-energy electron point source
microscope, which allows simultaneously probing the transmission for a large
angular range. The characteristics of low-energy electron transmission through
graphene depend on its electronic structure above the vacuum level. The
experimental technique described here allows mapping the unoccupied band
structure of freestanding two-dimensional materials as a function of energy and
probing angle, respectively in-plane momentum. Our experimental findings are
consistent with theoretical predictions of a resonance in the band structure of
graphene above the vacuum level [V. U. Nazarov, E. E. Krasovskii, and V. M.
Silkin, Physical Review B 87, 041405 (2013)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00429</id><created>2016-06-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Chattopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Amit K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasiev</keyname><forenames>Diar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugavanam</keyname><forenames>Srikanth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarasov</keyname><forenames>Nikita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Churkin</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Laminar-Turbulent Transition in Raman Fiber Lasers: A First Passage
  Statistics Based Analysis</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.stat-mech physics.data-an</categories><comments>To be published in Nature Scientific Report; 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Loss of coherence with increasing excitation amplitudes and spatial size
modulation is a fundamental problem in designing Raman fiber lasers. While it
is known that ramping up laser pump power increases the amplitude of stochastic
excitations, such higher energy inputs can also lead to a transition from a
linearly stable coherent laminar regime to a non-desirable disordered turbulent
state. This report presents a new statistical methodology, based on first
passage statistics, that classifies lasing regimes in Raman fiber lasers,
thereby leading to a fast and highly accurate identification of a strong
instability leading to a laminar-turbulent phase transition through a
self-consistently defined order parameter. The results have been consistent
across a wide range of pump power values, heralding a breakthrough in the
non-invasive analysis of fiber laser dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06902</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nava</keyname><forenames>Lara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gabici</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcowith</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morlino</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ptuskin</keyname><forenames>Vladimir S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear diffusion of cosmic rays escaping from supernova remnants -
  I. The effect of neutrals</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Revised to match the version published in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1592</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supernova remnants are believed to be the main sources of galactic Cosmic
Rays (CR). Within this framework, particles are accelerated at supernova
remnant shocks and then released in the interstellar medium. The mechanism
through which CRs are released and the way in which they propagate still remain
open issues. The main difficulty is the high non-linearity of the problem: CRs
themselves excite the magnetic turbulence that confines them close to their
sources. We solve numerically the coupled differential equations describing the
evolution in space and time of the escaping particles and of the waves
generated through the CR streaming instability. The warm ionized and warm
neutral phases of the interstellar medium are considered. These phases occupy
the largest fraction of the disc volume, where most supernovae explode, and are
characterised by the significant presence of neutral particles. The friction
between those neutrals and ions results in a very effective wave damping
mechanism. It is found that streaming instability affects the propagation of
CRs even in the presence of ion-neutral friction. The diffusion coefficient can
be suppressed by more than a factor of $\sim 2$ over a region of few tens of pc
around the remnant. The suppression increases for smaller distances. The
propagation of $\approx 10$ GeV particles is affected for several tens of
kiloyears after escape, while $\approx 1$ TeV particles are affected for few
kiloyears. This might have a great impact on the interpretation of gamma-ray
observations of molecular clouds located in the vicinity of supernova remnants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07922</id><created>2016-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sheu</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photo-creating supercooled spiral-spin states in a multiferroic
  manganite</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B: Rapid Communication (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.081107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that dynamics of the ab-spiral-spin order in a magnetoelectric
multiferroic Eu0.55Y0.45MnO3 can be unambiguously probed through optical second
harmonic signals, generated via the spin-induced ferroelectric polarization. In
the case of relatively weak photoexcitation,the ferroelectric and the
spiral-spin order remains interlocked, both relaxing through spin-lattice
relaxation in the non-equilibrium state. When the additional optical pulse
illuminating sample is intense enough to induced a local phase transition
thermally, the system creates a metastable state of the bc-spiral-spin order
(with the electric polarization P//c) via supercooling across the first-order
phase transition between ab- and bc-spiral. The supercooled state of bc-spiral
spin is formed in the thermodynamical ground state of ab-spiral (P//a),
displaying a prolonged lifetime with strong dependence on the magnetic field
along the a-axis. The observed photo-switching between the two distinct
multiferroic states sheds light on novel photoinduced phenomena in spiral-spin
multiferroics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04641</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Botteon</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gastaldello</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunetti</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kale</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A $\mathcal{M}\gtrsim3$ shock in `El Gordo' cluster and the origin of
  the radio relic</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables; Updated to match the accepted version
  in MNRAS; Results unchanged</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2089</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an X-ray and radio study of the famous `El Gordo', a massive and
distant ($z=0.87$) galaxy cluster. In the deep (340 ks) Chandra observation,
the cluster appears with an elongated and cometary morphology, a sign of its
current merging state. The GMRT radio observations at 610 MHz reveal the
presence of a radio halo which remarkably overlaps the X-ray cluster emission
and connects a couple of radio relics. We detect a strong shock
($\mathcal{M}\gtrsim3$) in the NW periphery of the cluster, co-spatially
located with the radio relic. This is the most distant ($z=0.87$) and one of
the strongest shock detected in a galaxy cluster. This work supports the
relic-shock connection and allows to investigate the origin of these radio
sources in a uncommon regime of $\mathcal{M}\gtrsim3$. For this particular case
we found that shock acceleration from the thermal pool is still a viable
possibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08207</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Stehlik</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maialle</keyname><forenames>M. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Degani</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petta</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Role of Multilevel Landau-Zener Interference in Extreme Harmonic
  Generation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the observation of multiphoton electric dipole spin resonance
processes in InAs nanowires, we theoretically study the transport dynamics of a
periodically driven five-level system, modeling the level structure of a
two-electron double quantum dot. We show that the observed multiphoton
resonances, which are dominant near interdot charge transitions, are due to
multilevel Landau-Zener-Stuckelberg-Majorana interference. Here a third energy
level serves as a shuttle that transfers population between the two resonant
spin states. By numerically integrating the master equation we replicate the
main features observed in the experiments: multiphoton resonances (as large as
8 photons), a robust odd-even dependence, and oscillations in the electric
dipole spin resonance signal as a function of energy level detuning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00436</id><created>2016-08-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Shengfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robbins</keyname><forenames>Mark O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanocapillary adhesion between parallel plates</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, Langmuir, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Langmuir 32, 7788 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b02024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular dynamics simulations are used to study capillary adhesion from a
nanometer scale liquid bridge between two parallel flat solid surfaces. The
capillary force and the meniscus shape of the bridge are computed as the
separation between the solid surfaces is varied. Macroscopic theory predicts
the meniscus shape and the contribution of liquid/vapor interfacial tension to
the capillary force quite accurately for separations as small as 2 or 3
molecular diameters (1-2nm). However the total capillary force differs in sign
and magnitude from macroscopic theory for separations less than about 5nm (8-10
diameters) because of molecular layering that is not included in macroscopic
theory. For these small separations, the pressure tensor in the fluid becomes
anisotropic. The components in the plane of the surface vary smoothly and are
consistent with theory based on the macroscopic surface tension. Capillary
adhesion is affected by only the perpendicular component, which has strong
oscillations as the molecular layering changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01877</id><created>2016-08-05</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric properties of graphyne from first-principles calculations</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The two-dimensional graphene-like carbon allotrope, graphyne, has been
recently fabricated and exhibits many interesting electronic properties. In
this work, we investigate the thermoelectric properties of {\gamma}-graphyne by
performing first-principles calculations combined with Boltzmann transport
theory for both electron and phonon. The carrier relaxation time is accurately
evaluated from the ultra-dense electron-phonon coupling matrix elements
calculated by adopting the density functional perturbation theory and Wannier
interpolation, rather than the generally used deformation potential theory
which only considers the electron-acoustic phonon scattering. It is found that
the thermoelectric performance of {\gamma}-graphyne exhibits a strong
dependence on the temperature and carrier type. At an intermediate temperature
of 600 K, a maximum ZT value of 1.5 and 1.0 can be achieved for the p- and
n-type systems, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02391</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barbiellini</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orikasa</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaprzyk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itou</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yung Jui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafiz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchimoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bansil</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identifying a descriptor for d-orbital delocalization in cathodes of Li
  batteries based on x-ray Compton scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures, and 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 109, 073102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4961055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss how x-ray Compton scattering spectra can be used for investigating
the evolution of electronic states in cathode materials of Li batteries under
the lithiation/delithiation process. In particular, our analysis of the Compton
spectra taken from polycrystalline LixCoO2 samples shows that the spectra are
dominated by the contribution of the O-2p redox orbital. We identify a distinct
signature of d-orbital delocalization, which is tied directly to the
conductivity of the material, providing a descriptor based on Compton spectra
for monitoring the lithiation range with improved conductivity and kinetics for
electrochemical operation. Our study demonstrates that Compton scattering
spectroscopy can provide a window for probing complex electronic mechanisms
underlying the charging and discharging processes in Li-battery materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03599</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsallis</keyname><forenames>Constantino</forenames></author></authors><title>Approach of complexity in nature: Entropic nonuniqueness</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages including 3 figures. To appear in Axioms. Guest Editor:
  Prof. Dr. Hans J. Haubold. The present invited overview belongs to the
  Special Issue &quot;Special Functions: Fractional Calculus and the Pathway for
  Entropy Dedicated to Professor Dr. Arak M. Mathai at the occasion of his 80th
  Birthday&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Axioms 5, 20 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/axioms5030020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boltzmann introduced in the 1870's a logarithmic measure for the connection
between the thermodynamical entropy and the probabilities of the microscopic
configurations of the system. His entropic functional for classical systems was
extended by Gibbs to the entire phase space of a many-body system, and by von
Neumann in order to cover quantum systems as well. Finally, it was used by
Shannon within the theory of information. The simplest expression of this
functional corresponds to a discrete set of $W$ microscopic possibilities, and
is given by $S_{BG}= -k\sum_{i=1}^W p_i \ln p_i$ ($k$ is a positive universal
constant; {\it BG} stands for {\it Boltzmann-Gibbs}). This relation enables the
construction of BG statistical mechanics. The BG theory has provided
uncountable important applications. Its application in physical systems is
legitimate whenever the hypothesis of {\it ergodicity} is satisfied. However,
{\it what can we do when ergodicity and similar simple hypotheses are
violated?}, which indeed happens in very many natural, artificial and social
complex systems. It was advanced in 1988 the possibility of generalizing BG
statistical mechanics through a family of nonadditive entropies, namely
$S_q=k\frac{1-\sum_{i=1}^W p_i^q}{q-1}$, which recovers the additive $S_{BG}$
entropy in the $q \to1$ limit. The index $q$ is to be determined from
mechanical first principles. Along three decades, this idea intensively evolved
world-wide (see Bibliography in \url{http://tsallis.cat.cbpf.br/biblio.htm}),
and led to a plethora of predictions, verifications, and applications in
physical systems and elsewhere. As expected whenever a {\it paradigm shift} is
explored, some controversy naturally emerged as well in the community. The
present status of the general picture is here described, starting from its
dynamical and thermodynamical foundations, and ending with its most recent
physical applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.04248</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.04248</id><created>2016-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jin-Si</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Ya-Zhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>Potential of mean force between like-charged nanoparticles: Many-body
  effect</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1038/srep23434</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ion-mediated interaction is important for the properties of polyelectrolytes
such as colloids and nucleic acids. The effective pair interactions between two
polyelectrolytes have been investigated extensively, but the many-body effect
for multiple polyelectrolytes still remains elusive. In this work, the
many-body effect in potential of mean force (PMF) between like-charged
nanoparticles in various salt solutions has been comprehensively examined by
Monte Carlo simulation and the nonlinear Poisson-Boltzmann theory. Our
calculations show that, at high 1:1 salt, the PMF is weakly repulsive and
appears additive, while at low 1:1 salt, the additive assumption overestimates
the repulsive many-body PMF. At low 2:2 salt, the pair PMF appears weakly
repulsive while the many-body PMF can become attractive. In contrast, at high
2:2 salt, the pair PMF is apparently attractive while the many-body effect can
cause a weaker attractive PMF than that from the additive assumption. Our
microscopic analyses suggest that the elusive many-body effect is attributed to
ion-binding which is sensitive to ion concentration, ion valence, number of
nanoparticles and charges on nanoparticles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05074</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahajan</keyname><forenames>Raghu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freeman</keyname><forenames>C. Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mumford</keyname><forenames>Sam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tubman</keyname><forenames>Norm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swingle</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement structure of non-equilibrium steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages + appendices, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the problem of calculating transport properties of interacting
quantum systems, specifically electrical and thermal conductivities, by
computing the non-equilibrium steady state (NESS) of the system biased by
contacts. Our approach is based on the structure of entanglement in the NESS.
With reasonable physical assumptions, we show that a NESS close to local
equilibrium is lightly entangled and can be represented via a computationally
efficient tensor network. We further argue that the NESS may be found by
dynamically evolving the system within a manifold of appropriate low
entanglement states. A physically realistic law of dynamical evolution is
Markovian open system dynamics, or the Lindblad equation. We explore this
approach in a well-studied free fermion model where comparisons with the
literature are possible. We study both electrical and thermal currents with and
without disorder, and compute entropic quantities such as mutual information
and conditional mutual information. We conclude with a discussion of the
prospects of this approach for the challenging problem of transport in strongly
interacting systems, especially those with disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05078</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Beom</keyname><forenames>Minje</forenames></author><author><keyname>Na</keyname><forenames>Chongsam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferguson</keyname><forenames>Jason W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. -C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The effects of individual metal contents on isochrones for C, N, O, Na,
  Mg, Al, Si, and Fe</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>published in ApJ (Aug 1. 2016) / accepted for publication in ApJ (May
  25. 2016) / 11 pages, 9 figures, 5 tables / ads address:
  http://adsabs.harvard.edu/abs/2016ApJ...826..155B</comments><journal-ref>2016ApJ...826..155B</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/2/155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The individual characteristics of C, N, O, Na, Mg, Al, Si, and Fe on
isochrones have been investigated in this study. Stellar models have been
constructed for various mixtures in which the content of each element is
changed up to the extreme value reported in recent studies, and the changes in
isochrone shape have been analyzed for the various mixtures. To express the
abundance variation of different elements with a single parameter, we have
focused on the relative changes in the total number of metal ions. A review of
the shape changes revealed that Na, Mg, and Al work the same way in stellar
models, as the well-known fact that C, N, and O have the same reactions in the
stellar interior. In addition, it was found that in high-metallicity conditions
the influence of Si and Fe on the red giant branch becomes smaller than that of
Na, Mg, and Al closer to the tip. Furthermore, the influence of Fe on the main
sequence is larger than that of Na, Mg, Al, and even Si.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05089</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Codes from High-Dimensional Manifolds</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct toric codes on various high-dimensional manifolds. Assuming a
conjecture in geometry we find families of quantum CSS stabilizer codes on $N$
qubits with logarithmic weight stabilizers and distance $N^{1-\epsilon}$ for
any $\epsilon&gt;0$. The conjecture is that there is a constant $C&gt;0$ such that
for any $n$-dimensional torus ${\mathbb T}^n={\mathbb R}^n/\Lambda$, where
$\Lambda$ is a lattice, the least volume unoriented $n/2$-dimensional surface
(using the Euclidean metric) representing nontrivial homology has volume at
least $C^n$ times the volume of the least volume $n/2$-dimensional hyperplane
representing nontrivial homology; in fact, it would suffice to have this result
for $\Lambda$ an integral lattice with the surface restricted to faces of a
cubulation by unit hypercubes. The main technical result is an estimate of
Rankin invariants\cite{rankin} for certain random lattices, showing that in a
certain sense they are optimal. Additionally, we construct codes with
square-root distance, logarithmic weight stabilizers, and inverse
polylogarithmic soundness factor (considered as quantum locally testable
codes\cite{qltc}). We also provide an short, alternative proof that the
shortest vector in the exterior power of a lattice may be
non-split\cite{coulangeon}.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05105</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Santana</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katzgraber</keyname><forenames>Helmut G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolutionary Approaches to Optimization Problems in Chimera Topologies</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cs.NE quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Genetic and Evolutionary Computation Conference
  (GECCO-2016), ACM Press, 397-404 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chimera graphs define the topology of one of the first commercially available
quantum computers. A variety of optimization problems have been mapped to this
topology to evaluate the behavior of quantum enhanced optimization heuristics
in relation to other optimizers, being able to efficiently solve problems
classically to use them as benchmarks for quantum machines. In this paper we
investigate for the first time the use of Evolutionary Algorithms (EAs) on
Ising spin glass instances defined on the Chimera topology. Three genetic
algorithms (GAs) and three estimation of distribution algorithms (EDAs) are
evaluated over $1000$ hard instances of the Ising spin glass constructed from
Sidon sets. We focus on determining whether the information about the topology
of the graph can be used to improve the results of EAs and on identifying the
characteristics of the Ising instances that influence the success rate of GAs
and EDAs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05113</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Voznyy</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Fengjia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ip</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiani</keyname><forenames>Amirreza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thon</keyname><forenames>Susanna M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kemp</keyname><forenames>Kyle W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levina</keyname><forenames>Larissa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sargent</keyname><forenames>Edward H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Passivation-sensitive exciton finestructure produces excess Stokes
  shifts in colloidal quantum dots</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The excitonic finestructure of colloidal quantum dots (CQDs) is comprised of
a manifold of transitions, of which only the lowest are populated and
contribute to photoluminescence. This leads to a Stokes shift in emission
relative to absorption. Here we show experimentally that the Stokes shift in Pb
and Cd-based chalcogenide CQDs is correlated with the degree of surface
passivation, and develop a model that explains how coupling to the surface
affects the core electronic states. Dark and bright transitions can reorder and
split, increasing the Stokes shift even without the formation of deep traps.
Our findings resolve the highly-debated topic of excess Stokes shifts in PbS
nanocrystals as due to parity-forbidden transitions instead of traps. We
predict that the Stokes shift in PbS can be eliminated via core stoichiometry
control, a critical step towards enhancing the open circuit voltage in quantum
dot solar cells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05115</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05115</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Christopher S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>Thomas N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspi</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Miniature X-ray Solar Spectrometer (MinXSS) CubeSats: spectrometer
  characterization techniques, spectrometer capabilities, and solar science
  objectives</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, 1 table; presented at SPIE 9905 (Space
  Telescopes and Instrumentation 2016: Ultraviolet to Gamma Ray) in Edinburgh,
  Scotland</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE 9905, Space Telescopes and Instrumentation 2016:
  Ultraviolet to Gamma Ray, 990509 (July 18, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2231945</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Miniature X-ray Solar Spectrometer (MinXSS) are twin 3U CubeSats. The
first of the twin CubeSats (MinXSS-1) launched in December 2015 to the
International Space Station for deployment in mid-2016. Both MinXSS CubeSats
utilize a commercial off the shelf (COTS) X-ray spectrometer from Amptek to
measure the solar irradiance from 0.5 to 30 keV with a nominal 0.15 keV FWHM
spectral resolution at 5.9 keV, and a LASP-developed X-ray broadband photometer
with similar spectral sensitivity. MinXSS design and development has involved
over 40 graduate students supervised by professors and professionals at the
University of Colorado at Boulder. The majority of previous solar soft X-ray
measurements have been either at high spectral resolution with a narrow
bandpass or spectrally integrating (broadband) photometers. MinXSS will conduct
unique soft X-ray measurements with moderate spectral resolution over a
relatively large energy range to study solar active region evolution, solar
flares, and the effects of solar soft X-ray emission on Earth's ionosphere.
This paper focuses on the X-ray spectrometer instrument characterization
techniques involving radioactive X-ray sources and the National Institute for
Standards and Technology (NIST) Synchrotron Ultraviolet Radiation Facility
(SURF). Spectrometer spectral response, spectral resolution, response linearity
are discussed as well as future solar science objectives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05125</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Talati</keyname><forenames>Daryoush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wazwaz</keyname><forenames>Abdul-Majid</forenames></author></authors><title>Some new integrable systems of two-component fifth order equations</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages. This paper is merger of complete version of a draft with
  archive number arXiv:1305.4567 and some other possible new systems</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we develop some fifth-order integrable coupled systems of weight
$0$ and $1$ which possess seventh-order symmetry. We establish four new
systems, where in some cases, related recursion operator and bi-Hamiltonian
formulations are given. We also investigate the integrability of the developed
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05146</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Oganesyan</keyname><forenames>Vardan</forenames></author></authors><title>Commuting differential operators of rank 2 with rational coefficients</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AG math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>23 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we find new self-adjoint commuting operators of rank 2 with
rational coefficients and prove that any elliptic and hyperelliptic curves of
genus 2 are spectral curves of commuting operators with rational coefficients.
Also the case when curves of genus 3 are spectral curves of commuting operators
with rational coefficients is studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05155</id><created>2016-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>T. Ferreira</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xavier</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaral</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tempor&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von der Weid</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum random number generation enhanced by weak-coherent states
  interference</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 19574 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.019574</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and demonstrate a technique for quantum random number generation
based on the random population of the output spatial modes of a beam splitter
when both inputs are simultaneously fed with indistinguishable weak coherent
states. We simulate and experimentally validate the probability of generation
of random bits as a function of the average photon number per input, and
compare it to the traditional approach of a single weak coherent state
transmitted through a beam-splitter, showing an improvement of up to 32\%. The
ensuing interference phenomenon reduces the probability of coincident counts
between the detectors associated with bits 0 and 1, thus increasing the
probability of occurrence of a valid output. A long bit string is assessed by a
standard randomness test suite with good confidence. Our proposal can be easily
implemented and opens attractive performance gains without a significant
trade-off.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05183</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Jinping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Chuanshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ziting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhanshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Ya</forenames></author></authors><title>Harmonic-seeded resonant Raman amplification in strong-field ionized
  nitrogen molecules</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Generation of free-space laser-like emissions of high spatiotemporal
coherence and narrow bandwidth in atmosphere opens promising opportunities for
remote spectroscopic sensing. Here, we report on generation of such laser-like
emissions, which results from the combined contributions of perturbative and
non-perturbative nonlinear optical effects in nitrogen molecules exposed to
intense mid-infrared laser fields. We systematically investigate the dependence
of the generated free-space laser spectrum on wavelength and power of the
driver laser. It is revealed that the free-space laser is produced by resonant
Raman amplification of the fifth harmonic of the driver pulses in rotational
wavepacket of the molecular nitrogen ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05189</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Eckerle</keyname><forenames>Kate</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Field Theories in The Mirror Quintic Moduli Space</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>54 pages, 22 figures, 4 tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the distribution of field theories that arise from the low
energy limit of flux vacua built on type IIB string theory compactified on the
mirror quintic. For a large collection of these models, we numerically
determine the distribution of Taylor coefficients in a polynomial expansion of
each model's scalar potential to fourth order, and show that they differ
significantly from potentials generated by random choices of such coefficients
over a flat measure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05190</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bavarsad</keyname><forenames>Ernest A.</forenames><affiliation>San Diego State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sandquist</keyname><forenames>Eric L.</forenames><affiliation>San Diego State University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shetrone</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames><affiliation>McDonald Observatory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Orosz</keyname><forenames>Jerome A.</forenames><affiliation>San Diego State University</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Detached Eclipsing Binary KV29 and the Age of the Open Cluster M11</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>31 pages, 11 figures, accepted to ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an extensive set of photometry and radial velocities for the
detached eclipsing binary KV 29 in the intermediate-aged open cluster M11 (NGC
6705). Spectroscopy shows that the system is double-lined and all available
evidence (proper motion, photometry, and position on the CMD) indicates it is a
member of the cluster. We find the period of the binary to be
$4.64276\pm0.00001$ days. We find masses $3.604^{+0.002}_{-0.011}M_\odot$ and
$1.837^{+0.001}_{-0.006}M_\odot$, and radii $5.392^{+0.018}_{-0.035}R_\odot$
and $1.656^{+0.007}_{-0.044}R_\odot$ for the primary and secondary stars,
respectively. Because the primary star in the binary is rapidly evolving and is
brighter than the cluster turnoff in a color-magnitude diagram, the measurement
of its radius leads to a strong constraint on the cluster age. We find the age
of M11 to be $222^{+2}_{-3}\pm15$ Myr, where the quoted uncertainties come from
statistical errors in the calculated masses and radii, and systematic
uncertainties due to the ambiguity of the metallicity of the open cluster and
variations within the isochrone models concerning heavy elements and convective
overshooting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05191</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05191</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Perera</keyname><forenames>Viranga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jackson</keyname><forenames>Alan P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asphaug</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballouz</keyname><forenames>Ronald-Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>The spherical Brazil Nut Effect and its significance to asteroids</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Icarus, Volume 278, 1 November 2016, Pages 194-203</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2016.06.014</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Many asteroids are likely rubble-piles that are a collection of smaller
objects held together by gravity and possibly cohesion. These asteroids are
seismically shaken by impacts, which leads to excitation of their constituent
particles. As a result it has been suggested that their surfaces and
sub-surface interiors may be governed by a size sorting mechanism known as the
Brazil Nut Effect. We study the behavior of a model asteroid that is a
spherical, self-gravitating aggregate with a binary size-distribution of
particles under the action of applied seismic shaking. We find that above a
seismic threshold, larger particles rise to the surface when friction is
present, in agreement with previous studies that focussed on cylindrical and
rectangular box configurations. Unlike previous works we also find that size
sorting takes place even with zero friction, though the presence of friction
does aid the sorting process above the seismic threshold. Additionally we find
that while strong size sorting can take place near the surface, the innermost
regions remain unsorted under even the most vigorous shaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05192</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcilazo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valcarce</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vijande</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal isospin few-body systems of nucleons and $\Xi$ hyperons</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C. 94, 024002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By using local central Yukawa-type interactions that reproduce the low-energy
parameters of the latest updates of the Nijmegen ESC08c potentials we show that
the $N\Xi$, $NN\Xi$, $N\Xi\Xi$ and $NN\Xi\Xi$ systems with maximal isospin are
bound. Since in these states the strong decay $N\Xi\to\Lambda\Lambda$ is
forbidden by isospin conservation, these strange few-body systems will be
stable under the strong interaction. These results may suggest that other
states with different number of $N$'s and $\Xi$'s in the maximal isospin
channel could also be bound.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05194</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Dries</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trager</keyname><forenames>S. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koopmans</keyname><forenames>L. V. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>A hierarchical Bayesian approach for reconstructing the Initial Mass
  Function of Single Stellar Populations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS, 30 pages, 28 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies based on the integrated light of distant galaxies suggest that
the initial mass function (IMF) might not be universal. Variations of the IMF
with galaxy type and/or formation time may have important consequences for our
understanding of galaxy evolution. We have developed a new stellar population
synthesis (SPS) code specifically designed to reconstruct the IMF. We implement
a novel approach combining regularization with hierarchical Bayesian inference.
Within this approach we use a parametrized IMF prior to regulate a direct
inference of the IMF. This direct inference gives more freedom to the IMF and
allows the model to deviate from parametrized models when demanded by the data.
We use Markov Chain Monte Carlo sampling techniques to reconstruct the best
parameters for the IMF prior, the age, and the metallicity of a single stellar
population. We present our code and apply our model to a number of mock single
stellar populations with different ages, metallicities, and IMFs. When
systematic uncertainties are not significant, we are able to reconstruct the
input parameters that were used to create the mock populations. Our results
show that if systematic uncertainties do play a role, this may introduce a bias
on the results. Therefore, it is important to objectively compare different
ingredients of SPS models. Through its Bayesian framework, our model is
well-suited for this.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05195</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Luning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neuscamman</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Amplitude determinant coupled cluster with pairwise doubles</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently developed pair coupled cluster doubles (pCCD) theory successfully
reproduces doubly occupied configuration interaction (DOCI) with mean field
cost. However, the projective nature of pCCD makes the method non-variational
and thus hard to improve systematically. As a variational alternative, we
explore the idea of coupled-cluster-like expansions based on amplitude
determinants and develop a specific theory similar to pCCD based on
determinants of pairwise doubles. The new ansatz admits a variational treatment
through Monte Carlo methods while remaining size-consistent and, crucially,
polynomial cost. In the dissociations of LiH, HF, H2O and N2, the method
performs very similarly to pCCD and DOCI, suggesting that coupled-cluster-like
ansatzes and variational evaluation may not be mutually exclusive.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05210</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Friess</keyname><forenames>Benedikt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenow</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Oppen</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umansky</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Klitzing</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smet</keyname><forenames>Jurgen H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative permittivity attests to local attractive interactions in bubble
  and stripe phases</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Full supplementary information will be available with final
  publication</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physics of itinerant electrons in condensed matter is by and large
governed by repulsive Coulomb forces. However, rare cases exist where local
attractive interactions emerge and prevail in determining the ground state of
the system despite the dominant Coulomb repulsion. The most notable example is
no doubt electron pairing, which leads to superconductivity and is mediated by
electron phonon coupling or more intricate mechanisms such as antiferromagnetic
spin order in high-temperature superconductors. The interplay of attractive and
repulsive interaction components may also instigate spontaneous symmetry
lowering and clustering of charges in geometric patterns such as bubbles and
stripes, provided these interactions act on different length scales. In
high-temperature superconductors, for instance, fluctuating stripe or nematic
ordering is intertwined with superconductivity itself. Both types of attractive
interaction based physics, pairing and charge ordering, are also at play in
high-quality two-dimensional electron systems exposed to a quantizing
perpendicular magnetic field for electrons describing larger orbits. This has
been concluded indirectly from the transport behaviour when such phases form.
An unambiguous manifestation of an underlying attractive interaction between
the electrons has however remained elusive. Here we report the observation of a
negative permittivity as an immediate consequence of local attractive
interaction rather than repulsion among the electrons when bubble and stripe
phases form. The implemented technique based on surface acoustic waves offers
directionality and confirms the stripe phase to be a strongly anisotropic
medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05223</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Gionti</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>J</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>O(d,d) duality transformations in F(R) theories of gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>6 pages ,contribution to the proceedings of the 14th Marcel Grossmann
  Meeting , Rome 12-18 July 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The argument of Hodge duality symmetry is introduced starting from the
electromagnetic field. Introducing bosonic string theory, O(d,d) duality
symmetry can be implemented when there exist d-symmetries, which allows one to
write Hodge-dual fields. A tree-level effective gravitational action of bosonic
string theory coupled with the dilaton field is considered. This theory
inherits the Busher's duality of its parent string theory. The dilaton field
can be recast into the Weyl's mode of the metric tensor in the Jordan frame.
This maps the effective one-loop bosonic string theory of gravity into a
Lagrangian of a f(R) function. Constraining this f(R)-Lagrangian on a FLRW
metric and using Noether symmetries approach for extended theory of gravity, it
is possible to show that the Lagrangian exibits a Gasperini-Veneziano duality
symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05232</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05232</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsiok</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomin</keyname><forenames>Yu. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ryzhov</keyname><forenames>V. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of random pinning on melting scenario of two-dimensional
  core-softened potential system</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1507.01802</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The random disorder can drastically change the melting scenario of
two-dimensional systems and has to be taken into account in the interpretation
of the experimental results. We present the results of the molecular dynamics
simulations of the two dimensional system with the core-softened potentials
with two repulsive steps in which a small fraction of the particles is pinned,
inducing quenched disorder. It is shown that without the quenched disorder the
system with small repulsive shoulder, which is close in the shape to the soft
disks, melts in accordance with the melting scenario proposed in Refs.
[30,31,33] (first-order liquid-hexatic and continuous hexatic-solid
transitions). Random pinning widens the hexatic phase, but leaves the melting
scenario unchanged. For the system with larger repulsive step at high densities
the conventional first-order transition takes place without random pinning.
However, in the presence of disorder the single first-order transition
transforms into two transitions, one of them (solid-hexatic) is the continuous
KTHNY-like transition, while the hexatic to isotropic liquid transition occurs
as the first order transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05240</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Trautner</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>CP and other Symmetries of Symmetries</title><categories>hep-ph cond-mat.other hep-th</categories><comments>PhD thesis, 130 pages, http://mediatum.ub.tum.de?id=1307248</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Outer automorphisms of symmetries (&quot;symmetries of symmetries&quot;) in
relativistic quantum field theories are studied, including charge conjugation
(C), space-reflection (P) , and time-reversal (T) transformations. The group
theory of outer automorphisms is pedagogically introduced and it is shown that
CP transformations are special outer automorphisms of the global, local, and
space-time symmetries of a theory. It is shown that certain discrete groups
allow for a group theoretical prediction of parameter independent CP violating
complex phases with fixed geometrical values. The remainder of this thesis
pioneers the study of outer automorphisms which are not related to C, P, or T.
It is shown how outer automorphisms, in general, relate symmetry invariants
and, in theories with spontaneous symmetry breaking, imply relations between
different vacuum expectation values. Thereby, outer automorphisms can give rise
to emergent symmetries. An example model with a discrete symmetry and three
copies of the Standard Model Higgs field is discussed, in which the rich outer
automorphism structure completely fixes the Higgs VEVs in their field space
direction, including CP violating relative phases. This underlies the
phenomenon of spontaneous geometrical CP violation. The possible relevance of
outer automorphisms for a wide field of future studies is highlighted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05245</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bokhove</keyname><forenames>Onno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedner</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Esler</keyname><forenames>Gavin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norbury</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turner</keyname><forenames>Matthew R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanneste</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cullen</keyname><forenames>Mike</forenames></author></authors><title>Convection in a Single Column -- Modelling, Algorithm and Analysis</title><categories>physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>Report of a study group in &quot;Environmental Modelling in Industry Study
  Group, 21st - 24th September 2015, Isaac Newton Institute, Cambridge&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The group focused on a model problem of idealised moist air convection in a
single column of atmosphere. Height, temperature and moisture variables were
chosen to simplify the mathematical representation (along the lines of the
Boussinesq approximation in a height variable defined in terms of pressure).
This allowed exact simple solutions of the numerical and partial differential
equation problems to be found. By examining these, we identify column
behaviour, stability issues and explore the feasibility of a more general
solution process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05249</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yaohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonexistence of time-periodic solutions of the Dirac equation in
  nonextreme Kerr-Newman-AdS spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc math.CA</categories><comments>13 pages, submitted</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In non-extreme Kerr-Newman-AdS spacetime, we prove that there is no
nontrivial Dirac particle which is $L^p$ for $0&lt;p\leq\frac{4}{3}$ with
arbitrary eigenvalue $\lambda$, and for $\frac{4}{3}&lt;p\leq\frac{4}{3-2q}$,
$0&lt;q&lt;\frac{3}{2}$ with eigenvalue $|\lambda|&gt;|Q|+q \kappa $, outside and away
from the event horizon. By taking $q=\frac{1}{2}$, we show that there is no
normalizable massive Dirac particle with mass greater than
$|Q|+\frac{\kappa}{2} $ outside and away from the event horizon in non-extreme
Kerr-Newman-AdS spacetime, and they must either disappear into the black hole
or escape to infinity, and this recovers the same result of Belgiorno and
Cacciatori in the case of $Q=0$ obtained by using spectral methods.
Furthermore, we prove that any Dirac particle with eigenvalue
$|\lambda|&lt;\frac{\kappa}{2} $ must be $L^2$ outside and away from the event
horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05251</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baoyin</keyname><forenames>Hexi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junfeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Configurations of Celestial Systems Comprised of Multiple
  Irregular Bodies</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>60 pages, 20 figures, The online version of this article
  (doi:10.1007/s10509-016-2884-z) contains supplementary material, which is
  available to authorized users. 6 videos, 5 rar files, 1 pdf file of figures</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and space science 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2884-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This manuscript considers the main features of the nonlinear dynamics of
multiple irregular celestial body systems. The gravitational potential, static
electric potential, and magnetic potential are considered. Based on the three
established potentials, we show that three conservative values exist for this
system, including a Jacobi integral. The equilibrium conditions for the system
are derived and their stability analyzed. The equilibrium conditions of a
celestial system comprised of n irregular bodies are reduced to 12n minus 9
equations. The dynamical results are applied to simulate the motion of
multiple-asteroid systems. The simulation is useful for the study of the
stability of multiple irregular celestial body systems and for the design of
spacecraft orbits to triple asteroid systems discovered in the solar system.
The dynamical configurations of the five triple-asteroid systems 45 Eugenia, 87
Sylvia, 93 Minerva, 216 Kleopatra, and 136617 1994CC, and the six-body system
134340 Pluto are calculated and analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05254</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05254</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>M&#xe9;ndez</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;ljivi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>&#x17d;.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudej</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casar</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Grid patterns, spatial inter-scan variations and scanning reading
  repeatability in radiochromic film dosimetry</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.ejmp.2016.08.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Purpose: When comparing different scans of the same radiochromic film,
several patterns can be observed. These patterns are caused by different
sources of uncertainty, which affect the repeatability of the scanner. The
purpose of this work was to study these uncertainties.
  Methods: The variance of the scanner noise, as a function of the pixel
position, was studied for different resolutions. The inter-scan variability of
the scanner response was analyzed taking into account spatial discrepancies.
Finally, the distance between the position of the same point in different scans
was examined.
  Results: The variance of noise follows periodical patterns in both axes,
causing the grid patterns. These patterns were identified for resolutions of
50, 72 and 96 dpi, but not for 150 dpi. Specially recognizable is the
sinusoidal shape with a period of 8.5 mm that is produced with 72 dpi.
Inter-scan variations of the response caused systematic relative dose
deviations larger than 1% in 5% of the red channel images, 9% of the green and
51% of the blue. No systematic deviation larger than 1% was found after
applying response corrections. The initial positioning and the speed of the
scanner lamp vary between scans.
  Conclusions: Three new sources of uncertainty, which influence radiochromic
film dosimetry with flatbed scanners, have been identified and analyzed in this
work: grid patterns, spatial inter-scan variations and scanning reading
repeatability. A novel correction method is proposed, which mitigates spatial
inter-scan variations caused by deviations in the autocalibration of the
individual Charge Coupled Device detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05260</id><created>2016-08-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Sidharth</keyname><forenames>Burra G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Grand Unification</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, IIAMIS-TR 08 2016 No.1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sidharth had shown that gravitation can be reconciled with electromagnetic
and other forces if we start from a Landau-Ginzburg phase transition. This is
further remarked upon and a unification of all forces of nature is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05261</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>de Wit</keyname><forenames>Thierry Dudok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lef&#xe8;vre</keyname><forenames>Laure</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clette</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainties in the Sunspot Numbers: Estimation and Implications</title><categories>astro-ph.SR physics.data-an</categories><comments>accepted in Solar Physics (2016), 24 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-0970-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sunspot number series are subject to various uncertainties, which are still
poorly known. The need for their better understanding was recently highlighted
by the major makeover of the international Sunspot Number [Clette et al., Space
Science Reviews, 2014]. We present the first thorough estimation of these
uncertainties, which behave as Poisson-like random variables with a
multiplicative coefficient that is time- and observatory-dependent. We provide
a simple expression for these uncertainties, and reveal how their evolution in
time coincides with changes in the observations, and processing of the data.
Knowing their value is essential for properly building composites out of
multiple observations, and for preserving the stability of the composites in
time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05262</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Olmi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunningham</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Elia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The segregation of starless and protostellar clumps in the Hi-GAL
  l=224deg region</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication on &quot;Astronomy and Astrophysics&quot;</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628519</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stars form in dense, dusty structures, which are embedded in larger clumps of
molecular clouds often showing a clear filamentary structure on large scales (&gt;
1pc). One of the best-studied regions in the Hi-GAL survey can be observed
toward the l=224deg field. Here, a filamentary region has been studied and it
has been found that protostellar clumps are mostly located along the main
filament, whereas starless clumps are detected off this filament and are
instead found on secondary, less prominent filaments. We want to investigate
this segregation effect and how it may affect the clumps properties. We mapped
the 12CO(1-0) line and its main three isotopologues toward the two most
prominent filaments observed toward the l=224deg field using the Mopra radio
telescope, in order to set observational constraints on the dynamics of these
structures and the associated starless and protostellar clumps. Compared to the
starless clumps, the protostellar clumps are more luminous, more turbulent and
lie in regions where the filamentary ambient gas shows larger linewidths. We
see evidence of gas flowing along the main filament, but we do not find any
signs of accretion flow from the filament onto the Hi-GAL clumps. We analyze
the radial column density profile of the filaments and their gravitational
stability. The more massive and highly fragmented main filament appears to be
thermally supercritical and gravitationally bound, assuming that all of the
non-thermal motion is contributing thermal-like support, suggesting a later
stage of evolution compared to the secondary filament. The status and
evolutionary phase of the Hi-GAL clumps would then appear to correlate with
that of the host filament.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05266</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Raimbault</keyname><forenames>Juste</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigating the Empirical Existence of Static User Equilibrium</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures. Forthcoming in Transportation Research Procedia,
  EWGT2016, 5-7 September 2016, Istanbul</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Static User Equilibrium is a powerful framework for the theoretical study
of traffic. Despite the restricting assumption of stationary flows that
intuitively limit its application to real traffic systems, many operational
models implementing it are still used without an empirical validation of the
existence of the equilibrium. We investigate its existence on a traffic dataset
of three months for the region of Paris, FR. The implementation of an
application for interactive spatio-temporal data exploration allows to
hypothesize a high spatial and temporal heterogeneity, and to guide further
quantitative work. The assumption of locally stationary flows is invalidated in
a first approximation by empirical results, as shown by a strong spatial and
temporal variability in shortest paths and in network topological measures such
as betweenness centrality. Furthermore, the behavior of spatial autocorrelation
index of congestion patterns at different spatial ranges suggest a chaotic
evolution at the local scale, especially during peak hours. We finally discuss
the implications of these empirical findings and describe further possible
developments based on the estimation of Lyapunov dynamical stability of traffic
flows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05270</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Devi</keyname><forenames>Yendrembam Chaoba</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patil</keyname><forenames>Alpesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Aritra N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Kaushlendra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Biswajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholtz</keyname><forenames>Frederik G</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting Connes' Finite Spectral Distance on Non-commutative Spaces :
  Moyal Plane and Fuzzy Sphere</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>33 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revise and extend the algorithm provided in [1] to compute the finite
Connes' distance between normal states. The original formula in [1] contains an
error and actually only provides a lower bound. The correct expression, which
we provide here, involves the computation of the infimum of an expression which
involves the &quot;transverse&quot; component of the algebra element in addition to the
&quot;longitudinal&quot; component of [1]. This renders the formula less user-friendly,
as the determination of the exact transverse component for which the infimum is
reached remains a non-trivial task, but under rather generic conditions it
turns out that the Connes' distance is proportional to the trace norm of the
difference in the density matrices, leading to considerable simplification. In
addition, we can determine an upper bound of the distance by emulating and
adapting the approach of [2] in our Hilbert-Schmidt operatorial formulation. We
then look for an optimal element for which the upper bound is reached. We are
able to find one for the Moyal plane through the limit of a sequence obtained
by finite dimensional projections of the representative of an element belonging
to a multiplier algebra, onto the subspaces of the total Hilbert space,
occurring in the spectral triple and spanned by the eigen-spinors of the
respective Dirac operator. This is in contrast with the fuzzy sphere, where the
upper bound, which is given by the geodesic of a commutative sphere is never
reached for any finite $n$-representation of $SU(2)$. Indeed, for the case of
maximal non-commutativity ($n = 1/2$), the finite distance is shown to coincide
exactly with the above mentioned lower bound, with the transverse component
playing no role. This, however starts changing from $n=1$ onwards and we try to
improve the estimate of the finite distance and provide an almost exact result,
using our new and modified algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05283</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaoran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Middey</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Yanwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kareev</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakhalian</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometrical lattice engineering of complex oxide heterostructures: a
  designer approach to emergent quantum states</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>MRS Communications (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1557/mrc.2016.24</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Epitaxial heterostructures composed of complex oxides have fascinated
researchers for over a decade as they offer multiple degrees of freedom to
unveil emergent many-body phenomena often unattainable in bulk. Recently, apart
from stabilizing such artificial structures along the conventional
[001]-direction, tuning the growth direction along unconventional
crystallographic axes has been highlighted as a promising route to realize
novel quantum many-body phases. Here we illustrate this rapidly developing
field of geometrical lattice engineering with the emphasis on a few
prototypical examples of the recent experimental efforts to design complex
oxide heterostructures along the (111) orientation for quantum phase discovery
and potential applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05296</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Kraus</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author></authors><title>NLO QCD off-shell effects for top pair production with a jet in the
  dilepton channel</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, 1 table, contribution to the proceedings of the
  4th Annual Large Hadron Collider Physics conference, 13-18 June 2016, Lund,
  Sweden</comments><report-no>TTK-16-29</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A short summary of a NLO QCD calculation for the top-quark pair production
with a jet in the dilepton decay channel is presented. The calculation takes
into account all double, single, non-resonant and interference contributions.
Thus, NLO QCD corrections are computed for the process pp -&gt; e+ ve mu- vm~ b b~
j + X. This calculation provides the first complete description, which
overcomes the narrow width approximation for ttj process in the dilepton decay
channel. Results for the total cross section and differential distributions for
the LHC at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV are shown.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05303</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05303</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Juh&#xe1;sz</keyname><forenames>Zolt&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic model for electron emission and negative- and positive-ion
  formation in keV molecular collisions</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review A 94, 022707 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.022707</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A statistical-type model is developed to describe the ion production and
electron emission in collisions of (molecular) ions with atoms. The model is
based on the Boltzmann population of the bound electronic energy levels of the
quasi molecule formed in the collision and the discretized continuum. The
discretization of the continuum is implemented by a free electron gas in a box
model assuming an effective square potential of the quasi molecule. The
temperature of the electron gas is calculated by taking into account a
thermodynamically adiabatic process due to the change of the effective volume
of the quasi molecule as the system evolves. The system may undergo a
transition with a small probability from the discretized continuum to the
states of the complementary continuum. It is assumed that these states are
decoupled from the thermodynamic time development. The decoupled states
overwhelmingly determine the yield of the asymptotically observed fragment
ions. The main motivation of this work is to describe the recently observed
$H^-$ ion production in $OH^+ + Ar$ collisions. The obtained differential cross
sections for $H^-$ formation, cation production and electron emission are close
to the experimental ones. Calculations for the atomic systems $O^+ + Ar$ and
$H^+ + Ar$ are also in reasonable agreement with the experiments indicating
that the model can be applied to a wide class of collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05304</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Govindaraj</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel Concept of Non-Debye Dipole Relaxation Processes for the
  Interpretation of Physical Origin of Dielectric Loss in the Glass Formers,
  Drugs, Polymers and Plastic Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>(i) glycerol (ii) 2-ethyl-1-hexanol results in the paper, Supplement
  materials on interesting features of the proposed model and further results
  of (1) 2-butanol (2) 2-Methylpentane 2,4 diol (3)1-proponal (4) Ethanol (5)
  Ketoprofen (6)Propylene carbonate (7) Ortho-carborane (8)Meta-carborane
  (9)1-cynoadamantane (10) Pentachloronitrobenzene</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physical origin of dielectric loss is shown to be sum of n number of
subunits relaxation of a molecule, where n=1,2,3.. For each subunit relaxation,
the idea of intermolecular dipole-dipole interactions triggered non-Debye
dipole, ($\bf G$)$_{n}$=((1-g$_d$)$\bf G$$_{0}$)$_{n}$, and the ensuing dual
dipole ($\bf G$$_{\pm}$)$_n$=($\bf G$$_0$$\pm$$\bf G$)$_n$, relaxation
processes is proposed, where $\bf G$$_{-}$=g$_{d}$$\bf G$$_{0}$, $\bf
G$$_{+}$=(2-g$_{d}$)$\bf G$$_{0}$, and $\bf G$$_{0}$ is a Debye dipole. Each
subunit motion is statistically highly independent process and discriminated by
Debye and non-Debye relaxation (NDR) time, where g$_d$ is an exponent 0&lt;g$_d$&lt;1
and signifies interaction strength with a redistribution and conservation of
Debye dielectric loss energy. The proposed concept provides a new insight for
the NDR and discloses the physical origin of $\alpha$, $\beta$, $\gamma$,
$\delta$ relaxations and excess wing of glass formers, plastic crystals, drugs,
etc., with an excellent agreement with experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05311</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Chapling</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Note on Closed-Form Expressions for Irreducible Loop Integrals</title><categories>hep-th math.CA math.PR</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><msc-class>41A60, 81T99, 60F25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a new analysis of the irreducible loop integrals first considered
in a 2003 paper of Wu. Using convergence ideas from probability, we produce
conditions on the regulator masses so that the integrals have well-defined
limits in the limit required by the regularisation technique; we then derive
closed-form expressions for the regularised forms of these integrals in terms
of incomplete Gamma-functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05312</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Labiano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Azzollini</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>J. I.</forenames><suffix>III</suffix></author><author><keyname>Beard</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dicken</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Mar&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geers</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glasse</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glauser</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gordon</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Justtanont</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klaassen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahuis</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrison</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieke</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vandenbussche</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wright</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The MIRI Medium Resolution Spectrometer calibration pipeline</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Conference Volume 9910, Observatory Operations: Strategies,
  Processes, and Systems VI, June 26, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2232554</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Mid-Infrared Instrument (MIRI) Medium Resolution Spectrometer (MRS) is
the only mid-IR Integral Field Spectrometer on board James Webb Space
Telescope. The complexity of the MRS requires a very specialized pipeline, with
some specific steps not present in other pipelines of JWST instruments, such as
fringe corrections and wavelength offsets, with different algorithms for point
source or extended source data. The MRS pipeline has also two different
variants: the baseline pipeline, optimized for most foreseen science cases, and
the optimal pipeline, where extra steps will be needed for specific science
cases. This paper provides a comprehensive description of the MRS Calibration
Pipeline from uncalibrated slope images to final scientific products, with
brief descriptions of its algorithms, input and output data, and the accessory
data and calibration data products necessary to run the pipeline.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05319</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Vicario</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovchinnikov</keyname><forenames>Andrey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chefonov</keyname><forenames>Oleg V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hauri</keyname><forenames>Christoph P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-octave spectrally tunable strong-field Terahertz laser</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ideal laser source for the emerging research field of nonlinear Terahertz
(THz) spectroscopy should offer radiation with a large versatility and deliver
both ultra-intense multi-octave spanning single-cycle pulses and
user-selectable multi-cycle pulses at narrow linewidth. The absence of such a
table-top source has hampered advances in numerous THz disciplines including
imaging, nonlinear photonics and spectroscopy, selective out-of-equilibrium
excitation of condensed matter and quantum systems. Here we introduce a highly
versatile table-top THz laser platform providing single-cycle GV/m transients
as well as spectrally narrow pulses tunable in bandwidth and central frequency
across 5 octaves with hundreds of MV/m field strength. The compact scheme is
based on optical rectification of a temporally modulated laser beam in organic
crystals. It allows for the selection of THz oscillation cycles from 1 to &gt;50
and central frequency tuning range from 0.5 to 7 THz by directly changing the
modulation period of the driving laser. The versatility of the THz source is
demonstrated by providing a broadband 5-octave spanning spectrum as well as a
spectrally narrow line tunable across the full optical rectification
phase-matching band with a minimum width of dv=30 GHz, corresponding to dE=0.13
meV and lambda^-1=1.1 cm-1. The presented table-top source shows performances
similar or even beyond to that of a large-scale THz electron accelerator
facility but offering in addition versatile multi-color and advanced
femtosecond pump-probe opportunities at ultralow timing jitter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05324</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Adhikary</keyname><forenames>Soumik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravishankar</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sandhir</keyname><forenames>Radha Pyari</forenames></author></authors><title>Is non-locality stronger in higher dimensions?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A critique of a prescription of non-locality in [Phys. Rev. Lett. 85, 4418
(2000)], [Phys. Rev. Lett. 88, 040404 (2002)], [Phys. Rev. Lett. 92, 130404
(2004)] that appears to be stronger and more general than the Bell-CHSH
formulation is presented. It is shown that, contrary to expectations, this
prescription fails to correctly identify a large family of maximally non-local
Bell states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05337</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsai</keyname><forenames>Wei-Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chien</keyname><forenames>Chia-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ping Chung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ou</keyname><forenames>Min-Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harutyunyan</keyname><forenames>Sergey R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yang-Yuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconductivity and Superconductor-Insulator Transition in Single
  Crystal Sb2Te3 Nanoflakes</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on transport properties of the topological insulator single crystal
$Sb2Te3$ nanoflakes with thickness about from 7 to 50nm. A steep drop of
resistance is appeared near $3K$ in the ultrathin $Sb2Te3$ nanoflakes,
manifesting a superconducting transition.The magnetic field induced
superconductor insulator transition of disordered 2D superconductor system is
observed in the nanoflakes.The results show that the existence of certain
optimum degree of disorder is a necessary condition for emergence of
superconductivity.Temperature dependence of magneto-resistance shows a
consecutive transformation of weak antilocalization cusp into the
superconducting transition at low field when $B &lt; BC$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05340</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05340</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Nazarenko</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kulinich</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic Kinematics of Two-Parametric Riemann Surface in Genus Two</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Hadronic J. 39 (2), 2016</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is considered a model of compact Riemann surface in genus two, represented
geometrically by two-parametric hyperbolic octagon with an order four
automorphism and described algebraically by the corresponding Fuchsian group.
Introducing the Fenchel--Nielsen variables, we compute the Weil--Petersson (WP)
symplectic two-form for parameter space and analyze the closed isoperimetric
orbits of octagons. WP-Area in parameter space and the canonical action--angle
variables for the orbits are found. Exploiting the ideas from the loop quantum
gravity, we generate relativistic kinematics by the Lorentz boost and quantize
WP-area. We treat the evolution in terms of global variables within the &quot;big
bounce&quot; concept.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05349</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05349</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Adamashvili</keyname><forenames>Guram</forenames></author></authors><title>Vector soliton of the Love wave in ZnO/LiNbO_{3} structure</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theory of an acoustic vector soliton of the Love wave is constructed. The
nonlinear Love wave propagating along the interface between of a plane surface
layer and the elastic semi-space under the condition of acoustic self-induced
transparency is investigated. A thin resonance transition layer containing
paramagnetic impurity atoms or semiconductor quantum dots sandwiched between
these two connected media. Explicit analytical expressions for the profile and
parameters of the Love vector soliton are obtained. It is shown that the
properties of the nonlinear Love wave depends on the parameters of the
transition resonance layer, the connected elastic media and the transverse
structure of the Love mode. Numerical investigations of the Love vector soliton
is executed for the parameters of the layered structure ZnO/LiNbO_{3} and
surface acoustic waves which can be reached in current experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05357</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Kristy A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Directed Channel Memristor for High Temperature Operation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ion-conducting memristors comprised of the layered chalcogenide materials
Ge2Se3/SnSe/Ag are described. The memristor, termed a self-directed channel
(SDC) device, can be classified as a generic memristor and can tolerate
continuous high temperature operation (at least 150 {\deg}C). Unlike other
chalcogenide-based ion conducting device types, the SDC does not require
complicated fabrication steps, such as photodoping or thermal annealing, making
these devices faster and more reliable to fabricate. Device pulsed response
shows fast state switching in the 10E-9 s range. Device cycling at both room
temperature and 140 {\deg}C show cycling lifetimes of at least 1 billion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05376</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05376</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Ablinger</keyname><forenames>Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behring</keyname><forenames>Arnd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bluemlein</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Freitas</keyname><forenames>Abilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Algorithms to solve coupled systems of differential equations in terms
  of power series</title><categories>cs.SC hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><report-no>DESY 16-160, DO-TH 16--19</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using integration by parts relations, Feynman integrals can be represented in
terms of coupled systems of differential equations. In the following we suppose
that the unknown Feynman integrals can be given in power series
representations, and that sufficiently many initial values of the integrals are
given. Then there exist algorithms that decide constructively if the
coefficients of their power series representations can be given within the
class of nested sums over hypergeometric products. In this article we will work
out the calculation steps that solve this problem. First, we will present a
successful tactic that has been applied recently to challenging problems coming
from massive 3-loop Feynman integrals. Here our main tool is to solve scalar
linear recurrences within the class of nested sums over hypergeometric
products. Second, we will present a new variation of this tactic which relies
on more involved summation technologies but succeeds in reducing the problem to
solve scalar recurrences with lower recurrence orders. The article will work
out the different challenges of this new tactic and demonstrates how they can
be treated efficiently with our existing summation technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05386</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Siddiqui</keyname><forenames>Rehan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jagpal</keyname><forenames>Rajinder</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salem</keyname><forenames>Naif Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quine</keyname><forenames>Brendan M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Short Wave upwelling Radiative Flux (SWupRF) within NIR range for the
  selected greenhouse wavelength bands of O2, H2O, CO2 and CH4 by Argus 1000
  along with GENSPECT line by line radiative transfer model</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>33 pages, 23 figures, 5 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This new study develops an algorithm for Short Wave upwelling Radiative Flux
(SWupRF) for the spectral variations within near infrared (NIR) from 1100 to
1700 nm wavelength band based on remote sensing data set of Argus 1000
micro-spectrometer observations. We calculate the SWupRF by investigating the
total radiative flux due to O2, H2O, CO2 and CH4 and also by the individual gas
within the selected wavelength bands of interest. A GENSPECT synthetic line by
line radiative transfer model is applied to perform radiative transfer
simulations to calculate the radiative flux by varying surface albedo, mixing
ratios of the selected greenhouse gases, surface temperature, solar sun and
zenith angles with different latitude and longitude of the instrument. Finally,
the SWupRFsyn estimated from GENSPECT was compared with SWupRFobs from Argus
1000 over a period of four years (2009 and 2013) covering all seasons. We
calculate and compare both the synthetic and real measured observed data set.
The synthetic model gives SWupRFsyn within the range of [0.3950 to 1.650] W/m2
and the selected Argus observed model gives SWupRFobs within the range of [0.10
to 3.15] W/m2. The simulated range of synthetic model also represents 1 to 32 K
rise of temperature within the different concentration of water vapor and other
gases. The authors determined that the satellite observed data of week 75 pass
43 &amp; week 08 pass 61 showing minimum 0.850 [0.10 to 1.60] W/m2 and maximum 1.65
[0.12 to 3.15] W/m2 respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05387</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Sisakht</keyname><forenames>E. Taghizadeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fazileh</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zare</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zarenia</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peeters</keyname><forenames>F. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain-induced topological phase transition in phosphorene and
  phosphorene nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 085417 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.085417</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the tight-binding (TB) approximation with inclusion of the spin-orbit
interaction, we predict a topological phase transition in the electronic band
structure of phosphorene in the presence of axial strains. We derive a
low-energy TB Hamiltonian that includes the spin-orbit interaction for bulk
phosphorene. Applying a compressive biaxial in-plane strain and perpendicular
tensile strain in ranges where the structure is still stable leads to a
topological phase transition. We also examine the influence of strain on zigzag
phosphorene nanoribbons (zPNRs) and the formation of the corresponding
protected edge states when the system is in the topological phase. For zPNRs up
to a width of 100 nm the energy gap is at least three orders of magnitude
larger than the thermal energy at room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05388</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Alisultanov</keyname><forenames>Z. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reis</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Graphene infrared light emitting diode (GILED)</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>3 pgs, 1 figure with 3 sub-figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present Letter proposes a device based on graphene for infrared light
emission. It is based on a n- and p-doped monolayer graphene (MGs), with Fermi
energies $E_F$ and -$E_F$, respectively, sandwiching a bilayer graphene (BG)
with bandgap $\Lambda=2|eV_g-\Delta|\geq 2E_F$, where $V_g$ is the gate voltage
across the BG and $\Delta$ the sub-lattice energy difference into each layer of
the BG. This device works as simple as tuning the gate voltage to decrease the
BG bandgap down to $2E_F$; and, once this condition is fulfilled, a current
flows from the n-doped MG to the p-doped MG. However, when electrons achieve
the other side of the device, i.e., into the p-doped MG, their energies ($E_F$)
are much bigger than the holes energies ($-E_F$), and thus these electrons
decay emitting infrared photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05403</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Richard I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of Cycle-to-cycle Modulated Spectral Line Variability and
  Velocity Gradients in Long-period Cepheids</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>17 pages, 14 figures, 4 tables, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work reports the discovery of cycle-to-cycle modulated spectral line and
atmospheric velocity gradient variability in long-period Cepheids based on 925
high-resolution optical spectra of $\ell$ Carinae (P $\sim$ 35.5 d) recorded
during three heavy duty-cycle monitoring campaigns (in 2014, 2015, and 2016).
Spectral line variability is investigated via cross-correlation functions
(CCFs) computed using three sets of spectral lines (weak, solar, strong). A
metallic line velocity gradient, {\delta}v$_r$ (t), is computed as the
difference between weak and strong-line RVs. CCF shape indicators BIS
(asymmetry), FWHM, and depth all exhibit clear phase-dependent variability
patterns that differ from one pulsation cycle to the next. Weak-line CCFs
exhibit these effects more clearly than strong-line CCFs. BIS exhibits the most
peculiar modulated variability and can be used to identify the presence of
cycle-to-cycle modulated line profile variations. {\delta}v$_r$ (t) clearly
exhibits cycle-to-cycle differences that correlate very closely with modulated
BIS variability, suggesting perturbations of the atmospheric velocity field as
the cause for modulated spectral line variability. These perturbations are most
significant during contraction and are not in phase with the pulsation,
transmitting information between consecutive pulsation cycles. This work shows
RV curve modulation to be a consequence of atmospheric velocity gradient
perturbations. Possible origins of these perturbations and their impact on
Cepheid RV measurements as well as the projection factor used in
Baade-Wesselink-type distance determinations are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0208081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0208081</id><created>2002-08-05</created><updated>2002-08-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bauke</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertens</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engel</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transition in Multiprocessor Scheduling</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, revtex4</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters, vol. 90, 158701 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.90.158701</doi><abstract>  The problem of distributing the workload on a parallel computer to minimize
the overall runtime is known as Multiprocessor Scheduling Problem. It is
NP-hard, but like many other NP-hard problems, the average hardness of random
instances displays an ``easy-hard'' phase transition. The transition in
Multiprocessor Scheduling can be analyzed using elementary notions from
crystallography (Bravais lattices) and statistical mechanics (Potts vectors).
The analysis reveals the control parameter of the transition and its critical
value including finite size corrections. The transition is identified in the
performance of practical scheduling algorithms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0402010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0402010</id><created>2004-01-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Bauke</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Franz</keyname><forenames>Silvio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mertens</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Number partitioning as random energy model</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8+2 pages, 9 figures, PDF only</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment, vol.
  2004, P04003, (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2004/04/P04003</doi><abstract>  Number partitioning is a classical problem from combinatorial optimisation.
In physical terms it corresponds to a long range anti-ferromagnetic Ising spin
glass. It has been rigorously proven that the low lying energies of number
partitioning behave like uncorrelated random variables. We claim that
neighbouring energy levels are uncorrelated almost everywhere on the energy
axis, and that energetically adjacent configurations are uncorrelated, too.
Apparently there is no relation between geometry (configuration) and energy
that could be exploited by an optimization algorithm. This ``local random
energy'' picture of number partitioning is corroborated by numerical
simulations and heuristic arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0105057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-19</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0105057</id><created>2001-05-11</created><updated>2016-08-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rigolin</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement, identical particles and the uncertainty principle</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, no figure; v2: title, abstract, and focus slightly changed;
  a couple of sections rewritten and a new one added; published version</comments><journal-ref>Commun. Theor. Phys. 66, 201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0253-6102/66/2/201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new uncertainty relation (UR) is obtained for a system of N identical pure
entangled particles if we use symmetrized observables when deriving the
inequality. This new expression can be written in a form where we identify a
term which explicitly shows the quantum correlations among the particles that
constitute the system. For the particular cases of two and three particles,
making use of the Schwarz inequality, we obtain new lower bounds for the UR
that are different from the standard one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
