<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:06:25Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-29" from="2016-08-29" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0705.3368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0705.3368</id><created>2007-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Shirokov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>A classification of Lie algebras of pseudounitary groups in the
  techniques of Clifford algebras</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><journal-ref>AACA, 20:2, 2010, 411-425</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00006-009-0177-0</doi><abstract>  In this paper we present new formulas, which represent commutators and
anticommutators of Clifford algebra elements as sums of elements of different
ranks. Using these formulas we consider subalgebras of Lie algebras of
pseudounitary groups. Our main techniques are Clifford algebras. We have find
12 types of subalgebras of Lie algebras of pseudounitary groups.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0708.1754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0708.1754</id><created>2007-08-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>De-sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>An-an</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hong-fei</forenames></author></authors><title>Treatment of Linear and Nonlinear Dielectric Property of Molecular
  Monolayer and Submonolayer with Microscopic Dipole Lattice Model: I. Second
  Harmonic Generation and Sum-Frequency Generation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>23 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>International Reviews in Physical Chemistry,27, 629-664, 2008</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/01442350802343981</doi><abstract>  In the currently accepted models of the nonlinear optics, the nonlinear
radiation was treated as the result of an infinitesimally thin polarization
sheet layer, and a three layer model was generally employed. The direct
consequence of this approach is that an apriori dielectric constant, which
still does not have a clear definition, has to be assigned to this polarization
layer. Because the Second Harmonic Generation (SHG) and the Sum-Frequency
Generation vibrational Spectroscopy (SFG-VS) have been proven as the sensitive
probes for interfaces with the submonolayer coverage, the treatment based on
the more realistic discrete induced dipole model needs to be developed. Here we
show that following the molecular optics theory approach the SHG, as well as
the SFG-VS, radiation from the monolayer or submonolayer at an interface can be
rigorously treated as the radiation from an induced dipole lattice at the
interface. In this approach, the introduction of the polarization sheet is no
longer necessary. Therefore, the ambiguity of the unaccounted dielectric
constant of the polarization layer is no longer an issue. Moreover, the
anisotropic two dimensional microscopic local field factors can be explicitly
expressed with the linear polarizability tensors of the interfacial molecules.
Based on the planewise dipole sum rule in the molecular monolayer, crucial
experimental tests of this microscopic treatment with SHG and SFG-VS are
discussed. Many puzzles in the literature of surface SHG and SFG spectroscopy
studies can also be understood or resolved in this framework. This new
treatment may provide a solid basis for the quantitative analysis in the
surface SHG and SFG studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0801.4080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0801.4080</id><created>2008-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent developments in heterotic compactifications</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages, LaTeX, 2 figures. Contribution to the proceedings of the
  Virginia Tech Sowers workshop, May 2007</comments><report-no>VPI-IPNAS-08-02</report-no><journal-ref>AMS/IP Stud.Adv.Math. 44 (2008) 209-230</journal-ref><abstract>  In this short review, we outline three sets of developments in understanding
heterotic string compactifications. First, we outline recent progress in
heterotic analogues of quantum cohomology computations. Second, we discuss a
potential swampland issue in heterotic strings, and new heterotic string
constructions that can be used to fill in the naively missing theories. Third,
we discuss recent developments in string compactifications on stacks and their
applications, concluding with an outline of work-in-progress on heterotic
string compactifications on gerbes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0806.1165</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0806.1165</id><created>2008-06-06</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bendaniel</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of Einstein-Weyl Causality on Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Originally Presented at the 16th UK and European Meeting on the
  Foundations of Physics. Present Version has considerable discussion of the
  implications of Einstein-Weyl causality on quantum mechanics, presented at
  the Vaxjo(2016) conference</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fundamental physical principle that has consequences for the topology of
space-time is the principle of Einstein-Weyl causality. We show here that this
may have implications on quantum mechanics, as well. Borchers and Sen have
rigorously investigated the mathematical implications of Einstein-Weyl
causality and shown the denumerable space-time Q^2 would be implied. They then
imbedded this space in a non-denumerable space but were left with important
philosophical paradoxes regarding the nature of the physical real line E, e.g.,
whether E = R, the real line of mathematics. Alternatively, their initial
result could suggest a constructible foundation. We have pursued such a program
and find it indeed provides a dense, denumerable space-time and, moreover, an
interesting connection with quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0812.2630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0812.2630</id><created>2008-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Hong-tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Ran-ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hong-fei</forenames></author></authors><title>Specific Na+ and K+ Cation Effects on the Interfacial Water Molecules at
  the Air/Aqueous Salt Solution Interfaces Probed with Non-resonant Second
  Harmonic Generation (SHG)</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>33 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem Phys, 130, 134709, ?2009?</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.3104609</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we report the polarization dependent non-resonant second harmonic
generation (SHG) measurement of the interfacial water molecules at the aqueous
solution of the following salts: NaF, NaCl, NaBr, KF, KCl, and KBr. Through
quantitative polarization analysis of the SHG data,the orientational parameter
D value and the relative surface density of the interfacial water molecules at
these aqueous solution surfaces were determined. From these results we found
that addition of each of the six salts caused increase of the thickness of the
interfacial water layer at the surfaces to a certain extent. Noticeably, both
the cations and the anions contributed to the changes, and the abilities to
increase the thickness of the interfacial water layer were in the following
order: KBr &gt; NaBr &gt; KCl &gt; NaCl ~ NaF &gt; KF. Since these changes can not be
factorized into individual anion and cation contributions, there are possible
ion pairing or association effects, especially for the NaF case. We also found
that the orientational parameter D values of the interfacial water molecules
changed to opposite directions for the aqueous solutions of the three sodium
salts versus the aqueous solutions of the three potassium salts. These findings
clearly indicated unexpected specific Na+ and K+ cation effects at the aqueous
solution surface. These effects were not anticipated from the recent molecular
dynamics (MD) simulation results, which concluded that the Na+ and K+ cations
can be treated as small non-polarizable hard ions and they are repelled from
the aqueous interfaces. These results suggest that the electrolyte aqueous
solution surfaces are more complex than the currently prevalent theoretical and
experimental understandings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0812.2632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0812.2632</id><created>2008-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Ran-ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>Hong-tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang*</keyname><forenames>Hong-fei</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic Evidence for the Specific Na+ and K+ Interactions with the
  Hydrogen-bonded Water Molecules at the Electrolyte Aqueous Solution Surfaces</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>15 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem Phys, 130, 134710,? 2009?</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.3104610</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sum frequency generation vibrational spectra of the water molecules at the
NaF and KF aqueous solution surfaces showed significantly different spectral
features and different concentration dependence. This result is the first
direct observation of the cation effects of the simple alkali cations, which
have been believed to be depleted from the aqueous surface, on the hydrogen
bonding structure of the water molecules at the electrolyte solution surfaces.
These observations may provide important clue to understand the fundamental
phenomenon of ions at the air/water interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1108.5447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1108.5447</id><created>2011-08-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Shirokov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Concepts of trace, determinant and inverse of Clifford algebra elements</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><msc-class>15A66</msc-class><journal-ref>Progress in analysis. Proceedings of the 8th congress ISAAC,
  Volume 1 (ISBN 978-5-209-04582-3/hbk). 187-194 (2012)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our paper we consider the notion of determinant of Clifford algebra
elements. We present some new formulas for determinant of Clifford algebra
elements for the cases of dimension 4 and 5. Also we consider the notion of
trace of Clifford algebra elements. We use the generalization of the Pauli's
theorem for 2 sets of elements that satisfy the main anticommutation conditions
of Clifford algebra.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.5242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.5242</id><created>2013-07-19</created><updated>2013-08-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verch</keyname><forenames>Rainer</forenames></author></authors><title>The Necessity of the Hadamard Condition</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2 24pp typos fixed, references added</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 30 (2013) 235027</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/30/23/235027</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hadamard states are generally considered as the physical states for linear
quantized fields on curved spacetimes, for several good reasons. Here, we
provide a new motivation for the Hadamard condition: for &quot;ultrastatic slab
spacetimes&quot; with compact Cauchy surface, we show that the Wick squares of all
time derivatives of the quantized Klein-Gordon field have finite fluctuations
only if the Wick-ordering is defined with respect to a Hadamard state. This
provides a converse to an important result of Brunetti and Fredenhagen. The
recently proposed &quot;S-J (Sorkin-Johnston) states&quot; are shown, generically, to
give infinite fluctuations for the Wick square of the time derivative of the
field, further limiting their utility as reasonable states. Motivated by the
S-J construction, we also study the general question of extending states that
are pure (or given by density matrices relative to a pure state) on a
double-cone region of Minkowski space. We prove a result for general quantum
field theories showing that such states cannot be extended to any larger
double-cone without encountering singular behaviour at the spacelike boundary
of the inner region. In the context of the Klein-Gordon field this shows that
even if an S-J state is Hadamard within the double cone, this must fail at the
boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.4184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.4184</id><created>2014-01-16</created><updated>2014-02-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xiong</keyname><forenames>Chi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pernice</keyname><forenames>Wolfram H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ngai</keyname><forenames>Joseph H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiner</keyname><forenames>James W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumah</keyname><forenames>Divine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Frederick J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Charles H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Hong X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Active silicon integrated nanophotonics: ferroelectric BaTiO3 devices</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett., 2014, 14 (3), pp 1419-1425</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/nl404513p</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The integration of complex oxides on silicon presents opportunities to extend
and enhance silicon technology with novel electronic, magnetic, and photonic
properties. Among these materials, barium titanate (BaTiO3) is a particularly
strong ferroelectric perovskite oxide with attractive dielectric and
electro-optic properties. Here we demonstrate nanophotonic circuits
incorporating ferroelectric BaTiO3 thin films on the ubiquitous
silicon-on-insulator (SOI) platform. We grow epitaxial, single-crystalline
BaTiO3 directly on SOI and engineer integrated waveguide structures that
simultaneously confine light and an RF electric field in the BaTiO3 layer.
Using on-chip photonic interferometers, we extract a large effective Pockels
coefficient of 213 plus minus 49 pm/V, a value more than six times larger than
found in commercial optical modulators based on lithium niobate. The
monolithically integrated BaTiO3 optical modulators show modulation bandwidth
in the gigahertz regime, which is promising for broadband applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.3544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.3544</id><created>2014-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liberati</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum fields in curved space-time, semiclassical gravity, quantum
  gravity phenomenology, and analogue models: Report on session D4 at GR20</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15pp. To appear in the GR20 Proceedings issue of General Relativity
  and Gravitation</comments><journal-ref>Gen Relativ Gravit (2014) 46: 1707</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-014-1707-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The talks given in parallel session D4 at the 20th International Conference
on General Relativity and Gravitation (Warsaw 2013) are summarized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.7083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.7083</id><created>2014-03-27</created><updated>2014-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical locality of the free Maxwell field</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27pp v3: Some comments added; minor corrections and typos fixed</comments><journal-ref>Annales Henri Poincar\'e 17 (2016) 401-436</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00023-015-0398-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the non-interacting source-free Maxwell field, described both in
terms of the vector potential and the field strength. Starting from the
classical field theory on contractible globally hyperbolic spacetimes, we
extend the classical field theory to general globally hyperbolic spacetimes in
two ways to obtain a &quot;universal&quot; theory and a &quot;reduced&quot; theory. The quantum
field theory in terms of the unital $*$-algebra of the smeared quantum field is
then obtained by an application of a suitable quantisation functor. We show
that the universal theories fail local covariance and dynamical locality owing
to the possibility of having non-trivial radicals in the classical and
non-trivial centres in the quantum case. The reduced theories are both locally
covariant and dynamically local. These models provide new examples relevant to
the discussion of how theories should be formulated so as to describe the same
physics in all spacetimes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1754</id><created>2014-04-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Hekmati</keyname><forenames>Pedram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mickelsson</keyname><forenames>Jouko</forenames></author></authors><title>Projective Families of Dirac operators on a Banach Lie Groupoid</title><categories>math.KT math-ph math.MP math.RT</categories><comments>22 pages</comments><msc-class>81R10, 19L50, 22A22, 22E65</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Noncommutative Geometry, 10 (2016) 1-23</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a Banach Lie group $G$ of unitary operators subject to a natural
trace condition. We compute the homotopy groups of $G$, describe its cohomology
and construct an $S^1$-central extension. We show that the central extension
determines a non-trivial gerbe on the action Lie groupoid $G\ltimes
\mathfrak{k}$, where $\mathfrak{k}$ denotes the Hilbert space of self-adjoint
Hilbert-Schmidt operators. With an eye towards constructing elements in twisted
K-theory, we prove the existence of a cubic Dirac operator $\mathbb{D}$ in a
suitable completion of the quantum Weil algebra $\mathcal{U}(\mathfrak{g})
\otimes Cl(\mathfrak{k})$, which is subsequently extended to a projective
family of self-adjoint operators $\mathbb{D}_A$ on $G\ltimes \frak{k}$. While
the kernel of $\mathbb{D}_A$ is infinite-dimensional, we show that there is
still a notion of finite reducibility at every point, which suggests a
generalized definition of twisted K-theory for action Lie groupoids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.1696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.1696</id><created>2014-05-07</created><updated>2015-02-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Prasun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chengalur</keyname><forenames>Jayaram N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goss</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arjunwadkar</keyname><forenames>Mihir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minter</keyname><forenames>Anthony H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brogan</keyname><forenames>Crystal L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazio</keyname><forenames>T. J. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>The structure function of Galactic \HI opacity fluctuations on AU scales
  based on MERLIN, VLA and VLBA data</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 Figures, 1 table. Accepted for publication in Monthly notices of
  royal astronomical society</comments><journal-ref>2014, MNRAS, 442, 647</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stu881</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use MERLIN, VLA and VLBA observations of Galactic \HI absorption towards
3C~138 to estimate the structure function of the \HI opacity fluctuations at AU
scales. Using Monte Carlo simulations, we show that there is likely to be a
significant bias in the estimated structure function at signal-to-noise ratios
characteristic of our observations, if the structure function is constructed in
the manner most commonly used in the literature. We develop a new estimator
that is free from this bias and use it to estimate the true underlying
structure function slope on length scales ranging $5$ to $40$~AU. From a power
law fit to the structure function, we derive a slope of $0.81^{+0.14}_{-0.13}$,
i.e. similar to the value observed at parsec scales. The estimated upper limit
for the amplitude of the structure function is also consistent with the
measurements carried out at parsec scales. Our measurements are hence
consistent with the \HI opacity fluctuation in the Galaxy being characterized
by a power law structure function over length scales that span six orders of
magnitude. This result implies that the dissipation scale has to be smaller
than a few AU if the fluctuations are produced by turbulence. This inferred
smaller dissipation scale implies that the dissipation occurs either in (i)
regions with densities $\gtrsim 10^3 $cm$^-3$ (i.e. similar to that inferred
for &quot;tiny scale&quot; atomic clouds or (ii) regions with a mix of ionized and atomic
gas (i.e. the observed structure in the atomic gas has a magneto-hydrodynamic
origin).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.6589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.6589</id><created>2014-07-24</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Haver</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Augustus J. E. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Truncation strategy for the series expressions in the advanced
  ENZ-theory of diffraction integrals</title><categories>physics.comp-ph math-ph math.MP physics.optics</categories><comments>67 pages, 20 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The advanced ENZ-theory of diffraction integrals, as published recently in J.
Europ. Opt. Soc. Rap. Public. 8, 13044 (2013), presents the diffraction
integrals per Zernike term in the form of doubly infinite series. These double
series involve, aside from an overall azimuthal factor, the products of Jinc
functions for the radial dependence and structural quantities $c_t$ that depend
on the optical parameters of the optical system (such as NA and refractive
indices) and the defocus value. The products in the double series have
coefficients that are related to Clebsch-Gordan coefficients and that depend on
the order of the Jinc function and the index $t$ of the structural quantity, as
well as on the azimuthal order and degree of the involved Zernike term. In
addition, the structural quantities themselves are also given in the form of
doubly infinite series. In this paper, we give truncation rules for the various
infinite series depending on specified required accuracy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.1645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.1645</id><created>2014-08-07</created><updated>2014-09-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Pure quasifree states of the Dirac field from the fermionic projector</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2 26pp. New results added concerning fluctuations of Wick
  polynomials</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 32 (2015) 095001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/32/9/095001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the quantised free Dirac field on oriented and globally
hyperbolic ultrastatic slab spacetimes with compact spatial section and
demonstrate how a gauge invariant, pure and quasifree state on the
C*-completion of the self-dual CAR-algebra can be extracted from the fermionic
projector construction of Finster and Reintjes. This state is analogous to the
&quot;SJ-state&quot; of the free scalar field recently discussed in the literature. We
prove that this state generically fails to be Hadamard. However, we also show
how a modified version of the construction, inspired by work of Brum and
Fredenhagen, yields states which are Hadamard. We also relate the Hadamard
condition to the finiteness of fluctuations of Wick polynomials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2449</id><created>2014-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Shirokov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of elements of spin groups using generalized Pauli's theorem</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Advances in Applied Clifford Algebras, 2014 (to appear)</comments><msc-class>15A66</msc-class><journal-ref>AACA, 52:1, 2015, 227-244</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00006-014-0471-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We formulate generalizations of Pauli's theorem on the cases of real and
complex Clifford algebras of even and odd dimensions. We give analogues of
these theorems in matrix formalism. Using these theorems we present an
algorithm for computing elements of spin groups that correspond to elements of
orthogonal groups as double cover.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2452</id><created>2014-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Shirokov</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Symplectic, orthogonal and linear Lie groups in Clifford algebra</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>15A66</msc-class><journal-ref>AACA, 25:3, 2015, 707-718</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00006-014-0520-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we prove isomorphisms between 5 Lie groups (of arbitrary
dimension and fixed signatures) in Clifford algebra and classical matrix Lie
groups - symplectic, orthogonal and linear groups. Also we obtain isomorphisms
of corresponding Lie algebras.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1415</id><created>2014-10-06</created><updated>2015-03-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Elgindi</keyname><forenames>Tarek M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Widmayer</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Sharp decay estimates for an anisotropic linear semigroup and
  applications to the SQG and inviscid Boussinesq systems</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages; revised proof of Proposition 2.1, corrected typos</comments><journal-ref>SIAM J. Math. Anal. (2015), 47 (6), 4672-4684</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/14099036X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At the core of this article is an improved, sharp dispersive estimate for the
anisotropic linear semigroup $e^{R_1 t}$ arising in both the study of the
dispersive SQG equation and the inviscid Boussinesq system. We combine the
decay estimate with a blow-up criterion to show how dispersion leads to
long-time existence of solutions to the dispersive SQG equation, improving the
results obtained using hyperbolic methods. In the setting of the inviscid
Boussinesq system it turns out that linearization around a specific stationary
solution leads to the same linear semigroup, so that we can make use of
analogous techniques to obtain stability of the stationary solution for an
increased timespan.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4750</id><created>2014-12-15</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nagy</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral Squaring</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure , references added, updated to match version in
  JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1607 (2016) 142</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct the states and symmetries of N = 4 super-Yang-Mills by tensoring
two N = 1 chiral multiplets and introducing two extra SUSY generators. This
allows us to write the maximal N = 8 supergravity as four copies of the chiral
multiplet. We extend this to higher dimensions and discuss applications to
scattering amplitudes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.00799</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.00799</id><created>2015-01-05</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Daniel B.</forenames><affiliation>University of Cyprus, ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bruni</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wands</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>ICG Portsmouth</affiliation></author></authors><title>The fully non-linear post-Friedmann frame-dragging vector potential:
  Magnitude and time evolution from N-body simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>Matches version published in MNRAS; substantially reduced number of
  figures compared to v1. Supplementary figures available at MNRAS website or
  in v1. Detailed follow up to http://arxiv.org/abs/1306.1562</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1390</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Newtonian simulations are routinely used to examine the matter dynamics on
non-linear scales. However, even on these scales, Newtonian gravity is not a
complete description of gravitational effects. A post-Friedmann approach shows
that the leading order correction to Newtonian theory is a vector potential in
the metric. This vector potential can be calculated from N-body simulations,
requiring a method for extracting the velocity field. Here, we present the full
details of our calculation of the post-Friedmann vector potential, using the
Delauney Tesselation Field Estimator (DTFE) code. We include a detailed
examination of the robustness of our numerical result, including the effects of
box size and mass resolution on the extracted fields. We present the power
spectrum of the vector potential and find that the power spectrum of the vector
potential is $\sim 10^5$ times smaller than the power spectrum of the fully
non-linear scalar gravitational potential at redshift zero. Comparing our
numerical results to perturbative estimates, we find that the fully non-linear
result can be more than an order of magnitude larger than the perturbative
estimate on small scales. We extend the analysis of the vector potential to
multiple redshifts, showing that this ratio persists over a range of scales and
redshifts. We also comment on the implications of our results for the validity
and interpretation of Newtonian simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02682</id><created>2015-01-12</created><updated>2015-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The split property for locally covariant quantum field theories in
  curved spacetime</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v3 27pp. Some typos and errors fixed. Version published in Lett Math
  Phys</comments><journal-ref>Letters in Mathematical Physics 105 (2015) 1633-1661</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11005-015-0798-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The split property expresses the way in which local regions of spacetime
define subsystems of a quantum field theory. It is known to hold for general
theories in Minkowski space under the hypothesis of nuclearity. Here, the split
property is discussed for general locally covariant quantum field theories in
arbitrary globally hyperbolic curved spacetimes, using a spacetime deformation
argument to transport the split property from one spacetime to another. It is
also shown how states obeying both the split and (partial) Reeh-Schlieder
properties can be constructed, providing standard split inclusions of certain
local von Neumann algebras. Sufficient conditions are given for the theory to
admit such states in ultrastatic spacetimes, from which the general case
follows. A number of consequences are described, including the existence of
local generators for global gauge transformations, and the classification of
certain local von Neumann algebras. Similar arguments are applied to the distal
split property and circumstances are exhibited under which distal splitting
implies the full split property.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.01022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.01022</id><created>2015-02-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiphase turbulent interstellar medium: some recent results from radio
  astronomy</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures. Invited review accepted for publication in the
  Proceedings of the Indian National Science Academy. The definitive version
  will be available at http://insaindia.org/journals/proceedings.php</comments><journal-ref>2015, Proc. of the Indian National Science Academy, 81, 583</journal-ref><doi>10.16943/ptinsa/2015/v81i3/48224</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radio frequency 1.4 GHz transition of the atomic hydrogen is one of the
important tracers of the diffuse neutral interstellar medium. Radio
astronomical observations of this transition, using either a single dish
telescope or an array interferometer, reveal different properties of the
interstellar medium. Such observations are particularly useful to study the
multiphase nature and turbulence in the interstellar gas. Observations with
multiple radio telescopes have recently been used to study these two closely
related aspects in greater detail. Using various observational techniques, the
density and the velocity fluctuations in the Galactic interstellar medium was
found to have a Kolmogorov-like power law power spectra. The observed power law
scaling of the turbulent velocity dispersion with the length scale can be used
to derive the true temperature distribution of the medium. Observations from a
large ongoing atomic hydrogen absorption line survey have also been used to
study the distribution of gas at different temperature. The thermal steady
state model predicts that the multiphase neutral gas will exist in cold and
warm phase with temperature below 200 K and above 5000 K respectively. However,
these observations clearly show the presence of a large fraction of gas in the
intermediate unstable phase. These results raise serious doubt about the
validity of the standard model, and highlight the necessity of alternative
theoretical models. Interestingly, numerical simulations suggest that some of
the observational results can be explained consistently by including the
effects of turbulence in the models of the multiphase medium. This review
article presents a brief outline of some of the basic ideas of radio
astronomical observations and data analysis, summarizes the results from recent
observations, and discusses possible implications of the results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.04642</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.04642</id><created>2015-02-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Fewster</keyname><forenames>Christopher J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Locally covariant quantum field theory and the problem of formulating
  the same physics in all spacetimes</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21pp. To appear in the themed issue &quot;New Geometric Concepts in the
  Foundations of Physics&quot; of Philosophical Transactions A of the Royal Society</comments><journal-ref>Phil. Trans. A Roy. Soc. 373:20140238 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsta.2014.0238</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The framework of locally covariant quantum field theory is discussed,
motivated in part using &quot;ignorance principles&quot;. It is shown how theories can be
represented by suitable functors, so that physical equivalence of theories may
be expressed via natural isomorphisms between the corresponding functors. The
inhomogeneous scalar field is used to illustrate the ideas. It is argued that
there are two reasonable definitions of the local physical content associated
with a locally covariant theory; when these coincide, the theory is said to be
dynamically local. The status of the dynamical locality condition is reviewed,
as are its applications in relation to (a) the foundational question of what it
means for a theory to represent the same physics in different spacetimes, and
(b) a no-go result on the existence of natural states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00126</id><created>2015-02-28</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Bao-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yu-Xiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-Dependent Scalar Fields in Modified Gravities in a Stationary
  Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J. C 76 (2016) 377</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4225-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most no-hair theorems involve the assumption that the scalar field is
independent of time. Recently in [Phys. Rev. D90 (2014) 041501(R)] the
existence of time-dependent scalar hair outside a stationary black hole in
general relativity was ruled out. We generalize this work to modified gravities
and non-minimally coupled scalar field with an additional assumption that the
spacetime is axisymmetric. It is shown that in higher-order gravity such as
metric $f(R)$ gravity the time-dependent scalar hair doesn't exist. While in
Palatini $f(R)$ gravity and non-minimally coupled case the time-dependent
scalar hair may exist.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03124</id><created>2015-04-13</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sarani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light deflection in Kerr field for off-equatorial source</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deflection angle for a light ray travelling in the equatorial plane of a
rotating Kerr mass has been already calculated by various investigators.
Considering the light ray to be travelling only slightly above the equatorial
plane, calculations have been made for such a ray for its deflection angle. In
this paper, we calculate deflection angles for the light ray at various
heights, which are small compared to the impact parameter and derive
corresponding analytical expressions for deflection angle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.03363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.03363</id><created>2015-05-13</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Juan</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina-Terriza</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romero-Isart</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-field Levitated Quantum Optomechanics with Nanodiamonds</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages (including appendix), 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 023841 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.023841</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically show that the dipole force of an ensemble of quantum
emitters embedded in a dielectric nanosphere can be exploited to achieve
near-field optical levitation. The key ingredient is that the polarizability
from the ensemble of embedded quantum emitters can be larger than the bulk
polarizability of the sphere, thereby enabling the use of repulsive optical
potentials and consequently the levitation using optical near-fields. In
levitated cavity quantum optomechanics, this could be used to boost the
single-photon coupling by combining larger polarizability to mass ratio, larger
field gradients, and smaller cavity volumes while remaining in the resolved
sideband regime and at room temperature. A case study is done with a
nanodiamond containing a high-density of silicon-vacancy color centers that is
optically levitated in the evanescent field of a tappered nano-fiber and
coupled to a high-finesse microsphere cavity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07835</id><created>2015-05-28</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goold</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riera</keyname><forenames>Arnau</forenames></author><author><keyname>del Rio</keyname><forenames>L&#xed;dia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skrzypczyk</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of quantum information in thermodynamics --- a topical review</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>published version. 34 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49, 143001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/14/143001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This topical review article gives an overview of the interplay between
quantum information theory and thermodynamics of quantum systems. We focus on
several trending topics including the foundations of statistical mechanics,
resource theories, entanglement in thermodynamic settings, fluctuation theorems
and thermal machines. This is not a comprehensive review of the diverse field
of quantum thermodynamics; rather, it is a convenient entry point for the
thermo-curious information theorist. Furthermore this review should facilitate
the unification and understanding of different interdisciplinary approaches
emerging in research groups around the world.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03970</id><created>2015-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chow</keyname><forenames>Weng W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Straatsma</keyname><forenames>Cameron J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Dana Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Numerical model for atomtronic circuit analysis</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures, accepted for publication in PRA</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A, 92, 013621 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.013621</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model for studying atomtronic devices and circuits based on finite
temperature Bose-condensed gases is presented. The approach involves
numerically solving equations of motion for atomic populations and coherences,
derived using the Bose-Hubbard Hamiltonian and the Heisenberg picture. The
resulting cluster expansion is truncated at a level giving balance between
physics rigor and numerical demand mitigation. This approach allows parametric
studies involving time scales that cover both the rapid population dynamics
relevant to non-equilibrium state evolution, as well as the much longer time
durations typical for reaching steady-state device operation. The model is
demonstrated by studying the evolution of a Bose-condensed gas in the presence
of atom injection and extraction in a double-well potential. In this
configuration phase-locking between condensates in each well of the potential
is readily observed, and its influence on the evolution of the system is
studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08858</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2016-07-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burton</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noble</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walton</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Axionic suppression of plasma wakefield acceleration</title><categories>hep-ph physics.acc-ph physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 385501</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/38/385501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Contemporary attempts to explain the existence of ultra-high energy cosmic
rays using plasma-based wakefield acceleration deliberately avoid non-Standard
Model particle physics. However, such proposals exploit some of the most
extreme environments in the Universe and it is conceivable that hypothetical
particles outside the Standard Model have significant implications for the
effectiveness of the acceleration process. Axions solve the strong CP problem
and provide one of the most important candidates for Cold Dark Matter, and
their potential significance in the present context should not be overlooked.
Our analysis of the field equations describing a plasma augmented with axions
uncovers a dramatic axion-induced suppression of the energy gained by a test
particle in the wakefield driven by a particle bunch, or an intense pulse of
electromagnetic radiation, propagating at ultra-relativistic speeds within the
strongest magnetic fields in the Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04219</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04219</id><created>2015-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Krefl</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Mellin-Barnes Representation of the Topological String</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><report-no>SNUTP15-006</report-no><doi>10.1007/s11005-016-0882-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We invoke integrals of Mellin-Barnes type to analytically continue the
Gopakumar-Vafa resummation of the topological string free energy in the string
coupling constant, leading to additional non-perturbative terms. We also
discuss in a similar manner the refined and Nekrasov-Shatashvili limit version
thereof. The derivation is straight-forward and essentially boils down to
taking residue. This allows us to confirm some related conjectures in the
literature at tree-level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06135</id><created>2015-09-21</created><updated>2015-10-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bibrzycki</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>Pedagogical University of Cracow</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kaminski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>H. Niewodniczanski Institute of Nuclear Physics PAN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Scalar isovector resonance photoproduction through the final state
  meson-meson interactions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. of Mod. Phys. A 31, 1650139 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501396</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct the amplitudes of $\pi\eta$ photoproduction taking into account
the effects of the $\pi\eta$ - $K\bar K$ interchannel coupling. The idea of our
model is close to the molecular description of scalar resonances with exception
that apart from the pseudoscalar loops we include also vector mesons in the
intermediate state loops. These amplitudes are used to calculate the $S$-wave
cross sections and mass distributions in the $\pi\eta$ effective mass region
corresponding to the scalar resonances $a_0(980)$ and $a_0(1450)$. The values
we obtained for $a_0(980)$ are comparable with predictions of other models
while the cross section for $a_0(1450)$ is about an order of magnitude larger
than prediction based on the quark model. We show that the amplitudes with
loops containing vector mesons calculated in the on-shell approximation are not
suppressed in contrast to amplitudes containing only pseudoscalar loops. We
estimate the cross sections for the $P$- and $D$- waves in the $\pi\eta$
channel.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07276</id><created>2015-09-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Keisuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hirotada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morimae</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamate</keyname><forenames>Shuhei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tani</keyname><forenames>Seiichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Power of Quantum Computation with Few Clean Qubits</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC</categories><comments>44 pages + cover page; the results in Section 8 are overlapping with
  the main results in arXiv:1409.6777</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of 43rd International Colloquium on Automata,
  Languages, and Programming (ICALP 2016), pp. 13:1-13:14</journal-ref><doi>10.4230/LIPIcs.ICALP.2016.13</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper investigates the power of polynomial-time quantum computation in
which only a very limited number of qubits are initially clean in the |0&gt;
state, and all the remaining qubits are initially in the totally mixed state.
No initializations of qubits are allowed during the computation, nor
intermediate measurements. The main results of this paper are unexpectedly
strong error-reducible properties of such quantum computations. It is proved
that any problem solvable by a polynomial-time quantum computation with
one-sided bounded error that uses logarithmically many clean qubits can also be
solvable with exponentially small one-sided error using just two clean qubits,
and with polynomially small one-sided error using just one clean qubit. It is
further proved in the case of two-sided bounded error that any problem solvable
by such a computation with a constant gap between completeness and soundness
using logarithmically many clean qubits can also be solvable with exponentially
small two-sided error using just two clean qubits. If only one clean qubit is
available, the problem is again still solvable with exponentially small error
in one of the completeness and soundness and polynomially small error in the
other. As an immediate consequence of the above result for the two-sided-error
case, it follows that the TRACE ESTIMATION problem defined with fixed constant
threshold parameters is complete for the classes of problems solvable by
polynomial-time quantum computations with completeness 2/3 and soundness 1/3
using logarithmically many clean qubits and just one clean qubit. The
techniques used for proving the error-reduction results may be of independent
interest in themselves, and one of the technical tools can also be used to show
the hardness of weak classical simulations of one-clean-qubit computations
(i.e., DQC1 computations).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01120</id><created>2015-10-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Kantharia</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anupama</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chitale</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishwara-Chandra</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prabhu</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashok</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>D. P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling the synchrotron light curves in recurrent novae V745 Scorpii
  and RS Ophiuchi</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>To appear in Proceedings of the meeting RETCO-II held at ARIES in May
  6-8, 2015</comments><journal-ref>2015, ASI Conference Series, 12, 107</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present the synchrotron light curve at 610 MHz from the
recurrent nova V745 Sco following its outburst on 6 February 2014. The system
has been detected and periodically monitored with the Giant Metrewave Radio
Telescope (GMRT) since 9 February 2014 as part of the Galactic Nova with GMRT
(GNovaG) project. The light curves are well fit by a model of synchrotron
emitting region obscured by foreground thermal gas which eventually becomes
optically thin to the low GMRT frequencies. We present the model fit to the
2014 data on V745 Sco and discuss it alongwith the model fit to the 1.4 GHz
data of the recurrent nova RS Ophiuchi following its outburst in 1985.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01906</id><created>2015-10-07</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Contatto</keyname><forenames>Felipe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunajski</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author></authors><title>First integrals of affine connections and Hamiltonian systems of
  hydrodynamic type</title><categories>math.DG hep-th nlin.SI</categories><comments>11 pages. Final version. The analysis of sufficient conditions
  expanded</comments><report-no>DAMTP-2015-58</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find necessary and sufficient conditions for a local geodesic flow of an
affine connection on a surface to admit a linear first integral. The conditions
are expressed in terms of two scalar invariants of differential orders 3 and 4
in the connection. We use this result to find explicit obstructions to the
existence of a Hamiltonian formulation of Dubrovin--Novikov type for a given
one--dimensional system of hydrodynamic type. We give several examples
including Zoll connections, and Hamiltonian systems arising from
two--dimensional Frobenius manifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02203</id><created>2015-10-08</created><updated>2015-11-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kantharia</keyname><forenames>N. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Prasun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anupama</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishwara-Chandra</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chitale</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prabhu</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>D. P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashok</keyname><forenames>N. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Insights into the evolution of symbiotic recurrent novae from radio
  synchrotron emission: V745 Scorpii and RS Ophiuchi</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Revised, matches version in print</comments><journal-ref>2016, MNRAS, 456, L49</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slv154</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present observations at 610 MHz and 235 MHz using the Giant Metrewave
Radio Telescope (GMRT) of the recurrent nova V745 Scorpii which recorded its
last outburst on 6 February 2014. This is the second symbiotic recurrent nova
whose light curve at low frequencies has been followed in detail, the first
being RS Ophiuchi in 2006. We fitted the 610 MHz light curve by a model of
synchrotron emission from an expanding shell being modified by radiative
transfer effects due to local absorbing gas consisting of a uniformly
distributed and a clumpy component. Using our model parameters, we find that
the emission at 235 MHz peaked around day 35 which is consistent with our GMRT
observations. The two main results of our study are: (1) The radio emission at
a given frequency is visible sooner after the outburst in successive outbursts
of both V745 Scorpii and RS Ophiuchi. The earlier detection of radio emission
is interpreted to be caused by decreasing foreground densities. (2) The clumpy
material, if exists, is close to the white dwarf and can be interpreted as
being due to the material from the hot accretion disk. The uniform density gas
is widespread and attributed to the winds blown by the white dwarf. We present
implications of these results on the evolution of both novae. Such studies
alongwith theoretical understanding have the potential of resolving several
outstanding issues such as why all recurrent novae are not detectable in
synchrotron radio and whether recurrent novae are progenitor systems of type 1a
supernova.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06408</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-07-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>B&#xe1;lint</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gilbert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xe1;ndori</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sz&#xe1;sz</keyname><forenames>Domokos</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf3;th</keyname><forenames>Imre P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author></authors><title>On the limiting Markov process of energy exchanges in a rarely
  interacting ball-piston gas</title><categories>math.DS cond-mat.stat-mech nlin.CD</categories><comments>23 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1598-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the process of energy exchanges generated by the elastic
collisions between a point-particle, confined to a two-dimensional cell with
convex boundaries, and a `piston', i.e. a line-segment, which moves back and
forth along a one-dimensional interval partially intersecting the cell. This
model can be considered as the elementary building block of a spatially
extended high-dimensional billiard modeling heat transport in a class of hybrid
materials exhibiting the kinetics of gases and spatial structure of solids.
Using heuristic arguments and numerical analysis, we argue that, in a regime of
rare interactions, the billiard process converges to a Markov jump process for
the energy exchanges and obtain the expression of its generator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08957</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xiongfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Zhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Bing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum random number generation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information 2, 16021 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/npjqi.2016.21</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum physics can be exploited to generate true random numbers, which play
important roles in many applications, especially in cryptography. Genuine
randomness from the measurement of a quantum system reveals the inherent nature
of quantumness --- coherence, an important feature that differentiates quantum
mechanics from classical physics. The generation of genuine randomness is
generally considered impossible with only classical means. Based on the degree
of trustworthiness on devices, quantum random number generators (QRNGs) can be
grouped into three categories. The first category, practical QRNG, is built on
fully trusted and calibrated devices and typically can generate randomness at a
high speed by properly modeling the devices. The second category is
self-testing QRNG, where verifiable randomness can be generated without
trusting the actual implementation. The third category, semi-self-testing QRNG,
is an intermediate category which provides a tradeoff between the
trustworthiness on the device and the random number generation speed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01540</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gorbushin</keyname><forenames>Nikolai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishuris</keyname><forenames>Gennady</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of dynamic failure of the discrete chain structure with
  non-local interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work the steady-state crack propagation in a chain of
oscillators with non-local interactions is considered. The interactions are
modeled as linear springs while the crack is presented by the absence of extra
springs. The problem is reduced to the Wiener-Hopf type and solution is
presented in terms of inverse Fourier transform. It is shown that the non-local
interactions may change the structure of the problem solution well-known from
the classical local interactions formulation. In particular, it may change the
range of the region of stable crack motion. The conclusions of the analysis are
supported by numerical results. Namely, the observed phenomenon is partially
clarified by evaluation of the structure profiles on the crack line ahead.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07071</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bornmann</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haunschild</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marx</keyname><forenames>Werner</forenames></author></authors><title>Policy documents as sources for measuring societal impact: How often is
  climate change research mentioned in policy-related documents?</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DL</categories><comments>in press at Scientometrics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the current UK Research Excellence Framework (REF) and the Excellence in
Research for Australia (ERA) societal impact measurements are inherent parts of
the national evaluation systems. In this study, we deal with a relatively new
form of societal impact measurements. Recently, Altmetric - a start-up
providing publication level metrics - started to make data for publications
available which have been mentioned in policy documents. We regard this data
source as an interesting possibility to specifically measure the (societal)
impact of research. Using a comprehensive dataset with publications on climate
change as an example, we study the usefulness of the new data source for impact
measurement. Only 1.2% (n=2,341) out of 191,276 publications on climate change
in the dataset have at least one policy mention. We further reveal that papers
published in Nature and Science as well as from the areas &quot;Earth and related
environmental sciences&quot; and &quot;Social and economic geography&quot; are especially
relevant in the policy context. Given the low coverage of the climate change
literature in policy documents, this study can be only a first attempt to study
this new source of altmetric data. Further empirical studies are necessary in
upcoming years, because mentions in policy documents are of special interest in
the use of altmetric data for measuring target-oriented the broader impact of
research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07257</id><created>2015-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Schattner</keyname><forenames>Yoni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerlach</keyname><forenames>Max H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trebst</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berg</keyname><forenames>Erez</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing Orders in a Nearly Antiferromagnetic Metal</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 097002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.097002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the onset of spin-density wave order in itinerant electron systems
via a two-dimensional lattice model amenable to numerically exact,
sign-problem-free determinantal quantum Monte Carlo simulations. The
finite-temperature phase diagram of the model reveals a dome-shaped $d$-wave
superconducting phase near the magnetic quantum phase transition. Above the
critical superconducting temperature, we observe an extended fluctuation
regime, which manifests itself in the opening of a gap in the electronic
density of states and an enhanced diamagnetic response. While charge density
wave fluctuations are moderately enhanced in the proximity of the magnetic
quantum phase transition, they remain short-ranged. The striking similarity of
our results to the phenomenology of many unconventional superconductors points
a way to a microscopic understanding of such strongly coupled systems in a
controlled manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07886</id><created>2015-12-24</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anacleto</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazeia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brito</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mota-Silva</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum-corrected two-dimensional Horava-Lifshitz black hole entropy</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, no figure, Latex; version to appear in Advances in High
  Energy Physics</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics 2016, 8465759 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/8465759</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we focus on the Halmiton-Jacobi method to determine several
thermodynamic quantities such as the temperature, entropy and specific heat of
two-dimensional Horava-Lifshitz black holes by using the generalized
uncertainty principles (GUP). We also address the product of horizons, mainly
concerning the event, Cauchy, cosmological and virtual horizons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09179</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradhan</keyname><forenames>Prabhakar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Backman</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing the sensitivity of mesoscopic light reflection statistics in
  weakly disordered media by interface reflections</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages,4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. B 30,1650155 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217979216501551</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Reflection statistics have not been well studied for optical random media
whose mean refractive indices do not match with the refractive indices of their
surrounding media. Here, we theoretically study how this refractive index
mismatch between a one dimensional (1D) optical sample and its surrounding
medium affects the reflection statistics in the weak disorder limit, when the
fluctuation part of the refractive index (dn) is much smaller than the mismatch
as well as the mean refractive index of the sample (dn &lt;&lt; &lt;n&gt;). In the
theoretical derivation, we perform a detailed calculation that results in the
analytical forms of mean and standard deviation (STD) of the reflectance in
terms of disorder parameters (dn and lc) in an index mismatched backscattering
system. Particularly, the orders of disorder parameters in STD of the
reflectance for index mismatched systems is shown to be lower ( (&lt;dn^2&gt; lc
)^1/2 ) than that of the matched systems (&lt;dn^2&gt; lc). By comparing STDs of the
reflection coefficient of index matched and mismatched systems, we show that
reflectance at the sample boundaries in index mismatched systems can enhance
the signal of the STD to the disorder parameters of the reflectance. In terms
of biophotonics applications, this result can lead to potential techniques that
effectively extract the sample disorder parameters by manipulating the index
mismatch conditions. Potential applications of the technique for enhancement in
sensitivity of cancer detection at single cell level are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01842</id><created>2016-01-08</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>Rana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Low density nuclear matter with quantum molecular dynamics : The role of
  the symmetry energy</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 025806 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.025806</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effect of isospin-dependent nuclear forces on the pasta phase in
the inner crust of neutron stars. To this end we model the crust within the
framework of quantum molecular dynamics (QMD). For maximizing the numerical
performance, a newly developed code has been implemented on GPU processors. As
a first application of the crust studies we investigate the dependence of the
particular pasta phases on the isospin dependence of the interaction, including
non-linear terms in this sector of the interactions. Our results indicate that
in contrast to earlier studies the phase diagram of the pasta phase is not very
sensitive to isospin effects. We show that the extraction of the isospin
parameters like asymmetry energy and slope from numerical data is affected by
higher-order terms in the asymmetry dependence of the energies per particle.
Furthermore, a rapid transition from the pasta to a homogeneous phase is
observed even for proton-to-neutron ratios typical for a supernova environment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03041</id><created>2016-01-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Changlani</keyname><forenames>Hitesh J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tubman</keyname><forenames>Norm M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Taylor L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge density waves in disordered media circumventing the Imry-Ma
  argument</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4+ pages, 4 figures. Supplemental (ancillary) information includes 3
  pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 31897 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep31897</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two powerful theoretical predictions, Anderson localization and the Imry-Ma
argument, impose significant restrictions on the phases of matter that can
exist in the presence of even the smallest amount of disorder in
one-dimensional systems. These predictions forbid conducting states and ordered
states respectively. It was thus remarkable that a mechanism to circumvent
Anderson localization relying on the presence of correlated disorder was found,
that is also realized in certain biomolecular systems. In a similar manner, we
show that the Imry-Ma argument can be circumvented resulting in the formation
of stable ordered states with discrete broken symmetries in disordered one
dimensional systems. Specifically, we simulate a family of Hamiltonians of
spinless fermions with correlated disorder and interactions, where we find that
a charge density wave is stable up to a finite critical disorder strength.
Having circumvented the Imry-Ma mechanism, we then investigate other mechanisms
by which disorder can destroy an ordered state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07218</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Turcati</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neves</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rio J&#xfa;nior</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex-mass shell renormalization of the higher-derivative
  electrodynamics</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures, replaced with published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76: 456</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4273-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a higher-derivative extension of QED modified by the addition of
a gauge-invariant dimension-6 kinetic operator in the U(1) gauge sector. The
Feynman diagrams at one-loop level are then computed. The modification in the
spin-1 sector leads the electron self-energy and vertex corrections diagrams
finite in the ultraviolet regime. Indeed, no regularization prescription is
used to calculate these diagrams because the modified propagator always occurs
coupled to conserved currents. Moreover, besides the usual massless pole in the
spin-1 sector, there is the emergence of a massive one, which becomes complex
when computing the radiative corrections at one-loop order. This imaginary part
defines the finite decay width of the massive mode. To check consistency, we
also derive the decay length using the electron--positron elastic scattering
and show that both results are equivalent. Because the presence of this
unstable mode, the standard renormalization procedures cannot be used and is
necessary adopt an appropriate framework to perform the perturbative
renormalization. For this purpose, we apply the complex-mass shell scheme (CMS)
to renormalize the aforementioned model. As an application of the formalism
developed, we estimate a quantum bound on the massive parameter using the
measurement of the electron anomalous magnetic moment and compute the Uehling
potential. At the end, the renormalization group is analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07910</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07910</id><created>2016-01-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Castro</keyname><forenames>Eduardo V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Gail</keyname><forenames>Raphael</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf3;pez-Sancho</keyname><forenames>M. Pilar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vozmediano</keyname><forenames>Mar&#xed;a A. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Hall metals from strong disorder in class A systems on partite
  lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 245414 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.245414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological matter is a trending topic in condensed matter: From a
fundamental point of view it has introduced new phenomena and tools, and for
technological applications, it holds the promise of basic stable quantum
computing. Similarly, the physics of localization by disorder, an old paradigm
of obvious technological importance in the field, continues revealing surprises
when new properties of matter appear. This work deals with the localization
behavior of electronic systems based on partite lattices with special attention
to the role of topology. We find an unexpected result from the point of view of
localization properties: A robust topological metallic state characterized by a
non--quantized Hall conductivity arises from strong disorder in class A (time
reversal symmetry broken) insulators. The key issue is the nature of the
disorder realization: selective disorder in only one sublattice in systems
based on bipartite lattices. The generality of the result is based on the
partite nature of most recent 2D materials as graphene or transition metal
dichalcogenides, and the possibility of the physical realization of the
particular disorder demonstrated in ref. 1. An anomalous Hall metal arises also
when the original clean insulator is topologically trivial.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.08016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.08016</id><created>2016-01-29</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Mads Kock</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svenningsen</keyname><forenames>Anette</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dohn</keyname><forenames>Niels Bonderup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lieberoth</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sherson</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>DiffGame: Game-based mathematics learning for physics</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Procedia - Social and Behavioral Sciences 228, 316-322 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Differentiation is a mathematical skill applied throughout science in order
to describe the change of a function with respect to a dependent variable.
Thus, an intuitive understanding of differentiation is necessary to work with
the mathematical frameworks used to describe physical systems in the higher
levels of education. In order to obtain this intuition repeated practice is
required. This paper presents the development of DiffGame, which consists of a
series of exercises that introduce the basic principles of differentiation for
high-school students through game-like elements. DiffGame have been tested with
117 first-year students from a single Danish high school, who did not have any
prior training in differentiation. The students' learning was assessed by the
data obtained directly from DiffGame. The test demonstrated the efficacy of
DiffGame, since students at all levels demonstrate a learning gain. In contrast
to previous studies demonstrating most learning in the lower tier of students,
the middle tier of students (based on overall performance) exhibits the largest
learning gains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00509</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schwarz</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;der</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qu</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoth</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rieger</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimality of spatially inhomogeneous search strategies</title><categories>q-bio.SC cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures (including supplementary material), published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 068101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.068101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider random search processes alternating stochastically between
diffusion and ballistic motion, in which the distribution function of ballistic
motion directions varies from point to point in space. The specific space
dependence of the directional distribution together with the switching rates
between the two modes of motion establishes a spatially inhomogeneous search
strategy. We show that the mean first passage times for several standard search
problems - narrow escape, reaction partner finding, reaction-escape - can be
minimized with a directional distribution that is reminiscent of the spatial
organization of the cytoskeleton filaments of cells with a centrosome: radial
ballistic transport from center to periphery and back, and ballistic transport
in random directions within a concentric shell of thickness $\Delta_{\rm opt}$
along the domain boundary. The results suggest that living cells realize
efficient search strategies for various intracellular transport problems
economically through a spatial cytoskeleton organization that involves radial
microtubules in the central region and only a narrow actin cortex rather than a
cell body filled with randomly oriented actin filaments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06182</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Macrostate equivalence of two general ensembles and specific relative
  entropies</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 020101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.020101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The two criteria of ensemble equivalence, i.e. the macrostate equivalence and
the measure equivalence, are investigated for a general pair of states. The
macrostate equivalence implies the two ensembles are indistinguishable by the
measurement of macroscopic quantities obeying the large-deviation principle,
and the measure equivalence means that the specific relative entropy of these
two states vanishes in the thermodynamic limit. It is shown that the measure
equivalence implies the macrostate equivalence for a general pair of states by
deriving an inequality connecting the large-deviation rate functions to the
specific relative Renyi entropies. The result is applicable to both quantum and
classical systems. As applications, a sufficient condition for thermalization,
the timescale of quantum dynamics of macrovariables, and the second law with
strict irreversibility in a quantum quench are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07569</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07569</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kleyna</keyname><forenames>Jan T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Quan-Zhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Man-To</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meech</keyname><forenames>Karen J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wainscoat</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Micheli</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keane</keyname><forenames>Jacqueline V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weaver</keyname><forenames>Harold A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The catastrophic fragmentation of Comet 332P (Ikeya-Murakami)</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, published in ApJ Letters</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 827, Issue 2, article
  id. L26, pp. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/827/2/L26</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe 2016 January to April observations of the fragments of
332P/Ikeya-Murakami, a comet earlier observed in a 2010 October outburst
(Ishiguro et al 2014). We present photometry of the fragments, and perform
simulations to infer the time of breakup. We argue that the eastern-most
rapidly brightening fragment ($F4$) best corresponds to the original nucleus,
rather than the initial bright fragment $F1$. We compute radial and tangential
non-gravitational parameters, $A_1 = (1.5 \pm 0.4) \times 10^{-8}$ AU
day$^{-2}$ and $(7.2 \pm 1.9) \times 10^{-9}$ AU day$^{-2}$; both are
consistent with zero at the $4\sigma$ level. Monte Carlo simulations indicate
that the fragments were emitted on the outbound journey well after the 2010
outburst, with bright fragment $F1$ splitting in mid--2013 and the fainter
fragments within months of the 2016 January recovery. Western fragment $F7$ is
the oldest, dating from 2011. We suggest that the delayed onset of the
splitting is consistent with a self-propagating crystallization of water ice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08362</id><created>2016-02-26</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dorlas</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>Ciara</forenames></author></authors><title>The strong converse theorem for the product-state capacity of quantum
  channels with ergodic Markovian memory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, single column</comments><report-no>DIAS-STP-16-02</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Establishing the strong converse theorem for a communication channel confirms
that the capacity of that channel, that is, the maximum achievable rate of
reliable information communication, is the ultimate limit of communication over
that channel. Indeed, the strong converse theorem for a channel states that
coding at a rate above the capacity of the channel results in the convergence
of the error to its maximum value 1 and that there is no trade-off between
communication rate and decoding error. Here we prove that the strong converse
theorem holds for the product-state capacity of quantum channels with ergodic
Markovian correlated memory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02513</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02513</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Choudhuri</keyname><forenames>Samir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bharadwaj</keyname><forenames>Somnath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Nirupam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Abhik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Sk. Saiyad</forenames></author></authors><title>Tapering the sky response for angular power spectrum estimation from
  low-frequency radio-interferometric data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. The definitive
  version will be available at http://mnrasl.oxfordjournals.org/</comments><journal-ref>2016, MNRAS, 459, 151</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw607</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is important to correctly subtract point sources from
radio-interferometric data in order to measure the power spectrum of diffuse
radiation like the Galactic synchrotron or the Epoch of Reionization 21-cm
signal. It is computationally very expensive and challenging to image a very
large area and accurately subtract all the point sources from the image. The
problem is particularly severe at the sidelobes and the outer parts of the main
lobe where the antenna response is highly frequency dependent and the
calibration also differs from that of the phase center. Here we show that it is
possible to overcome this problem by tapering the sky response. Using simulated
150 MHz observations, we demonstrate that it is possible to suppress the
contribution due to point sources from the outer parts by using the Tapered
Gridded Estimator to measure the angular power spectrum C_l of the sky signal.
We also show from the simulation that this method can self-consistently compute
the noise bias and accurately subtract it to provide an unbiased estimation of
C_l.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02653</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-03-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrara</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kallosh</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Proeyen</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrase</keyname><forenames>Timm</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear Versus Non-linear Supersymmetry, in General</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 p</comments><report-no>CERN-TH-2016-052, TUW-16-05</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1604:065, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)065</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study superconformal and supergravity models with constrained superfields.
The underlying version of such models with all unconstrained superfields and
linearly realized supersymmetry is presented here, in addition to the physical
multiplets there are Lagrange multiplier (LM) superfields. Once the equations
of motion for the LM superfields are solved, some of the physical superfields
become constrained. The linear supersymmetry of the original models becomes
non-linearly realized, its exact form can be deduced from the original linear
supersymmetry. Known examples of constrained superfields are shown to require
the following LM's: chiral superfields, linear superfields, general complex
superfields, some of them are multiplets with a spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04200</id><created>2016-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishikawa</keyname><forenames>Yoshihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hukushima</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions and ordering structures of a model of chiral
  helimagnet in three dimensions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064428 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064428</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phase transitions in a classical Heisenberg spin model of a chiral helimagnet
with the Dzyaloshinskii--Moriya (DM) interaction in three dimensions are
numerically studied. By using the event-chain Monte Carlo algorithm recently
developed for particle and continuous spin systems, we perform equilibrium
Monte Carlo simulations for large systems up to about $10^6$ spins. Without
magnetic fields, the system undergoes a continuous phase transition with
critical exponents of the three-dimensional \textit{XY} model, and a uniaxial
periodic helical structure emerges in the low temperature region. In the
presence of a magnetic field perpendicular to the axis of the helical
structure, it is found that there exists a critical point on the temperature
and magnetic-field phase diagram and that above the critical point the system
exhibits a phase transition with strong divergence of the specific heat and the
uniform magnetic susceptibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06565</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lubasch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuks</keyname><forenames>Johanna I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Appel</keyname><forenames>Heiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubio</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cirac</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ba&#xf1;uls</keyname><forenames>Mari-Carmen</forenames></author></authors><title>Systematic construction of density functionals based on matrix product
  state computations</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures, accepted version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 083039 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/8/083039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a systematic procedure for the approximation of density
functionals in density functional theory that consists of two parts. First, for
the efficient approximation of a general density functional, we introduce an
efficient ansatz whose non-locality can be increased systematically. Second, we
present a fitting strategy that is based on systematically increasing a
reasonably chosen set of training densities. We investigate our procedure in
the context of strongly correlated fermions on a one-dimensional lattice in
which we compute accurate training densities with the help of matrix product
states. Focusing on the exchange-correlation energy, we demonstrate how an
efficient approximation can be found that includes and systematically improves
beyond the local density approximation. Importantly, this systematic
improvement is shown for target densities that are quite different from the
training densities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08698</id><created>2016-03-29</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kudryavtseva</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soomere</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Validation of the multi-mission altimeter wave height data for the
  Baltic Sea region</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures, Estonian Journal of Earth Sciences</comments><journal-ref>Estonian Journal of Earth Sciences, 2016, 65, 3, pp. 161-175</journal-ref><doi>10.3176/earth.2016.13</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a complete cross-validation of significant wave heights (SWH)
extracted from altimetry data from all ten existing satellites with available
in situ (buoy and echosounder) wave measurements for the Baltic Sea basin. The
main purpose is to select an adequate altimetry data subset for a subsequent
evaluation of the wave climate. The satellite measurements with the backscatter
coefficients &gt; 13.5 cdb, errors in the SWH normalized standard deviation &gt; 0.5
m and snapshots with centroids closer than 0.2 degrees to the land are not
reliable. The ice flag usually denotes the ice concentration of &gt; 50%. The
presence of ice affects the SWH data starting from concentrations 10%, but
substantial effects are only evident for concentrations &gt; 30%. The altimetry
data selected based on these criteria have very good correspondence with in
situ data, except for GEOSAT Phase 1 data (1985-1989) that could not be
validated. The root-mean-square difference of altimetry and in situ data is in
the range of 0.23-0.37, which is significant for the Baltic Sea, compared with
an average wave height of ~1 m. The bias for CRYOSAT-2, ERS-2, JASON-1/2 and
SARAL data is below 0.06 m. The ENVISAT, ERS-1, GEOSAT and TOPEX satellites
revealed larger biases up to 0.23 m. The SWH time series from several satellite
pairs (ENVISAT/JASON-1, SARAL/JASON-2, ERS-1/TOPEX) exhibit substantial mutual
temporal drift and part of them evidently are not homogeneous in time. A new
high-resolution SWH data set from the SARAL satellite reveals a very good
correspondence with the in situ data and with the data stream from previous
satellites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09403</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09403</id><created>2016-03-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Francs</keyname><forenames>G. Colas des</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barthes</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouhelier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weeber</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dereux</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmonic Purcell factor and coupling efficiency to surface plasmons.
  Implications for addressing and controlling optical nanosources</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>Journal of Optics (in press)</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Optics 18, p. 094005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/9/094005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Purcell factor $F_p$ is a key quantity in cavity quantum electrodynamics
(cQED) that quantifies the coupling rate between a dipolar emitter and a cavity
mode. Its simple form $F_p\propto Q/V$ unravels the possible strategies to
enhance and control light-matter interaction. Practically, efficient
light-matter interaction is achieved thanks to either i) high quality factor
$Q$ at the basis of cQED or ii) low modal volume $V$ at the basis of
nanophotonics and plasmonics. In the last decade, strong efforts have been done
to derive a plasmonic Purcell factor in order to transpose cQED concepts to the
nanocale, in a scale-law approach. In this work, we discuss the plasmonic
Purcell factor for both delocalized (SPP) and localized (LSP)
surface-plasmon-polaritons and briefly summarize the expected applications for
nanophotonics. On the basis of the SPP resonance shape (Lorentzian or Fano
profile), we derive closed form expression for the coupling rate to delocalized
plasmons. The quality factor factor and modal confinement of both SPP and LSP
are quantified, demonstrating their strongly subwavelength behaviour.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09634</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zhuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ruoxu</forenames></author></authors><title>Toda-like (0,2) mirrors to products of projective spaces</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>35 pages, LaTeX; v2: typos fixed; v3: more typos fixed</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1608 (2016) 093</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)093</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the open problems in understanding (0,2) mirror symmetry concerns the
construction of Toda-like Landau-Ginzburg mirrors to (0,2) theories on Fano
spaces. In this paper, we begin to fill this gap by making an ansatz for (0,2)
Toda-like theories mirror to (0,2) supersymmetric nonlinear sigma models on
products of projective spaces, with deformations of the tangent bundle,
generalizing a special case previously worked out for P1xP1. We check this
ansatz by matching correlation functions of the B/2-twisted Toda-like theories
to correlation functions of corresponding A/2-twisted nonlinear sigma models,
computed primarily using localization techniques. These (0,2) Landau-Ginzburg
models admit redundancies, which can lend themselves to multiple
distinct-looking representatives of the same physics, which we discuss.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01690</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kashani-Poor</keyname><forenames>Amir-Kian</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantization condition from exact WKB for difference equations</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages. v2 : minor changes, clarifications and references added.
  v3: typos corrected</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP06(2016)180</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A well-motivated conjecture states that the open topological string partition
function on toric geometries in the Nekrasov-Shatashvili limit is annihilated
by a difference operator called the quantum mirror curve. Recently, the complex
structure variables parameterizing the curve, which play the role of
eigenvalues for related operators, were conjectured to satisfy a quantization
condition non-perturbative in the NS parameter $\hbar$. Here, we argue that
this quantization condition arises from requiring single-valuedness of the
partition function, combined with the requirement of smoothness in the
parameter $\hbar$. To determine the monodromy of the partition function, we
study the underlying difference equation in the framework of exact WKB.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03621</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>Niravkumar D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nocera</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arita</keyname><forenames>Ryotaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreo</keyname><forenames>Adriana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dagotto</keyname><forenames>Elbio</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties and pairing tendencies of the iron-based
  superconducting ladder BaFe$_2$S$_3$: combined ab initio and density matrix
  renormalization group study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent discovery of superconductivity under high pressure in the two-leg
ladder compound BaFe$_2$S$_3$ [H. Takahashi et al., Nature Materials 14, 1008
(2015)] opens a broad avenue of research, because it represents the first
report of pairing tendencies in a quasi one-dimensional iron-based high
critical temperature superconductor. Similarly as in the case of the cuprates,
ladders and chains can be far more accurately studied using many-body
techniques and model Hamiltonians than their layered counterparts, particularly
if several orbitals are active. In this publication, we derive a two-orbital
Hubbard model from first principles that describes individual ladders of
BaFe$_2$S$_3$. The model is studied with the density matrix renormalization
group. These first reported results are exciting for two reasons: (i) at
half-filling, ferromagnetic order emerges as the dominant magnetic pattern
along the rungs of the ladder, and antiferromagnetic order along the legs, in
excellent agreement with neutron experiments; (ii) pairs form in the strong
coupling regime, as found by studying the binding energy of two holes doped on
the half-filled system. In addition, Orbital Selective Mott Phase
characteristics develop with doping, with only one Wannier orbital receiving
the hole carriers while the other remains half-filled. These results suggest
that the analysis of models for iron-based two-leg ladders could clarify the
origin of pairing tendencies and other exotic properties of iron-based high
critical temperature superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06101</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Liujun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haah</keyname><forenames>Jeongwan</forenames></author></authors><title>Spurious Long-range Entanglement and Replica Correlation Length</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 12 figures; (v2) more references, added discussion on Gibbs
  states and higher dimensions</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075151 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075151</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological entanglement entropy has been regarded as a smoking-gun signature
of topological order in two dimensions, capturing the total quantum dimension
of the topological particle content. An extrapolation method on cylinders has
been used frequently to measure the topological entanglement entropy. Here, we
show that a class of short-range entangled 2D states, when put on an infinite
cylinder of circumference $L$, exhibits the entanglement R\'enyi entropy of any
integer index $\alpha \ge 2$ that obeys $S_\alpha = a L - \gamma$ where $a,
\gamma &gt; 0 $. Under the extrapolation method, the subleading term $\gamma$
would be identified as the topological entanglement entropy, which is spurious.
A nonzero $\gamma$ is always present if the 2D state reduces to a certain
symmetry-protected topological 1D state, upon disentangling spins that are far
from the entanglement cut. The internal symmetry that stabilizes $\gamma &gt; 0$
is not necessarily a symmetry of the 2D state, but should be present after the
disentangling reduction. If the symmetry is absent, $\gamma$ decays
exponentially in $L$ with a characteristic length, termed as a replica
correlation length, which can be arbitrarily large compared to the two-point
correlation length of the 2D state. We propose a simple numerical procedure to
measure the replica correlation length through replica correlation functions.
We also calculate the replica correlation functions for representative wave
functions of abelian discrete gauge theories and the double semion theory in
2D, to show that they decay abruptly to zero. This supports a conjecture that
the replica correlation length being small implies that the subleading term
from the extrapolation method determines the total quantum dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06272</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mehdipour</keyname><forenames>S. Hamid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmadi</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>A comparison of remnants in noncommutative Bardeen black holes</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures, references added</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys Space Sci (2016) 361: 314</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2904-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the mass term of the Bardeen metric in the presence of a
noncommutative geometry induced minimal length. In this setup, the proposal of
a stable black hole remnant as a candidate to store information is confirmed.
We consider the possibility of having an extremal configuration with one
degenerate event horizon and compare different sizes of black hole remnants. As
a result, once the magnetic charge $g$ of the noncommutative Bardeen solution
becomes larger, both the minimal nonzero mass $M_0$ and the minimal nonzero
horizon radius $r_0$ get larger. This means, subsequently, under the condition
of an adequate amount of $g$, the three parameters $g$, $M_0$, and $r_0$ are in
a connection with each other linearly. According to our results, a
noncommutative Bardeen black hole is colder than the noncommutative
Schwarzschild black hole and its remnant is bigger, so the minimum required
energy for the formation of such a black hole at particle colliders will be
larger. We also find a closely similar result for the Hayward solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06548</id><created>2016-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Everitt</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henshaw</keyname><forenames>Michael J de C</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dwyer</keyname><forenames>Vincent M</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Systems Engineering: A structured approach to accelerating the
  development of a quantum technology industry</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Invited contribution to 18th International Conference on Transparent
  Optical Networks ICTON 2016 (topic: quantum photonics). Discussion paper
  (four pages, no figures, perspectives/opinion piece - does not contain new
  scientific findings)</comments><journal-ref>2016 18th International Conference on Transparent Optical Networks
  (ICTON)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ICTON.2016.7550613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exciting possibilities in the field of new quantum technologies extend
far beyond the well-reported application of quantum computing. Precision
timing, gravity sensors and imagers, cryptography, navigation, metrology,
energy harvesting and recovery, biomedical sensors and imagers, and real-time
optimisers all indicate the potential for quantum technologies to provide the
basis of a technological revolution. From the field of Systems Engineering
emerges a focused strategy for the development cycle, enabling the existence of
hugely complex products. It is through the adoption of systems thinking that
the semiconductor industry has achieved massive industrial and economic impact.
Quantum technologies rely on delicate, non-local and/or entangled degrees of
freedom - leading to great potential, but also posing new challenges to the
development of products and industries. We discuss some of the challenges and
opportunities regarding the implementation of Systems Engineering and systems
thinking into the quantum technologies space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08192</id><created>2016-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Fefferman</keyname><forenames>Bill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hirotada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Cedric Yen-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morimae</keyname><forenames>Tomoyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Space-Efficient Error Reduction for Unitary Quantum Computations</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC</categories><comments>Accepted to ICALP 2016</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of 43rd International Colloquium on Automata,
  Languages, and Programming (ICALP 2016), pp. 14:1-14:14</journal-ref><doi>10.4230/LIPIcs.ICALP.2016.14</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper develops general space-efficient methods for error reduction for
unitary quantum computation. Consider a polynomial-time quantum computation
with completeness $c$ and soundness $s$, either with or without a witness
(corresponding to QMA and BQP, respectively). To convert this computation into
a new computation with error at most $2^{-p}$, the most space-efficient method
known requires extra workspace of ${O \bigl( p \log \frac{1}{c-s} \bigr)}$
qubits. This space requirement is too large for scenarios like
logarithmic-space quantum computations. This paper presents error-reduction
methods for unitary quantum computations (i.e., computations without
intermediate measurements) that require extra workspace of just ${O \bigl( \log
\frac{p}{c-s} \bigr)}$ qubits. This in particular gives the first methods of
strong amplification for logarithmic-space unitary quantum computations with
two-sided bounded error. This also leads to a number of consequences in
complexity theory, such as the uselessness of quantum witnesses in
bounded-error logarithmic-space unitary quantum computations, the PSPACE upper
bound for QMA with exponentially-small completeness-soundness gap, and strong
amplification for matchgate computations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08780</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2016-08-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zidong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimson</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferroelectrics Manipulate Magnetic Bloch Skyrmions in a Composite
  Bilayer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, Supplemental Material at:
  http://dx.doi.org/10.13140/RG.2.1.2015.8326/1 for animations about dynamical
  results</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theoretical investigation demonstrates that the composite bilayer (i.e.,
chiral-magnetic/ferroelectric bilayer) offers the possibility of
electric-induced magnetic Skyrmions [Phys. Rev. B \textbf{94}, 014311 (2016)].
In this Article, we propose a micromagnetic model to physically manipulate
magnetic Bloch Skyrmions propagating in a chiral-magnetic thin film with a
polarized ferroelectric essential to drive the system through the converse
magnetoelectric effect. Effects caused by different velocities of the
propagation, sizes of the thin film, and strength of the magnetoelectric
couplings strongly impact on quality and quantity of the magnetic Skyrmions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00994</id><created>2016-05-03</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tchoumakov</keyname><forenames>Serguei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Civelli</keyname><forenames>Marcello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goerbig</keyname><forenames>Mark O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic-field-induced relativistic properties in type-I and type-II
  Weyl semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures; 3 pages of supplementary material incorporated;
  published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 086402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.086402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate Weyl semimetals with tilted conical bands in a magnetic field.
Even when the cones are overtilted (type-II Weyl semimetal), Landau-level
quantization can be possible as long as the magnetic field is oriented close to
the tilt direction. Most saliently, the tilt can be described within the
relativistic framework of Lorentz transformations that give rise to a rich
spectrum, displaying new transitions beyond the usual dipolar ones in the
optical conductivity. We identify particular features in the latter that allow
one to distinguish between semimetals of different types.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01066</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Koll</keyname><forenames>Daniel D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbot</keyname><forenames>Dorian S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature Structure and Atmospheric Circulation of Dry, Tidally Locked
  Rocky Exoplanets</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal 825 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/2/99</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next-generation space telescopes will observe the atmospheres of rocky
planets orbiting nearby M-dwarfs. Understanding these observations will require
well-developed theory in addition to numerical simulations. Here we present
theoretical models for the temperature structure and atmospheric circulation of
dry, tidally locked rocky exoplanets with grey radiative transfer and test them
using a general circulation model (GCM). First, we develop a
radiative-convective model that captures surface temperatures of slowly
rotating and cool atmospheres. Second, we show that the atmospheric circulation
acts as a global heat engine, which places strong constraints on large-scale
wind speeds. Third, we develop a radiative-convective-subsiding model which
extends our radiative-convective model to hot and thin atmospheres. We find
that rocky planets develop large day-night temperature gradients at a ratio of
wave-to-radiative timescales up to two orders of magnitude smaller than the
value suggested by work on hot Jupiters. The small ratio is due to the heat
engine inefficiency and asymmetry between updrafts and subsidence in convecting
atmospheres. Fourth, we show using GCM simulations that rotation only has a
strong effect on temperature structure if the atmosphere is hot or thin. Our
models let us map out atmospheric scenarios for planets such as GJ 1132b and
show how thermal phase curves could constrain them. Measuring phase curves of
short-period planets will require similar amounts of time on the James Webb
Space Telescope as detecting molecules via transit spectroscopy, so future
observations should pursue both techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03207</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2016-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Bei</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological String Theory Revisited I: The Stage</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>42 pages; References added</comments><report-no>UTTG-06-16</report-no><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A 31 (2016) 1650135</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we reformulate topological string theory using supermanifolds
and supermoduli spaces, following the approach worked out by Witten for
superstring perturbation theory in arXiv:1209.5461. We intend to make the
construction geometrical in nature, by using supergeometry techniques
extensively. The goal is to establish the foundation of studying topological
string amplitudes in terms of integration over appropriate supermoduli spaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03961</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vercnocke</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrase</keyname><forenames>Timm</forenames></author></authors><title>Constrained superfields from an anti-D3-brane in KKLT</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages, v2: references added</comments><report-no>TUW-16-10</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1608:132, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)132</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The KKLT construction of dS vacua relies on an uplift term that arises from
an anti-D3-brane. It was argued by Kachru, Pearson and Verlinde that this
anti-D3-brane is an excited state in a supersymmetric theory since it can decay
to a supersymmetric ground state. Hence the anti-D3-brane breaks supersymmetry
spontaneously and one should be able to package all the world-volume fields on
the anti-D3-brane into a four dimensional $\cal{N}=1$ supersymmetric action.
Here we extend previous results and identify the constrained superfields that
correspond to all the degrees of freedom on the anti-D3-brane. In particular,
we show explicitly that the four 4D worldvolume spinors give rise to
constrained chiral multiplets $S$ and $Y^i$, $i=1,2,3$ that satisfy
$S^2=SY^i=0$. We also conjecture (and provide evidence in a forthcoming
publication) that the vector field $A_\mu$ and the three scalars $\phi^i$ give
rise to a field strength multiplet $W_\alpha$ and three chiral multiplets $H^i$
that satisfy the constraints $S W_\alpha= \bar{D}_{\dot \alpha} (S \bar
H^i)=0$. This is the first time that such constrained multiplets appear in
string theory constructions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04057</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jariwala</keyname><forenames>Deep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davoyan</keyname><forenames>Artur R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tagliabue</keyname><forenames>Giulia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sherrott</keyname><forenames>Michelle C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Joeson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atwater</keyname><forenames>Harry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Near Unity Absorption in Van der Waals Semiconductors for Ultrathin
  Optoelectronics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Manuscript plus supplement. 5 figures in manuscript</comments><journal-ref>Nano Letters, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b01914</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate near unity, broadband absorbing optoelectronic devices using
sub-15 nm thick transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) of molybdenum and
tungsten as van der Waals semiconductor active layers. Specifically, we report
that near-unity light absorption is possible in extremely thin (&lt; 15 nm) Van
der Waals semiconductor structures by coupling to strongly damped optical modes
of semiconductor/metal heterostructures. We further fabricate Schottky junction
devices using these highly absorbing heterostructures and characterize their
optoelectronic performance. Our work addresses one of the key criteria to
enable TMDCs as potential candidates to achieve high optoelectronic efficiency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04269</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Almeida</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lefe O. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piattella</keyname><forenames>Oliver F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Davi C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A method for evaluating models that use galaxy rotation curves to derive
  the density profiles</title><categories>astro-ph.GA gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures, 4 tables. v2: diverse text improvements, no
  changes in the conclusions. Version accepted in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 462, 2706 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1844</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are some approaches, either based on General Relativity (GR) or
modified gravity, that use galaxy rotation curves to derive the matter density
of the corresponding galaxy, and this procedure would either indicate a partial
or a complete elimination of dark matter in galaxies. Here we review these
approaches, clarify the difficulties on this inverted procedure, present a
method for evaluating them, and use it to test two specific approaches that are
based on GR: the Cooperstock-Tieu (CT) and the Balasin-Grumiller (BG)
approaches. Using this new method, we find that neither of the tested
approaches can satisfactorily fit the observational data without dark matter.
The CT approach results can be significantly improved if some dark matter is
considered, while for the BG approach no usual dark matter halo can improve its
results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04541</id><created>2016-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ilssar</keyname><forenames>Dotan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bucher</keyname><forenames>Izhak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flashner</keyname><forenames>Henryk</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling and closed loop control of near-field acoustically levitated
  objects</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>24 pages, 12 figures. Submitted to Mechanical systems and signal
  processing</comments><doi>10.1016/j.ymssp.2016.08.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present paper introduces a novel approach for modelling the governing,
slow dynamics of near-field acoustically levitated objects. This model is
sufficiently simple and concise to enable designing a closed-loop controller,
capable of accurate vertical positioning of a carried object. The near-field
acoustic levitation phenomenon exploits the compressibility, the nonlinearity
and the viscosity of the gas trapped between a rapidly oscillating surface and
a freely suspended planar object, to elevate its time averaged pressure above
the ambient pressure. By these means, the vertical position of loads weighing
up to several kilograms can be varied between dozens and hundreds of
micrometers. The simplified model developed in this paper is a second order
ordinary differential equation where the height-dependent stiffness and damping
terms of the gas layer are derived explicitly. This simplified model replaces a
traditional model consisting of the equation of motion of the levitated object,
coupled to a nonlinear partial differential equation, accounting for the
behavior of the entrapped gas. Due to the relatively simple form of the model
developed here, it constitutes a convenient foundation for model based control
algorithms, governing the slow dynamics of near-field acoustically levitated
objects. Indeed, based on the former, a height dependent, gain scheduled PID
controller is developed and verified numerically and experimentally, both
providing satisfying results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04887</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-05-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hess</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Raedt</keyname><forenames>Hans</forenames></author><author><keyname>Michielsen</keyname><forenames>Kristel</forenames></author></authors><title>From Boole to Leggett-Garg: Epistemology of Bell-type Inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Added two paragraphs + references to discuss recent experiment</comments><journal-ref>Advances in Mathematical Physics Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  4623040, 7 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/4623040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1862, George Boole derived an inequality for variables, now known as
Boolean variables, that in his opinion represents a demarcation line between
possible and impossible experience. This inequality forms an important
milestone in the epistemology of probability theory and probability measures.
  In 1985 Leggett and Garg derived a physics related inequality, mathematically
identical to Boole's, that according to them represents a demarcation between
macroscopic realism and quantum mechanics. Their formalism, constructed for the
magnetic flux of SQUIDS, includes general features and applies also to many
other quantum experiments.
  We show that a wide gulf, a wide divide, separates the &quot;sense impressions&quot;
and corresponding data, as well as the postulates of macroscopic realism, from
the mathematical abstractions that are used to derive the inequality of
Leggett-Garg. If the gulf can be bridged, one may indeed derive the said
inequality, which is then clearly a demarcation between possible and impossible
experience: it cannot be violated and is not violated by quantum theory. We
deduce from this fact that a violation of the Leggett-Garg inequality does not
mean that the SQUID-flux is not there when nobody looks, as Leggett-Garg
suggest, but instead that the probability measures may not be what Leggett-Garg
have assumed them to be, when no data can be secured that directly relate to
them. We show that similar considerations apply to other well known quantum
interpretation-puzzles including that of the two-slit experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07926</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mcnamara</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Crassous</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Amon</keyname><forenames>Axelle</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author></authors><title>Eshelby inclusions in granular matter: theory and simulations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physical Review E , American Physical Society (APS), 2016, 94,
  pp.022907</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022907</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a numerical implementation of an active inclusion in a granular
material submitted to a biaxial test. We discuss the dependence of the response
to this perturbation on two parameters: the intra-granular friction coefficient
on one hand, the degree of the loading on the other hand. We compare the
numerical results to theoretical predictions taking into account the change of
volume of the inclusion as well as the anisotropy of the elastic matrix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09710</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09710</id><created>2016-05-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Amor</keyname><forenames>Benjamin R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaub</keyname><forenames>Michael T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yaliraki</keyname><forenames>Sophia N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barahona</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction of allosteric sites and mediating interactions through
  bond-to-bond propensities</title><categories>q-bio.BM physics.bio-ph physics.data-an q-bio.QM</categories><comments>30 pages, including 17 pages main text + 13 pages supplementary
  information. 7 Figures and 3 tables (main) + 5 Figures and 6 tables
  (supplementary)</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, Article number: 12477 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12477</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Allosteric regulation is central to many biochemical processes. Allosteric
sites provide a target to fine-tune protein activity, yet we lack computational
methods to predict them. Here, we present an efficient graph-theoretical
approach for identifying allosteric sites and the mediating interactions that
connect them to the active site. Using an atomistic graph with edges weighted
by covalent and non-covalent bond energies, we obtain a bond-to-bond propensity
that quantifies the effect of instantaneous bond fluctuations propagating
through the protein. We use this propensity to detect the sites and
communication pathways most strongly linked to the active site, assessing their
significance through quantile regression and comparison against a reference set
of 100 generic proteins. We exemplify our method in detail with three
well-studied allosteric proteins: caspase-1, CheY, and h-Ras, correctly
predicting the location of the allosteric site and identifying key allosteric
interactions. Consistent prediction of allosteric sites is then attained in a
further set of 17 proteins known to exhibit allostery. Because our propensity
measure runs in almost linear time, it offers a scalable approach to
high-throughput searches for candidate allosteric sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00017</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00017</id><created>2016-05-31</created><updated>2016-08-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hambye</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teresi</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs doublet decay as the origin of the baryon asymmetry</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for PRL. References added</comments><report-no>ULB-TH/16-08</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 091801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.091801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a question which curiously had not been properly considered so
far: in the standard seesaw model what is the minimum value the mass of a
right-handed (RH) neutrino must have for allowing successful leptogenesis via
CP-violating decays? To answer this question requires to take into account a
number of thermal effects. We show that, for low RH neutrino masses and thanks
to these effects, leptogenesis turns out to proceed efficiently from the decay
of the Standard Model (SM) scalar doublet components into a RH neutrino and a
lepton. Such decays produce the asymmetry at low temperatures, slightly before
sphaleron decoupling. If the RH neutrino has thermalized prior from producing
the asymmetry, this mechanism turns out to lead to the bound $m_N&gt;2$ GeV. If,
instead, the RH neutrinos have not thermalized, leptogenesis from these decays
is enhanced further and can be easily successful, even at lower scales. This
Higgs-decay leptogenesis new mechanism works without requiring an interplay of
flavor effects and/or cancellations of large Yukawa couplings in the neutrino
mass matrix. Last but not least, such a scenario turns out to be testable, from
direct production of the RH neutrino(s).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01657</id><created>2016-06-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Turkulets</keyname><forenames>Yury</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bick</keyname><forenames>Tamar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shalish</keyname><forenames>Ilan</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface effect that causes a peak in band-edge photocurrent spectra: a
  quantitative model</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. D: Appl. Phys. 49, 365104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0022-3727/49/36/365104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Band edge photocurrent spectra are typically observed in either of two
shapes: a peak or a step. In this study, we show that the photocurrent band
edge response of a GaN layer forms a peak, while the same response in GaN
nanowires takes the form of a step, both are red-shifted to the actual band
edge energy. Although this apparent inconsistency is not limited to GaN, the
physics of this phenomenon has been unclear. To understand the physics behind
these observations, we propose a model explaining the apparent discrepancy as
resulting from a structure-dependent surface-effect. To test the model, we
experiment with a GaAs layer showing that we can deliberately switch between a
step and a peak. We demonstrate that using this quantitative model one may
obtain the exact band edge transition energy, regardless of the red-shift
variance, as well as the density of the surface state charges that cause the
red shift. The model thus adds quantitative features to photocurrent
spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01926</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Metcalfe</keyname><forenames>Travis S.</forenames><affiliation>SSI</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Egeland</keyname><forenames>Ricky</forenames><affiliation>HAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>van Saders</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames><affiliation>Carnegie</affiliation></author></authors><title>Stellar Evidence that the Solar Dynamo may be in Transition</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 tables, 2 figures. ApJL accepted, Colloquium available at
  https://youtu.be/_3MdLAt8i-o</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J 826, L2 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/826/1/L2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Precise photometry from the Kepler space telescope allows not only the
measurement of rotation in solar-type field stars, but also the determination
of reliable masses and ages from asteroseismology. These critical data have
recently provided the first opportunity to calibrate rotation-age relations for
stars older than the Sun. The evolutionary picture that emerges is surprising:
beyond middle-age the efficiency of magnetic braking is dramatically reduced,
implying a fundamental change in angular momentum loss beyond a critical Rossby
number (Ro~2). We compile published chromospheric activity measurements for the
sample of Kepler asteroseismic targets that were used to establish the new
rotation-age relations. We use these data along with a sample of well
characterized solar analogs from the Mount Wilson HK survey to develop a
qualitative scenario connecting the evolution of chromospheric activity to a
fundamental shift in the character of differential rotation. We conclude that
the Sun may be in a transitional evolutionary phase, and that its magnetic
cycle might represent a special case of stellar dynamo theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03250</id><created>2016-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Bravina</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>B. H. Brusheim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crkovsk&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyyubova</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkikh</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lokhtin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malinina</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazarova</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrushanko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Snigirev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabrodin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>HYDRO + JETS (HYDJET++) event generator for Pb+Pb collisions at LHC</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, contribution to Proceedings of the Winter
  Workshop on Nuclear Dynamics 2016</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 736 (2016) 012024</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/736/1/012024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Monte Carlo event generator HYDJET++ is one of the few generators,
designed for the calculations of heavy-ion collisions at ultrarelativistic
energies, which combine treatment of soft hydro-like processes with the
description of jets traversing the hot and dense partonic medium. The model is
employed to study the azimuthal anisotropy phenomena, dihadron angular
correlations and event-by-event (EbyE) fluctuations of the anisotropic flow in
Pb+Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}} = 2.76$ TeV. The interplay of soft and hard
processes describes the violation of the mass hierarchy of meson and baryon
elliptic and triangular flows at p_T &gt; 2 GeV/c, the fall-off of the flow
harmonics at intermediate transverse momenta, and the worsening of the
number-of-constituent-quark (NCQ) scaling of elliptic/triangular flow at LHC
compared to RHIC energies. The cross-talk of v_2 and v_3 leads to emergence of
higher order harmonics in the model and to appearance of the ridge structure in
dihadron angular correlations in a broad pseudorapidity range. HYDJET++
possesses also the dynamical EbyE fluctuations of the anisotropic flow. The
model results agree well with the experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03947</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-08-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sannomiya</keyname><forenames>Noriaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsura</keyname><forenames>Hosho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetry breaking and Nambu-Goldstone fermions in an extended
  Nicolai model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, v2: typos corrected. This version will appear in
  Phys. Rev. D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 045014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.045014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a model of interacting spinless fermions in a one dimensional
lattice with supersymmetry (SUSY). The Hamiltonian is given by the
anti-commutator of two supercharges $Q$ and $Q^\dagger$, each of which is
comprised solely of fermion operators and possesses one adjustable parameter
$g$. When the parameter $g$ vanishes, the model is identical to the one studied
by Nicolai [H. Nicolai, J. Phys. A: Math. Gen. \textbf{9}, 1497 (1976)], where
the zero-energy ground state is exponentially degenerate. On the other hand, in
the large-$g$ limit the model reduces to the free-fermion chain with a
four-fold degenerate ground state. We show that for finite chains SUSY is
spontaneously broken when $g &gt; 0$. We also rigorously prove that for
sufficiently large $g$ the ground-state energy density is nonvanishing in the
infinite-volume limit. We further analyze the nature of the low-energy
excitations by employing various techniques such as rigorous inequalities,
exact numerical diagonalization, and renormalization group method with
bosonization. The analysis reveals that the low-energy excitations are
described by massless Dirac fermions (or Thirring fermions more generally),
which can be thought of as Nambu-Goldstone fermions from the spontaneous SUSY
breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07261</id><created>2016-06-23</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>C. J. A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinelli</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calabrese</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>M. P. L. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Real-time cosmography with redshift derivatives</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures; submitted to Phys. Rev. D; v2: clarifications and
  references added in reply to referee reports (matches published version)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 043001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.043001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The drift in the redshift of objects passively following the cosmological
expansion has long been recognized as a key model-independent probe of
cosmology. Here, we study the cosmological relevance of measurements of time or
redshift derivatives of this drift, arguing that the combination of first and
second redshift derivatives is a powerful test of the $\Lambda$CDM cosmological
model. In particular, the latter can be obtained numerically from a set of
measurements of the drift at different redshifts. We show that, in the
low-redshift limit, a measurement of the derivative of the drift can provide a
constraint on the jerk parameter, which is $j=1$ for flat $\Lambda$CDM, while
generically $j\neq1$ for other models. We emphasize that such a measurement is
well within the reach of the ELT-HIRES and SKA Phase 2 array surveys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07483</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07483</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>Brett A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carroll</keyname><forenames>P. Brandon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loomis</keyname><forenames>Ryan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finneran</keyname><forenames>Ian A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jewell</keyname><forenames>Philip R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Remijan</keyname><forenames>Anthony J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blake</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of the Interstellar Chiral Molecule Propylene Oxide
  (CH$_3$CHCH$_2$O)</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><journal-ref>Science 2016, 352, 1449</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aae0328</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Life on Earth relies on chiral molecules, that is, species not superimposable
on their mirror images. This manifests itself in the selection of a single
molecular handedness, or homochirality, across the biosphere. We present the
astronomical detection of a chiral molecule, propylene oxide (CH$_3$CHCH$_2$O),
in absorption toward the Galactic Center. Propylene oxide is detected in the
gas phase in a cold, extended molecular shell around the embedded, massive
protostellar clusters in the Sagittarius B2 star-forming region. This material
is representative of the earliest stage of solar system evolution in which a
chiral molecule has been found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08617</id><created>2016-06-28</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Niksic</keyname><forenames>Tamara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vretenar</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Sloppy nuclear energy density functionals: effective model reduction</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 024333 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.024333</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Concepts from information geometry are used to analyse parameter sensitivity
for a nuclear energy density functional, representative of a class of
semi-empirical functionals that start from a microscopically motivated ansatz
for the density dependence of the energy of a system of protons and neutrons.
It is shown that such functionals are sloppy, characterized by an exponential
range of sensitivity to parameter variations. Responsive to only a few stiff
parameter combinations, they exhibit an exponential decrease of sensitivity to
variations of the remaining soft parameters. By interpreting the space of model
predictions as a manifold embedded in the data space, with the parameters of
the functional as coordinates on the manifold, it is also shown that the
exponential distribution of model manifold widths corresponds to the
distribution of parameter sensitivity. Using the Manifold Boundary
Approximation Method, we illustrate how to systematically construct effective
nuclear density functionals of successively lower dimension in parameter space
until sloppiness is eventually eliminated and the resulting functional contains
only stiff combinations of parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09089</id><created>2016-06-29</created><updated>2016-08-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bilitewski</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>Nigel R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthetic dimensions in the strong-coupling limit: supersolids and
  pair-superfluids</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>accepted version, 10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 023630 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.023630</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the many-body phases of bosonic atoms with $N$ internal states
confined to a 1D optical lattice under the influence of a synthetic magnetic
field and strong repulsive interactions. The $N$ internal states of the atoms
are coupled via Raman transitions creating the synthetic magnetic field in the
space of internal spin states corresponding to recent experimental
realisations. We focus on the case of strong $\mbox{SU}(N)$ invariant local
density-density interactions in which each site of the 1D lattice is at most
singly occupied, and strong Raman coupling, in distinction to previous work
which has focused on the weak Raman coupling case. This allows us to keep only
a single state per site and derive a low energy effective spin $1/2$ model. The
effective model contains first-order nearest neighbour tunnelling terms, and
second-order nearest neighbour interactions and correlated next-nearest
neighbour tunnelling terms. By adjusting the flux $\phi$ one can tune the
relative importance of first-order and second-order terms in the effective
Hamiltonian. In particular, first-order terms can be set to zero, realising a
novel model with dominant second-order terms. We show that the resulting
competition between density-dependent tunnelling and repulsive density-density
interaction leads to an interesting phase diagram including a phase with
long-ranged pair-superfluid correlations. The method can be straightforwardly
extended to higher dimensions and lattices of arbitrary geometry including
geometrically frustrated lattices where the interplay of frustration,
interactions and kinetic terms is expected to lead to even richer physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09551</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>Logan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>Ankit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choudhary</keyname><forenames>Alok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolverton</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>A General-Purpose Machine Learning Framework for Predicting Properties
  of Inorganic Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures, 3 tables</comments><doi>10.1038/npjcompumats.2016.28</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A very active area of materials research is to devise methods that use
machine learning to automatically extract predictive models from existing
materials data. While prior examples have demonstrated successful models for
some applications, many more applications exist where machine learning can make
a strong impact. To enable faster development of machine-learning-based models
for such applications, we have created a framework capable of being applied to
a broad range of materials data. Our method works by using a chemically diverse
list of attributes, which we demonstrate are suitable for describing a wide
variety of properties, and a novel method for partitioning the data set into
groups of similar materials in order to boost the predictive accuracy. In this
manuscript, we demonstrate how this new method can be used to predict diverse
properties of crystalline and amorphous materials, such as band gap energy and
glass-forming ability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01840</id><created>2016-07-06</created><updated>2016-07-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lo</keyname><forenames>Chung-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pochung</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling in driven dynamics starting in the vicinity of a quantum
  critical point</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the driven critical dynamics with an equilibrium initial state near
a quantum critical point. In contrast to the original Kibble-Zurek mechanism,
which describes the driven dynamics starting from an adiabatic stage that is
far from the critical point, the initial adiabacity is broken in this scenario.
As a result, the scaling behavior cannot be described by the original
Kibble-Zurek scaling. In this work we propose a scaling theory, which includes
the initial parameters as additional scaling variables, to characterize the
scaling behavior. In particular, this scaling theory can be used to describe
the driven scaling behavior starting from a finite-temperature equilibrium
state near a quantum critical point. We numerically confirm the scaling theory
by simulating the real-time dynamics of the one-dimensional quantum Ising model
at both zero and finite temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02499</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02499</id><created>2016-07-08</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Newell</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGuire</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum control in nearly non-degenerate qubits interacting with light</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the time evolution of nearly degenerate two-state systems with an
external interaction. Conditions in which full population transfer is possible
when the two-states become degenerate are considered. A new variation of the
coupled differential equations for the probability amplitudes suggests a
possible singularity in the time evolution of the system. The singularity
occurs at the point in time where full control in the degenerate limit is
achieved. We solve this new variation to derive more information about
non-degenerate population control. The new results of numerical calculations
for occupational probabilities of non-degenerate systems are presented and
interpreted. These results are used to understand how population control breaks
down as the photon energy and the energy of the system are changed.
Applications are discussed, with an emphasis on interactions of twisted-vortex
and plane-wave photons with a variety of targets, including macroscopic gas
cells of atoms, of large single crystals, and of molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03911</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Melo</keyname><forenames>Djair</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de F&#xed;sica, Universidade Federal de Alagoas, Macei&#xf3;, AL, Brazil</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>Ivna</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de F&#xed;sica, Universidade Federal de Alagoas, Macei&#xf3;, AL, Brazil</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Moraes</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames><affiliation>Departamento de F&#xed;sica, CCEN, Universidade Federal da Para&#xed;ba, Jo&#xe3;o Pessoa, PB, Brazil, Departamento de F&#xed;sica, Universidade Federal Rural de Pernambuco, Recife, PE, Brazil</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fumeron</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames><affiliation>Institut Jean Lamour, Universit&#xe9; de Lorraine, Vand&#x153;uvre les Nancy, France</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Erms</forenames><affiliation>Escola Polit&#xe9;cnica de Pernambuco, Universidade de Pernambuco, Recife, PE, Brazil</affiliation></author></authors><title>Thermal diode made by nematic liquid crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 Postscript figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A, Volume 380, Issue 38, 7 September 2016, Pages
  3121 to 3127</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.07.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work investigates how a thermal diode can be designed from a nematic
liquid crystal confined inside a cylindrical capillary. In the case of
homeotropic anchoring, a defect structure called escaped radial disclination
arises. The asymmetry of such structure causes thermal rectification rates up
to 3.5\% at room temperature, comparable to thermal diodes made from carbon
nanotubes. Sensitivity of the system with respect the heat power supply, the
geometry of the capillary tube and the molecular anchoring angle is also
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04294</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Fuminobu</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Perturbations of Axion with a Dynamical Decay Constant</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 1 figure, v2: published in JCAP</comments><report-no>SISSA 39/2016/FISI, TU-1026, IPMU16-0118</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)056</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/056</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A QCD axion with a time-dependent decay constant has been known to be able to
accommodate high-scale inflation without producing topological defects or too
large isocurvature perturbations on CMB scales. We point out that a dynamical
decay constant also has the effect of enhancing the small-scale axion
isocurvature perturbations. The enhanced axion perturbations can even exceed
the periodicity of the axion potential, and thus lead to the formation of
axionic domain walls. Unlike the well-studied axionic walls, the walls produced
from the enhanced perturbations are not bounded by cosmic strings, and thus
would overclose the universe independently of the number of degenerate vacua
along the axion potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04482</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Ganesan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Subrata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krishna</keyname><forenames>Nanda Gopala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilango</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamruddin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyagi</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>A comparative study on defect estimation using XPS and Raman
  spectroscopy in few layer nanographitic structures</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Chem. Chem. Phys., 18, (2016) 22160-22167</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6CP02033J</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Defects in planar and vertically oriented nanographitic structures (NGSs)
synthesized by plasma enhanced chemical vapor deposition (PECVD) has been
investigated using Raman and X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy. While Raman
spectra reveal the dominance of vacancy and boundary type defects respectively
in vertical and planar NGSs, XPS provides additional information on vacancy
related defect peaks at C 1s spectrum that originate from non-conjugated carbon
atoms in hexagonal lattice. Although an excellent correlation prevails between
these two techniques, our results show that estimation of surface defects by
XPS is more accurate than Raman analysis. Nuances of these techniques are
discussed in the context of assessing defects in nanographitic structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06816</id><created>2016-07-22</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Goodson</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luebbers</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heitsch</keyname><forenames>Fabian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frazer</keyname><forenames>Christopher C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical enrichment of the pre-solar cloud by supernova dust grains</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 10 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS. Movies can
  be found here: http://user.physics.unc.edu/~mdgood86/research.html</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1796</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The presence of short-lived radioisotopes (SLRs) in solar system meteorites
has been interpreted as evidence that the solar system was exposed to a
supernova shortly before or during its formation. Yet results from
hydrodynamical models of SLR injection into the proto-solar cloud or disc
suggest that gas-phase mixing may not be efficient enough to reproduce the
observed abundances. As an alternative, we explore the injection of SLRs via
dust grains as a way to overcome the mixing barrier. We numerically model the
interaction of a supernova remnant containing SLR-rich dust grains with a
nearby molecular cloud. The dust grains are subject to drag forces and both
thermal and non-thermal sputtering. We confirm that the expanding gas shell
stalls upon impact with the dense cloud and that gas-phase SLR injection occurs
slowly due to hydrodynamical instabilities at the cloud surface. In contrast,
dust grains of sufficient size (&gt; 1 micron) decouple from the gas and penetrate
into the cloud within 0.1 Myr. Once inside the cloud, the dust grains are
destroyed by sputtering, releasing SLRs and rapidly enriching the dense
(potentially star-forming) regions. Our results suggest that SLR transport on
dust grains is a viable mechanism to explain SLR enrichment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02237</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02237</id><created>2016-08-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Qintong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murray</keyname><forenames>Peyton</forenames></author><author><keyname>You</keyname><forenames>Lu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>Caihua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wenjing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khan</keyname><forenames>Usman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Junling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Xiufeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic fingerprint of interfacial coupling between CoFe and nanoscale
  ferroelectric domain walls</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters, 109, 082906 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4961545</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetoelectric coupling in ferromagnet/multiferroic systems is often
manifested in the exchange bias effect, which may have combined contributions
from multiple sources, such as domain walls, chemical defects or strain. In
this study we magnetically &quot;fingerprint&quot; the coupling behavior of CoFe grown on
epitaxial BiFeO3 (BFO) thin films by magnetometry and
first-order-reversal-curves (FORC). The contribution to exchange bias from
71{\deg}, 109{\deg} and charged ferroelectric domain walls (DWs) was elucidated
by the FORC distribution. CoFe samples grown on BFO with 71{\deg} DWs only
exhibit an enhancement of the coercivity, but little exchange bias. Samples
grown on BFO with 109{\deg} DWs and mosaic DWs exhibit a much larger exchange
bias, with the main enhancement attributed to 109{\deg} and charged DWs. Based
on the Malozemoff random field model, a varying-anisotropy model is proposed to
account for the exchange bias enhancement. This work sheds light on the
relationship between the exchange bias effect of the CoFe/BFO heterointerface
and the ferroelectric DWs, and provides a path for multiferroic device analysis
and design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03674</id><created>2016-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Henne</keyname><forenames>Vincent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pruzhinskaya</keyname><forenames>Maria Victorovna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosnet</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leget</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Francois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>Emille</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciulli</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gris</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Says</keyname><forenames>Louis-Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangler</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>The influence of host galaxy morphology on the properties of Type Ia
  supernovae from the JLA compilation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>30 pages, 4 figures, submitted to New Astronomy</comments><journal-ref>New Astronomy 51 (2017), pp. 43-50</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.newast.2016.08.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The observational cosmology with distant Type Ia supernovae (SNe) as standard
candles claims that the Universe is in accelerated expansion, caused by a large
fraction of dark energy. In this paper we investigate the SN Ia environment,
studying the impact of the nature of their host galaxies on the Hubble diagram
fitting. The supernovae (192 SNe) used in the analysis were extracted from
Joint-Light-curves-Analysis (JLA) compilation of high-redshift and nearby
supernovae which is the best one to date. The analysis is based on the
empirical fact that SN Ia luminosities depend on their light curve shapes and
colors. We confirm that the stretch parameter of Type Ia supernovae is
correlated with the host galaxy type. The supernovae with lower stretch are
hosted mainly in elliptical and lenticular galaxies. No significant correlation
between SN Ia colour and host morphology was found.
  We also examine how the luminosities of SNe Ia change depending on host
galaxy morphology after stretch and colour corrections. Our results show that
in old stellar populations and low dust environments, the supernovae are
slightly fainter. SNe Ia in elliptical and lenticular galaxies have a higher
$\alpha$ (slope in luminosity-stretch) and $\beta$ (slope in luminosity-colour)
parameter than in spirals. However, the observed shift is at the 1-$\sigma$
uncertainty level and, therefore, can not be considered as significant.
  We confirm that the supernova properties depend on their environment and that
the incorporation of a host galaxy term into the Hubble diagram fit is expected
to be crucial for future cosmological analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05199</id><created>2016-08-18</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>M&#xf6;ller</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegener</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Production of nuclear sources and nuclear batteries by proton
  irradiation</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The decay of instable nuclei is being used in a broad range of applications
from detector calibration to power sources. As the public acceptance of
classical fission nuclear technology is decaying and its integral costs are
enormous, alternative production routes are required. The mathematical
formalism and fundamental considerations are presented for the use of ion
accelerators for isotope production. A focus is put on the production of
nuclear power sources to substitute Pu-238 based batteries. 20 MeV protons are
found to produce {\alpha} emitting polonium isotopes from bismuth with an
energy efficiency of up to 0.031%. Some hours are required to produce a 1Wth
power source of the 2.9 year half-life {\alpha} emitter Po-208 with a suitable
accelerator. The accelerator approach offers more flexibility for tailoring of
nuclear products and less waste. The technical requirements are close to and
compatible with the planned International Fusion Materials Irradiation Facility
accelerator
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05298</id><created>2016-08-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Caruso</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author></authors><title>Life and space dimensionality: A brief review of old and new entangled
  arguments</title><categories>physics.hist-ph astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Astrobiology and Outreach 4 (2) a.n. 152 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A general sketch on how the problem of space dimensionality depends on
anthropic arguments is presented. Several examples of how life has been used to
constraint space dimensionality (and vice-versa) are reviewed. In particular,
the influences of three-dimensionality in the solar system stability and the
origin of life on Earth are discussed. New constraints on space dimensionality
and on its invariance in very large spatial and temporal scales are also
stressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06345</id><created>2016-08-22</created><updated>2016-08-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Kainan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongwu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geng</keyname><forenames>Shaojuan</forenames></author></authors><title>A new scheme based on the Hermite expansion to construct lattice
  Boltzmann models associated with arbitrary specific heat ratio</title><categories>physics.comp-ph hep-lat physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1606.06107</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new lattice Boltzmann scheme associated with flexible specific heat ratio
is proposed. The new free degree is introduced via the internal energy
associated with the internal structure. The evolution equation of the
distribution function is reduced to two evolution equations. One is connected
to the density and velocity, the other is of the energy. A two-dimensional
lattice Boltzmann model and a three-dimensional lattice Boltzmann model are
derived via the Hermite expansion. The two lattice Boltzmann models are applied
to simulating the shock tube of one dimension. Good agreement between the
numerical results and the analytical solutions are obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06590</id><created>2016-08-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Salvi</keyname><forenames>Joshua D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maoil&#xe9;idigh</keyname><forenames>D&#xe1;ibhid &#xd3;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudspeth</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification of Bifurcations from Observations of Noisy Biological
  Oscillators</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.CB q-bio.NC</categories><comments>6 figures, 1 supporting material</comments><journal-ref>Biophysical Journal 111(4):798-812 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.bpj.2016.07.027</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Hair bundles are biological oscillators that actively transduce mechanical
stimuli into electrical signals in the auditory, vestibular, and lateral-line
systems of vertebrates. A bundle's function can be explained in part by its
operation near a particular type of bifurcation, a qualitative change in
behavior. By operating near different varieties of bifurcation, the bundle
responds best to disparate classes of stimuli. We show how to determine the
identity of and proximity to distinct bifurcations despite the presence of
substantial environmental noise.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07285</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Matthew A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Roberto P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puzia</keyname><forenames>Thomas H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mieske</keyname><forenames>Steffen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eigenthaler</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bovill</keyname><forenames>Mia Sauda</forenames></author></authors><title>The Survey of Centaurus A's Baryonic Structures (SCABS). I. Survey
  Description and Initial Source Catalogues</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 15 figures, 6 tables; submitted to MNRAS; full catalogues
  to be released upon publication</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new, wide-field, optical ($u'g'r'i'z'$) Dark Energy Camera
observations covering $\sim21\,{\rm deg}^2$ centred on the nearby giant
elliptical galaxy NGC5128 called &quot;The Survey of Centaurus A's Baryonic
Structures&quot; (SCABS). The data reduction and analysis procedures are described
including initial source detection, photometric and astrometric calibration,
image stacking, and point-spread function modelling. We estimate 50 and 90
percent, field-dependent, point-source completeness limits of at least
$u'=24.08$ and $23.62$ mag (AB), $g'=22.67$ and $22.27$ mag, $r'=22.46$ and
$22.00$ mag, $i'=22.05$ and $21.63$ mag, and $z'=21.71$ and $21.34$ mag. Deeper
imaging in the $u'$-, $i'$- and $z'$-bands provide the fainter limits for the
inner $\sim3\,{\rm deg}^2$ of the survey, and we find very stable photometric
sensitivity across the entire field of view. Source catalogues are released in
all filters including spatial, photometric, and morphological information for a
total of $\sim5\times10^5-1.5\times10^6$ detected sources (filter-dependent).
We finish with a brief discussion of potential science applications for the
data including, but not limited to, upcoming works by the SCABS team.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07290</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Lund</keyname><forenames>Mikkel N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>Sarbani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aguirre</keyname><forenames>V&#xed;ctor Silva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaplin</keyname><forenames>William J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serenelli</keyname><forenames>Aldo M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Rafael A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latham</keyname><forenames>David W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casagrande</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bieryla</keyname><forenames>Allyson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>Guy R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viani</keyname><forenames>Lucas S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchhave</keyname><forenames>Lars A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miglio</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soderblom</keyname><forenames>David R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>Jeff A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefanik</keyname><forenames>Robert P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Handberg</keyname><forenames>Rasmus</forenames></author></authors><title>Asteroseismology of the Hyades with K2: first detection of main-sequence
  solar-like oscillations in an open cluster</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables; accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Hyades open cluster was targeted during Campaign 4 (C4) of the NASA K2
mission, and short-cadence data were collected on a number of cool
main-sequence stars. Here, we report results on two F-type stars that show
detectable oscillations of a quality that allows asteroseismic analyses to be
performed. These are the first ever detections of solar-like oscillations in
main-sequence stars in an open cluster.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07297</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Payel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Angus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Binney</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizing stellar halo populations II: The age gradient in blue
  horizontal-branch stars</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>18 pages, 15 figures, 3 tables, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2167</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The distribution of Milky Way halo blue horizontal-branch (BHB) stars is
examined using action-based extended distribution functions (EDFs) that
describe the locations of stars in phase space, metallicity, and age. The
parameters of the EDFs are fitted using stars observed in the Sloan Extension
for Galactic Understanding and Exploration-II (SEGUE-II) survey that trace the
phase-space kinematics and chemistry out to ~70 kpc. A maximum a posteriori
probability (MAP) estimate method and a Markov Chain Monte Carlo method are
applied, taking into account the selection function in positions, distance, and
metallicity for the survey. The best-fit EDF declines with actions less steeply
at actions characteristic of the inner halo than at the larger actions
characteristic of the outer halo, and older ages are found at smaller actions
than at larger actions. In real space, the radial density profile steepens
smoothly from -2 at ~2 kpc to -4 in the outer halo, with an axis ratio ~0.7
throughout. There is no indication for rotation in the BHBs, although this is
highly uncertain. A moderate level of radial anisotropy is detected, with
$\beta_s$ varying from isotropic to between ~0.1 and ~0.3 in the outer halo
depending on latitude. The BHB data are consistent with an age gradient of
-0.03 Gyr kpc$^{-1}$, with some uncertainty in the distribution of the larger
ages. These results are consistent with a scenario in which older, larger
systems contribute to the inner halo, whilst the outer halo is primarily
comprised of younger, smaller systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07318</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Smolski</keyname><forenames>Viktor O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Honglei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vodopyanov</keyname><forenames>Konstantin L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Massively parallel dual-comb molecular detection with subharmonic
  optical parametric oscillators</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mid-infrared (mid-IR) spectroscopy offers unparalleled sensitivity for the
detection of trace gases, solids and liquids, which is based on the existence
of strong telltale vibrational bands in this part of the spectrum. It was shown
more than a decade ago that a dual-comb Fourier spectroscopy could provide
superior spectral coverage combined with high resolution and extremely fast
data acquisition. Capabilities of this method were limited because of
difficulty of producing twins of mutually coherent frequency combs in the mid-
IR. Here we report a phase-coherent and broadband dual-comb system that is
based on a pair of subharmonic (frequency-divide-by-two) optical parametric
oscillators, pumped in turn by two phase-locked thulium fiber lasers at
2-micron wavelength. We demonstrate simultaneous detection of multiple
molecular species in the whole band of 3.2-5.3 microns (frequency span 1200
cm^{-1}) augmented by the pump laser band of 1.85-2 microns (span 400 cm^{-1}),
with spectral resolution 0.01-0.07 cm^{-1} and acquisition speed of up to
160,000 resolution elements in few seconds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07322</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Estrela</keyname><forenames>Raissa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valio</keyname><forenames>Adriana</forenames></author></authors><title>Stellar magnetic cycles in the solar-like stars Kepler-17 and Kepler-63</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ. 18 pages, 27 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The stellar magnetic field plays a crucial role in the star internal
mechanisms, as in the interactions with its environment. The study of starspots
provides information about the stellar magnetic field, and can characterise the
cycle. Moreover, the analysis of solar-type stars is also useful to shed light
onto the origin of the solar magnetic field. The objective of this work is to
characterise the magnetic activity of stars. Here, we studied two solar-type
stars Kepler-17 and Kepler-63 using two methods to estimate the magnetic cycle
length. The first one characterises the spots (radius, intensity, and location)
by fitting the small variations in the light curve of a star caused by the
occultation of a spot during a planetary transit. This approach yields the
number of spots present in the stellar surface and the flux deficit subtracted
from the star by their presence during each transit. The second method
estimates the activity from the excess in the residuals of the transit
lightcurves. This excess is obtained by subtracting a spotless model transit
from the lightcurve, and then integrating all the residuals during the transit.
The presence of long term periodicity is estimated in both time series. With
the first method, we obtained $P_{\rm cycle}$ = 1.12 $\pm$ 0.16 yr (Kepler-17)
and $P_{\rm cycle}$ = 1.27 $\pm$ 0.16 yr (Kepler-63), and for the second
approach the values are 1.35 $\pm$ 0.27 yr and 1.27 $\pm$ 0.12 yr,
respectively. The results of both methods agree with each other and confirm
their robustness.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07325</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Marvian</keyname><forenames>Iman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lloyd</keyname><forenames>Seth</forenames></author></authors><title>From clocks to cloners: Catalytic transformations under covariant
  operations and recoverability</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages+4 pages of Supplementary Material. Comments Welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are various physical scenarios in which one can only implement
operations with a certain symmetry. Under such restriction, a system in a
symmetry-breaking state can be used as a catalyst, e.g. to prepare another
system in a desired symmetry-breaking state. This sort of (approximate)
catalytic state transformations are relevant in the context of (i) state
preparation using a bounded-size quantum clock or reference frame, where the
clock or reference frame acts as a catalyst, (ii) quantum thermodynamics, where
again a clock can be used as a catalyst to prepare states which contain
coherence with respect to the system Hamiltonian, and (iii) cloning of unknown
quantum states, where the given copies of state can be interpreted as a
catalyst for preparing the new copies. Using a recent result of Fawzi and
Renner on approximate recoverability, we show that the achievable accuracy in
this kind of catalytic transformations can be determined by a single function,
namely the relative entropy of asymmetry, which is equal to the difference
between the entropy of state and its symmetrized version: if the desired state
transition does not require a large increase of this quantity, then it can be
implemented with high fidelity using only symmetric operations. Our lower bound
on the achievable fidelity is tight in the case of cloners, and can be achieved
using the Petz recovery map, which interestingly turns out to be the optimal
cloning map found by Werner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07333</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Adkins</keyname><forenames>Gregory S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Angular decomposition of tensor products of a vector</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The tensor product of $L$ copies of a single vector, such as $p_{i_1} ...
p_{i_L}$, can be analyzed in terms of angular momentum. When $p_{i_1} ...
p_{i_L}$ is decomposed into a sum of components $( p_{i_1} ... p_{i_L}
)^L_\ell$, each characterized by angular momentum $\ell$, the components are in
general complicated functions of the $p_i$ vectors, especially so for large
$\ell$. We obtain a compact expression for $( p_{i_1} ... p_{i_L} )^L_\ell$
explicitly in terms of the $p_i$ valid for all $L$ and $\ell$. We use this
decomposition to perform three-dimensional Fourier transforms of functions like
$p^n \hat p_{i_1} ... \hat p_{i_L}$ that are useful in describing particle
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07359</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07359</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dine</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Scalars and the Cosmos: Nambu-Goldstone and Otherwise</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Talk at Nambu Memorial Symposium, 2016; 17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This talk focuses on the role of light scalars in cosmology, both Nambu
Goldstone bosons and pseudo moduli. The former include QCD axions, which might
constitute the dark matter, and more general axions, which, under certain
conditions, might play the role of inflatons, implementing {\it natural
inflation}. The latter are the actors in (generalized) hybrid inflation. They
rather naturally yield large field inflation, even mimicking chaotic inflation
for suitable ranges of parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07360</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly polarized components of integrated pulse profiles</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures,Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1956</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Highly polarized components of pulse profiles are investigated by analyzing
observational data and simulating the emission processes. The highly polarized
components appear at the leading or trailing part of a pulse profile, which
preferably have a flat spectrum and a flat polarization angle curve compared
with the low polarized components. By considering the emission processes and
propagation effects, we simulate the distributions of wave modes and fractional
linear polarization within the entire pulsar emission beam. We show that the
highly polarized components can appear at the leading, central, and/or trailing
parts of pulse profiles in the models, depending on pulsar geometry. The
depolarization is caused by orthogonal modes or scattering. When a sight line
cuts across pulsar emission beam with a small impact angle, the detected highly
polarized component will be of the O mode, and have a flat polarization angle
curve and/or a flat spectrum as observed. Otherwise, the highly polarized
component will be of the X mode and have a steep polarization angle curve.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07363</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Opoku</keyname><forenames>Alex A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edusei</keyname><forenames>Kwame Owusu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ansah</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Transition in Conditional Curie-Weiss Model</title><categories>math.PR physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proposes a conditional Curie-Weiss model as a model for opinion
formation in a society polarized along two opinions, say opinions 1 and 2. The
model comes with interaction strength $\beta&gt;0$ and bais $h$. Here the
population in question is divided into three main groups, namely: Group one
consisting of individuals who have decided on opinion 1. Let the proportion of
this group be given by $s$. Group two consisting of individauls who have chosen
opinion 2. Let $r$ be their proportion.
  Group three consisting of individuals who are yet to decide and they will
decide based on their environmental conditions. Let $1-s-r$ be the proportion
of this group. We show that the specific magnetization of the associated
conditional Curie-Weiss model has a first order phase transition (discontinuous
jump in specific magnetization) at $\beta^*=\left(1-s-r\right)^{-1}$. It is
also shown that not all the discontinuous jumps in magnetization will result in
phase change. We point out how an extention of this model could serve as a
random field Curie-Weiss model where the random field distribution has
nonvanishing mean.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07380</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jalal</keyname><forenames>Somenath</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Ising Systems, Edge Modes, and Rabi Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>School of Physical Sciences, Jawaharlal Nehru University, New Delhi,
  India, Ph.D. thesis, 127 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The thesis contains theoretical study of number of systems in low dimension,
which are related to quantum Ising model. The main results are emergence of
Majorana fermions in condensed matter system. We discuss an array of cavity-QED
system, describing atom-photon (spin-boson) interacting problem, namely Rabi
lattice model, and calculated its phase diagram. More importantly we showed
that in any dimension, the system has Ising dynamics in strong atom-photon
coupling limit. For 1D, a special relation between end-to-end spin-spin
correlation is presented, which is very much different form the bulk spin-spin
correlation. The entanglement between cavities is calculated and shown to have
maximum value at the phase transition point. Other problems we studied were the
frustrated quantum Ising model and its phase diagram as well as existence of
Majorana like edge modes in different phases of the model. The fermionic
version of the frustrated quantum Ising problem is also presented. On a
different but related note, we present some beautiful results on Falicov
Kimball (FK) model, a fermionic model similar to Hubbard model, on a square
lattice. Using a canonical representation for electrons (invented by Brijesh
Kumar), the FK model is mapped to classical Ising model (at infinite Hubbard
interaction limit) on 2D lattice. We performed classical Monte Carlo simulation
to study magnetization as a function of Hubbard interaction and also as a
function of temperature. The motivation was to study (quantum) charge
fluctuation (thus, quantum fluctuation of top of classical Ising
thermodynamics) due to finite Hubbard interaction term.
  We also devote a chapter for basic numerical techniques, such as Density
matrix Renormalization Group method, Exact diagonalization for spin system and
classical Monte Carlo simulation (for classical 2D Ising model), which we have
used in this thesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07381</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishiura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mushiake</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawazura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osawa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujinami</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yano</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saitoh</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamasaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kashyap</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakatsuka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuyama</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of Wave Electric Fields in Plasmas by Electro-Optic Probe</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>submitted to Review of Scientific Instruments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electric field measurement in plasmas permits quantitative comparison between
the experiment and the simulation in this study. An electro-optic (EO) sensor
based on Pockels effect is demonstrated to measure wave electric fields in the
laboratory magnetosphere of the RT-1 device with high frequency heating
sources. This system gives the merits that electric field measurements can
detect electrostatic waves separated clearly from wave magnetic fields, and
that the sensor head is separated electrically from strong stray fields in
circumference. The electromagnetic waves are excited at the double loop antenna
for ion heating in electron cyclotron heated plasmas. In the air, the measured
wave electric fields are in good absolute agreement with those predicted by the
TASK/WF2 code. In inhomogeneous plasmas, the wave electric fields in the
peripheral region are enhanced compared with the simulated electric fields. The
potential oscillation of the antenna is one of the possible reason to explain
the experimental results qualitatively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07387</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07387</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ioffe</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolevatova</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishnianidze</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>SUSY Method for the Three-Dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger Equation with
  Effective Mass</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>21 p.p</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters, A380 (2016) 3349-3354</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The three-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger equation with a position-dependent
(effective) mass is studied in the framework of Supersymmetrical (SUSY) Quantum
Mechanics. The general solution of SUSY intertwining relations with first order
supercharges is obtained without any preliminary constraints. Several forms of
coefficient functions of the supercharges are investigated and analytical
expressions for the mass function and partner potentials are found. As usual
for SUSY Quantum Mechanics with nonsingular superpotentials, the spectra of
intertwined Hamiltonians coincide up to zero modes of supercharges, and the
corresponding wave functions are connected by intertwining relations. All
models are partially integrable by construction: each of them has at least one
second order symmetry operator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07391</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07391</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Mads Kock</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borre</keyname><forenames>Camilla Clement</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lieberoth</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sherson</keyname><forenames>Jacob</forenames></author></authors><title>Knowledge Formation and Inter-Game Transfer With Classical and Quantum
  Physics</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, Work in Progress Paper for ECGBL '16</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to facilitate an intuitive understanding of classical physics
concepts we have developed Potential Penguin - a game where players manipulate
the landscape around a sliding penguin in order to control its movement. The
learning goal of Potential Penguin is to familiarize players with kinetic
energy and potential energy - the energies associated with movement and
position in the landscape respectively. The game levels introduce the concepts
one by one, as players are tasked with sliding the penguin through a landscape
towards a specific location, while keeping the velocity under control. When the
player manipulates the landscape, the potential energy of the penguin is
changed, which determines the penguin's movement. To build a strong connection
between theory and game the analytical expressions for kinetic and potential
energy are displayed during play with font sizes continually growing and
shrinking according to changes in each energy type. With Potential Penguin we
hope to study whether visualizing the amount of kinetic and potential energy
through visible mathematical expressions generates a connection between the
intuitive actions taken in the game and the underlying physics concepts. The
knowledge about kinetic and potential energy gained with Potential Penguin can
also be used to understand most of the physics behind the citizen science game
Quantum Moves, which has the goal of building a working quantum computer. The
two games share the principle of the core interaction - manipulating the
potential-energy landscape. We aim to investigate whether a proficiency and
understanding of Potential Penguin predicts a better performance in Quantum
Moves and a deeper understanding of the quantum physics behind that game.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07396</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07396</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagomarsino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sciortino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Controlled variation of the refractive index in ion-damaged diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 19 (5-6), 428-431 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2009.12.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A fine control of the variation of the refractive index as a function of
structural damage is essential in the fabrication of diamond-based optical and
photonic devices. We report here about the variation of the real part of the
refractive index at lambda=632.8 nm in high quality single crystal diamond
damaged with 2 and 3 MeV protons at low-medium fluences (10^13 - 10^17 ions
cm^-2). After implanting the samples in 125x125 um^2 areas with a raster
scanning ion microbeam, the variation of optical thickness of the implanted
regions was measured with laser interferometric microscopy. The results were
analyzed with a model based on the specific damage profile. The technique
allows the direct fabrication of optical structures in bulk diamond based on
the localized variation of the refractive index, which will be explored in
future works.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07402</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Endo</keyname><forenames>Takako</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawai</keyname><forenames>Hikari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konno</keyname><forenames>Norio</forenames></author></authors><title>Stationary measures for the three-state Grover walk with one defect in
  one dimension</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtain stationary measures for the one-dimensional three-state Grover walk
with one defect by solving the corresponding eigenvalue problem. We clarify a
relation between stationary and limit measures of the walk.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07404</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Rohit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Kishore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandy</keyname><forenames>Malay K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to Comment on Nonlocal quartic interactions and universality
  classes in perovskite manganites</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 0 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Comment [arXiv:cond-mat.stat.mech., 1602.02087v1 (2016)] has raised questions
claiming that the nonlocal model Hamiltonian presented in [Phys. Rev. E 92,
012123 (2015)] is equivalent to the standard (short-ranged) \Phi^4 theory.
These claims are based on a low momentum expansion of the interaction vertex
that cannot be applied to the vertex factors containing both low and high
momenta inside the loop-integrals. Elaborating upon the important steps of the
momentum shell decimation scheme, employed in the renormalization-group
calculation, we explicitly show the interplay of internal (high) and external
(low) momenta determining the loop integrals for self-energy and vertex
functions giving rise to corrections (to the bare parameters) different from
those of the standard (short-ranged) \Phi^4 theory. Employing explicit
mathematical arguments, we show that this difference persists when the range of
interaction is assumed to be long (short) ranged with respect to the lattice
constant (correlation-length), yielding the critical exponents as given in the
original paper.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07405</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellotti</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct fabrication and IV characterization of sub-surface conductive
  channels in diamond with MeV ion implantation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal B 75 (2), 127 132 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2009-00427-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work we report about the investigation of the conduction
mechanism of sp2 carbon micro-channels buried in single crystal diamond. The
structures are fabricated with a novel technique which employs a MeV focused
ion-beam to damage diamond in conjunction with variable thickness masks. This
process changes significantly the structural proprieties of the target
material, because the ion nuclear energy loss induces carbon conversion from
sp3 to sp2 state mainly at the end of range of the ions (few micrometers).
Furthermore, placing a mask with increasing thickness on the sample it is
possible to modulate the channels depth at their endpoints, allowing their
electrical connection with the surface. A single-crystal HPHT diamond sample
was implanted with 1.8 MeV He+ ions at room temperature, the implantation
fluence was set in the range 2.1x10^16 - 6.3x10^17 ions cm^-2, determining the
formation of buried micro-channels at 3 um. After deposition of metallic
contacts at the channels' endpoints, the electrical characterization was
performed measuring the I-V curves at variable temperatures in the 80-690 K
range. The Variable Range Hopping model was used to fit the experimental data
in the ohmic regime, allowing the estimation of characteristic parameters such
as the density of localized states at the Fermi level. A value of 5.5x10^17
states cm-3 eV-1 was obtained, in satisfactory agreement with values previously
reported in literature. The power-law dependence between current and voltage is
consistent with the space charge limited mechanism at moderate electric fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07409</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Re</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratesi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albonico</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multitechnique characterization of lapis lazuli for provenance study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Analytical and Bioanalytical Chemistry 395 (7), 2211 2217 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00216-009-3039-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lapis Lazuli is one of the oldest precious stone, being used for glyptic as
early as 7000 years ago: jewels, amulets, seals and inlays are examples of
objects produced using this material. Only few sources of Lapis Lazuli exist in
the world due to the low probability of geological conditions in which it can
form, so that the possibility to associate the raw material to man-made objects
helps to reconstruct trade routes. Since art objects produced using Lapis
Lazuli are valuable, only non-destructive investigations can be carried out to
identify the provenance of the raw materials. Ionoluminescence (IL) is a good
candidate for this task. Similarly to cathodoluminescence (CL), IL consists in
the collection of luminescence spectra induced by MeV ion (usually protons)
irradiation. The main advantage of IL consists in the possibility of working in
air while measuring simultaneously the composition of major and trace element
by means of complementary Ion Beam Analysis techniques like PIXE or PIGE
(Particle Induce X-ray or Gamma-ray Emission). In the present work a systematic
study of the luminescence properties of Lapis Lazuli under charged particles
irradiation is reported. In a first phase a multi-technique approach was
adopted (CL, SEM with microanalysis, micro-Raman) to characterise luminescent
minerals. This characterisation was propaedeutic for IL/PIXE/PIGE measurements
carried out on significant areas selected on the basis of results obtained
previously. Criteria to identify provenance of Lapis Lazuli from four of the
main sources (Afghanistan, Pamir Mountains in Tajikistan, Chile and Siberia)
were proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07416</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bravina</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zabrodin</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Directed flow in heavy-ion collisions at NICA: what is interesting to
  measure?</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, Contribution to the NICA White Paper (EPJA,
  topical issue)</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A52, 245 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16245-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the formation of the directed flow of hadrons in nuclear collisions
at energies between AGS and SPS in Monte Carlo cascade model. The slope of the
proton flow at midrapidity tends to zero (softening) with increasing impact
parameter of the collision. For very peripheral topologies this slope becomes
negative (antiflow). The effect is caused by rescattering of hadrons in
remnants of the colliding nuclei. Since the softening of the proton flow can be
misinterpreted as indication of the presence of quark-gluon plasma, we propose
several measurements at NICA facility which can help one to distinguish between
the cases with and without the plasma formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07427</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellotti</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budnyk</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colombo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksic</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giudice</keyname><forenames>A. Lo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manfredotti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastuovic</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Picollo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skukan</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittone</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct fabrication of three-dimensional buried conductive channels in
  single crystal diamond with ion microbeam induced graphitization</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>27 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Diamond and Related Materials 18, 870-876 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.diamond.2008.10.068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a novel method for the fabrication of three-dimensional buried
graphitic micropaths in single crystal diamond with the employment of focused
MeV ions. The use of implantation masks with graded thickness at the
sub-micrometer scale allows the formation of conductive channels which are
embedded in the insulating matrix at controllable depths. In particular, the
modulation of the channels depth at their endpoints allows the surface
contacting of the channel terminations with no need of further fabrication
stages. In the present work we describe the sample masking, which includes the
deposition of semi spherical gold contacts on the sample surface, followed by
MeV ion implantation. Because of the significant difference between the
densities of pristine and amorphous or graphitized diamond, the formation of
buried channels has a relevant mechanical effect on the diamond structure,
causing localized surface swelling, which has been measured both with
interferometric profilometry and atomic force microscopy. The electrical
properties of the buried channels are then measured with a two point probe
station: clear evidence is given that only the terminal points of the channels
are electrically connected with the surface, while the rest of the channels
extends below the surface. IV measurements are employed also to qualitatively
investigate the electrical properties of the channels as a function of
implantation fluence and annealing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07429</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Erokhin</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berkov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimization of nanocomposite materials for permanent magnets by
  micromagnetic simulations: effect of the intergrain exchange and the hard
  grains shape</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we perform the detailed numerical analysis of remagnetization
processes in nanocomposite magnetic materials consisting of magnetically hard
grains (i.e. grains made of a material with a high magnetocrystalline
anisotropy) embedded into a magnetically soft phase. Such materials are widely
used for the production of permanent magnets, because they combine the high
remanence with the large coercivity. We perform simulations of nanocomposites
with Sr-ferrite as the hard phase and Fe or Ni as the soft phase, concentrating
our efforts on analyzing the effects of ({\it i}) the imperfect intergrain
exchange and ({\it ii}) the non-spherical shape of hard grains. We demonstrate
that - in contrast to the common belief - the maximal energy product is
achieved not for systems with the perfect intergrain exchange, but for
materials where this exchange is substantially weakened. We also show that the
main parameters of the hysteresis loop - remanence, coercivity and the energy
product - exhibit non-trivial dependencies on the shape of hard grains, and
provide detailed explanations for our results. Simulation predictions obtained
in this work open new ways for the optimization of materials for permanent
magnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07432</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kedia</keyname><forenames>Sunita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Sucharita</forenames></author></authors><title>Random Laser Emission at Dual Wavelengths in a Donor-Acceptor Dye
  Mixture Solution</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The work was aimed to generate random laser emissions simultaneously at two
wavelengths in a weakly scattering system containing mixture of binary dyes,
rhodamine-B (Rh-B) and oxazine-170 (O-170) dispersed with ZnO nano-particles
served as scattering centres. Random lasing performances for individual Rh-B
dye were extensively studied for varying small signal gain/scatterer density
and found lasing threshold significantly depend upon number density of
dispersed nano-particles. In spite of inefficient pumping, we demonstrated
possibility of random lasing in O-170 dye solution on account of resonance
energy transfer from Rh-B dye served as donor. At optimum concentrations of
fluorophores and scatterer in dye mixture solution, incoherent random lasing
was effectively attained simultaneously at two wavelengths centered 90 nm
apart. Dual-emission intensities, lasing thresholds and rate of amplifications
were found to be equivalent for both donor and acceptor in dye mixture
solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07438</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Petkov</keyname><forenames>Vesselin</forenames></author></authors><title>Location and Weyl formula for the eigenvalues of some non self-adjoint
  operators</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>35P20 (Primary), 35P25 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a survey of some recent results concerning the location and the
Weyl formula for the complex eigenvalues of two non self-adjoint operators. We
study the eigenvalues of the generator $G$ of the contraction semigroup
$e^{tG}, \: t \geq 0,$ related to the wave equation in an unbounded domain
$\Omega$ with dissipative boundary conditions on $\partial \Omega$. Also one
examines the interior transmission eigenvalues (ITE) in a bounded domain $K$
obtaining a Weyl formula with remainder for the counting function $N(r)$ of
complex (ITE). The analysis is based on a semi-classical approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07457</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Salnikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetrization: AKSZ and beyond?</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>32 pages, including an appendix</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we describe multigraded generalizations of some constructions
useful for mathematical understanding of gauge theories: we perform a
near-at-hand generalization of the Aleksandrov--Kontsevich--Schwarz--Zaboronsky
procedure, we also extend the formalism of $Q$-bundles introduced first by A.
Kotov and T. Strobl. We compare these approaches studying some supersymmetric
sigma models important in theoretical physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07459</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Nissen</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiphasic interactions between nucleotides and target proteins</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft q-bio.BM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nucleotides guanosine tetraphosphate (ppGpp) and guanosine pentaphosphate
(pppGpp) bind to target proteins to promote bacterial survival (Corrigan et al.
2016). Thus, the binding of the nucleotides to RsgA, a GTPase, inhibits the
hydrolysis of GTP. The dose response, taken to be curvilinear with respect to
the logarithm of the inhibitor concentration, is instead much better (P&lt;0.001
when the 6 experiments are combined) represented as multiphasic, with high to
exceedingly high absolute r values for the straight lines, and with transitions
in the form of non-contiguities (jumps). Profiles for the binding of
radiolabeled nucleotides to HprT and Gmk, GTP synthesis enzymes, were,
similarly, taken to be curvilinear with respect to the logarithm of the protein
concentration. However, the profiles are again much better represented as
multiphasic than as curvilinear (the P values range from 0.047 to &lt;0.001 for
each of the 8 experiments for binding of ppGpp and pppGpp to HprT). The binding
of GTP to HprT and the binding of the three nucleotides to Gmk are also poorly
represented by curvilinear profiles, but well represented by multiphasic
profiles (straight and, in part, parallel lines).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07465</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chun</keyname><forenames>Hyunchae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Iris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faulkner</keyname><forenames>Grahame</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clarke</keyname><forenames>Larry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>Bryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>Glenn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capon</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niskanen</keyname><forenames>Antti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wabnig</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>OBrien</keyname><forenames>Dominic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bitauld</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Motion-Compensated Handheld Quantum Key Distribution System</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mobile devices have become an inseparable part of our everyday life. They are
used to transmit an ever-increasing amount of sensitive health, financial and
personal information. This exposes us to the growing scale and sophistication
of cyber-attacks. Quantum Key Distribution (QKD) can provide unconditional and
future-proof data security but implementing it for handheld mobile devices
comes with specific challenges. To establish security, secret keys of
sufficient length need to be transmitted during the time of a handheld
transaction (~1s) despite device misalignment, ambient light and user's
inevitable hand movements. Transmitters and receivers should ideally be compact
and low-cost, while avoiding security loopholes. Here we demonstrate the first
QKD transmission from a handheld transmitter with a key-rate large enough to
overcome finite key effects. Using dynamic beam-steering,
reference-frame-independent encoding and fast indistinguishable pulse
generation, we obtain a secret key rate above 30kb/s over a distance of 0.5m
under ambient light conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07469</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Golestanian</keyname><forenames>Ramin</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to Comment on &quot;Enhanced diffusion of enzymes that catalyze
  exothermic reactions&quot;</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>Reply to Comment arXiv:1608.05433</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Catalytically active enzymes have recently been observed to exhibit enhanced
diffusion. In a recent work [C. Riedel et al., Nature 517, 227 (2015)], it has
been suggested that this phenomenon is correlated with the degree of
exothermicity of the reaction, and a mechanism was proposed to explain the
phenomenon based on channeling the released heat into the center of mass
kinetic energy of the enzyme. I addressed this question by comparing four
different mechanisms, and concluded that collective heating is the strongest
candidate out of those four to explain the phenomenon, and in particular,
several orders of magnitude stronger than the mechanism proposed by Riedel et
al. In a recent preprint (arXiv:1608.05433), K. Tsekouras, C. Riedel, R.
Gabizon, S. Marqusee, S. Presse, and C. Bustamante present a comment on my
paper [R. Golestanian, Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 108102 (2015); arXiv:1508.03219],
which I address here in this reply.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07471</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07471</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Zare</keyname><forenames>Soroush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassanabadi</keyname><forenames>Hassan</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of Quasi-Oscillator in Position-Dependent Mass Formalism</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>any comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After introducing Schr\&quot;odinger equation within position- dependent mass
formalism, a quasi-oscillator has been considered. Eigen functions and energy
spectra have been obtained analytical. Then thermodynamic properties,
information entropy and uncertainty in coordinate and momentum corresponding
the considered system have calculated as well as some depicted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07478</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07478</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Ziwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lingyun</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying the $\rho$ resonance parameters with staggered fermions</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 034505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.034505</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We deliver a lattice study of $\rho$ resonance parameters with p-wave
$\pi\pi$ scattering phases, which are extracted by finite-size methods at one
center-of-mass frame and four moving frames for six MILC lattice ensembles with
pion masses ranging from $346$ to $ 176$ MeV. The effective range formula is
applied to describe the scattering phases as a function of the energy covering
the resonance region, this allows us to extract $\rho$ resonance parameters and
to investigate the quark-mass dependence. Lattice studies with three flavors of
the Asqtad-improved staggered fermions enable us to use the moving-wall source
technique on large lattice spatial dimensions ($L=64$) and small light $u/d$
quarks. Numerical computations are carried out at two lattice spacings, $a
\approx 0.12$ and $0.09$ fm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07479</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Lagomarsino</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivero</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vannoni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calusi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuntini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Massi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of light guiding in ion-implanted diamond</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 105, 233903 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.105.233903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the feasibility of fabricating light-waveguiding
microstructures in bulk single-crystal diamond by means of direct ion
implantation with a scanning microbeam, resulting in the modulation of the
refractive index of the ion-beam damaged crystal. Direct evidence of
waveguiding through such buried microchannels is obtained with a phase-shift
micro-interferometric method allowing the study of the multi-modal structure of
the propagating electromagnetic field. The possibility of defining optical and
photonic structures by direct ion writing opens a range of new possibilities in
the design of quantum-optical devices in bulk single crystal diamond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07480</id><created>2016-08-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Rajagopal</keyname><forenames>Adharsh</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical Management Techniques for Organic Solar Cells</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Thesis (M.S.)--University of Florida, 2014. Adviser: XUE,JIANGENG</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this thesis, two different optical management techniques for organics
based solar cells are explored. The first part is focused on the development of
a textured rear reflector for OPVs. The use of textured reflector (TR)
facilitates an increase in the optical path length along with light trapping
within the active layer. TR was fabricated through a relatively simpler
technique by depositing metal films over a microlens array (MLA). Zinc oxide
nanoparticles were used to minimize the shadowing effect. Using TR,
enhancements in short-circuit current density and power conversion efficiencies
up to 10-25% were demonstrated for a polymer based organic solar cell. The
second part is focused on improving the effectiveness of MLA incorporation in
OPVs. The increase in path length achieved using MLA can be improved by
increasing the refractive index of MLA and incorporating MLA directly on the
transparent electrode instead of glass substrate. This approach could avoid the
optical losses occurring at the interface between MLA and glass substrate and
increase the net path length of light within the active layer. Initial
experimental results are discussed to understand the potential of this
approach. Approximately, ~15% enhancement in short-circuit current density was
achieved by using MLA directly on the transparent electrode in ITO-free
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07501</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Andrade-II</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karapetyan</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deppman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernal-Castillo</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balabekyan</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demekhina</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adam</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzm&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Systematic study of actinide and pre-actinide fission modes</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we present new experimental data on mass distribution of
fission fragments from $^{241}$Am proton-induced fission at $660$ MeV measured
at the LNR Phasotron (JINR). The systematic analysis of several measured
fragment mass distributions from different fission reactions available in the
literature is also presented. The proton-induced fission of $^{241}$Am,
$^{237}$Np and $^{238}$U at 26.5, 62.9 and 660 MeV was studied. The
proton-induced fission of $^{232}$Th was studied at 26.5, 62.9 and 190 MeV. The
fission of $^{208}$Pb also by a proton was investigated at 190, 500 and 1000
MeV. The fission of $^{197}$Au was studied for 190 and 800 MeV protons.
Bremsstrahlung reactions with maximum photon energies of 50 and 3500 MeV were
studied for $^{232}$Th and $^{238}$U. The framework of the Random Neck Rupture
Model was applied in the analysis. The roles of the neutron excess and of the
so called fissility parameter were also investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07506</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author></authors><title>General Construction of Tubular Geometry</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>40 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of locally describing tubular geometry around a
submanifold embedded in a (pseudo)Riemannian manifold in its general form.
Given the geometry of ambient space in an arbitrary coordinate system and
equations determining the submanifold in the same system, we compute the
tubular expansion coefficients in terms of this {\it a priori data}. This is
done by using an indirect method that crucially applies the tubular expansion
theorem for vielbein previously derived. With an explicit construction
involving the relevant coordinate and non-coordinate frames we verify
consistency of the whole method up to quadratic order in vielbein expansion.
Furthermore, we perform certain (long and tedious) higher order computation
which verifies the first non-trivial spin connection term in the expansion for
the first time. Earlier a similar method was used to compute tubular geometry
in loop space. We explain this work in the light of our general construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07512</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goracke</keyname><forenames>Byron D.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dalton</keyname><forenames>Sean M.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Atmospheric constituents and surface-level UVB: implications for a
  paleoaltimetry proxy and attempts to reconstruct UV exposure during volcanic
  episodes</title><categories>physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>Access: http://authors.elsevier.com/a/1TcSd,Ig45ZtO</comments><doi>10.1016/j.epsl.2016.08.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chemical and morphological features of spores and pollens have been linked to
changes in solar ultraviolet radiation (specifically UVB, 280-315 nm) at
Earth's surface. Variation in UVB exposure as inferred from these features has
been suggested as a proxy for paleoaltitude. While UVB irradiance does increase
with altitude above sea level, a number of other factors affect the irradiance
at any given place and time. In this modeling study we use the TUV atmospheric
radiative transfer model to investigate dependence of surface-level UVB
irradiance and relative biological impact on a number of constituents in
Earth's atmosphere that are variable over long and short time periods. We
consider changes in O3 column density, and SO2 and sulfate aerosols due to
periods of volcanic activity, including that associated with the formation of
the Siberian Traps. We find that UVB irradiance may be highly variable under
volcanic conditions and variations in several of these atmospheric constituents
can easily mimic or overwhelm changes in UVB irradiance due to changes in
altitude. On the other hand, we find that relative change with altitude is not
very sensitive to different sets of atmospheric conditions. Any paleoaltitude
proxy based on UVB exposure requires confidence that the samples under
comparison were located at roughly the same latitude, under very similar O3 and
SO2 columns, with similar atmospheric aerosol conditions. In general, accurate
estimates of the surface-level UVB exposure at any time and location require
detailed radiative transfer modeling taking into account a number of
atmospheric factors; this result is important for paleoaltitude proxies as well
as attempts to reconstruct the UV environment through geologic time and to tie
extinctions, such as the end-Permian mass extinction, to UVB irradiance
changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07519</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chat&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Hugues</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manneville</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase Diagram of the Two-Dimensional Complex Ginzburg-Landau Equation</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>as a follow up of complains from readers, provides color pictures
  improving over the publisher's web version which displays badly resolved
  black-and-white scans of the figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 224 (1996) 348--368</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/0378-4371(95)00361-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  After a brief introduction to the complex Ginzburg-Landau equation, some of
its important features in two space dimensions are reviewed. A comprehensive
study of the various phases observed numerically in large systems over the
whole parameter space is then presented. The nature of the transitions between
these phases is investigated and some theoretical problems linked to the phase
diagram are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07528</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Santana</keyname><forenames>Octavio J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Silvania A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Leo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Araujo</keyname><forenames>Luis E. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak measurement og the composite Goo-Haenchen shift in the critical
  region</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 41, 3884-3887 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.003884</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By using a weak measurement technique, we investigated the interplay between
the angular and lateral Goos-Haenchen shift of a focused He-Ne laser beam for
incidence near the critical angle. We verified that this interplay dramatically
affects the composite Goos-Haenchen shift of the propagated beam. The
experimental results confirm theoretical predictions that recently appeared in
the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07535</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>Gabriela C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Leonardo S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>Fabiano L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forgerini</keyname><forenames>Fabricio L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex Network Analysis of Brazilian Power Grid</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Power Grids and other delivery networks has been attracted some attention by
the network literature last decades. Despite the Power Grids dynamics has been
controlled by computer systems and human operators, the static features of this
type of network can be studied and analyzed. The topology of the Brazilian
Power Grid (BPG) was studied in this work. We obtained the spatial structure of
the BPG from the ONS (electric systems national operator), consisting of
high-voltage transmission lines, generating stations and substations. The local
low-voltage substations and local power delivery as well the dynamic features
of the network were neglected. We analyze the complex network of the BPG and
identify the main topological information, such as the mean degree, the degree
distribution, the network size and the clustering coefficient to caracterize
the complex network. We also detected the critical locations on the network
and, therefore, the more susceptible points to lead to a cascading failure and
even to a blackouts. Surprisely, due to the characteristic of the topology and
physical structure of the network, we show that the BPG is resilient against
random failures, since the random removal of links does not affect
significantly the size of the largest cluster. We observe that when a fraction
of the links are randomly removed, the network may disintegrates into smaller
and disconnected parts, however, the power grid largest component remains
connected. We believe that the even a static study of the network topology can
help to identify the critical situations and also prevent failures and possible
blackouts on the network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07546</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Pauletti</keyname><forenames>Diogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Copetti</keyname><forenames>Marcus Vinicius Fontana</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic mapping of the physical properties of supernova remnant
  N\,49</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>9 pages, 14 figures. Accepted for publication in Astronomy and
  Astrophysics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical conditions inside a supernova remnant can vary significantly between
different positions. However, typical observational data are integrated data or
contemplate specific portions of the remnant. We study the spatial variation in
the physical properties of the N\,49 supernova remnant based on a spectroscopic
mapping of the whole nebula. Long-slit spectra were obtained with the slit
($\sim4\arcmin \times 1.03\arcsec$) aligned along the east-west direction from
29 different positions spaced by $2\arcsec$ in declination. A total of 3248 1D
spectra were extracted from sections of $2\arcsec$ of the 2D spectra. More than
60 emission lines in the range 3550\,\AA{} to 8920\,\AA{} were measured in
these spectra. Maps of the fluxes and of intensity ratios of these emission
lines were built with a spatial resolution of $2\arcsec \times 2\arcsec$. An
electron density map has been obtained using the [S\,{\sc
ii}]\,$\lambda6716/\lambda6731$ line ratio. Values vary from
$\sim$500\,cm$^{-3}$ at the northeast region to more than 3500 cm$^{-3}$ at the
southeast border. We calculated electron temperature using line ratio sensors
for the ions S$^{+}$, O$^{++}$, O$^{+}$, and N$^{+}$. Values are about
3.6$\times10^{4}$\,K for the O$^{++}$ sensor and about 1.1$\times10^{4}$\,K for
other sensors. The H$\alpha$/H$\beta$ ratio map presents a ring structure with
higher values that may result from collisional excitation of hydrogen. We
detected an area with high values of [N\,{\sc ii}]\,$\lambda6583$/H$\alpha$
extending from the remnant center to its northeastern border, that can be
indicating an overabundance of nitrogen in the area due to contamination by the
progenitor star. We found a radial dependence in many line intensity ratio
maps. We observed an increase toward the remnant borders of the intensity ratio
of any two lines in which the numerator comes before in a sequence of lines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07551</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07551</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Hamerly</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent LQG Control, Free-Carrier Oscillations, Optical Ising Machines
  and Pulsed OPO Dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph nlin.PS physics.optics</categories><comments>414 pages, 12 tables, 158 figures, 332 references. Stanford
  University PhD thesis. Readers: Harold Hwang, Surya Ganguli, Patrick Hayden</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Broadly speaking, this thesis is about nonlinear optics, quantum mechanics,
and computing. More specifically, it covers four main topics: Coherent LQG
Control, Free-Carrier Oscillations, Optical Ising Machines and Pulsed OPO
Dynamics. Tying them all together is a theory of open quantum systems called
the SLH model, which I introduce in Chapters 1-2. The SLH model is a general
framework for open quantum systems that interact through bosonic fields, and is
the basis for the quantum circuit theory developed in the text. Coherent LQG
control is discussed in Chapters 3-4, where I demonstrate that coherent
feedback outperforms measurement-based feedback for certain linear
quadratic-Gaussian (LQG) problems, and explain the discrepancy by the former's
simultaneous utilization of both light quadratures. Semiclassical
truncated-Wigner techniques for quantum-optical networks are discussed in
Chapter 5, leading to a thorough discussion of quantum noise in systems with
free-carrier nonlinearities (Chapter 6), comparison to the Kerr nonlinearity,
and potential applications for analog computing based on limit cycles and
amplification (Chapters 7-8). Ising machines based on optical parametric
oscillators (OPOs) are discussed in Chapters 9-10, the former focusing on large
1D and 2D networks of OPOs, and the latter on the dynamics of a single OPO in
the ultrafast, synchronously-pumped regime. Optical properties and design
considerations for silicon photonic waveguides are are treated in Chapter 11.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07556</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Longo</keyname><forenames>Savino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roney</keyname><forenames>John Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation Hardness of 30 cm Long CsI(Tl) Crystals</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>This is an author-created, un-copyedited version of an article
  accepted for publication/published in Journal of Instrumentation. IOP
  Publishing Ltd is not responsible for any errors or omissions in this version
  of the manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version of Record is
  available online at http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1748-0221/11/08/P08017</comments><journal-ref>S. Longo and J.M. Roney 2016 JINST 11 P08017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/08/P08017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of the degradation in performance of 30 cm long CsI(Tl)
scintillation crystals exposed to 1 MeV photon doses of 2, 10, 35, 100 and 1000
Gy are presented. The light yield, light yield longitudinal non-uniformity,
scintillation decay times, energy resolution and timing resolution of a set of
spare crystals from the BABAR and Belle experiments are studied as a function
of these doses. In addition, a model that describes the plateau observed in the
light output loss as a function of dose in terms of increase in concentrations
of absorption centres with irradiation is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07565</id><created>2016-08-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Koester</keyname><forenames>Benjamin P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grom</keyname><forenames>Galina</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKay</keyname><forenames>Timothy A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Patterns of Gendered Performance Difference in Introductory STEM Courses</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, submitted to Physical Review - Physics Education
  Research. Supplemental material at
  http://github.com/bkoester/PLA/tree/master/2016_paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Grades provide students with their primary performance feedback: signals
which affect academic choices. Variations in grading practice among courses
impose grade penalties (and bonuses) on students who take them. These grade
penalties are sometimes gendered. Using extensive data from the University of
Michigan, we report on patterns of grade penalty and gendered performance
difference across 116 large courses. We find that significant gendered
performance differences are ubiquitous in large introductory STEM lecture
courses. They are largely absent in both STEM labs and in lecture courses in
other disciplines. Exploring the features of these courses, we hypothesize that
evaluation methods used in STEM lecture courses interact with stereotype threat
to create these gendered performance differences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ph/0603008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ph/0603008</id><created>2006-03-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rai</keyname><forenames>Ajay Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandya</keyname><forenames>J N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinodkumar</keyname><forenames>P C</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-lying di-hadronic states in relativistic harmonic model</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, accepted to publish in Indian Journal of Physics</comments><journal-ref>Indian J Phys (2006) 80:387</journal-ref><abstract>  Di-hadronic molecules such as di-meson, meson-baryon and di-baryon states are
studied in the relativistic confinement model. We have computed the binding
energy of the di-hadronic systems like $K-N$, $\Pi-N$, $\rho-N$ etc., as
penta-quark states, 2$\pi$, $\rho-\rho$, $K-K^*$, $K^*-K^*$, $D-D^*$ etc. as
tetra-quark states and $N-N$, $N-\Delta$, $\Delta-\Delta$ etc. as di-baryonic
states using a molecular interaction provided by asymptotic expression of the
confined gluon exchange potential. We find the lowest penta-quark state lies in
the energy range of 1.180 - 2.247 GeV as predicted by other theoretical models.
The exotic states such as $f0 (0.982)$, $h1 (1.170)$, $f0 (1.70)$, $f2
(1.565)$, $f2 (1.95)$, $\psi(4.040)$ etc. are identified as the di-mesonic
hadron molecules. The low-lying di-baryon molecular states found to be in the
range of 1.990-2.907 GeV with their binding energies lying between 112-120 MeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-th/0309270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-29</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-th/0309270</id><created>2003-09-30</created><updated>2004-04-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Donagi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katz</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharpe</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of D-branes with Higgs vevs</title><categories>hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>46 pages, LaTeX; v2: typos fixed; v3: more typos fixed</comments><report-no>ILL-(TH)-03-09</report-no><journal-ref>Adv.Theor.Math.Phys. 8 (2005) 813-859</journal-ref><doi>10.4310/ATMP.2004.v8.n5.a3</doi><abstract>  In this paper we continue previous work on counting open string states
between D-branes by considering open strings between D-branes with nonzero
Higgs vevs, and in particular, nilpotent Higgs vevs, as arise, for example,
when studying D-branes in orbifolds. Ordinarily Higgs vevs can be interpreted
as moving the D-brane, but nilpotent Higgs vevs have zero eigenvalues, and so
their interpretation is more interesting -- for example, they often correspond
to nonreduced schemes, which furnishes an important link in understanding old
results relating classical D-brane moduli spaces in orbifolds to Hilbert
schemes, resolutions of quotient spaces, and the McKay correspondence. We give
a sheaf-theoretic description of D-branes with Higgs vevs, including nilpotent
Higgs vevs, and check that description by noting that Ext groups between the
sheaves modelling the D-branes, do in fact correctly count open string states.
In particular, our analysis expands the types of sheaves which admit on-shell
physical interpretations, which is an important step for making derived
categories useful for physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
