<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:50:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-08-12" from="2016-08-12" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1302.2931</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1302.2931</id><created>2013-02-12</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Izosimov</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author></authors><title>Flat bi-Hamiltonian structures and invariant densities</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>10 pages; Lett Math Phys (2016)</comments><doi>10.1007/s11005-016-0875-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A bi-Hamiltonian structure is a pair of Poisson structures $\mathcal P$,
$\mathcal Q$ which are compatible, meaning that any linear combination $\alpha
\mathcal P + \beta \mathcal Q$ is again a Poisson structure. A bi-Hamiltonian
structure $(\mathcal P, \mathcal Q)$ is called flat if $\mathcal P$ and
$\mathcal Q$ can be simultaneously brought to a constant form in a neighborhood
of a generic point. We prove that a generic bi-Hamiltonian structure $(\mathcal
P, \mathcal Q)$ on an odd-dimensional manifold is flat if and only if there
exists a local density which is preserved by all vector fields Hamiltonian with
respect to $\mathcal P$, as well as by all vector fields Hamiltonian with
respect to $\mathcal Q$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.7516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.7516</id><created>2013-05-26</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sverdlov</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>Connection between GRW &quot;spontaneous collapse&quot; and Mensky's &quot;restricted
  path integral&quot; models</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics, 46(7), 825-835 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0004-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we will show how Mensky's model of &quot;restricted path integrals&quot;
can be derived from GRW &quot;spontaneous collapse&quot; model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.5880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.5880</id><created>2013-07-19</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sverdlov</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>Mensky's path integral and photon mass</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is commonly assumed that zero and non-zero photon mass would lead to
qualitatively different physics. For example, massless photon has two
polarization degrees of freedom, while massive photon at least three. This
feature seems counter-intuitive. In this paper we will show that if we change
propagator by setting $i \epsilon$ (needed to avoid poles) to a finite value,
and also introduce it in a way that breaks Lawrentz symmetry, then we would
obtain the continuous transition we desire once the speed of the photons is
&quot;large enough&quot; with respect to &quot;preferred&quot; frame. The two transverse
polarization degrees of freedom will be long lived, while longitudinal will be
short lived. Their lifetime will be near-zero if $m \ll \sqrt{\epsilon}$, which
is where the properties of two circular polarizations arize. The $i \epsilon$
corresponds to the intensity of Mensky's &quot;continuous measurement&quot; and the short
lifetime of the longitudinal photons can be understood as the &quot;conversion&quot; of
quantum degrees of freedom (photons) into &quot;classical&quot; ones by the measurement
device (thus getting rid of the former). While the &quot;classical&quot; trajectory of
the longitudinal photons does arize, it plays no physical role due to quantum
Zeno effect: intuitively, it is similar to an electron being kept at a ground
state due to continuous measurement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.8007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.8007</id><created>2013-07-30</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boche</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Minglai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deppe</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#xf6;tzel</keyname><forenames>Janis</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical-Quantum Arbitrarily Varying Wiretap Channel: Ahlswede
  dichotomy, Positivity, Resources, Super Activation</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Quantum Information Processing, August 2016, pp. 1-43</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1384-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish Ahlswede dichotomy for arbitrarily varying classical-quantum
wiretap channels. This means that either the deterministic secrecy capacity of
an arbitrarily varying classical-quantum wiretap channel is zero or it equals
its randomness-assisted secrecy capacity. We analyze the secrecy capacity of
arbitrarily varying classical-quantum wiretap channels when the sender and the
receiver use various resources. It turns out that having randomness, common
randomness, and correlation as resources are very helpful for achieving a
positive deterministic secrecy capacity of arbitrarily varying
classical-quantum wiretap channels. We prove the phenomenon super-activation
for arbitrarily varying classical-quantum wiretap channels, i.e., if we use two
arbitrarily varying classical-quantum wiretap channels, both with zero
deterministic secrecy capacity together, they allow perfect secure
transmission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.6906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.6906</id><created>2014-10-25</created><updated>2015-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Silenko</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin precession of a particle with an electric dipole moment:
  contributions from classical electrodynamics and from the Thomas effect</title><categories>hep-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, final version</comments><journal-ref>Physica Scripta 90, 065303 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-8949/90/6/065303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The new derivation of the equation of the spin precession is given for a
particle possessing electric and magnetic dipole moments. Contributions from
classical electrodynamics and from the Thomas effect are explicitly separated.
A fully covariant approach is used. The final equation is expressed in a very
simple form in terms of the fields in the instantaneously accompanying frame.
The Lorentz transformations of the electric and magnetic dipole moments and of
the spin are derived from basic equations of classical electrodynamics. For
this purpose, the Maxwell equations in matter are used and the result is
confirmed by other methods. An antisymmetric four-tensor is correctly
constructed from the electric and magnetic dipole moments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07291</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07291</id><created>2015-02-25</created><updated>2015-04-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Martinello</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Checchin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassellino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melnychuk</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sergatskov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Flux Dynamics in Horizontally Cooled Superconducting Cavities</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 118, 044505 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4927519</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous studies on magnetic flux expulsion as a function of cooling details
have been performed for superconducting niobium cavities with the cavity beam
axis placed parallel respect to the helium cooling flow, and findings showed
that for sufficient cooling thermogradients all magnetic flux could be expelled
and very low residual resistance could be achieved. In this paper we
investigate the flux trapping and its impact on radio frequency surface
resistance when the resonators are positioned perpendicularly to the helium
cooling flow, which is representative of how superconducting radio-frequency
(SRF) cavities are cooled in an accelerator. We also extend the studies to
different directions of applied magnetic field surrounding the resonator.
Results show that in the cavity horizontal configuration there is a different
impact of the various field components on the final surface resistance, and
that several parameters have to be considered to understand flux dynamics. A
newly discovered phenomenon of concentration of flux lines at the cavity top
leading to cavity equator temperature rise is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05194</id><created>2015-04-20</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Josiah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bildsten</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Runaway During the Evolution of ONeMg Cores towards
  Accretion-Induced Collapse</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>20 pages, 17 figures, 2 tables; published in MNRAS, updated to
  reflect published erratum</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv1804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the evolution of degenerate electron cores primarily composed of the
carbon burning products oxygen, neon, and magnesium (hereafter ONeMg cores)
that are undergoing compression. Electron capture reactions on A=20 and A=24
isotopes reduce the electron fraction and heat the core. We develop and use a
new capability of the Modules for Experiments in Stellar Astrophysics (MESA)
stellar evolution code that provides a highly accurate implementation of these
key reactions. These new accurate rates and the ability of MESA to perform
extremely small spatial zoning demonstrates a thermal runaway in the core
triggered by the temperature and density sensitivity of the Ne-20 electron
capture reactions. Both analytics and numerics show that this thermal runaway
does not trigger core convection, but rather leads to a centrally concentrated
(r &lt; km) thermal runaway that will subsequently launch an oxygen deflagration
wave from the center of the star. We use MESA to perform a parameter study that
quantifies the influence of the magnesium mass fraction, the central
temperature, the compression rate, and uncertainties in the electron capture
reaction rates on the ONeMg core evolution. This allows us to establish a lower
limit on the central density at which the oxygen deflagration wave initiates of
$\rho_c &gt; 8.5 \times 10^9\, \textrm{g cm}^{-3}$. Based on previous work and
order-of-magnitude calculations, we expect objects which ignite oxygen at or
above these densities to collapse and form a neutron star. Calculations such as
these are an important step in producing more realistic progenitor models for
studies of the signature of accretion-induced collapse.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02593</id><created>2015-06-08</created><updated>2016-08-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nayak</keyname><forenames>Gouranga C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Proof of NRQCD Factorization at All Order in Coupling Constant in Heavy
  Quarkonium Production</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>Final Version, Accepted for Publication in Eur. Phys. J. C, 37 Pages
  Latex</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:448</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4297-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently the proof of factorization in heavy quarkonium production in NRQCD
color octet mechanism is given at next-to-next-to-leading order (NNLO) in
coupling constant by using diagrammatic method of QCD. In this paper we prove
factorization in heavy quarkonium production in NRQCD color octet mechanism at
all order in coupling constant by using path integral method of QCD. Our proof
is valid to all powers in the heavy quark relative velocity. We find that the
gauge invariance and the factorization at all order in coupling constant
require gauge-completed non-perturbative NRQCD matrix elements that were
introduced previously to prove factorization at NNLO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06584</id><created>2015-07-23</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Metsaev</keyname><forenames>R. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-cone AdS/CFT-adapted approach to AdS fields/currents, shadows, and
  conformal fields</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX-2e, 38+8 pages v2: Conclusion below eq.(7.54) and footnote 26
  added. Typos in eqs.(2.47) and (6.25) corrected</comments><report-no>FIAN-TD-2015-06</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light-cone gauge formulation of fields in AdS space and conformal field
theory in flat space adapted for the study of AdS/CFT correspondence is
developed. Arbitrary spin mixed-symmetry fields in AdS space and arbitrary spin
mixed-symmetry currents, shadows, and conformal fields in flat space are
considered on an equal footing. For the massless and massive fields in AdS and
the conformal fields in flat space, simple light-cone gauge actions leading to
decoupled equations of motion are found. For the currents and shadows, simple
expressions for all 2-point functions are also found. We demonstrate that
representation of conformal algebra generators on space of currents, shadows,
and conformal fields can be built in terms of spin operators entering the
light-cone gauge formulation of AdS fields. This considerably simplifies the
study of AdS/CFT correspondence. Light-cone gauge actions for totally symmetric
arbitrary spin long conformal fields in flat space are presented. We apply our
approach to the study of totally antisymmetric (one-column) and mixed-symmetry
(two-column) fields in AdS space and currents, shadows, and conformal fields in
flat space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08916</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Endres</keyname><forenames>Michael G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shindler</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiburzi</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker-Loud</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive photons: an infrared regularization scheme for lattice QCD+QED</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables; significant revisions to abstract and
  main text; revised presentation of results for clarity (results unchanged);
  acknowledgements updated; matches published version</comments><report-no>MIT-CTP/4691, JLAB-THY-15-2112, NT@WM-15-12</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 072002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.072002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Standard methods for including electromagnetic interactions in lattice
quantum chromodynamics calculations result in power-law finite-volume
corrections to physical quantities. Removing these by extrapolation requires
costly computations at multiple volumes. We introduce a photon mass to
alternatively regulate the infrared, and rely on effective field theory to
remove its unphysical effects. Electromagnetic modifications to the hadron
spectrum are reliably estimated with a precision and cost comparable to
conventional approaches that utilize multiple larger volumes. A significant
overall cost advantage emerges when accounting for ensemble generation. The
proposed method may benefit lattice calculations involving multiple charged
hadrons, as well as quantum many-body computations with long-range Coulomb
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02189</id><created>2015-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Peyskens</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhakal</keyname><forenames>Ashim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dorpe</keyname><forenames>Pol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Nicolas Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baets</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface enhanced Raman spectroscopy using a single mode
  nanophotonic-plasmonic platform</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Submitted to Nature Photonics</comments><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.5b00487</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface Enhanced Raman Spectroscopy (SERS) is a well-established technique
for enhancing Raman signals. Recently photonic integrated circuits have been
used, as an alternative to microscopy based excitation and collection, to probe
SERS signals from external metallic nanoparticles. However, in order to develop
quantitative on-chip SERS sensors, integration of dedicated nanoplasmonic
antennas and waveguides is desirable. Here we bridge this gap by demonstrating
for the first time the generation of SERS signals from integrated bowtie
nanoantennas, excited and collected by a single mode waveguide, and rigorously
quantify the enhancement process. The guided Raman power generated by a
4-Nitrothiophenol coated bowtie antenna shows an 8 x 10^6 enhancement compared
to the free-space Raman scattering. An excellent correspondence is obtained
between the theoretically predicted and observed absolute Raman power. This
work paves the way towards fully integrated lab-on-a-chip systems where the
single mode SERS-probe can be combined with other photonic, fluidic or
biological functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02369</id><created>2015-09-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Galisova</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of the exactly solvable spin-electron tetrahedral chain</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>3 pages, 5 figures, contribution to proceedings of The Eleventh
  International School on Theoretical Physics Symmetry and Structural
  Properties of Condensed Matter (SSPCM14) in Rzesz\'ow, Poland</comments><journal-ref>Acta Phys. Pol. A 128 (2015) 156-158</journal-ref><doi>10.12693/APhysPolA.128.156</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An exactly solvable spin-electron tetrahedral chain, where the Ising spins
localized at nodal lattice sites regularly alternate with three equivalent
lattice sites available for one mobile electron is considered. The system with
ferromagnetic interaction between the Ising spins and electrons exhibits an
enhanced magnetocaloric effect (MCE) in the limit $H/|J|\to 0$ when the entropy
is very small, whereas the system with antiferromagnetic interaction between
the Ising spins and electrons exhibits an enhanced MCE around the field $H/J=1$
when the entropy is sufficiently close to the value $S/2N =
\ln[(1+\sqrt{5})/2]$. We study the thermodynamics of the system in these field
regions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06367</id><created>2015-09-21</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bousquet</keyname><forenames>Gabriel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Triantafyllou</keyname><forenames>Michael S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slotine</keyname><forenames>Jean-Jacques E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic Solution to the Rayleigh Problem of Dynamic Soaring</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Albatrosses can travel a thousand kilometers daily over the oceans. This feat
is achieved through dynamic soaring, a non-flapping flight strategy where
propulsive energy is extracted from horizontal wind shears. Dynamic soaring has
been described as a sequence of half-turns connecting upwind climbs and
downwind dives through the surface shear layer. We analytically and numerically
investigate the aerodynamically optimal flight trajectory for varying shear
thicknesses. Contrary to current thinking, but consistent with GPS recordings
of flying albatrosses, in thin shears the optimal trajectory is composed of
small angle arcs. Essentially, the albatross is a flying sailboat, sequentially
acting as sail and keel, and most efficient when remaining crosswind. Our
analysis constitutes a general framework for dynamic soaring, and more broadly
energy extraction in complex winds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06491</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Sanchari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>Somenath</forenames></author></authors><title>Wien's Displacement Law in Rindler Space</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 Pages REVTEX file, a new section is added, conclusion part is
  rewritten</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we have developed the formalisms for the modified form of
Wien displacement laws for both the gas of electromagnetic waves and a gas of
de Broglie waves in Rindler space. In the case of de Broglie waves we assume
both fermion type and boson type materials. Following the classic work of Wien,
we assume that the wall of the enclosure containing the photon gas or the gas
of de Broglie waves, is expanding adiabatically with a uniform acceleration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03215</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benassi</keyname><forenames>Costanza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lees</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueltschi</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation inequalities for the quantum XY model</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><msc-class>82B10, 82B20, 82B26</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. 164, 1157-1166 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1580-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show the positivity or negativity of truncated correlation functions in
the quantum XY model with spin 1/2 (at any temperature) and spin 1 (in the
ground state). These Griffiths-Ginibre inequalities of the second kind
generalise an earlier result of Gallavotti.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00531</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2016-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lim</keyname><forenames>Charles Ci Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimality of semiquantum nonlocality in the presence of high
  inconclusive rates</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages + 3 figures. Presented in the 1st International Workshop on
  Trustworthy Quantum Information, 6/28-7/2, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor,
  Michigan, US; Similar to published version (references to quantum steering
  added)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 020101(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.020101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum nonlocality is a counterintuitive phenomenon that lies beyond the
purview of causal influences. Recently, Bell inequalities have been generalized
to the case of quantum inputs, leading to a powerful family of semi-quantum
Bell inequalities that are capable of detecting any entangled state. Here, we
focus on a different problem and investigate how the local-indistinguishability
of quantum inputs and postselection may affect the requirements to detect
semi-quantum nonlocality. To this end, we consider a semi-quantum nonlocal game
based on locally-indistinguishable qubit inputs and derive its postselected
local and quantum bounds by using a novel connection to the
local-distinguishability of quantum states. Interestingly, we find that the
postselected local bound is independent of the measurement efficiency and that
the Bell violation increases with lower measurement efficiencies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02083</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02083</id><created>2015-11-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Boyer</keyname><forenames>Timothy H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical Zero-Point Radiation and Relativity: The Problem of Atomic
  Collapse Revisited</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><journal-ref>Foundations of Physics 46, 880-890 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10701-016-0008-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physicists of the early 20th century were unaware of two aspects which
are vital to understanding some aspects of modern physics within classical
theory. The two aspects are: 1) the presence of classical electromagnetic
zero-point radiation, and 2) the importance of special relativity. In classes
in modern physics today, the problem of atomic collapse is still mentioned in
the historical context of the early 20th century. However, the classical
problem of atomic collapse is currently being treated in the presence of
classical zero-point radiation where the problem has been transformed. The
presence of classical zero-point radiation indeed keeps the electron from
falling into the Coulomb potential center. However, the old collapse problem
has been replaced by a new problem where the zero-point radiation may give too
much energy to the electron so as to cause self-ionization. Special relativity
may play a role in understanding this modern variation on the atomic collapse
problem, just as relativity has proved crucial for a classical understanding of
blackbody radiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07473</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Salehi</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author></authors><title>High-speed FSK Modulator Using Switched-capacitor Resonators</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>This article has been administratively withdrawn because of
  authorship dispute and retraction by the journal</comments><doi>10.1002/cta.2157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, an ultra-fast frequency shift-keying (FSK) modulation
technique based on switched capacitor resonators is presented. It is
demonstrated that switching a reactive component such as a capacitor, in a
high-Q resonator with proper switching signal can preserve the stored energy
and shift it to a different frequency. Switching boundaries are found by
continuity of electric charge and magnetic flux. It is shown that if switching
time is synchronous with zero crossing of the voltage signal across the
switched capacitor, impulsive components can be avoided and continuity of
electric charge is satisfied without energy dissipation. We use this property
to realize a fast binary frequency-shift keying (FSK) modulator with only a
single RF source. In this technique, the modulation rate is independent of the
resonator bandwidth and can be as high as the lower carrier frequency.
Experimental results are presented to validate the simulations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01765</id><created>2015-12-06</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Antognini</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author></authors><title>Muonic atoms and the nuclear structure</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>ICOLS 2015, Singapore. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1509.03235</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-precision laser spectroscopy of atomic energy levels enables the
measurement of nuclear properties. Sensitivity to these properties is
particularly enhanced in muonic atoms which are bound systems of a muon and a
nucleus. Exemplary is the measurement of the proton charge radius from muonic
hydrogen performed by the CREMA collaboration which resulted in an order of
magnitude more precise charge radius as extracted from other methods but at a
variance of 7 standard deviations. Here, we summarize the role of muonic atoms
for the extraction of nuclear charge radii, we present the status of the so
called &quot;proton charge radius puzzle&quot;, and we sketch how muonic atoms can be
used to infer also the magnetic nuclear radii, demonstrating again an
interesting interplay between atomic and particle/nuclear physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04029</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04029</id><created>2015-12-13</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Najarbashi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seifi</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum phase transition in the Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya interaction with
  inhomogeneous magnetic field: Geometric approach</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 7 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:quant-ph/0212133 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we generalize the results of S. Oh (Physics Letters A. 644-647
\textbf{373 }) to Dzyaloshinski-Moriya model under nonuniform external magnetic
field to investigate the relation between entanglement, geometric phase (or
Berry phase) and quantum phase transition. We use quaternionic representation
to relate the geometric phase to the quantum phase transition. For small values
of DM parameter, the Berry phase is more appropriate than the concurrence
measure, while for large values, the concurrence is a good indicator to show
the phase transition. On the other hand, by increasing the DM interaction the
phase transition occurs for large values of anisotropy parameter. In addition,
for small values of magnetic field the concurrence measure is appropriate
indicator for quantum phase transition, but for large values of magnetic field
the Berry phase shows a sharp changes in the phase transition points. The
results show that the Berry phase and concurrence form a complementary system
from phase transition point of view.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06680</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Akashi</keyname><forenames>Ryosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sano</keyname><forenames>Wataru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arita</keyname><forenames>Ryotaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuneyuki</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible &quot;Magn\'eli&quot; phases and self-alloying in the superconducting
  sulfur hydride</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures. ver2: Tc calculation and Xray simulation added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 075503 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.075503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically give an infinite number of metastable crystal structures for
the superconducting sulfur hydride H$_{x}$S under pressure. It has been thought
that theoretically predicted structures of H$_{2}$S and H$_{3}$S exhibit low
and high $T_{\rm c}$ in the experiment, respectively. The newly found
structures are long-period modulated crystals where slab-like H$_{2}$S and
H$_{3}$S regions intergrow in a microscopic scale. The extremely small
formation enthalpy for the H$_{2}$S--H$_{3}$S boundary indicated with the
first-principles calculations suggests possible alloying of these phases
through formation of local H$_{3}$S regions. The modulated structures and
gradual alloying transformations between them not only explain the peculiar
pressure dependence of $T_{\rm c}$ in sulfur hydride observed experimentally,
but also could prevail in the experimental samples under various compression
schemes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08794</id><created>2015-12-29</created><updated>2016-01-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fargion</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oliva</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ucci</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Why not any tau double bang in Icecube, yet?</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><report-no>C14-05-26.7</report-no><journal-ref>PoS FRAPWS2014 (2016) 028, ISSN: 18248039</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High Energy Neutrino Astronomy has been revealed by a sudden change in the
flavor composition around maximal energies since three years of recording in
ice km detector. However these discover didn' t led to any clear promised
Neutrino Astronomy land yet. No correlation with hard gamma sources was found.
Moreover the astrophysical spectra expected at Fermi value, seem to converge to
a softer value, also required to avoid any Glashow resonant neutrino signal. We
suggest a main solution within a composite flux ruled by prompt atmospheric
neutrinos. Nevertheless the recent discover of twentyone crossing muons at
hundreds TeVs had shown a first narrow overlapped doublet and a correlated
track with a peculiar hard UHECR event clustering pointing to a well known
microjet in bynary precession; these first connections hint for a non
negligible astrophysical component making neutrino astronomy anyway already
more than a hope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00180</id><created>2016-01-02</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Da-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>GRB/GW association: Long-short GRB candidates, time-lag, measuring
  gravitational wave velocity and testing Einstein's equivalence principle</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, published in The Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 827 (2016), Number 1, 75</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/827/1/75</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Short-duration gamma-ray bursts (SGRBs) are widely believed to be powered by
the mergers of compact binaries, such as binary neutron stars or possibly
neutron star-black hole binaries. Though the prospect of detecting SGRBs with
gravitational wave (GW) signals by the advanced Laser Interferometer
Gravitational-Wave Observatory (LIGO)/VIRGO network is promising, no known SGRB
has been found within the expected advanced LIGO/VIRGO sensitivity range for
binary neutron star systems. We find, however, that the two long-short GRBs
(GRB 060505 and GRB 060614) may be within the horizon of advanced GW detectors.
In the upcoming era of GW astronomy, the merger origin of some long-short GRBs,
as favored by the macronova signature displayed in GRB 060614, can be
unambiguously tested. The model-dependent time lags between the merger and the
onset of the prompt emission of the GRB are estimated. The comparison of such
time lags between model predictions and the real data expected in the era of
the GW astronomy would be helpful in revealing the physical processes taking
place at the central engine (including the launch of the relativistic outflow,
the emergence of the outflow from the dense material ejected during the merger,
and the radiation of gamma rays). We also show that the speed of GWs, with or
without a simultaneous test of Einstein's equivalence principle, can be
directly measured to an accuracy of $\sim 3\times 10^{-8}~{\rm cm~s^{-1}}$ or
even better in the advanced LIGO/VIRGO era. The Astrophysical Journal, Volume
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05101</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05101</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ingalls</keyname><forenames>James G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krick</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carey</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stauffer</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lowrance</keyname><forenames>Patrick J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grillmair</keyname><forenames>Carl J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buzasi</keyname><forenames>Derek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deming</keyname><forenames>Drake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diamond-Lowe</keyname><forenames>Hannah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evans</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morello</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevenson</keyname><forenames>Kevin B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capak</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glaccum</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>Seppo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surace</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Storrie-Lombardi</keyname><forenames>Lisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Repeatability and Accuracy of Exoplanet Eclipse Depths Measured with
  Post-Cryogenic Spitzer</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Astronomical Journal, Accepted 2016 May 26; 33 Pages; 19 figures</comments><journal-ref>AJ, 152, 44 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-6256/152/2/44</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the repeatability, reliability, and accuracy of differential
exoplanet eclipse depth measurements made using the InfraRed Array Camera
(IRAC) on the Spitzer Space Telescope during the post-cryogenic mission. We
have re-analyzed an existing 4.5 {\mu}m data set, consisting of 10 observations
of the XO-3b system during secondary eclipse, using seven different techniques
for removing correlated noise. We find that, on average, for a given technique,
the eclipse depth estimate is repeatable from epoch to epoch to within 156
parts per million (ppm). Most techniques derive eclipse depths that do not vary
by more than a factor 3 of the photon noise limit. All methods but one
accurately assess their own errors: for these methods, the individual
measurement uncertainties are comparable to the scatter in eclipse depths over
the 10 epoch sample. To assess the accuracy of the techniques as well as to
clarify the difference between instrumental and other sources of measurement
error, we have also analyzed a simulated data set of 10 visits to XO-3b, for
which the eclipse depth is known. We find that three of the methods (BLISS
mapping, Pixel Level Decorrelation, and Independent Component Analysis) obtain
results that are within three times the photon limit of the true eclipse depth.
When averaged over the 10 epoch ensemble, 5 out of 7 techniques come within 60
ppm of the true value. Spitzer exoplanet data, if obtained following current
best practices and reduced using methods such as those described here, can
measure repeatable and accurate single eclipse depths, with close to
photon-limited results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05497</id><created>2016-01-20</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Rong-Gen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Zong-Kuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author></authors><title>Dodging the cosmic curvature to probe the constancy of the speed of
  light</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, several corrections and updates to match the published
  version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a new model-independent method to probe the constancy of the speed
of light $c$. In our method, the degeneracy between the cosmic curvature and
the speed of light can be eliminated, which makes the test more natural and
general. Combining the independent observations of Hubble parameter $H(z)$ and
luminosity distance $d_L(z)$, we use the model-independent smoothing technique,
Gaussian processes, to reconstruct them and then detect variation of the speed
of light. We find no signal of deviation from the present value of the speed of
light $c_0$. Moreover, to demonstrate the improvement in probing the constancy
of the speed of light from future experiments, we produce a series of simulated
data. The Dark Energy Survey will be able to detect $\Delta c /c_0 \sim 1\%$ at
$\sim 1.5\sigma$ confidence level and $\Delta c /c_0 \sim 2\%$ at $\sim
3\sigma$ confidence level. If the errors are reduced to one-tenth of the
expected DES ones, it can detect a $\Delta c /c_0 \sim 0.1\%$ variation at
$\sim 2\sigma$ confidence level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00625</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Ana M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sundararaman</keyname><forenames>Ravishankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narang</keyname><forenames>Prineha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goddard</keyname><forenames>William A.</forenames><suffix>III</suffix></author><author><keyname>Atwater</keyname><forenames>Harry A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio phonon coupling and optical response of hot electrons in
  plasmonic metals</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages with 12 figures. SI includes tabulation of temperature and
  frequency dependent dielectric functions</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 075120 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.075120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrafast laser measurements probe the non-equilibrium dynamics of excited
electrons in metals with increasing temporal resolution. Electronic structure
calculations can provide a detailed microscopic understanding of hot electron
dynamics, but a parameter-free description of pump-probe measurements has not
yet been possible, despite intensive research, because of the phenomenological
treatment of electron-phonon interactions. We present ab initio predictions of
the electron-temperature dependent heat capacities and electron-phonon coupling
coefficients of plasmonic metals. We find substantial differences from
free-electron and semi-empirical estimates, especially in noble metals above
transient electron temperatures of 2000 K, because of the previously-neglected
strong dependence of electron-phonon matrix elements on electron energy. We
also present first-principles calculations of the electron-temperature
dependent dielectric response of hot electrons in plasmonic metals, including
direct interband and phonon-assisted intraband transitions, facilitating
complete theoretical predictions of the time-resolved optical probe signatures
in ultrafast laser experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03126</id><created>2016-02-08</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Riquelme</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verscharen</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author></authors><title>PIC Simulations of the Effect of Velocity Space Instabilities on
  Electron Viscosity and Thermal Conduction</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/824/2/123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In low-collisionality plasmas, velocity-space instabilities are a key
mechanism providing an effective collisionality for the plasma. We use
particle-in-cell (PIC) simulations to study the interplay between electron and
ion-scale velocity-space instabilities and their effect on electron pressure
anisotropy, viscous heating, and thermal conduction. The adiabatic invariance
of the magnetic moment in low-collisionality plasmas leads to pressure
anisotropy, $p_{\perp,j} &gt; p_{||,j}$, if the magnetic field $\vec{B}$ is
amplified ($p_{\perp,j}$ and $p_{||,j}$ denote the pressure of species $j$
[electron, ion] perpendicular and parallel to $\vec{B}$). If the resulting
anisotropy is large enough, it can in turn trigger small-scale plasma
instabilities. Our PIC simulations explore the nonlinear regime of the mirror,
ion-cyclotron, and electron whistler instabilities, through continuous
amplification of the magnetic field $|\vec{B}|$ by an imposed shear in the
plasma. In the regime $1 \lesssim \beta_j \lesssim 20$ ($\beta_j \equiv 8\pi
p_j/|\vec{B}|^2$), the saturated electron pressure anisotropy, $\Delta
p_e/p_{||,e}$, is determined mainly by the (electron-lengthscale) whistler
marginal stability condition, with a modest factor of $\sim 1.5-2$ decrease due
to the trapping of electrons by the mirrors. We explicitly calculate the mean
free path of the electrons and ions along the mean magnetic field and provide a
simple physical prescription for the mean free path and thermal conductivity in
low-collisionality $\beta_j \gtrsim 1$ plasmas. Our results imply that
velocity-space instabilities likely decrease the thermal conductivity of plasma
in the outer parts of massive, hot, galaxy clusters. We also discuss the
implications of our results for electron heating and thermal conduction in
low-collisionality accretion flows onto black holes, including Sgr A* in the
Galactic Center.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04460</id><created>2016-02-14</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Fu-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Si-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Da-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of the Tentative Association between GW150914 and a {\it
  Fermi}-GBM Transient</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>6 emulateapj pages including 2 eps figures, the version published in
  ApJL</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, 827: L16 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/827/1/L16</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The merger-driven Gamma-ray Bursts (GRBs) and their associated gravitational
wave (GW) radiation, if both successfully detected, have some far-reaching
implications, including for instance: (i) The statistical comparison of the
physical properties of the short/long-short GRBs with and without GW detection
can test the general origin model; (ii) Revealing the physical processes taking
place at the central engine; (iii) Measuring the velocity of the Gravitational
wave directly/accurately. In this work we discuss these implications in the
case of possible association of GW150914/ GBM transient 150914. We compared GBM
transient 150914 with other SGRBs and found that such an event {may be} a
distinct outlier in some statistical diagrams, possibly due to its specific
binary-black-hole merger origin. However, the presence of a &quot;new&quot; group of
SGRBs with &quot;unusual&quot; physical parameters is also possible. If the outflow of
GBM transient 150914 was launched by the accretion onto the nascent black hole,
the magnetic activity rather than the neutrino process is likely responsible
for the energy extraction and the accretion disk mass is estimated to be $\sim
10^{-5}~M_\odot$. The GW150914/GBM transient 150914 association, {if confirmed,
would} provide the first opportunity to directly measure the GW velocity and
its departure from the speed of the light {should be within} a factor of $\sim
10^{-17}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04534</id><created>2016-02-14</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Sound Velocity and Dielectric Shift in Glass: a
  Renormalization Technique for Mechanical and Dielectric Susceptibilities from
  Generic Coupled Block Model</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author, because the
  renormalization equation lacks a detailed discussion of the sign of the glass
  non-elastic susceptibility, which may lead to a qualitatively different
  conclusion compared to the current result in this paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Glass sound velocity shift was observed to be longarithmically temperature
dependent in both relaxation and resonance regimes: $\Delta c/c=\mathcal{C}\ln
T$. It does not monotonically increase with temperature from $T=0$K, but to
reach a maximum around a few Kelvin. Different from tunneling-two-level-system
(TTLS) which gives the slope ratio between relaxation and resonance regimes
$\mathcal{C}^{\rm rel }:\mathcal{C}^{\rm res }=-\frac{1}{2}:1$, we develop a
generic coupled block model to give $\mathcal{C}^{\rm rel }:\mathcal{C}^{\rm
res }=-1:1$, which agrees well with the majority of experimental measurements.
We use electric dipole-dipole interaction to carry out a similar behavior for
glass dielectric constant shift $\Delta \epsilon/\epsilon=\mathcal{C}\ln T$.
The slope ratio between relaxation and resonance regimes is $\mathcal{C}^{\rm
rel}:\mathcal{C}^{\rm res}=1:-1$ which agrees with dielectric measurements
quite well. By developing a renormalization procedure for non-elastic
stress-stress and dielectric susceptibilities, we prove these universalities
essentially come from $1/r^3$ long range interactions, independent of
materials' microscopic properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00450</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanakata</keyname><forenames>Paul Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>David K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Harold S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization and valley switching in monolayer group-IV
  monochalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94 (3), 035304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.035304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Group-IV monochalcogenides are a family of two-dimensional puckered materials
with an orthorhombic structure that is comprised of polar layers. In this
article, we use first principles calculations to show the multistability of
monolayer SnS and GeSe, two prototype materials where the direction of the
puckering can be switched by application of tensile stress or electric field.
Furthermore, the two inequivalent valleys in momentum space, which are dictated
by the puckering orientation, can be excited selectively using linearly
polarized light, and this provides an additional tool to identify the
polarization direction. Our findings suggest that SnS and GeSe monolayers may
have observable ferroelectricity and multistability, with potential
applications in information storage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02395</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02395</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Nagao</keyname><forenames>Kazuma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danshita</keyname><forenames>Ippei</forenames></author></authors><title>Damping of the Higgs and Nambu-Goldstone modes of superfluid Bose gases
  at finite temperatures</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>YITP-16-34</report-no><journal-ref>Progress of Theoretical and Experimental Physics, 063I01 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw061</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study collective modes of superfluid Bose gases in optical lattices at
commensurate fillings. We focus on the vicinity of the quantum phase transition
to the Mott insulator, where there exists the Higgs amplitude mode in addition
to the Nambu-Goldstone phase mode associated with the spontaneous U(1) symmetry
breaking. We analyze finite-temperature effects on the damping of the
collective modes by using an effective spin-1 model and the field theoretical
methods based on the finite-temperature Green's function. We calculate the
damping rates up to 1-loop order and evaluate them analytically and
numerically. We show that the damping rate of the Higgs mode increases with
increasing the temperature but it remains underdamped up to a typical
temperature achieved in experiments. Moreover, we find that the Nambu-Goldstone
mode attenuates via a Landau damping process resulting from interactions with
the Higgs mode and it can be overdamped at the typical temperature in a certain
parameter region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05672</id><created>2016-03-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Fallek</keyname><forenames>Spencer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herold</keyname><forenames>Creston</forenames></author><author><keyname>McMahon</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maller</keyname><forenames>Kara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Kenneth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amini</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport Implementation of the Bernstein-Vazirani Algorithm with Ion
  Qubits</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys.18(2016)083030</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/8/083030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using trapped ion quantum bits in a scalable microfabricated surface trap, we
perform the Bernstein-Vazirani algorithm. Our architecture relies upon ion
transport and can readily be expanded to larger systems. The algorithm is
demonstrated using two- and three-ion chains. For three ions, an improvement is
achieved compared to a classical system using the same number of oracle
queries. For two ions and one query, we correctly determine an unknown bit
string with probability 97.6(8)%. For three ions, we succeed with probability
80.9(3)%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00725</id><created>2016-04-03</created><updated>2016-06-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ch&#xe1;vez-Carlos</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastarrachea-Magnani</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lerma-Hern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirsch</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical chaos in atom-field systems</title><categories>nlin.CD cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 022209 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022209</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relation between the onset of chaos and critical phenomena, like Quantum
Phase Transitions (QPT) and Excited-State Quantum Phase transitions (ESQPT), is
analyzed for atom-field systems. While it has been speculated that the onset of
hard chaos is associated with ESQPT based in the resonant case, the
off-resonant cases show clearly that both phenomena, ESQPT and chaos, respond
to different mechanisms. The results are supported in a detailed numerical
study of the dynamics of the semiclassical Hamiltonian of the Dicke model. The
appearance of chaos is quantified calculating the largest Lyapunov exponent for
a wide sample of initial conditions in the whole available phase space for a
given energy. The percentage of the available phase space with chaotic
trajectories is evaluated as a function of energy and coupling between the
qubit and bosonic part, allowing to obtain maps in the space of coupling and
energy, where ergodic properties are observed in the model. Different sets of
Hamiltonian parameters are considered, including resonant and off-resonant
cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01305</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bury</keyname><forenames>Marcin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deak</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutak</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sapeta</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author></authors><title>Single and double inclusive forward jet production at the LHC at
  $\sqrt{s}$ = 7 and 13 TeV</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures, version accepted for PLB</comments><report-no>IFJPAN-IV-2016-6; CERN-TH-2016-077</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B, Volume 760, 10 September 2016, Pages 594-601</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a description of the transverse momentum spectrum of single
inclusive forward jets produced at the LHC, at the center-of-mass energies of 7
and 13 TeV, using the high energy factorization (HEF) framework. We
subsequently study double inclusive forward jet production and, in particular,
we calculate contributions to azimuthal angle distributions coming from double
parton scattering. We also compare our results for double inclusive jet
production to those obtained with the Pythia Monte Carlo generator. This
comparison confirms that the HEF resummation acts like an initial state parton
shower. It also points towards the need to include final state radiation
effects in the HEF formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01381</id><created>2016-03-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Koshev</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshev</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuzina</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Voltammetry: mathematical modelling and Inverse Problem</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Chemometrics and Intelligent Laboratory Systems, Vol.157, 2016,
  pp.78-84</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chemolab.2016.06.022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the fast semi-analytical method of modelling the polarization
curves in the voltammetric experiment. The method is based on usage of the
special func- tions and shows a big calculation speed and a high accuracy and
stability. Low computational needs of the proposed algorithm allow us to state
the set of Inverse Problems of voltammetry for the reconstruction of metal ions
concentrations or the other parameters of the electrolyte under investigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01438</id><created>2016-04-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Inclusive production of X$\rightarrow b\bar{b}$ plus a recoil for the
  LHC Run-II</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL (Europhysics Letters), 115 (2016) 11002</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/11002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This letter presents a study of the inclusive production of X$\rightarrow
b\bar{b}$ plus a recoil, using simulated samples of $pp$ collisions at
$\sqrt{s}=14$ TeV for an integrated luminosity in the range between 30
fb$^{-1}$ to 3 ab$^{-1}$. The case for experiments to include un-prescaled
$b$-tag multijet triggers for this topology is made and the ideal jet
thresholds are discussed. The sensitivity to Standard Model Higgs with a
transverse momentum of at least 200 GeV is evaluated with respect to a
continuous background, dominated by multijet processes. The mass of
$b$-jet-pairs is analysed, quoting sensitivity to cross-sections in the range
of 1 to 2 pb, for 100 fb$^{-1}$, covering the Higgs production cross section of
1.8 pb. The trigger strategy presented in this letter is compared to triggers
already in use, showing an increase on the signal efficiency for masses below
200 GeV and a performance comparable to a logic OR of all the currently
available akin triggers for higher masses. The robustness of the expected
sensitivity against systematic uncertainties is estimated by considering
various typical sources, such as those on the fitting parameters of the
continuous background, shape uncertainties affecting the signal acceptance and
the background modelling. The accuracy of a Higgs production cross section
measurements is also discussed, quoting sensitivity to deviations of 50% for
100 fb$^{-1}$ and 10% for 3 ab$^{-1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01456</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rollins</keyname><forenames>Jameson Graef</forenames></author></authors><title>Distributed State Machine Supervision for Long-baseline
  Gravitational-wave Detectors</title><categories>astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories><comments>Version 2: 11 pages, 9 figures. Submitted to Review of Scientific
  Instruments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Laser Interferometer Gravitational-wave Observatory (LIGO) consists of
two identical yet independent, widely-separated, long-baseline
gravitational-wave detectors. Each Advanced LIGO detector consists of complex
optical-mechanical systems isolated from the ground by multiple layers of
active seismic isolation, all controlled by hundreds of fast, digital, feedback
control systems. This article describes a novel state machine-based automation
platform developed to handle the automation and supervisory control challenges
of these detectors. The platform, called \textit{Guardian}, consists of
distributed, independent, state machine automaton nodes organized
hierarchically for full detector control. User code is written in standard
Python and the platform is designed to facilitate the fast-paced development
process associated with commissioning the complicated Advanced LIGO
instruments. While developed specifically for the Advanced LIGO detectors,
Guardian is a generic state machine automation platform that is useful for
experimental control at all levels, from simple table-top setups to large-scale
multi-million dollar facilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01488</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Munshi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yum</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rebhi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>An exacting transition probability measurement - a direct test of atomic
  many-body theories</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci Rep 6, 29772 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new protocol for measuring the branching fraction of hydrogenic atoms with
only statistically limited uncertainty is proposed and demonstrated for the
decay of the P$_{3/2}$ level of the barium ion, with precision below $0.5\%$.
Heavy hydrogenic atoms like the barium ion are test beds for fundamental
physics such as atomic parity violation and they also hold the key to
understanding nucleo-synthesis in stars. To draw definitive conclusion about
possible physics beyond the standard model by measuring atomic parity violation
in the barium ion it is necessary to measure the dipole transition
probabilities of low-lying excited states with precision better than $1\%$.
Furthermore, enhancing our understanding of the $\it{barium-puzzle}$ in barium
stars requires branching fraction data for proper modelling of
nucleo-synthesis. Our measurements are the first to provide a direct test of
quantum many-body calculations on the barium ion with precision below one
percent and more importantly with no known systematic uncertainties. The unique
measurement protocol proposed here can be easily extended to any decay with
more than two channels and hence paves the way for measuring the branching
fractions of other hydrogenic atoms with no significant systematic
uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01535</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01535</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-07-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongbao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Junkun</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero Temperature Holographic Superfluids with Two Competing Orders</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages, 9 figures. Refs added. Version to appear in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 046003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.046003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We initiate the investigation of the zero temperature holographic superfluids
with two competing orders, where besides the vacuum phase, two one band
superfluid phases, the coexistent superfluid phase has also been found in the
AdS soliton background for the first time. We construct the complete phase
diagram in the $e-\mu$ plane by numerics, which is consistent with our
qualitative analysis. Furthermore, we calculate the corresponding optical
conductivity and sound speed by the linear response theory. The onset of pole
of optical conductivity at $\omega=0$ indicates that the spontaneous breaking
phase always represents the superfluid phase, and the residue of pole is
increased with the chemical potential, which is consistent with the fact that
the particle density is essentially the superfluid density for zero temperature
superfluids. In addition, the resulting sound speed demonstrates the
non-smoothness at the critical points as the order parameter of condensate,
which indicates that the phase transitions can also be identified by the
behavior of sound speed. Moreover, as expected from the boundary conformal
field theory, the sound speed saturates to $\frac{1}{\sqrt{2}}$ at the large
chemical potential limit for our two band holographic superfluid model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01714</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-04-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chien</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shufeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature Dependence of Angular Momentum Transport Across Interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.054413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Angular momentum transport in magnetic multilayered structures plays a
central role in spintronic physics and devices. The angular momentum currents
or spin currents are carried by either quasi-particles such as electrons and
magnons, or by macroscopic order parameters such as local magnetization of
ferromagnets. Based on the generic interface exchange interaction, we develop a
microscopic theory that describes interfacial spin conductance for various
interfaces among non-magnetic metals, ferromagnetic and antiferromagnetic
insulators. Spin conductance and its temperature dependence are obtained for
different spin batteries including spin pumping, temperature gradient and spin
Hall effect. As an application of our theory, we calculate the spin current in
a trilayer made of a ferromagnetic insulator, an antiferromagnetic insulator
and a non-magnetic heavy metal. The calculated results on the temperature
dependence of spin conductance quantitatively agree with the existing
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02385</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Breton</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Cacqueray</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delagnes</keyname><forenames>&#xc9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grabas</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maalmi</keyname><forenames>Jihane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minafra</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Royon</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saimpert</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements of timing resolution of ultra-fast silicon detectors with
  the SAMPIC waveform digitizer</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>31 pages, 15 figures, accepted by Nuclear Inst. and Methods in
  Physics Research, A</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.08.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The SAMpler for PICosecond time (SAMPIC) chip has been designed by a
collaboration including CEA/IRFU/SEDI, Saclay and CNRS/LAL/SERDI, Orsay. It
benefits from both the quick response of a time to digital converter and the
versatility of a waveform digitizer to perform accurate timing measurements.
Thanks to the sampled signals, smart algorithms making best use of the pulse
shape can be used to improve time resolution. A software framework has been
developed to analyse the SAMPIC output data and extract timing information by
using either a constant fraction discriminator or a fast cross-correlation
algorithm. SAMPIC timing capabilities together with the software framework have
been tested using pulses generated by a signal generator or by a silicon
detector illuminated by a pulsed infrared laser. Under these ideal experimental
conditions, the SAMPIC chip has proven to be capable of timing resolutions down
to 4 ps with synthesized signals and 40 ps with silicon detector signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02798</id><created>2016-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wimmer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chadova</keyname><forenames>Kristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seemann</keyname><forenames>Marten</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;dderitzsch</keyname><forenames>Diemo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebert</keyname><forenames>Hubert</forenames></author></authors><title>A fully relativistic description of spin-orbit torques by means of
  linear response theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 tables, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 054415 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.054415</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Symmetry and magnitude of spin-orbit torques (SOT), i.e., current-induced
torques on the magnetization of systems lacking inversion symmetry, are
investigated in a fully relativistic linear response framework based on the
Kubo formalism. By applying all space-time symmetry operations contained in the
magnetic point group of a solid to the relevant response coefficient, the
torkance expressed as torque-current correlation function, restrictions to the
shape of the direct and inverse response tensors are obtained. These are shown
to apply to the corresponding thermal analogues as well, namely the direct and
inverse thermal SOT in response to a temperature gradient or heat current.
Using an implementation of the Kubo-Bastin formula for the torkance into a
first-principles multiple-scattering Green's function framework and accounting
for disorder effects via the so-called coherent potential approximation (CPA),
all contributions to the SOT in pure systems, dilute as well as concentrated
alloys can be treated on equal footing. This way, material specific values for
all torkance tensor elements in the fcc (111) trilayer alloy system Pt |
Fe$_x$Co$_{1-x}$ | Cu are obtained over a wide concentration range and
discussed in comparison to results for electrical and spin conductivity, as
well as to previous work - in particular concerning symmetry w.r.t.
magnetization reversal and the nature of the various contributions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05690</id><created>2016-04-19</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miranda</keyname><forenames>O. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tortola</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valle</keyname><forenames>J. W. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>New ambiguity in probing CP violation in neutrino oscillations</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures, matches published version</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-21</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 061804 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.061804</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  If neutrinos get mass via the seesaw mechanism the mixing matrix describing
neutrino oscillations can be effectively non-unitary. We show that in this case
the neutrino appearance probabilities involve a new CP phase, phi, associated
to non-unitarity. This leads to an ambiguity in extracting the &quot;standard&quot;
three--neutrino phase delta_CP, which can survive even after neutrino and
antineutrino channels are combined. Its existence should be taken into account
in the planning of any oscillation experiment aiming at a robust measurement of
delta_CP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06437</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06437</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-05-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Braun</keyname><forenames>Andreas P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watari</keyname><forenames>Taizan</forenames></author></authors><title>Heterotic-Type IIA Duality and Degenerations of K3 Surfaces</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>76 pages, 8 figures; v2: minor changes</comments><report-no>IPMU16-0055</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1608 (2016) 034</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2016)034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the duality between four-dimensional N=2 compactifications of
heterotic and type IIA string theories. Via adiabatic fibration of the duality
in six dimensions, type IIA string theory compactified on a K3-fibred
Calabi-Yau threefold has a potential heterotic dual compactification. This
adiabatic picture fails whenever the K3 fibre degenerates into multiple
components over points in the base of the fibration. Guided by monodromy, we
identify such degenerate K3 fibres as solitons generalizing the NS5-brane in
heterotic string theory. The theory of degenerations of K3 surfaces can then be
used to find which solitons can be present on the heterotic side. Similar to
small instanton transitions, these solitons escort singular transitions between
different Calabi-Yau threefolds. Starting from well-known examples of
heterotic--type IIA duality, such transitions can take us to type IIA
compactifications with unknown heterotic duals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08176</id><created>2016-04-27</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kaniewski</keyname><forenames>J&#x119;drzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic and nearly optimal self-testing bounds for the
  Clauser-Horne-Shimony-Holt and Mermin inequalities</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures. v2: fixed an inconsistency in specifying the
  extraction channel, improved presentation; v3: published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 070402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.070402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-testing refers to the phenomenon that certain extremal quantum
correlations (almost) uniquely identify the quantum system under consideration.
For instance observing the maximal violation of the CHSH inequality certifies
that the two parties share a singlet. While self-testing results are known for
several classes of states, in many cases they are only applicable if the
observed statistics are almost perfect, which makes them unsuitable for
practical applications. Practically relevant self-testing bounds are much less
common and moreover they all result from a single numerical method (with one
exception which we discuss in detail). In this work we present a new technique
for proving analytic self-testing bounds of practically relevant robustness. We
obtain improved bounds for the case of self-testing the singlet using the CHSH
inequality (in particular we show that non-trivial fidelity with the singlet
can be achieved as long as the violation exceeds $\beta^{*} = (16 + 14
\sqrt{2})/17 \approx 2.11$). In case of self-testing the tripartite GHZ state
using the Mermin inequality we derive a bound which not only improves on
previously known results but turns out to be tight. We discuss other scenarios
to which our technique can be immediately applied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00649</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00649</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kopp</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skordis</keyname><forenames>Constantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Dan B.</forenames></author></authors><title>An extensive investigation of the Generalised Dark Matter model</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>37 pages, 10 figures, minor changes to match to match Phys. Rev. D
  94, 043512 (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 043512 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.043512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Cold Dark Matter (CDM) model, wherein the dark matter is treated as a
pressureless perfect fluid, provides a good fit to galactic and cosmological
data. With the advent of precision cosmology, it should be asked whether this
simplest model needs to be extended, and whether doing so could improve our
understanding of the properties of dark matter. One established
parameterisation for generalising the CDM fluid is the Generalised Dark Matter
(GDM) model, in which dark matter is an imperfect fluid with pressure and shear
viscosity that fulfill certain closure equations. We investigate these closure
equations and the three new parametric functions they contain: the background
equation of state w, the speed of sound c_s^2 and the viscosity c_{vis}^2.
Taking these functions to be constant parameters, we analyse an exact solution
of the perturbed Einstein equations in a GDM-dominated universe and discuss the
main effects of the three parameters on the Cosmic Microwave Background (CMB).
Our analysis suggests that the CMB alone is not able to distinguish between the
GDM sound speed and viscosity parameters, but that other observables, such as
the matter power spectrum, are required to break this degeneracy. We also
consider other descriptions of imperfect fluids that have a non-perturbative
definition and relate these to the GDM model. In particular, we consider scalar
fields, an effective field theory (EFT) of fluids, an EFT of Large Scale
Structure, non-equilibrium thermodynamics and tightly-coupled fluids. These
descriptions could be used to extend the GDM model into the nonlinear regime of
structure formation, which is necessary if the wealth of data available on
those scales is to be employed in constraining the model. We also derive the
initial conditions for adiabatic and isocurvature perturbations and provide the
result in a form ready for implementation in Einstein-Boltzmann solvers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01891</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01891</id><created>2016-05-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Bilardello</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donadi</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinante</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bassi</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Bounds on collapse models from cold-atom experiments</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications, 462,
  764-782 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.06.134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spontaneous localization mechanism of collapse models induces a Brownian
motion in all physical systems. This effect is very weak, but experimental
progress in creating ultracold atomic systems can be used to detect it. In this
paper, we considered a recent experiment [1], where an atomic ensemble was
cooled down to picokelvins. Any Brownian motion induces an extra increase of
the position variance of the gas. We study this effect by solving the dynamical
equations for the Continuous Spontaneous Localizations (CSL) model, as well as
for its non-Markovian and dissipative extensions. The resulting bounds, with a
95% of confidence level, are beaten only by measurements of spontaneous X-ray
emission and by experiments with cantilever (in the latter case, only for rC &gt;
10^(-7) m, where rC is one of the two collapse parameters of the CSL model). We
show that, contrary to the bounds given by X-ray measurements, non-Markovian
effects do not change the bounds, for any reasonable choice of a frequency
cutoff in the spectrum of the collapse noise. Therefore the bounds here
considered are more robust. We also show that dissipative effects are
unimportant for a large spectrum of temperatures of the noise, while for low
temperatures the excluded region in the parameter space is the more reduced,
the lower the temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03800</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scaffidi</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigrist</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kallin</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames></author></authors><title>Leggett modes and multi-band superconductivity in Sr2RuO4</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Published version, 9 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 064508 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.064508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sr$_2$RuO$_4$ is a prototypical multi-band superconductor with three bands
crossing the Fermi level. These bands exhibit distinct dimensional
characteristics, with one quasi-2D $\gamma$-band and two quasi-1D $\alpha$- and
$\beta$-bands. This leads to the expectation that the superconductivity on the
$\gamma$-band may be only weakly Josephson-coupled to that on the other two
bands. Based on an explicit microscopic weak coupling calculation appropriate
for Sr$_2$RuO$_4$, we study the collective Leggett modes associated with the
relative phase oscillations between the bands and show that a relatively soft
Leggett mode exists due to the comparatively weaker inter-band Josephson
coupling. These calculations also provide insight into why the superconducting
gap magnitudes may be comparable on all three bands, despite the noticeable
differences between the $\gamma$ and $\alpha, \beta$ bands. The analyses can be
readily applied to other multi-band superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05249</id><created>2016-05-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Okninski</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized solutions of the Dirac equation, W bosons, and beta decay</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><msc-class>35Q41</msc-class><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, Volume 2016 (2016), Article ID
  2689742</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/2689742</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the 7x7 Hagen-Hurley equations describing spin 1 particles. We split
these equations, in the interacting case, into two Dirac equations with
non-standard solutions. It is argued that these solutions describe decay of a
virtual W boson in beta decay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08049</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-07-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garcia-Cely</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heeck</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author></authors><title>Indirect searches of dark matter via polynomial spectral features</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>19 pages, modified title, added references, minor changes. To appear
  in JCAP</comments><report-no>ULB-TH/16-07</report-no><journal-ref>JCAP08(2016)023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/08/023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the spectra arising from non-relativistic dark matter annihilations
or decays into intermediary particles with arbitrary spin, which subsequently
produce neutrinos or photons via two-body decays. Our approach is model
independent and predicts spectral features restricted to a kinematic box. The
overall shape within that box is a polynomial determined by the polarization of
the decaying particle. We illustrate our findings with two examples. First,
with the neutrino spectra arising from dark matter annihilations into the
massive Standard Model gauge bosons. Second, with the gamma-ray and neutrino
spectra generated by dark matter annihilations into hypothetical massive spin-2
particles. Our results are in particular applicable to the 750 GeV diphoton
excess observed at the LHC if interpreted as a spin-0 or spin-2 particle
coupled to dark matter. We also derive limits on the dark matter annihilation
cross section into this resonance from the non-observation of the associated
gamma-ray spectral features by the H.E.S.S. telescope.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01544</id><created>2016-06-05</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Yichao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>Xiaohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>Continuum dynamics of the formation, migration and dissociation of
  self-locked dislocation structures on parallel slip planes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jmps.2016.08.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In continuum models of dislocations, proper formulations of short-range
elastic interactions of dislocations are crucial for capturing various types of
dislocation patterns formed in crystalline materials. In this article, the
continuum dynamics of straight dislocations distributed on two parallel slip
planes is modelled through upscaling the underlying discrete dislocation
dynamics. Two continuum velocity field quantities are introduced to facilitate
the discrete-to-continuum transition. The first one is the local migration
velocity of dislocation ensembles which is found fully independent of the
short-range dislocation correlations. The second one is the decoupling velocity
of dislocation pairs controlled by a threshold stress value, which is proposed
to be the effective flow stress for single slip systems. Compared to the almost
ubiquitously adopted Taylor relationship, the derived flow stress formula
exhibits two features that are more consistent with the underlying discrete
dislocation dynamics: i) the flow stress increases with the in-plane component
of the dislocation density only up to a certain value, hence the derived
formula admits a minimum inter-dislocation distance within slip planes; ii) the
flow stress smoothly transits to zero when all dislocations become
geometrically necessary dislocations. A regime under which inhomogeneities in
dislocation density grow is identified, and is further validated through
comparison with discrete dislocation dynamical simulation results. Based on the
findings in this article and in our previous works, a general strategy for
incorporating short-range dislocation correlations in continuum models of
dislocations is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03389</id><created>2016-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Reis</keyname><forenames>R. D. dos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ajeesh</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arnold</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shekhar</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naumann</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicklas</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hassinger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the search for the chiral anomaly in Weyl semimetals: The negative
  longitudinal magnetoresistance</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 085006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/8/085006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the existence of massless chiral (Weyl) fermions has been
postulated in a class of semi-metals with a non-trivial energy dispersion.These
materials are now commonly dubbed Weyl semi-metals (WSM).One predicted property
of Weyl fermions is the chiral or Adler-Bell-Jackiw anomaly, a chirality
imbalance in the presence of parallel magnetic and electric fields. In WSM, it
is expected to induce a negative longitudinal magnetoresistance (NMR), the
chiral magnetic effect.Here, we present experimental evidence that the
observation of the chiral magnetic effect can be hindered by an effect called
&quot;current jetting&quot;. This effect also leads to a strong apparent NMR, but it is
characterized by a highly non-uniform current distribution inside the sample.
It appears in materials possessing a large field-induced anisotropy of the
resistivity tensor, such as almost compensated high-mobility semimetals due to
the orbital effect.In case of a non-homogeneous current injection, the
potential distribution is strongly distorted in the sample.As a consequence, an
experimentally measured potential difference is not proportional to the
intrinsic resistance.Our results on the MR of the WSM candidate materials NbP,
NbAs, TaAs, TaP exhibit distinct signatures of an inhomogeneous current
distribution, such as a field-induced &quot;zero resistance' and a strong dependence
of the `measured resistance&quot; on the position, shape, and type of the voltage
and current contacts on the sample. A misalignment between the current and the
magnetic-field directions can even induce a &quot;negative resistance&quot;.
Finite-element simulations of the potential distribution inside the sample,
using typical resistance anisotropies, are in good agreement with the
experimental findings. Our study demonstrates that great care must be taken
before interpreting measurements of a NMR as evidence for the chiral anomaly in
putative Weyl semimetals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03990</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aspelmeier</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katzgraber</keyname><forenames>Helmut G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface free-energy exponent in the one-dimensional Ising spin glass
  with long-range interactions in both the droplet and broken replica symmetry
  regions</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 022116 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.022116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The one-dimensional Ising spin-glass model with power-law long-range
interactions is a useful proxy model for studying spin glasses in higher space
dimensions and for finding the dimension at which the spin-glass state changes
from having broken replica symmetry to that of droplet behavior. To this end we
have calculated the exponent that describes the difference in free energy
between periodic and antiperiodic boundary conditions. Numerical work is done
to support some of the assumptions made in the calculations and to determine
the behavior of the interface free-energy exponent of the power law of the
interactions. Our numerical results for the interface free-energy exponent are
badly affected by finite-size problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04174</id><created>2016-06-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Martinello</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassellino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Checchin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melnychuck</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sergatskov</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zasadzinski</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of interstitial impurities on the field dependent microwave
  surface resistance of niobium</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 109, 062601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4960801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous work has demonstrated that the radio frequency surface resistance of
niobium resonators is dramatically reduced when nitrogen impurities are
dissolved as interstitial in the material. The origin of this effect is
attributed to the lowering of the Mattis and Bardeen surface resistance
contribution with increasing accelerating field. Meanwhile, an enhancement of
the sensitivity to trapped magnetic field is typically observed for such
cavities. In this paper we conduct the first systematic study on these
different components contributing to the total surface resistance as a function
of different levels of dissolved nitrogen, in comparison with standard surface
treatments for niobium resonators. Adding these results together we are able to
show for the first time which is the optimum surface treatment that maximizes
the Q-factor of superconducting niobium resonators as a function of expected
trapped magnetic field in the cavity walls. These results also provide new
insights on the physics behind the change in the field dependence of the Mattis
and Bardeen surface resistance, and of the trapped magnetic vortex induced
losses in superconducting niobium resonators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06358</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lamm</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebed</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>High Resolution Nonperturbative Light-Front Simulations of the True
  Muonium Atom</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, Matches PRD version except for additional
  references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 016004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.016004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Through the development of a parallel code called TMSWIFT, an extensive
light-front quantization study of the nonperturbative spectrum of the bound
state $(\mu^+\mu^-)$, true muonium, has been performed. Using Pad\'{e}
approximants, it has been possible to extract continuum and infinite-cutoff
limits for the singlet and triplet states for a range of values of the coupling
constant $\alpha$. This data set allows for an investigation of the $\alpha$
dependence of the light-front spectra, the results of which are compared to
standard calculations. Decay constants have also been obtained. Improved
calculations have been undertaken for the energy shifts due to the presence of
a second, lighter flavor ($e$). Finally, initial results for three-flavor ($e$,
$\mu$, $\tau$) calculations are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05304</id><created>2016-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Reithmann</keyname><forenames>Emanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reese</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frey</keyname><forenames>Erwin</forenames></author></authors><title>A nonequilibrium diffusion and capture mechanism ensures
  tip-localization of regulating proteins on dynamic filaments</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.SC</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, and 9 pages supplemental material (including 8
  figures and 1 table)</comments><report-no>LMU-ASC 032/16</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 078102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.078102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diffusive motion of regulatory enzymes on biopolymers with eventual capture
at a reaction site is a common feature in cell biology. Using a lattice gas
model we study the impact of diffusion and capture for a microtubule polymerase
and a depolymerase. Our results show that the capture mechanism localizes the
proteins and creates large-scale spatial correlations. We develop an analytic
approximation that globally accounts for relevant correlations and yields
results that are in excellent agreement with experimental data. Our results
show that diffusion and capture operates most efficiently at cellular enzyme
concentrations which points to in vivo relevance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07619</id><created>2016-07-26</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Belloni</keyname><forenames>Diogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giersz</keyname><forenames>Mirek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Askar</keyname><forenames>Abbas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leigh</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hypki</keyname><forenames>Arkadiusz</forenames></author></authors><title>MOCCA-SURVEY database I. Accreting white dwarf binary systems in
  globular clusters -- I. cataclysmic variables -- present-day population</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>21 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables; minor changes made to the text,
  accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1841</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, which is the first in a series of papers associated with
cataclysmic variables and related objects, we introduce the CATUABA code, a
numerical machinery written for analysis of the MOCCA simulations, and show
some first results by investigating the present-day population of cataclysmic
variables in globular clusters. Emphasis was given on their properties and the
observational selection effects when observing and detecting them. In this work
we analysed in this work six models, including three with Kroupa distributions
of the initial binaries. We found that for models with Kroupa initial
distributions, considering the standard value of the efficiency of the common
envelope phase adopted in BSE, no single cataclysmic variable was formed only
via binary stellar evolution, i. e., in order to form them, strong dynamical
interactions have to take place. We show and explain why this is inconsistent
with observational and theoretical results. Our results indicate that the
population of cataclysmic variables in globular clusters is, mainly, in the
last stage of their evolution and observational selection effects can
drastically change the expected number of observed cataclysmic variables. We
show that the probability of observing them during the outbursts is extremely
small and conclude that the best way of looking for cataclysmic variables in
globular clusters is by searching for variabilities during quiescence, instead
of during outbursts. For that, one would need a very deep observation which
could reach magnitudes $\gtrsim$ 27 mag. Finally, we argue that cataclysmic
variables in globular clusters are not necessarily magnetic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08042</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>Bernd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Long</keyname><forenames>Nguyen H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavropoulos</keyname><forenames>Phivos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;gel</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokrousov</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of complex disorder on skew-scattering Hall effects in
  $L1_0$-ordered FePt alloy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 060406(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.060406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show by first-principles calculations that the skew-scattering anomalous
Hall and spin-Hall angles of L$1_0$-ordered FePt drastically depend on
different types of disorder. A different sign of the AHE is obtained when
slightly deviating from the stoichiometric ratio towards the Fe-rich side as
compared to the Pt-rich side. For stoichiometric samples, short-range ordering
of defects has a profound effect on the Hall angles and can change them by a
factor of $2$ as compared to the case of uncorrelated disorder. This might
explain the vast range of anomalous Hall angles measured in experiments, which
undergo different preparation procedures and thus might differ in their
crystallographic quality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08052</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Gorji</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Late time cosmic acceleration from natural infrared cutoff?</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures, accepted for publication in PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 760 (2016) 769</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, inspired by the ultraviolet deformation of the
Friedmann-Lema\^{\i}tre-Robertson-Walker geometry in loop quantum cosmology, we
formulate an infrared-modified cosmological model. We obtain the associated
deformed Friedmann and Raychaudhuri equations and we show that the late time
cosmic acceleration can be addressed by the infrared corrections. As a
particular example, we applied the setup to the case of matter dominated
universe. This model has the same number of parameters as $\Lambda$CDM, but a
dynamical dark energy generates in the matter dominated era at the late time.
According to our model, as the universe expands, the energy density of the cold
dark matter dilutes and when the Hubble parameter approaches to its minimum,
the infrared effects dominate such that the effective equation of state
parameter smoothly changes from $w_{_{\rm eff}}=0$ to $w_{_{\rm eff}}=-2$.
Interestingly and nontrivially, the unstable de Sitter phase with $w_{_{\rm
eff}}=-1$ is corresponding to $\Omega_m=\Omega_d =0.5$ and the universe crosses
the phantom divide from the quintessence phase with $w_{_{\rm eff}}&gt;-1$ and
$\Omega_m&gt; \Omega_d$ to the phantom phase with $w_{_{\rm eff}}&lt;-1$ and $
\Omega_m&lt;\Omega_d$ which shows that the model is observationally viable. The
results show that the universe finally ends up in a big rip singularity for a
finite time proportional to the inverse of the minimum of the Hubble parameter.
Moreover, we consider the dynamical stability of the model and we show that the
universe starts from the matter dominated era at the past attractor with
$w_{_{\rm eff}}=0$ and ends up in a future attractor at the big rip with
$w_{_{\rm eff}}=-2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01215</id><created>2016-08-03</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galal</keyname><forenames>Hossam</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasmons and terahertz devices in graphene</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>The contents of this Master thesis has been formulated into the
  following research papers, submitted to Arxiv: 1) Multi-resonance split ring
  resonator structures at sub-terahertz frequencies (arXiv:1608.02729). 2)
  Split ring resonator resonance assisted terahertz antennas (arXiv:1608.01841)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a novel scheme for efficient manipulation and detection of
terahertz (THz) radiation. Our work consists of two parts; with a focus on
proving the concept of our novel scheme, and the exploitation of graphene's
peculiar properties.
  For the first part, we report on the successful demonstration of two
multiresonance Split Ring Resonator (SRR) designs, for efficient modulation of
THz frequency beams. The two designs are based on SRR intracoupling, with
multiple predefined resonances covering the bandwidth 40-300 GHz. The
simulation results obtained have been experimentally verified.
  The second part of the work reports on the computational development of novel
architectures of low-impedance broadband antennas, for efficient detection of
THz frequency beams. The conceived Split Ring Resonator-Resonance Assisted
(SRR-RA) antennas are based on both a capacitive and inductive scheme,
exploiting a 200 $\Omega$ and 400 $\Omega$ impedance, respectively. Moreover,
the impedance is tunable by varying the geometry's coupling parameters,
allowing for better matching with the detector circuit for maximum power
extraction. Our results have been obtained at simulation level for a 1.5 THz
operation frequency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03089</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Hui-Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fei</keyname><forenames>Shao-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li-Jost</keyname><forenames>Xianqing</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-observable Uncertainty Relations in Product Form of Variances</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures in Scientific Reports 2016</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6 (2016) 31192</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep31192</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the product form uncertainty relations of variances for
$n\,(n\geq 3)$ quantum observables. In particular, tight uncertainty relations
satisfied by three observables has been derived, which is shown to be better
than the ones derived from the strengthened Heisenberg and the generalized
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger uncertainty relations, and some existing uncertainty relation
for three spin-half operators. Uncertainty relation of arbitrary number of
observables is also derived. As an example, the uncertainty relation satisfied
by the eight Gell-Mann matrices is presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03295</id><created>2016-08-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Malijevsk&#xfd;</keyname><forenames>Alexandr</forenames></author></authors><title>Povrchov\'e f\'azov\'e p\v{r}echody a kritick\'e jevy</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Brief introduction to the theory of surface phase transitions at planar
interfaces, such as wetting phenomena (in Czech).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03320</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolognesi</keyname><forenames>Tommaso</forenames><affiliation>Istituto di Scienza e Tecnologie dell'Informazione &quot;A. Faedo&quot;, Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ciancia</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames><affiliation>Istituto di Scienza e Tecnologie dell'Informazione &quot;A. Faedo&quot;, Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nominal Cellular Automata</title><categories>cs.FL cs.LO nlin.CG</categories><comments>In Proceedings ICE 2016, arXiv:1608.03131</comments><proxy>EPTCS</proxy><journal-ref>EPTCS 223, 2016, pp. 24-35</journal-ref><doi>10.4204/EPTCS.223.2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The emerging field of Nominal Computation Theory is concerned with the theory
of Nominal Sets and its applications to Computer Science. We investigate here
the impact of nominal sets on the definition of Cellular Automata and on their
computational capabilities, with a special focus on the emergent behavioural
properties of this new model and their significance in the context of
computation-oriented interpretations of physical phenomena. A preliminary
investigation of the relations between Nominal Cellular Automata and Wolfram's
Elementary Cellular Automata is also carried out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03332</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03332</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhizhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Philip E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>Izabela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Huifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the Effect of Dissolved Hydrogen Sulfide on Mg2+-water Complex
  on Dolomite {104} Surfaces</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Physical Chemistry C 118.29 (2014): 15716-15722</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The key kinetic barrier to dolomite formation is related to the surface
Mg2+-H2O complex, which hinders binding of surface Mg2+ ions to the CO3 2- ions
in solution. It has been proposed that this reaction can be catalyzed by
dissolved hydrogen sulfide. To characterize the role of dissolved hydrogen
sulfide in the dehydration of surface Mg 2+ ions, ab initio simulations based
on density functional theory (DFT) were carried out to study the thermodynamics
of competitive adsorption of hydrogen sulfide and water on dolomite (104)
surfaces from solution. We find that water is thermodynamically more stable on
the surface with the difference in adsorption energy of -13.6 kJ/mol (in
vacuum) and -12.8 kJ/mol (in aqueous solution). However, aqueous hydrogen
sulfide adsorbed on the surface increases the Mg2+-H2O distances on surrounding
surface sites. Two possible mechanisms were proposed for the catalytic effects
of adsorbed hydrogen sulfide on the anhydrous Ca-Mg-carbonate crystallization
at low temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03357</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishihaya</keyname><forenames>Shinichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozuka</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwasa</keyname><forenames>Yoshihiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawasaki</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of Insulator-Metal Phase Transitions in Epitaxial Tungsten
  Oxide Films during Electrolyte-Gating</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>25 pages, 6 figures, ACS Applied Matter. in press</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An interface between an oxide and an electrolyte gives rise to various
processes as exemplified by electrostatic charge accumulation/depletion and
electrochemical reactions such as intercalation/decalation under electric
field. Here we directly compare typical device operations of those in electric
double layer transistor geometry by adopting ${A}$-site vacant perovskite
WO$_3$ epitaxial thin films as a channel material and two different
electrolytes as gating agent. $\textit{In situ}$ measurements of x-ray
diffraction and channel resistance performed during the gating revealed that in
both the cases WO$_3$ thin film reaches a new metallic state through multiple
phase transitions, accompanied by the change in out-of-plane lattice constant.
Electrons are electrostatically accumulated from the interface side with an
ionic liquid, while alkaline metal ions are more uniformly intercalated into
the film with a polymer electrolyte. We systematically demonstrate this
difference in the electrostatic and electrochemical processes, by comparing
doped carrier density, lattice deformation behavior, and time constant of the
phase transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03358</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03358</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhizhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Philip E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>Izabela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Huifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of the role of polysaccharide in the dolomite growth at
  low temperature by using atomistic simulations</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>Langmuir 31.38 (2015): 10435-10442</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dehydration of water from surface Mg2+ is most likely the rate-limiting step
in the dolomite growth at low temperature. Here, we investigate the role of
polysaccharide in this step using classical molecular dynamics (MD)
calculations. Free energy (potential of mean force, PMF) calculations have been
performed for water molecules leaving the first two hydration layers above the
dolomite (104) surface under the following three conditions: without catalyst,
with monosaccharide (mannose) and with oligosaccharide (three units of
mannose). MD simulations reveal that there is no obvious effect of
monosaccharide in lowering the dehydration barrier for surface Mg2+. However,
we found that there are metastable configurations of oligosaccharide, which can
decrease the dehydration barrier of surface Mg2+ by about 0.7-1.1 kcal/mol. In
these configurations, the molecule lies relatively flat on the surface and
forms a bridge shape. The hydrophobic space near the surface created by the
non-polar -CH groups of the oligosaccharide in the bridge conformation is the
reason for the observed reduction of dehydration barrier.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03361</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03361</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhizhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konishi</keyname><forenames>Hiromi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szlufarska</keyname><forenames>Izabela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Philip E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Huifang</forenames></author></authors><title>Z-contrast imaging and ab initio study on &quot;d&quot; superstructure in
  sedimentary dolomite</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>American Mineralogist 99.7 (2014): 1413-1419</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nano-precipitates with tripled periodicity along the c-axis are observed in a
Ca-rich dolomite sample from Proterozoic carbonate rocks with &quot;molar tooth&quot;
structure. This observation is consistent with previous description of d
reflections. High-angle annular dark-field STEM imaging (or Z-contrast imaging)
that avoids dynamic diffraction as seen in electron diffraction and
high-resolution TEM imaging modes, confirms that d reflections correspond to
nanoscale precipitates aligned parallel to (001) of the host dolomite. The
lamellae precipitates have a cation ordering sequence of Ca-Ca-Mg-Ca-Ca- Mg
along the c direction resulting in a chemical composition of Ca0.67Mg0.33CO3.
This superstructure is attributed to the extra or d reflections, thus is
referred to as the d superstructure in this study. The structure can be simply
described as interstratified calcite/dolomite. The crystal structure of the d
superstructure calculated from density functional theory (DFT) has a space
group of P31c and has a and c unit-cell parameters of 4.879 and 16.260 {\AA},
respectively, values between those of dolomite and calcite. The detailed
structural characteristics and parameters obtained from ab initio calculations
are also reported in this paper. The method of combining Z-contrast imaging and
ab initio calculations can be used for solving structures of other
nano-precipitates and nano-phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03363</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhizhang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konishi</keyname><forenames>Hiromi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Philip E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Huifang</forenames></author></authors><title>STEM investigation of exsolution lamellae and &quot;c&quot; reflections in Ca-rich
  dolomite from the Platteville Formation, western Wisconsin</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><journal-ref>American Mineralogist 98.4 (2013): 760-766</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dolomite crystals in partially dolomitized limestone from the Platteville
Formation are both compositionally and microstructurally heterogeneous. A
single dolomite crystal usually contains three phases: the host Ca-rich
dolomite [Ca1.14Mg0.86(CO3)2], an Fe-bearing dolomite
[Ca1.06Mg0.80Fe0.14(CO3)2], and calcite inclusions. These three phases show
similar orientations. The Ca-rich dolomite exhibits modulated microstructures
with wavelength ranging from 7 to 30 nm. The modulated microstructures are not
evident in Fe-bearing dolomite. Modulations in the Ca-rich dolomite have three
predominant orientation ranges in the studied sample: from (205) to (104), from
(001) to (-101), and ~(110), which are consistent with previous studies.
Bright-field (BF) and high-angle annular dark-field (HAADF) images confirm that
these modulations are due to chemical variation rather than strain or
diffraction contrast. The Ca-rich lamellae are Mg-rich calcite with
compositions ranging from Ca0.85Mg0.15CO3 to Ca0.70Mg0.30CO3. The observed
results indicate that these Ca-rich exsolution lamellae formed during
diagenesis. In this study, three kinds of &quot;c&quot;-reflections, which are weak spots
in the halfway position between the principal reflections along the (104)*,
(112)*, and (110)* directions, have been found in the diffraction patterns of
some Ca-rich dolomite. Mg-Ca ordering in x-y planes was not observed directly
in Z-contrast images. FFT patterns from the Z-contrast images do not show
&quot;c&quot;-reflections. STEM images confirm that the &quot;c&quot;-reflections could result from
multiple diffraction between the host dolomite and twinned Mg-calcite
nano-lamellae under TEM imaging and diffraction modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03364</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03364</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surendran</keyname><forenames>Prince</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jose</keyname><forenames>Smitha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Tien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrera</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitlock</keyname><forenames>Shannon</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLean</keyname><forenames>Russell</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sidorov</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannaford</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic lattices for ultracold atoms and degenerate quantum gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Science Bulletin (2016) 61(14):1097-1106</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11434-016-1123-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review recent developments in the use of magnetic lattices as a
complementary tool to optical lattices for trapping periodic arrays of
ultracold atoms and degenerate quantum gases. Recent advances include the
realisation of Bose-Einstein condensation in multiple sites of a magnetic
lattice of one-dimensional microtraps, the trapping of ultracold atoms in
square and triangular magnetic lattices, and the fabrication of magnetic
lattice structures with sub-micron period suitable for quantum tunnelling
experiments. Finally, we describe a proposal to utilise long-range interacting
Rydberg atoms in a large spacing magnetic lattice to create interactions
between atoms on neighbouring sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03366</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xiucong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravity Gradient Tensor Eigendecomposition for Spacecraft Positioning</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Guidance, Control, and Dynamics, Vol. 38, No. 11, 2015,
  pp.2200-2206</journal-ref><doi>10.2514/1.G001195</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Note, a new approach to spacecraft positioning based on GGT inversion
is presented. The gravity gradient tensor is initially measured in the
gradiometer reference frame (GRF) and then transformed to the Earth-Centered
Earth-Fixed (ECEF) frame via attitude information as well as Earth rotation
parameters. Matrix Eigen-Decomposition is introduced to directly translate GGT
into position based on the fact that the eigenvalues and eigenvectors of GGT
are simplespecific functions of spherical coordinates of the observation
position. without the need of an initial position. Unlike the strategy of
inertial navigation aiding, no prediction or first guess of the spacecraft
position is needed. The method makes use of the J2 gravity model, and is
suitable for space navigation where higher frequency terrain contributions to
the GGT signals can be neglected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03367</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03367</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xiucong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Pei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macabiau</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-Earth Orbit Determination from Gravity Gradient Measurements</title><categories>astro-ph.IM cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>34 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Acta Astronautica,Vol.123, 2016, pp.350-362</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.actaastro.2016.03.012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An innovative orbit determination method which makes use of gravity gradients
for Low-Earth-Orbiting satellites is proposed. The measurement principle of
gravity gradiometry is briefly reviewed and the sources of measurement error
are analyzed. An adaptive hybrid least squares batch filter based on
linearization of the orbital equation and unscented transformation of the
measurement equation is developed to estimate the orbital states and the
measurement biases. The algorithm is tested with the actual flight data from
the European Space Agency Gravity field and steady-state Ocean Circulation
Explorer. The orbit determination results are compared with the GPS-derived
orbits. The radial and cross-track position errors are on the order of tens of
meters, whereas the along-track position error is over one order of magnitude
larger. The gravity gradient based orbit determination method is promising for
potential use in GPS-denied spacecraft navigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03436</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Karsten</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Sergei D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aziz</keyname><forenames>Saadullah G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bokarev</keyname><forenames>Sergey I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear dynamical correlation effects in X-ray spectroscopy from a
  time-domain perspective</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To date X-ray spectroscopy has become a routine tool that can reveal highly
local and element-specific information on the electronic structure of atoms in
complex environments. Here, we focus on nuclear dynamical effects in X-ray
spectra and develop a rigorous time-correlation method employing ground state
molecular dynamics simulations. The importance of nuclear correlation phenomena
is demonstrated by comparison against the results from the conventional
sampling approach for gas phase water. In contrast to the first-order
absorption, second-order resonant inelastic scattering spectra exhibit
pronounced fingerprints of nuclear motions. The developed methodology does not
depend on the accompanying electronic structure method in principle as well as
on the spectral range and, thus, can be applied to, e.g., UV and X-ray
photo-electron and Auger spectroscopies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03453</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Denisov</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evdokimov</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luki&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Strahinja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uji&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Predrag</forenames></author></authors><title>Muon Beam at the Fermilab Test Beam Area</title><categories>physics.acc-ph hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-TM-2627-E</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The intensities and profiles of the muon beam behind the beam dump of the
Fermilab test beam area when the facility is running in the &quot;pion&quot; beam mode
are measured and summarized in this note. This muon beam with momenta in the
range 10 - 50 GeV/c provides an opportunity to perform various measurements in
parallel with other users of the test beam area.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03454</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>CERN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Proceedings of the 2014 Joint International Accelerator School: Beam
  Loss and Accelerator Protection (JAS 2014), Newport Beach, CA, USA, 5-14 Nov
  2014</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><comments>17 lectures, 440 pages, published as CERN Yellow Report
  https://cds.cern.ch/record/1641418</comments><proxy>Scientific Information Service Cern</proxy><report-no>CERN-2016-002</report-no><doi>10.5170/CERN-2016-002</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Many particle accelerators operate with very high beam power and very high
energy stored in particle beams as well as in magnet systems. In the future,
the beam power in high intensity accelerators will further increase. The
protection of the accelerator equipment from the consequences of uncontrolled
release of the energy is essential. This was the motivation for organizing a
first school on beam losses and accelerator protection (in general referred to
as machine protection). During the school the methods and technologies to
identify, mitigate, monitor and manage the technical risks associated with the
operation of accelerators with high-power beams or subsystems with large stored
energy were presented. At the completion of the school the participants should
have been able to understand the physical phenomena that can damage machine
subsystems or interrupt operations and to analyze an accelerator facility to
produce a register of technical risks and the corresponding risk mitigation and
management strategies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03466</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Mukesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Buddenbrock</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrabarty</keyname><forenames>Nabarun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cornell</keyname><forenames>Alan S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kar</keyname><forenames>Deepak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mandal</keyname><forenames>Tanumoy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mellado</keyname><forenames>Bruce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyaya</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reed</keyname><forenames>Robert G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>Xifeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenology of additional scalar bosons at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 tables, submitted to SAIP 2016, South Africa proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The confirmation of the Higgs boson in Run I data at the Large Hadron
Collider (LHC) and the excesses in recent Run II data suggest scenarios beyond
the Standard Model (SM). We pursue a study in a minimal model which is an
extension of a scalar doublet in the SM known as two-Higgs doublet model
(THDM). Following earlier suggestions two real scalars $\chi$ and $S$ have been
introduced in the THDM where $\chi$ is treated as a candidate for dark matter.
$\chi$ does not receive any vacuum expectation value ($vev$) in the model
whereas the Higgs-like scalar $S$ acquires $vev$. This allows small mixing
between the $CP$-even scalars of the THDM, $h$, $H$ and $S$. In this study the
mass spectrum of new scalars is taken to be $2 m_h &lt; m_H &lt; 2 m_t$, $m_\chi &lt;
m_h/2$, $m_h \lesssim m_S \lesssim m_H - m_h$, $m_A &gt; 2 m_t$ and $m_H^\pm &lt;
m_A$, where $m_h$ and $m_t$ is masses of the SM Higgs and top-quark
respectively, $m_H, m_A$ and $m_{H^\pm}$ are the masses of the heavy $CP$-even
scalar $H$, $CP$-odd scalar $A$, and charged Higgs $H^\pm$, respectively. A
partial list of potential search channels at the LHC has been provided with
possible phenomenological consequences. The expected phenomenology and
constraints on parameters are also discussed in a model-independent approach .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03467</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03467</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>van Kessenich</keyname><forenames>L. Michiels</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Arcangelis</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Synaptic plasticity and neuronal refractory time cause scaling behaviour
  of neuronal avalanches</title><categories>q-bio.NC nlin.AO</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, to be published in Scientific Reports</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neuronal avalanches measured in vitro and in vivo in different cortical
networks consistently exhibit power law behaviour for the size and duration
distributions with exponents typical for a mean field self-organized branching
process. These exponents are also recovered in neuronal network simulations
implementing various neuronal dynamics on different network topologies. They
can therefore be considered a very robust feature of spontaneous neuronal
activity. Interestingly, this scaling behaviour is also observed on regular
lattices in finite dimensions, which raises the question about the origin of
the mean field behaviour observed experimentally. In this study we provide an
answer to this open question by investigating the effect of activity dependent
plasticity in combination with the neuronal refractory time in a neuronal
network. Results show that the refractory time hinders backward avalanches
forcing a directed propagation. Hebbian plastic adaptation plays the role of
sculpting these directed avalanche patterns into the topology of the network
slowly changing it into a branched structure where loops are marginal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03479</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohlbrecher</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porcar</keyname><forenames>Lionel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lettinga</keyname><forenames>Minne Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>The connection between shear thinning and biaxial orientation for
  quasi-ideal rods</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.3390/polym8080291</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The complete orientational ordering tensor of quasi-ideal colloidal rods is
obtained as a function of shear rate by performing rheo-SANS (rheology with
small angle neutron scattering) measurements on isotropic fd-virus suspensions
in the two relevant scattering planes, the flow-gradient (1-2) and the
flow-vorticity (1-3) plane. Microscopic ordering can be identified as the
origin of the observed shear thinning. A qualitative description of the
rheological response by Smoluchowski, as well as Doi--Edwards--Kuzuu theory is
possible, as we obtain a master curve for different concentrations, scaling the
shear rate with the apparent collective rotational diffusion coefficient.
However, the observation suggests that the interdependence of ordering and
shear thinning at small shear rates is stronger than predicted. The extracted
zero-shear viscosity matches the concentration dependence of the self-diffusion
of rods in semi-dilute solutions, while the director tilts close towards the
flow direction already at very low shear rates. In contrast, we observe a
smaller dependence on the shear rate in the overall ordering at high shear
rates, as well as an ever-increasing biaxiality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03481</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03481</id><created>2016-08-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Bertoldi</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guillermet</keyname><forenames>A. Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miranda</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Einstein nanocrystal</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Revista Mexicana de Fisica E 62 60-65 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the simplest possible model of nanocrystal consisting in a simple
cubic lattice with a small number of atoms (NA ~ 10-10^3), where each atom is
linked to its nearest neighbor by a quantum harmonic potential. Some properties
(entropy, temperature, specific heat) of the nanocrystal are calculated
numerically but exactly within the framework of the microcanonical ensemble. We
find that the presence of a surface in the nanocrystal modifies the
thermostatistic properties to a greater extent than the small number of atoms
in the system. The specific heat Cv behaves similarly to the Einstein solid,
with an asymptotic value for high temperatures that differs from that of the
Dulong-Petit law by a term of the order of NA^(-1/3) and that can be explained
easily in terms of the surface. The entropy is non-additive, but this is due to
the presence of the surface and we show that the additivity is recovered in the
thermodynamic limit. Finally, we find that, when calculations follow the
canonical ensemble, results differ little for small systems (NA = 27) and are
inexistent for larger systems (NA = 1000).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03484</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Correia</keyname><forenames>Alexandre C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bou&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>Gwena&#xeb;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laskar</keyname><forenames>Jacques</forenames></author></authors><title>Secular and tidal evolution of circumbinary systems</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM math.DS</categories><comments>40 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10569-016-9709-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the secular dynamics of three-body circumbinary systems under
the effect of tides. We use the octupolar non-restricted approximation for the
orbital interactions, general relativity corrections, the quadrupolar
approximation for the spins, and the viscous linear model for tides. We derive
the averaged equations of motion in a simplified vectorial formalism, which is
suitable to model the long-term evolution of a wide variety of circumbinary
systems in very eccentric and inclined orbits. In particular, this vectorial
approach can be used to derive constraints for tidal migration, capture in
Cassini states, and stellar spin-orbit misalignment. We show that circumbinary
planets with initial arbitrary orbital inclination can become coplanar through
a secular resonance between the precession of the orbit and the precession of
the spin of one of the stars. We also show that circumbinary systems for which
the pericenter of the inner orbit is initially in libration present chaotic
motion for the spins and for the eccentricity of the outer orbit. Because our
model is valid for the non-restricted problem, it can also be applied to any
three-body hierarchical system such as star-planet-satellite systems and triple
stellar systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03488</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03488</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Hattam</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author></authors><title>Travelling wave solutions of the perturbed mKdV equation that represent
  traffic congestion</title><categories>math.DS nlin.PS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A well-known optimal velocity (OV) model describes vehicle motion along a
single lane road, which reduces to a perturbed modified Korteweg-de Vries
(mKdV) equation within the unstable regime. Steady travelling wave solutions to
this equation are then derived with a multi-scale perturbation technique. The
first order solution in the hierarchy is written in terms of slow and fast
variables. At the following order, a system of differential equations are
highlighted that govern the slowly evolving properties of the leading solution.
Then, it is shown that the critical points of this system signify travelling
waves without slow variation. As a result, a family of steady waves with
constant amplitude and period are identified. When periodic boundary conditions
are satisfied, these solutions' parameters are associated with the driver's
sensitivity, $\hat{a}$, which appears in the OV model. For some given
$\hat{a}$, solutions of both an upward and downward form exist, with the
downward type corresponding to traffic congestion. Numerical simulations are
used to validate the asymptotic analysis and also to examine the long-time
behaviour of our solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03489</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Melissinos</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author></authors><title>Use of the gravitational-wave interferometers to test Lorentz invariance
  violation</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Currently operating gravitational-wave interferometers are Michelson
interferometers with effective arm length L ~ 4x10e5 m. While the
interferometer remains in lock, data at the fsr sideband frequency encode
information on slow phase changes in the f ~ 10e-5 Hz range, with a fringe
sensitivity ~ 10e-10. Preliminary LIGO data presented in 2009 show no Lorentz
violating signal at the second harmonic of the Earth's sidereal frequency. This
sets a limit on a possible change in refractine index, dn/n &lt; 2x10e-22, an
improvement of more than three orders of magnitude over existing limits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03503</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Baldini</keyname><forenames>Edoardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borroni</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arrell</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Mourik</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carbone</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author></authors><title>A Versatile Setup for Ultrafast Broadband Optical Spectroscopy of
  Coherent Collective Modes in Strongly Correlated Quantum Systems</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A femtosecond pump-probe setup is described that is optimised for broadband
transient reflectivity experiments on solid samples over a wide range of
temperatures. By combining a temporal resolution of 45 fs and a broad detection
range between 1.75 and 2.85 eV, this apparatus can provide insightful
information on the interplay between coherent collective modes and high-energy
electronic excitations, which is one of the distinctive characteristics of
strongly interacting and correlated quantum systems. The use of a single-shot
readout CMOS array detector at frame rates up to 10 kHz allows to resolve
coherent oscillations with amplitudes below 10$^{-4}$ in $\Delta$R/R. We
demonstrate the operation of this setup on the prototypical charge-transfer
insulator La$_2$CuO$_4$, revealing the presence of coherent optical phonons
with frequencies as high as 13 THz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03540</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Dullemond</keyname><forenames>Cornelis Petrus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harsono</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stammler</keyname><forenames>Sebastian Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansen</keyname><forenames>Anders</forenames></author></authors><title>Forming chondrules in impact splashes - II Volatile retention</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solving the mystery of the origin of chondrules is one of the most elusive
goals in the field of meteoritics. Recently the idea of planet(esimal)
collisions releasing splashes of lava droplets, long considered out of favor,
has been reconsidered as a possible origin of chondrules by several papers. One
of the main problems with this idea is the lack of quantitative and simple
models that can be used to test this scenario by directly comparing to the many
known observables of chondrules. In Paper I of this series we presented a
simple thermal evolution model of a spherically symmetric expanding cloud of
molten lava droplets that is assumed to emerge from a collision between two
planetesimals. In the present paper, number II of this series, we use this
model to calculate whether or not volatile elements such as Na and K will
remain abundant in these droplets or whether they will get depleted due to
evaporation. The high density of the droplet cloud (e.g. small distance between
adjacent droplets) causes the vapor to quickly reach saturation pressure and
thus shutting down further evaporation. We show to which extent, and under
which conditions, this keeps the abundances of these elements high, as is seen
in chondrules. We find that for most parameters of our model (cloud mass,
expansion velocity, initial temperature) the volatile elements Mg, Si and Fe
remain entirely in the chondrules. The Na and K abundances inside the droplets
will initially stay mostly at their initial values due to the saturation of the
vapor pressure, but at some point start to drop due to the cloud expansion.
However, as soon as the temperature starts to decrease, most or all of the
vapor recondenses again. At the end the Na and K elements retain most of their
initial abundances, albeit occasionally somewhat reduced, depending on the
parameters of the expanding cloud model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03559</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Sales</keyname><forenames>Jorge Henrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Alfredo Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thibes</keyname><forenames>Ronaldo</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting fermion helicity flip in Podolsky's Electromagnetism</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin projection of a massive particle onto its direction of motion is
called helicity (or &quot;handedness&quot;). It can therefore be positive or negative.
When a particle's helicity changes from positive to negative (or vice-versa)
due to its interaction with other particles or fields, we say there is a
helicity flip. In this work we show that such helicity flip can be seen for an
electron of $20 MeV$ of energy interacting with a charged scalar meson through
the exchange of a virtual photon. This photon {\it does not} necessarily need
to be Podolsky's proposed photon; in fact, it is independent of it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03561</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Leppert</keyname><forenames>Linn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reyes-Lillo</keyname><forenames>Sebastian E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neaton</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electric field and strain induced Rashba effect in hybrid halide
  perovskites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using first principles density functional theory calculations, we show how
Rashba-type energy band splitting in the hybrid organic-inorganic halide
perovskites APbX$_3$ (A=CH$_3$NH$_3^+$, CH(NH$_2$)$_2^+$, Cs$^+$ and X=I, Br)
can be tuned and enhanced with electric fields and anisotropic strain. In
particular, we demonstrate that the magnitude of the Rashba splitting of
tetragonal (CH$_3$NH$_3$)PbI$_3$ grows with increasing macroscopic alignment of
the organic cations and electric polarization, indicating appreciable
tunability with experimentally-feasible applied fields, even at room
temperature. Further, we quantify the degree to which this effect can be tuned
via chemical substitution at the A and X sites, which alters amplitudes of
different polar distortion patterns of the inorganic PbX$_3$ cage that directly
impact Rashba splitting. In addition, we predict that polar phases of CsPbI$_3$
and (CH$_3$NH$_3$)PbI$_3$ with $R3c$ symmetry possessing considerable Rashba
splitting might be accessible at room temperature via anisotropic strain
induced by epitaxy, even in the absence of electric fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03573</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Varela</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pantellini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moncuquet</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of the interplanetary magnetic field orientation and intensity in
  the mass and energy deposition on the Hermean surface</title><categories>astro-ph.EP physics.space-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.pss.2016.06.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of the present study is to simulate the interaction between the solar
wind and the Hermean magnetosphere. We use the MHD code PLUTO in spherical
coordinates with an axisymmetric multipolar expansion of the Hermean magnetic
field, to perform a set of simulations with different interplanetary magnetic
field orientations and intensities. We fix the hydrodynamic parameters of the
solar wind to study the distortions driven by the interplanetary magnetic field
in the topology of the Hermean magnetosphere, leading to variations of the mass
and energy deposition distributions, the integrated mass deposition, the oval
aperture, the area covered by open magnetic field lines and the regions of
efficient particle sputtering on the planet surface. The simulations show a
correlation between the reconnection regions and the local maxima of plasma
inflow and energy deposition on the planet surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03576</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-08-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03576</id><created>2016-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Himanshu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaushik</keyname><forenames>Atul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seeman</keyname><forenames>Nadrian C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiti</keyname><forenames>Prabal K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanoscale Structure and Elasticity of Pillared DNA Nanotubes</title><categories>cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>Published in ACS Nano</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano, July 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b03360</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an atomistic model of pillared DNA nanotubes (DNTs) and their
elastic properties which will facilitate further studies of these nanotubes in
several important nanotechnological and biological applications. In particular,
we introduce a computational design to create an atomistic model of a 6-helix
DNT (6HB) along with its two variants, 6HB flanked symmetrically by two double
helical DNA pillars (6HB+2) and 6HB flanked symmetrically by three double
helical DNA pillars (6HB+3). Analysis of 200 ns all-atom simulation
trajectories in the presence of explicit water and ions shows that these
structures are stable and well behaved in all three geometries. Hydrogen
bonding is well maintained for all variants of 6HB DNTs. We calculate the
persistence length of these nanotubes from their equilibrium bend angle
distributions. The values of persistence length are ~10 {\mu}m, which is 2
orders of magnitude larger than that of dsDNA. We also find a gradual increase
of persistence length with an increasing number of pillars, in quantitative
agreement with previous experimental findings. To have a quantitative
understanding of the stretch modulus of these tubes we carried out
nonequilibrium Steered Molecular Dynamics (SMD). The linear part of the force
extension plot gives stretch modulus in the range of 6500 pN for 6HB without
pillars which increases to 11,000 pN for tubes with three pillars. The values
of the stretch modulus calculated from contour length distributions obtained
from equilibrium MD simulations are similar to those obtained from
nonequilibrium SMD simulations. The addition of pillars makes these DNTs very
rigid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
