<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:27:40Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-01-16" from="2016-01-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0709.1215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0709.1215</id><created>2007-09-09</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Huckleberry</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puettmann</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zirnbauer</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Haar expectations of ratios of random characteristic polynomials</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>LaTeX, 70 pages, Complex Analysis and its Synergies (2016) 2:1</comments><doi>10.1186/s40627-015-0005-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute Haar ensemble averages of ratios of random characteristic
polynomials for the classical Lie groups K = O(N), SO(N), and USp(N). To that
end, we start from the Clifford-Weyl algebera in its canonical realization on
the complex of holomorphic differential forms for a C-vector space V. From it
we construct the Fock representation of an orthosymplectic Lie superalgebra osp
associated to V. Particular attention is paid to defining Howe's oscillator
semigroup and the representation that partially exponentiates the Lie algebra
representation of sp in osp. In the process, by pushing the semigroup
representation to its boundary and arguing by continuity, we provide a
construction of the Shale-Weil-Segal representation of the metaplectic group.
  To deal with a product of n ratios of characteristic polynomials, we let V =
C^n \otimes C^N where C^N is equipped with its standard K-representation, and
focus on the subspace of K-equivariant forms. By Howe duality, this is a
highest-weight irreducible representation of the centralizer g of Lie(K) in
osp. We identify the K-Haar expectation of n ratios with the character of this
g-representation, which we show to be uniquely determined by analyticity, Weyl
group invariance, certain weight constraints and a system of differential
equations coming from the Laplace-Casimir invariants of g. We find an explicit
solution to the problem posed by all these conditions. In this way we prove
that the said Haar expectations are expressed by a Weyl-type character formula
for all integers N \ge 1. This completes earlier work by Conrey, Farmer, and
Zirnbauer for the case of U(N).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1111.1929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1111.1929</id><created>2011-11-08</created><updated>2012-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dimopoulos</keyname><forenames>Konstantinos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarides</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagstaff</keyname><forenames>Jacques M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Eliminating the eta-problem in SUGRA Hybrid Inflation with Vector
  Backreaction</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages. Published in JCAP. Minor corrections. References added</comments><journal-ref>JCAP02(2012)018</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2012/02/018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that, when the inflaton field modulates the gauge kinetic
function of the gauge fields in supergravity realisations of inflation, the
dynamic backreaction leads to a new inflationary attractor solution, in which
the inflaton's variation suffers additional impedance. As a result, slow-roll
inflation can naturally occur along directions of the scalar potential which
would be too steep and curved to support it otherwise. This provides a generic
solution to the infamous eta-problem of inflation in supergravity. Moreover, it
is shown that, in the new inflationary attractor, the spectral index of the
generated curvature perturbations is kept mildly red despite eta of order
unity. The above findings are applied to a model of hybrid inflation is
supergravity with a generic Kaehler potential. The spectral index of the
generated curvature perturbations is found to be 0.97 - 0.98, in excellent
agreement with observations. The gauge field can play the role of the vector
curvaton after inflation but observable statistical anisotropy requires
substantial tuning of the gauge coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.0698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.0698</id><created>2013-11-04</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Romero-Berm&#xfa;dez</keyname><forenames>Aurelio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Antonio M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shape resonances and shell effects in thin-film multiband
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 89, 024510 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.024510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study analytically the evolution of superconductivity in clean
quasi-two-dimensional multiband supercon- ductors as the film thickness enters
the nanoscale region by mean-field and semiclassical techniques. Tunneling into
the substrate and finite lateral size effects, which are important in
experiments, are also considered in our model. As a result, it is possible to
investigate the interplay between quantum coherence effects, such as shape
resonances and shell effects, with the potential to enhance superconductivity,
and the multiband structure and the coupling to the substrate that tend to
suppress it. The case of magnesium diboride, which is the conventional
superconductor with the highest critical temperature, is discussed in detail.
Once the effect of the substrate is considered, we still observe quantum size
effects such as the oscillation of the critical temperature with the thickness
but without a significant enhancement of superconductivity. In thin films with
a sufficiently longer superconducting coherence length, it is, however,
possible to increase the critical temperature above the bulk limit by tuning
the film thickness or lateral size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.4193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.4193</id><created>2013-11-17</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Romero-Berm&#xfa;dez</keyname><forenames>Aurelio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Antonio M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Size effects in superconducting thin films coupled to a substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 89, 064508 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.064508</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experimental advances in surface science have made it possible to
track the evolution of superconductivity in films as the thickness enters the
nanoscale region where it is expected that the substrate plays an important
role. Here, we put forward a mean-field, analytically tractable, model that
describes size effects in ultrathin films coupled to the substrate. We restrict
our study to one-band, crystalline, weakly coupled superconductors with no
impurities. The thin-film substrate/vacuum interfaces are described by a simple
asymmetric potential well and a finite quasiparticle lifetime. Boundary
conditions are chosen to comply with the charge neutrality condition. This
model provides a fair description of experimental results in ultrathin lead
films: on average, the superconducting gap decreases with thickness and it is
always below the bulk value. Clear oscillations, remnants of the shape
resonances, are still observed for intermediate thicknesses. For materials with
a weaker electron-phonon coupling and negligible disorder, a modest enhancement
of superconductivity seems to be feasible. The relaxation of the charge
neutrality condition, which is in principle justified in complex oxide
heterostructures and other materials, would lead to a much stronger enhancement
of superconductivity by size effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.3140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.3140</id><created>2014-01-14</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tan&#x131;r</keyname><forenames>Ayse G&#xfc;ne&#x15f;</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xfc;le&#xe7;</keyname><forenames>&#xd6;zge</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct determination of internal radiation dose in human blood</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>12 pages,7 figures This paper has been withdrawn by the author
  because arXiv:1401.6856 (external radiation dose) and arXiv:1401.5386
  (internal radiation dose) are combined as one paper titled &quot;Direct
  determination of radiation dose in human blood&quot; (identifier: arXiv:1405.5386)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this study is to measure the internal radiation dose using a
human blood sample. In the literature, there is no process that allows the
direct measurement of the internal radiation dose received by a person. The
luminescence counts from a blood sample having a laboratory-injected radiation
dose and the waste blood of the patient injected with a radiopharmaceutical for
diagnostic purposes were both measured. The decay and dose-response curves were
plotted for the different doses. The doses received by the different blood
aliquots can be determined by interpolating the luminescence counts to the
dose-response curve. This study shows that the dose received by a person can be
measured directly, simply and retrospectively by using only a very small amount
of blood sample. The results will have important ramifications for the medicine
and healthcare fields in particular. This will also be very important in cases
of suspicion of radiation poisoning, malpractice and so on.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.6856</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.6856</id><created>2014-01-27</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tanir</keyname><forenames>AG</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gulec</keyname><forenames>O</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahiner</keyname><forenames>E</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolukdemir</keyname><forenames>MH</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koc</keyname><forenames>K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meric</keyname><forenames>N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keles</keyname><forenames>SK</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kucuk</keyname><forenames>O</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct determination of external radiation dose in human blood</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures This paper has been withdrawn by the author
  because arXiv:1401.6856 (external radiation dose) and arXiv:1401.5386
  (internal radiation dose) are combined as one paper titled &quot;Direct
  determination of radiation dose in human blood&quot; (identifier: arXiv:1405.5386)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study it was shown that it is possible to determine radiation doses
from external beam therapy both directly and retrospectively from a human blood
sample. To the best of our knowledge no other studies exist on the direct
measurement of doses received by a person from external beam therapy. Optically
stimulated luminescence counts from a healthy blood sample exposed to an
external radiation source were measured. Blood aliquots were given 0, 1, 2, 3,
4, 5, 10, 15, 20, 25, 50, 100 and 200Gy beta doses and their decay and
dose-response curves were plotted. While the luminescence intensities were
found to be relatively low for the doses smaller than 10Gy, they were measured
considerably higher for doses greater than 10Gy. The dose received by the blood
aliquots was determined by interpolating the luminescence counts of 10Gy to the
dose-response curve. This study has important ramifications for healthcare,
medicine and radiation protection
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7629</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7629</id><created>2014-01-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Avan</keyname><forenames>Jean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ragoucy</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubtsov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantization and dynamisation of Trace-Poisson brackets</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>26 pages</comments><report-no>LAPTH-007/14</report-no><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 341 (2016) 263-287</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantization problem for the trace-bracket algebra, derived from double
Poisson brackets, is discussed. We obtain a generalization of the boundary YBE
(or so-called ABCD-algebra) for the quantization of quadratic trace-brackets. A
dynamical deformation is proposed on the lines of Gervais-Neveu-Felder
dynamical quantum algebras.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.1071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.1071</id><created>2014-02-05</created><updated>2014-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bachelot</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Klein-Gordon equation near a De Sitter brane in an Anti-de Sitter
  bulk</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>29 pages, 3 figures</comments><msc-class>35L53, 35Q, 83E</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Pures Appl., 105, 165-197, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we investigate the Klein-Gordon equation in the past causal
domain of a De Sitter brane imbedded in a Anti-de Sitter bulk. We solve the
global mixed hyperbolic problem. We prove that any finite energy solution can
be expressed as a Kaluza-Klein tower that is a superposition of free fields in
the Steady State Universe, of which we study the asymptotic behaviours. We show
that the leading term of a gravitational fluctuation is a massless graviton,
i.e. the De Sitter brane is linearly stable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.6441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.6441</id><created>2014-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Delfosse</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhentao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomass&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phan</forenames></author></authors><title>A note on the minimum distance of quantum LDPC codes</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.CO math.IT</categories><journal-ref>Mathematical Foundations of Computer Science 2014, Vol. 8635 LNCS
  pp 239-250</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-662-44465-8_21</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a new lower bound on the minimum distance of a family of quantum
LDPC codes based on Cayley graphs proposed by MacKay, Mitchison and
Shokrollahi. Our bound is exponential, improving on the quadratic bound of
Couvreur, Delfosse and Z\'emor. This result is obtained by examining a family
of subsets of the hypercube which locally satisfy some parity conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.3989</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.3989</id><created>2014-05-15</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Regula</keyname><forenames>Bartosz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Martino</keyname><forenames>Sara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Soojoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adesso</keyname><forenames>Gerardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong monogamy conjecture for multiqubit entanglement: The four-qubit
  case</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures; v3: Errors in class-2 and class-7 states in Table
  I and Figure 2(a) are corrected with respect to the published version. All
  conclusions are unaffected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 113, 110501 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.113.110501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the distribution of bipartite and multipartite entanglement in
multiqubit states. In particular we define a set of monogamy inequalities
sharpening the conventional Coffman-Kundu-Wootters constraints, and we provide
analytical proofs of their validity for relevant classes of states. We present
extensive numerical evidence validating the conjectured strong monogamy
inequalities for arbitrary pure states of four qubits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.2598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.2598</id><created>2014-08-11</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>Daniel O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeLuca</keyname><forenames>Edward E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mininni</keyname><forenames>Pablo D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulations of the Kelvin-Helmholtz instability driven by coronal mass
  ejections in the turbulent corona</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent high resolution AIA/SDO images show evidence of the development of the
Kelvin-Helmholtz instability, as coronal mass ejections (CMEs) expand in the
ambient corona. A large-scale magnetic field mostly tangential to the interface
is inferred, both on the CME and on the background sides. However, the magnetic
field component along the shear flow is not strong enough to quench the
instability. There is also observational evidence that the ambient corona is in
a turbulent regime, and therefore the criteria for the development of the
instability are a-priori expected to differ from the laminar case. To study the
evolution of the Kelvin-Helmholtz instability with a turbulent background, we
perform three-dimensional simulations of the incompressible magnetohydrodynamic
equations. The instability is driven by a velocity profile tangential to the
CME-corona interface, which we simulate through a hyperbolic tangent profile.
The turbulent background is generated by the application of a stationary
stirring force. We compute the instability growth-rate for different values of
the turbulence intensity, and find that the role of turbulence is to attenuate
the growth. The fact that the Kelvin-Helmholtz instability is observed, sets an
upper limit to the correlation length of the coronal background turbulence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2765</id><created>2014-09-09</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lau</keyname><forenames>Siu-Cheong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tseng</keyname><forenames>Li-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yau</keyname><forenames>Shing-Tung</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Kaehler SYZ mirror symmetry</title><categories>math.DG hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><msc-class>53D37, 14J33, 53Z05</msc-class><journal-ref>Communications in Mathematical Physics 340 (2015), Issue 1, pp
  145-170</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-015-2454-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study SYZ mirror symmetry in the context of non-Kaehler Calabi-Yau
manifolds. In particular, we study the six-dimensional Type II supersymmetric
$SU(3)$ systems with Ramond-Ramond fluxes, and generalize them to higher
dimensions. We show that Fourier-Mukai transform provides the mirror map
between these Type IIA and Type IIB supersymmetric systems in the semi-flat
setting. This is concretely exhibited by nilmanifolds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.4223</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.4223</id><created>2014-09-15</created><updated>2015-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wagstaff</keyname><forenames>Jacques M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Robi</forenames></author></authors><title>Extragalactic magnetic fields unlikely generated at the electroweak
  phase transition</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. Comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter we show that magnetic fields generated at the electroweak
phase transition are most likely too weak to explain the void magnetic fields
apparently observed today unless they have considerable helicity. We show that,
in the simplest estimates, the helicity naturally produced in conjunction with
the baryon asymmetry is too small to explain observations, which require a
helicity fraction at least of order $10^{-14}-10^{-10}$ depending on the void
fields constraint used. Therefore new mechanisms to generate primordial
helicity are required if magnetic fields generated during the electroweak phase
transition should explain the extragalactic fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1641</id><created>2014-10-07</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>J&#xf8;rgen Ellegaard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masulli</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaetz</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author></authors><title>Formal Connections for families of Star Products</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages, some typos fixed, references improved, to appear in Commun.
  Math. Phys</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define the notion of a formal connection for a smooth family of star
products with fixed underlying symplectic structure. Such a formal connection
allows one to relate star products at different points in the family. This
generalizes the formal Hitchin connection introduced by the first author. We
establish a necessary and sufficient condition that guarantees the existence of
a formal connection, and we describe the space of formal connections for a
family as an affine space modelled by the derivations of the star products.
Moreover we show that if the parameter space has trivial first cohomology group
any two flat formal connections are related by an automorphism of the family of
star products.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.5151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.5151</id><created>2014-10-20</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fily</keyname><forenames>Yaouen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baskaran</keyname><forenames>Aparna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagan</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and density distribution of strongly confined noninteracting
  nonaligning self-propelled particles in a nonconvex boundary</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>12 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 91, 012125 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.91.012125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of non-aligning, non-interacting self-propelled
particles confined to a box in two dimensions. In the strong confinement limit,
when the persistence length of the active particles is much larger than the
size of the box, particles stay on the boundary and align with the local
boundary normal. It is then possible to derive the steady-state density on the
boundary for arbitrary box shapes. In non-convex boxes, the non-uniqueness of
the boundary normal results in hysteretic dynamics and the density is
non-local, i.e. it depends on the global geometry of the box. These findings
establish a general connection between the geometry of a confining box and the
behavior of an ideal active gas it confines, thus providing a powerful tool to
understand and design such confinements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.2762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.2762</id><created>2014-12-08</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kemper</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sentef</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moritz</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freericks</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devereaux</keyname><forenames>T. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct observation of Higgs mode oscillations in the pump-probe
  photoemission spectra of electron-phonon mediated superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 224517 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.224517</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the non-equilibrium Keldysh formalism, we solve the equations of motion
for electron-phonon superconductivity, including an ultrafast pump field. We
present results for time-dependent photoemission spectra out of equilibrium
which probes the dynamics of the superconducting gap edge. The partial melting
of the order by the pump field leads to oscillations at twice the melted gap
frequency, a hallmark of the Higgs or amplitude mode. Thus the Higgs mode can
be directly excited through the nonlinear effects of an electromagnetic field
and detected without any additional symmetry breaking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.2917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.2917</id><created>2014-12-09</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berezin</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dokuchaev</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eroshenko</keyname><forenames>Yu. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherically symmetric conformal gravity and &quot;gravitational bubbles&quot;</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)019</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The general structure of the spherically symmetric solutions in the Weyl
conformal gravity is described. The corresponding Bach equations are derived
for the special type of metrics, which can be considered as the representative
of the general class. The complete set of the pure vacuum solutions is found.
It consists of two classes. The first one contains the solutions with constant
two-dimensional curvature scalar of our specific metrics, and the
representatives are the famous Robertson--Walker metrics. One of them we called
the &quot;gravitational bubbles&quot;, which is compact and with zero Weyl tensor. Thus,
we obtained the pure vacuum curved space-times (without any material sources,
including the cosmological constant) what is absolutely impossible in General
Relativity. Such a phenomenon makes it easier to create the universe from
&quot;nothing&quot;. The second class consists of the solutions with varying curvature
scalar. We found its representative as the one-parameter family. It appears
that it can be conformally covered by the thee-parameter Mannheim--Kazanas
solution. We also investigated the general structure of the energy-momentum
tensor in the spherical conformal gravity and constructed the vectorial
equation that reveals clearly some features of non-vacuum solutions. Two of
them are explicitly written, namely, the metrics \`a la Vaidya, and the
electrovacuum space-time metrics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4297</id><created>2014-12-13</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Baobao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Jihong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Huaiming</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties of spin-1/2 Fermi gases with ferromagnetic
  interaction</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 88, 246 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60341-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the magnetic properties of spin-$1/2$ charged Fermi gases with
ferromagnetic coupling via mean-field theory, and find the interplay among the
paramagnetism, diamagnetism and ferromagnetism. Paramagnetism and diamagnetism
compete with each other. When increasing the ferromagnetic coupling the
spontaneous magnetization occurs in a weak magnetic field. The critical
ferromagnetic coupling constant of the paramagnetic phase to ferromagnetic
phase transition increases linearly with the temperature. Both the
paramagnetism and diamagnetism increase when the magnetic field increases. It
reveals the magnetization density $\bar M$ increases firstly as the temperature
increases, and then reaches a maximum. Finally the magnetization density $\bar
M$ decreases smoothly in the high temperature region. The domed shape of the
magnetization density $\bar M$ variation is different from the behavior of Bose
gas with ferromagnetic coupling. We also find the curve of susceptibility
follows the Curie-Weiss law, and for a given temperature the susceptibility is
directly proportional to the Land\'{e} factor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.6812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.6812</id><created>2014-12-21</created><updated>2015-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bandopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Swarnali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chaudhuri</keyname><forenames>Debasish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Macrospin in external magnetic field: Entropy production and fluctuation
  theorems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures; version accepted for publication in JStat</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics: Theory and Experiment 2015,
  P11002 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2015/11/P11002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider stochastic rotational dynamics of a macrospin at a constant
temperature, in presence of an external magnetic field. Starting from the
appropriate Langevin equation which contains multiplicative noise, we calculate
entropy production (EP) along stochastic trajectories, and obtain fluctuation
theorems. The system remains inherently out of equilibrium due to a spin torque
supporting azimuthal current, leading to an excess EP apart from the EP due to
heat dissipation. The anomaly may be removed using a redefinition of dissipated
heat and stochastic work done. Using numerical simulations, we obtain
distribution functions for entropy production along stochastic trajectories to
find good agreement with the detailed fluctuation theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.04379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.04379</id><created>2015-01-18</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Zhun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Twist-3 fragmentation functions in a spectator model with gluon
  rescattering</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>typo corrected, version published in PLB</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the twist-3 fragmentation functions $H$ and $\tilde{H}$, by applying
a spectator model. In the calculation we consider the effect of the gluon
rescattering at one loop level. We find that in this case the hard-vertex
diagram, which gives zero contribution to the Collins function, does contribute
to the fragmentation function $H$. The calculation shows that the twist-3 T-odd
fragmentation functions are free of light-cone divergences. The parameters of
the model are fitted from the known parametrization of the unpolarized
fragmentation $D_1$ and the Collins function $H_1^\perp$. We find our result
for the favored fragmentation function is consistent with the recent extraction
on $H$ and $\tilde{H}$ from pp data. We also check numerically the equation of
motion relation for $H$, $\tilde{H}$ and find that relation holds fairly well
in the spectator model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06453</id><created>2015-01-26</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schulte</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;rch</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leroux</keyname><forenames>Ian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Piet O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerer</keyname><forenames>Klemens</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Algorithmic Readout in Multi-Ion Clocks</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages + 7 pages appendix; 5 figures; v3: published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 013002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.013002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical clocks based on ensembles of trapped ions offer the perspective of
record frequency uncertainty with good short-term stability. Most suitable
atomic species lack closed transitions for fast detection such that the clock
signal has to be read out indirectly through transferring the quantum state of
clock ions to co-trapped logic ions by means of quantum logic operations. For
ensembles of clock ions existing methods for quantum logic readout require a
linear overhead in either time or the number of logic ions. Here we report a
quantum algorithmic readout whose overhead scales logarithmically with the
number of clock ions in both of these respects. We show that the readout
algorithm can be implemented with a single application of a multi-species
quantum gate, which we describe in detail for a crystal of Aluminum and Calcium
ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06503</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06503</id><created>2015-01-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golovina</keyname><forenames>Anastasia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veselic</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Hamiltonians with weak random abstract perturbation. I. Initial
  length scale estimate</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><doi>10.1007/s00023-016-0465-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study random Hamiltonians on finite-size cubes and waveguide segments of
increasing diameter. The number of random parameters determining the operator
is proportional to the volume of the cube. In the asymptotic regime where the
cube size, and consequently the number of parameters as well, tends to
infinity, we derive deterministic and probabilistic variational bounds on the
lowest eigenvalue, i.e. the spectral minimum, as well as exponential
off-diagonal decay of the Green function at energies above, but close to the
overall spectral bottom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00006</id><created>2015-01-30</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Heung-Sik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Eric Kin-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong Baek</forenames></author></authors><title>Predominance of the Kitaev interaction in a three-dimensional honeycomb
  iridate: from ab-initio to spin model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters, 112 (2015) 67004</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/112/67004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recently discovered three-dimensional hyperhoneycomb iridate,
$\beta$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$, has raised hopes for the realization of dominant Kitaev
interaction between spin-orbit entangled local moments due to its near-ideal
lattice structure. If true, this material may lie close to the sought-after
quantum spin liquid phase in three dimensions. Utilizing ab-initio electronic
structure calculations, we first show that the spin-orbit entangled basis,
$j_{\rm eff}$=1/2, correctly captures the low energy electronic structure. The
effective spin model derived in the strong coupling limit supplemented by the
ab-initio results is shown to be dominated by the Kitaev interaction. We
demonstrated that the possible range of parameters is consistent with a
non-coplanar spiral magnetic order found in a recent experiment. All of these
analyses suggest that $\beta$-Li$_2$IrO$_3$ may be the closest among known
materials to the Kitaev spin liquid regime.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.00131</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.00131</id><created>2015-01-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Mak</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griffiths</keyname><forenames>Stephen D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear instabilities in shallow-water magnetohydrodynamics</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>31 pages, 15 figures, Journal of Fluid Mechanics template, submitted
  to Journal of Fluid Mechanics; comments welcome</comments><journal-ref>J. Fluid Mech. (2016), 788, 767-796</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.718</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the framework of shallow-water magnetohydrodynamics, we investigate
the linear instability of horizontal shear flows, influenced by an aligned
magnetic field and stratification. Various classical instability results, such
as H{\o}iland's growth rate bound and Howard's semi-circle theorem, are
extended to this shallow-water system for quite general profiles. Two specific
piecewise-constant velocity profiles, the vortex sheet and the rectangular jet,
are studied analytically and asymptotically; it is found that the magnetic
field and stratification (as measured by the Froude number) are generally both
stabilising, but weak instabilities can be found at arbitrarily large Froude
number. Numerical solutions are computed for corresponding smooth velocity
profiles, the hyperbolic-tangent shear layer and the Bickley jet, for a uniform
background field. A generalisation of the long-wave asymptotic analysis of
Drazin &amp; Howard (1962) is employed in order to understand the instability
characteristics for both profiles. For the shear layer, the mechanism
underlying the primary instability is interpreted in terms of
counter-propagating Rossby waves, thereby allowing an explication of the
stabilising effects of the magnetic field and stratification.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03616</id><created>2015-02-12</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Romero-Berm&#xfa;dez</keyname><forenames>Aurelio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Garc&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Antonio M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Conductivity and entanglement entropy of high dimensional holographic
  superconductors</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>38 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2015) 033</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2015)033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dependence of the conductivity and the entanglement
entropy on the space-time dimensionality $d$ in two holographic
superconductors: one dual to a quantum critical point with spontaneous symmetry
breaking, and the other modeled by a charged scalar that condenses at a
sufficiently low temperature in the presence of a Maxwell field. In both cases
the gravity background is asymptotically Anti de Sitter (AdS). In the large $d$
limit we obtain explicit analytical results for the conductivity at zero
temperature and the entanglement entropy by a $1/d$ expansion. We show that the
entanglement entropy is always smaller in the broken phase. As dimensionality
increases, the entanglement entropy decreases, the coherence peak in the
conductivity becomes narrower and the ratio between the energy gap and the
critical temperature decreases. These results suggest that the condensate
interactions become weaker in high spatial dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06042</id><created>2015-03-20</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>H1</keyname><forenames>The</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaborations</keyname><forenames>ZEUS</forenames></author></authors><title>Combination of Differential D^{*\pm} Cross-Section Measurements in
  Deep-Inelastic ep Scattering at HERA</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>37 pages, 14 figures, 9 tables, published: JHEP 09(2015)149</comments><report-no>DESY-15-037</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  H1 and ZEUS have published single-differential cross sections for inclusive
D^{*\pm}-meson production in deep-inelastic ep scattering at HERA from their
respective final data sets. These cross sections are combined in the common
visible phase-space region of photon virtuality Q2 &gt; 5 GeV2, electron
inelasticity 0.02 &lt; y &lt; 0.7 and the D^{*\pm} meson's transverse momentum pT
(D^*) &gt; 1.5 GeV and pseudorapidity |eta(D^*)| &lt; 1.5. The combination procedure
takes into account all correlations, yielding significantly reduced
experimental uncertainties. Double-differential cross sections d2s /dQ2dy are
combined with earlier D^{*\pm} data, extending the kinematic range down to Q2 &gt;
1.5 GeV2. Perturbative next-to-leadingorder QCD predictions are compared to the
results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.08787</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.08787</id><created>2015-03-30</created><updated>2015-07-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Valle</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Robust light transport in non-Hermitian photonic lattices</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>revised and extended version, to appear in Sci. Rep</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 5, 13376 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep13376</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combating the effects of disorder on light transport in micro- and
nano-integrated photonic devices is of major importance from both fundamental
and applied viewpoints. In ordinary waveguides, imperfections and disorder
cause unwanted back-reflections, which hinder large-scale optical integration.
Topological photonic structures, a new class of optical systems inspired by
quantum Hall effect and topological insulators, can realize robust transport
via topologically-protected unidirectional edge modes. Such waveguides are
realized by the introduction of synthetic gauge fields for photons in a
two-dimensional structure, which break time reversal symmetry and enable
one-way guiding at the edge of the medium. Here we suggest a different route
toward robust transport of light in lower-dimensional (1D) photonic lattices,
in which time reversal symmetry is broken because of the {\it non-Hermitian}
nature of transport. While a forward propagating mode in the lattice is
amplified, the corresponding backward propagating mode is damped, thus
resulting in an asymmetric transport that is rather insensitive to disorder or
imperfections in the structure. Non-Hermitian transport in two lattice models
is considered: a tight-binding lattice with an imaginary gauge field
(Hatano-Nelson model), and a non-Hermitian driven binary lattice. In the former
case transport in spite of disorder is ensured by a mobility edge that arises
because of a non-Hermitian delocalization transition. The possibility to
observe non-Hermitian delocalization induced by a synthetic 'imaginary' gauge
field is suggested using an engineered coupled-resonator optical waveguide
(CROW) structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01289</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01289</id><created>2015-04-06</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of the correlation between flow harmonics of different order
  in lead-lead collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}$=2.76 TeV with the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>22 pages plus author list + cover pages (35 pages total), 16 figures,
  submitted to Phys. Rev. C., All figures including auxiliary figures can be
  found at https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/HION-2014-03/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-079</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 92, 034903 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.92.034903</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Correlations between the elliptic or triangular flow coefficients $v_m$
($m$=2 or 3) and other flow harmonics $v_n$ ($n$=2 to 5) are measured using
$\sqrt{s_{NN}}=2.76$ TeV Pb+Pb collision data collected in 2010 by the ATLAS
experiment at the LHC, corresponding to an integrated lumonisity of 7
$\mu$b$^{-1}$. The $v_m$-$v_n$ correlations are measured in midrapidity as a
function of centrality, and, for events within the same centrality interval, as
a function of event ellipticity or triangularity defined in a forward rapidity
region. For events within the same centrality interval, $v_3$ is found to be
anticorrelated with $v_2$ and this anticorrelation is consistent with similar
anticorrelations between the corresponding eccentricities $\epsilon_2$ and
$\epsilon_3$. On the other hand, it is observed that $v_4$ increases strongly
with $v_2$, and $v_5$ increases strongly with both $v_2$ and $v_3$. The trend
and strength of the $v_m$-$v_n$ correlations for $n$=4 and 5 are found to
disagree with $\epsilon_m$-$\epsilon_n$ correlations predicted by
initial-geometry models. Instead, these correlations are found to be consistent
with the combined effects of a linear contribution to $v_n$ and a nonlinear
term that is a function of $v_2^2$ or of $v_2v_3$, as predicted by hydrodynamic
models. A simple two-component fit is used to separate these two contributions.
The extracted linear and nonlinear contributions to $v_4$ and $v_5$ are found
to be consistent with previously measured event-plane correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03633</id><created>2015-04-14</created><updated>2015-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nascimento</keyname><forenames>Fellype do</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moshkalev</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machida</keyname><forenames>Munemasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parada</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author></authors><title>Treatment of PDMS surfaces using pulsed DBD plasmas: comparing the use
  of different gases and its influence on adhesion</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Japanese Journal of Applied Physics, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/JJAP.55.021602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present some results of the treatment of polydimethylsiloxane
(PDMS) surfaces using pulsed dielectric barrier discharge plasmas. The results
of plasma treatment using different gases and mixtures, argon, argon plus water
vapor, helium, helium plus water vapor, nitrogen and nitrogen plus water vapor,
were compared testing the adhesion between two PDMS samples for each kind of
plasma. We also studied the water contact angle in function of plasma process
time of PDMS surfaces with each kind of plasma treatment. The plasma was
characterized by optical emission spectroscopy (OES) to identify the emitting
species and determine the plasma temperatures. The plasma temperature for each
process was estimated comparing the spectrum obtained by OES with the spectrum
generated by SpecAir simulation code. Measurements of power delivered to the
plasmas were also performed. As the results, all the process using different
gases show good adhesion efficacy between PDMS samples when long exposure time
(larger than 150 seconds) is applied. However, when only a few discharges are
applied to PDMS samples the helium plasma process presented best results.
Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) analysis of PDMS samples treated with helium
plasma showed reduction in the surface roughness, which increase the surface
contact area and improves the adhesion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03859</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03859</id><created>2015-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dornheim</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groth</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filinov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonitz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Permutation blocking path integral Monte Carlo: A highly efficient
  approach to the simulation of strongly degenerate non-ideal fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17, 073017 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Correlated fermions are of high interest in condensed matter (Fermi liquids,
Wigner molecules), cold atomic gases and dense plasmas. Here we propose a novel
approach to path integral Monte Carlo (PIMC) simulations of strongly degenerate
non-ideal fermions at finite temperature by combining a fourth-order
factorization of the density matrix with antisymmetric propagators, i.e.,
determinants, between all imaginary time slices. To efficiently run through the
modified configuration space, we introduce a modification of the widely used
continuous space worm algorithm, which allows for an efficient sampling at
arbitrary system parameters. We demonstrate how the application of determinants
achieves an effective blocking of permutations with opposite signs, leading to
a significant relieve of the fermion sign problem. To benchmark the capability
of our method regarding the simulation of degenerate fermions, we consider
multiple electrons in a quantum dot and compare our results with other ab
initio techniques, where they are available. The present permutation blocking
path integral Monte Carlo approach allows us to obtain accurate results even
for $N=20$ electrons at low temperature and arbitrary coupling, where no other
ab initio results have been reported, so far.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06404</id><created>2015-04-24</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Williamson</keyname><forenames>Lewis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blakie</keyname><forenames>P. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal coarsening dynamics of a quenched ferromagnetic spin-1
  condensate</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 025301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.025301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that a quasi-two-dimensional spin-1 condensate quenched to a
ferromagnetic phase undergoes universal coarsening in its late time dynamics.
The quench can be implemented by a sudden change in the applied magnetic field
and, depending on the final value, the ferromagnetic phase has easy-axis
(Ising) or easy-plane (XY) symmetry, with different dynamical critical
exponents. Our results for the easy-plane phase reveal a fractal domain
structure and the crucial role of polar-core spin vortices in the coarsening
dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.08162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.08162</id><created>2015-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Synthetic gauge fields for light beams in optical resonators</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 40, 2941 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.40.002941</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method to realize artificial magnetic fields for light waves trapped in
passive optical cavities with anamorphic optical elements is theoretically
proposed. In particular, when a homogeneous magnetic field is realized, a
highly-degenerate Landau level structure for the frequency spectrum of the
transverse resonator modes is obtained, corresponding to a cyclotron motion of
the optical cavity field. This can be probed by transient excitation of the
passive optical resonator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.02084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.02084</id><created>2015-05-08</created><updated>2015-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Scharnhorst</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xfc;bbena</keyname><forenames>Jannes B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannig</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakobsen</keyname><forenames>Kornelius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leroux</keyname><forenames>Ian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Piet O.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-bandwidth transfer of phase stability through a fiber frequency
  comb</title><categories>physics.optics physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. To be published in Optics Express. Clarified
  method for measuring laser noise spectra. Improved spectroscopic data in Fig.
  3, with motional decoherence now suppressed</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 23, 19771-19776 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.23.019771</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate phase locking of a 729 nm diode laser to a 1542 nm master
laser via an erbium-doped-fiber frequency comb, using a transfer-oscillator
feedforward scheme which suppresses the effect of comb noise in an
unprecedented 1.8 MHz bandwidth. We illustrate its performance by carrying out
coherent manipulations of a trapped calcium ion with 99 % fidelity even at
few-microsecond timescales. We thus demonstrate that transfer-oscillator
locking can provide sufficient phase stability for high-fidelity quantum logic
manipulation even without pre-stabilization of the slave diode laser.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04138</id><created>2015-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunable dynamic Fano resonances in coupled-resonant optical waveguide</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figures, 6 pages, to be published in Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A A 91, 063809 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.91.063809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A route toward lineshape engineering of Fano resonances in photonic
structures is theoretically proposed, which uses dynamic modulation of the
refractive index of a microcavity. The method is exemplified by considering
coupled-resonator optical waveguide systems. An exact Floquet analysis, based
on coupled-mode theory, is presented. Two distinct kinds of resonances can be
dynamically created, depending on whether the static structure sustains a
localized mode or not. In the former case a single Fano resonance arises, which
can be tuned in both frequency and line width by varying the refractive index
modulation amplitude and frequency. In the latter case two resonances, in the
form of narrow asymmetric dips in the transmittance, are found, which can
overlap resulting in an electromagnetically-induced transparency effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03441</id><created>2015-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Czerwi&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>Artur</forenames></author></authors><title>Applications of the Stroboscopic Tomography to Selected 2-Level
  Decoherence Models</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Int. J. Theor. Phys. 55 (2), 658-668 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10773-015-2703-2</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</license><abstract>  In the paper we discuss possible applications of the so-called stroboscopic
tomography (stroboscopic observability) to selected decoherence models of
2-level quantum systems. The main assumption behind our reasoning claims that
the time evolution of the analyzed system is given by a master equation of the
form $\dot{\rho} = \mathbb{L} \rho$ and the macroscopic information about the
system is provided by the mean values $m_i (t_j) = Tr(Q_i \rho(t_j))$ of
certain observables $\{Q_i\}_{i=1} ^r $ measured at different time instants
$\{t_j\}_{j=1}^p$. The goal of the stroboscopic tomography is to establish the
optimal criteria for observability of a quantum system, i.e. minimal value of
$r$ and $p$ as well as the properties of the observables $\{Q_i\}_{i=1} ^r $.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03652</id><created>2015-06-11</created><updated>2015-06-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Posik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surrow</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Research and Development of Commercially Manufactured Large GEM Foils</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>Submitted to NIM A</comments><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2015.08.048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With future experiments proposing detectors that utilize very large-area GEM
foils, there is a need for commercially available GEM foils. Double-mask
etching techniques pose a clear limitation in the maximum size of GEM foils. In
contrast, single-mask techniques developed at CERN would allow one to overcome
those limitations. However with interest in GEM foils increasing and CERN being
the only main distributor, keeping up with the demand for GEM foils will be
difficult. Thus the commercialization of GEMs has been established by Tech-Etch
of Plymouth, MA, USA using single-mask techniques.
  We report on the electrical and geometrical properties, along with the inner
and outer hole diameter size uniformity of 10 $\times$ 10 cm$^2$ and
40$\times$40 cm$^2$ GEM foils. The Tech-Etch foils were found to have excellent
electrical properties. The measured mean optical properties were found to
reflect the desired parameters and are consistent with those measured in
double-mask GEM foils, and show good hole diameter uniformity over the active
area. These foils are well suited for future applications in nuclear and
particle physics where tracking devices are needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06349</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06349</id><created>2015-06-21</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yun-He</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing models of vacuum energy interacting with cold dark matter</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures; final version published in Physical Review D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 023002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.023002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We test the models of vacuum energy interacting with cold dark matter and try
to probe the possible deviation from the $\Lambda$CDM model using current
observations. We focus on two specific models, $Q=3\beta H\rho_{\Lambda}$ and
$Q=3\beta H\rho_c$. The data combinations come from the Planck 2013 data, the
baryon acoustic oscillations measurements, the type-Ia supernovae data, the
Hubble constant measurement, the redshift space distortions data and the galaxy
weak lensing data. For the $Q=3\beta H\rho_c$ model, we find that it can be
tightly constrained by all the data combinations, while for the $Q=3\beta
H\rho_{\Lambda}$ model, there still exist significant degeneracies between
parameters. The tightest constraints for the coupling constant are
$\beta=-0.026^{+0.036}_{-0.053}$ (for $Q=3\beta H\rho_{\Lambda}$) and
$\beta=-0.00045\pm0.00069$ (for $Q=3\beta H\rho_c$) at the $1\sigma$ level. For
all the fit results, we find that the null interaction $\beta=0$ is always
consistent with data. Our work completes the discussion on the interacting dark
energy model in the recent Planck 2015 papers. Considering this work together
with the Planck 2015 results, it is believed that there is no evidence for the
models beyond the standard $\Lambda$CDM model from the point of view of
possible interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06701</id><created>2015-06-22</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Di Candia</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felicetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deppe</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marx</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gross</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum teleportation of propagating quantum microwaves</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Quantum Technology 2, 25 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjqt/s40507-015-0038-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Propagating quantum microwaves have been proposed and successfully
implemented to generate entanglement, thereby establishing a promising platform
for the realisation of a quantum communication channel. However, the
implementation of quantum teleportation with photons in the microwave regime is
still absent. At the same time, recent developments in the field show that this
key protocol could be feasible with current technology, which would pave the
way to boost the field of microwave quantum communication. Here, we discuss the
feasibility of a possible implementation of microwave quantum teleportation in
a realistic scenario with losses. Furthermore, we propose how to implement
quantum repeaters in the microwave regime without using photodetection, a key
prerequisite to achieve long distance entanglement distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02783</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02783</id><created>2015-07-10</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bentley</keyname><forenames>C. D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>A. R. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hope</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Trapped ion scaling with pulsed fast gates</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>2015 New J. Phys. 17 103025</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/10/103025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fast entangling gates for trapped ions offer vastly improved gate operation
times relative to implemented gates, as well as approaches to trap scaling.
Gates on neighbouring ions only involve local ions when performed sufficiently
fast, and we find that even a fast gate between distant ions with few degrees
of freedom restores all the motional modes given more stringent gate speed
conditions. We compare pulsed fast gate schemes, defined by a timescale faster
than the trap period, and find that our proposed scheme has less stringent
requirements on laser repetition rate for achieving arbitrary gate time targets
and infidelities well below $10^{-4}$. By extending gate schemes to ion
crystals, we explore the effect of ion number on gate fidelity for coupling
neighbouring pairs of ions in large crystals. Inter-ion distance determines the
gate time, and a factor of five increase in repetition rate, or correspondingly
the laser power, reduces the infidelity by almost two orders of magnitude. We
also apply our fast gate scheme to entangle the first and last ions in a
crystal. As the number of ions in the crystal increases, significant increases
in the laser power are required to provide the short gate times corresponding
to fidelity above 0.99.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03010</id><created>2015-07-10</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Subo</forenames><affiliation>KIAA-PKU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shappee</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames><affiliation>Carnegie</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Prieto</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames><affiliation>UDP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Jha</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames><affiliation>Rutgers</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stanek</keyname><forenames>K. Z.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio State</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Holoien</keyname><forenames>T. W. -S.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio State</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kochanek</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio State</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio State</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morrell</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames><affiliation>LCO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>I. B.</forenames><affiliation>Carnegie</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beacom</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bersier</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brimacombe</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bufano</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conseil</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danilet</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falco</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grupe</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiyota</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicholls</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olivares</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pignata</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pojmanski</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simonian</keyname><forenames>G. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szczygiel</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wozniak</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>ASASSN-15lh: A Highly Super-Luminous Supernova</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Published in the January 15, 2016 Issue of Science Magazine</comments><doi>10.1126/science.aac9613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the discovery of ASASSN-15lh (SN 2015L), which we interpret as the
most luminous supernova yet found. At redshift z = 0.2326, ASASSN-15lh reached
an absolute magnitude of M_{u,AB} = -23.5+/-0.1 and bolometric luminosity L_bol
= (2.2+/-0.2)x 10^45 ergs s^-1, which is more than twice as luminous as any
previously known supernova. It has several major features characteristic of the
hydrogen-poor super-luminous supernovae (SLSNe-I), whose energy sources and
progenitors are currently poorly understood. In contrast to most previously
known SLSNe-I that reside in star-forming dwarf galaxies, ASASSN-15lh appears
to be hosted by a luminous galaxy (M_K ~ -25.5) with little star formation. In
the 4 months since first detection, ASASSN-15lh radiated (1.1+/- 0.2)x10^52
ergs, challenging the magnetar model for its engine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04148</id><created>2015-07-15</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Titimbo</keyname><forenames>Kelvin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmermann</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giusti</keyname><forenames>Francesca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Randi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boschetto</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parmigiani</keyname><forenames>Fulvio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Floreanini</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benatti</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fausti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon number statistics uncover the fluctuations in non-equilibrium
  lattice dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages (main text), 5 figures, 11 pages (supplementary information)</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communication, 6, 10249 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms10249</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fluctuations of the atomic positions are at the core of a large class of
unusual material properties ranging from quantum para-electricity to high
temperature superconductivity. Their measurement in solids is the subject of an
intense scientific debate focused on seeking a methodology capable of
establishing a direct link between the variance of the atomic displacements and
experimentally measurable observables. Here we address this issue by means of
non-equilibrium optical experiments performed in shot-noise limited regime. The
variance of the time dependent atomic positions and momenta is directly mapped
into the quantum fluctuations of the photon number of the scattered probing
light. A fully quantum description of the non-linear interaction between
photonic and phononic fields is benchmarked by unveiling the squeezing of
thermal phonons in $\alpha$-quartz.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04801</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04801</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Kelly A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>Jared H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge filling factors in clean and disordered arrays of tunnel
  junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 5, 17572 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep17572</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We simulate one-dimensional arrays of tunnel junctions using the kinetic
Monte Carlo method to study charge filling behaviour in the large charging
energy limit. By applying a small fixed voltage bias and varying the offset
voltage, we investigate this behaviour in clean and disordered arrays (both
weak and strong disorder effects). The offset voltage dependent modulation of
the current is highly sensitive to background charge disorder and exhibits
substantial variation depending on the strength of the disorder. We show that
while small fractional charge filling factors are likely to be washed out in
experimental devices due to strong background charge disorder, larger factors
may be observable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05401</id><created>2015-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sturm</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furthm&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bechstedt</keyname><forenames>Friedhelm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt-Grund</keyname><forenames>R&#xfc;diger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grundmann</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author></authors><title>Dielectric tensor of monoclinic Ga$_2$O$_3$ single crystals in the
  spectral range $0.5 - 8.5\,$eV</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>APL Mater. 3, 106106 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4934705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dielectric tensor of $\beta$-Ga$_2$O$_3$ was determined by generalized
spectroscopic ellipsometry in a wide spectral range from $0.5\,\mathrm{eV}$ to
$8.5\,\mathrm{eV}$ as well as by calculation including quasiparticle bands and
excitonic effects. The dielectric tensors obtained by both methods are in
excellent agreement with each other and the observed transitions in the
dielectric function are assigned to the corresponding valence bands. It is
shown that the off-diagonal element of the dielectric tensor reaches values up
to $|\varepsilon_{xz} | \approx 0.30 $ and cannot be neglected. Even in the
transparent spectral range where it is quite small ($|\varepsilon_{xz} | &lt; 0.02
$) it causes a rotation of the dielectric axes around the symmetry axis of up
to $20^\circ$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06713</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06713</id><created>2015-07-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Shastri</keyname><forenames>Bhavin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nahmias</keyname><forenames>Mitchell A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tait</keyname><forenames>Alexander N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Alejandro W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prucnal</keyname><forenames>Paul R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical laser spike processing</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 19126 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep19126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novel materials and devices in photonics have the potential to revolutionize
optical information processing, beyond conventional binary-logic approaches.
Laser systems offer a rich repertoire of useful dynamical behaviors, including
the excitable dynamics also found in the time-resolved &quot;spiking&quot; of neurons.
Spiking reconciles the expressiveness and efficiency of analog processing with
the robustness and scalability of digital processing. We demonstrate that
graphene-coupled laser systems offer a unified low-level spike optical
processing paradigm that goes well beyond previously studied laser dynamics. We
show that this platform can simultaneously exhibit logic-level restoration,
cascadability and input-output isolation---fundamental challenges in optical
information processing. We also implement low-level spike-processing tasks that
are critical for higher level processing: temporal pattern detection and stable
recurrent memory. We study these properties in the context of a fiber laser
system, but the addition of graphene leads to a number of advantages which stem
from its unique properties, including high absorption and fast carrier
relaxation. These could lead to significant speed and efficiency improvements
in unconventional laser processing devices, and ongoing research on graphene
microfabrication promises compatibility with integrated laser platforms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07651</id><created>2015-07-28</created><updated>2015-09-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Della Valle</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Hermitian transparency and one-way transport in low-dimensional
  lattices by an imaginary gauge field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>final version, to appear in Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 094204 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.094204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unidirectional and robust transport is generally observed at the edge of two-
or three-dimensional quantum Hall and topological insulator systems. A hallmark
of these systems is topological protection, i.e. the existence of propagative
edge states that cannot be scattered by imperfections or disorder in the
system. A different and less explored form of robust transport arises in
non-Hermitian systems in the presence of an {\it imaginary} gauge field. As
compared to topologically-protected transport in quantum Hall and topological
insulator systems, robust non-Hermitian transport can be observed in {\it
lower} dimensional (i.e. one dimensional) systems. In this work the transport
properties of one-dimensional tight-binding lattices with an imaginary gauge
field are theoretically investigated, and the physical mechanism underlying
robust one-way transport is highlighted. Back scattering is here forbidden
because reflected waves are evanescent rather than propagative. Remarkably, the
spectral transmission of the non-Hermitian lattice is shown to be mapped into
the one of the corresponding Hermitian lattice, i.e. without the gauge field,
{\it but} computed in the complex plane. In particular, at large values of the
gauge field the spectral transmittance becomes equal to one, even in the
presence of disorder or lattice imperfections. This phenomenon can be referred
to as {\it one-way non-Hermitian transparency}. Robust one-way transport can be
also realized in a more realistic setting, namely in heterostructure systems,
in which a non-Hermitian disordered lattice is embedded between two homogeneous
Hermitian lattices. Such a double heterostructure realizes asymmetric
(non-reciprocal) wave transmission. A physical implementation of non-Hermtian
transparency, based on light transport in a chain of optical microring
resonators, is suggested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01120</id><created>2015-08-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Moldabekov</keyname><forenames>Zhandos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoof</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludwig</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonitz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramazanov</keyname><forenames>Tlekkabul</forenames></author></authors><title>Statically screened ion potential and Bohm potential in a quantum plasma</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Plasmas 22, 102104 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4932051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The effective potential $\Phi$ of a classical ion in a weakly correlated
quantum plasma in thermodynamic equilibrium at finite temperature is well
described by the RPA screened Coulomb potential. Additionally, collision
effects can be included via a relaxation time ansatz (Mermin dielectric
function). These potentials are used to study the quality of various statically
screened potentials that were recently proposed by Shukla and Eliasson (SE)
[Phys. Rev. Lett. {\bf 108}, 165007 (2012)], Akbari--Moghanjoughi (AM) [Phys.
Plasmas {\bf 22}, 022103 (2015)] and Stanton and Murillo (SM) [Phys. Rev. E
{\bf 91}, 033104 (2015)] starting from quantum hydrodynamic theory (QHD). Our
analysis reveals that the SE potential is qualitatively different from the full
potential, whereas the SM potential (at any temperature) and the AM potential
(at zero temperature) are significantly more accurate. This confirms the
correctness of the recently derived [Michta {\em et al.}, Contrib. Plasma Phys.
{\bf 55}, (2015)] pre-factor $1/9$ in front of the Bohm term of QHD for
fermions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01425</id><created>2015-08-06</created><updated>2016-01-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duerr</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Pavel Fileviez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Juri</forenames></author></authors><title>Gamma Lines from Majorana Dark Matter</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, version to appear in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 023509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.023509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss simple models which predict the existence of significant gamma-ray
fluxes from dark matter annihilation. In this context the dark matter candidate
is a Majorana fermion with velocity-suppressed tree-level annihilation into
Standard Model fermions but unsuppressed annihilation into photons. These gamma
lines can easily be distinguished from the continuum and provide a possibility
to test these models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02947</id><created>2015-08-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Schl&#xfc;nzen</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hermanns</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonitz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verdozzi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio transport results for strongly correlated fermions</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 035107 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.035107</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum transport of strongly correlated fermions is of central interest in
condensed matter physics. Here, we present first-principle nonequilibrium Green
functions results using $T$-matrix selfenergies for finite Hubbard clusters of
dimension $1,2,3$. We compute the expansion dynamics following a potential
quench and predict its dependence on the interaction strength and particle
number. We discover a universal scaling, allowing an extrapolation to
infinite-size systems, which shows excellent agreement with recent cold atom
diffusion experiments [Schneider et al., Nat. Phys. 8, 213 (2012)].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03221</id><created>2015-08-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Dornheim</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoof</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groth</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filinov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonitz</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Permutation blocking path integral Monte Carlo approach to the uniform
  electron gas at finite temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 204101 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4936145</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The uniform electron gas (UEG) at finite temperature is of high current
interest due to its key relevance for many applications including dense plasmas
and laser excited solids. In particular, density functional theory heavily
relies on accurate thermodynamic data for the UEG. Until recently, the only
existing first-principle results had been obtained for $N=33$ electrons with
restricted path integral Monte Carlo (RPIMC), for low to moderate density,
  $r_s = \overline{r}/a_B \gtrsim 1$. This data has been complemented by
Configuration path integral Monte Carlo (CPIMC) simulations for $r_s \leq 1$
that substantially deviate from RPIMC towards smaller $r_s$ and low
temperature. In this work, we present results from an independent third
method---the recently developed permutation blocking path integral Monte Carlo
(PB-PIMC) approach [T. Dornheim \textit{et al.}, NJP \textbf{17}, 073017
(2015)] which we extend to the UEG. Interestingly, PB-PIMC allows us to perform
simulations over the entire density range down to half the Fermi temperature
($\theta=k_BT/E_F=0.5$) and, therefore, to compare our results to both
aforementioned methods. While we find excellent agreement with CPIMC, where
results are available, we observe deviations from RPIMC that are beyond the
statistical errors and increase with density.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03900</id><created>2015-08-16</created><updated>2015-08-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yinwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hanyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yunwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickard</keyname><forenames>Chris J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Joseph R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Needs</keyname><forenames>Richard J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wentao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yanwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Errea</keyname><forenames>Ion</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calandra</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauri</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yanming</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissociation products and structures of solid H2S at strong compression</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 020103(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.020103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrogen sulfides have recently received a great deal of interest due to the
record high superconducting temperatures of up to 203 K observed on strong
compression of dihydrogen sulfide (H2S). A joint theoretical and experimental
study is presented in which decomposition products and structures of compressed
H2S are characterized, and their superconducting properties are calculated. In
addition to the experimentally known H2S and H3S phases, our first-principles
structure searches have identified several energetically competitive
stoichiometries that have not been reported previously; H2S3, H3S2, and H4S3.
In particular, H4S3 is predicted to be thermodynamically stable within a large
pressure range of 25-113 GPa. High-pressure room-temperature X-ray diffraction
measurements confirm the presence of H3S and H4S3 through decomposition of H2S
that emerge at 27 GPa and coexist with residual H2S, at least up to the highest
pressure studied in our experiments of 140 GPa. Electron-phonon coupling
calculations show that H4S3 has a small Tc of below 2 K, and that H2S is mainly
responsible for the observed superconductivity of samples prepared at low
temperature (&lt;100K).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04937</id><created>2015-08-20</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asaka</keyname><forenames>Takehiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsuyuki</keyname><forenames>Takanao</forenames></author></authors><title>Seesaw mechanism at electron-electron colliders</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, REVTeX 4; v2: added references, modified Fig. 6;
  v3: corrected typos, added references, published version; v4: corrected typos
  in Eq. (31) and the caption of Fig. 3</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 094012 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.094012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the Standard Model with right-handed neutrinos to explain the
masses of active neutrinos by the seesaw mechanism. Since active neutrinos as
well as heavy neutral leptons are Majorana fermions in this case, the lepton
number violating process can be induced. We discuss the inverse neutrinoless
double beta decay $e^- e^- \to W^- W^-$ in the framework of the seesaw
mechanism and its detectability at future colliders. It is shown that the cross
section can be 17 fb for $\sqrt{s}=3$ TeV even with the stringent constraint
from the neutrinoless double beta decays if three (or more) right-handed
neutrinos exist. In such a case, the future $e^- e^-$ colliders can test lepton
number violation mediated by a right-handed neutrino lighter than about 10 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05864</id><created>2015-08-21</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lagos</keyname><forenames>Macarena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noller</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author></authors><title>New massive bigravity cosmologies with double matter coupling</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>Last version includes minor changes to text and references</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)023</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a previously largely unexplored branch of homogeneous and isotropic
background solutions in ghost-free massive bigravity with consistent double
matter coupling. For a certain family of parameters we find `self-inflated'
FLRW cosmologies, i.e. solutions with an accelerated early-time period during
the radiation-dominated era. In addition, these solutions also display an
accelerated late-time period closely mimicking GR with a cosmological constant.
Interestingly, within this family, the particular case of $\beta_1=\beta_3=0$
gives bouncing cosmologies, where there is an infinite contracting past, a
non-zero minimum value of the scale factor at the bounce, and an infinite
expanding future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06988</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06988</id><created>2015-08-24</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Patrick Das</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathemagical 2014 - An Indian Perspective</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>This is an augmented version of my article `A Mathemagical Year!'
  (DOI: 10.13140/2.1.4349.1204)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mathematics is probably the only subject that can be classified both as art
as well as science - former, because it is not constrained by the real world
and latter because it is a logical system with precisely defined rules as well
as primitives that lead to unambiguous nontrivial theorems. Indian (and of
Indian origin) mathematicians have continued to do seminal work till present
times, culminating in Manjul Bhargava receiving the Fields Medal last year. In
such fabulous times, a non-mathematician ponders about the nature of
mathematics, and revisits the question: why are fundamental laws of Nature
inherently mathematical?
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00648</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00648</id><created>2015-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization without recurrence and pseudo-Bloch oscillations in optics</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>4 figure, 6 pages</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 40, 4707 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.40.004707</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical localization, i.e. the absence of secular spreading of a quantum or
classical wave packet, is usually associated to Hamiltonians with purely point
spectrum, i.e. with a normalizable and complete set of eigenstates, which show
quasi-periodic dynamics (recurrence). Here we show rather counter-intuitively
that dynamical localization can be observed in Hamiltonians with absolutely
continuous spectrum, where recurrence effects are forbidden. An optical
realization of such an Hamiltonian is proposed based on beam propagation in a
self-imaging optical resonator with a phase grating. Localization without
recurrence in this system is explained in terms of pseudo-Bloch optical
oscillations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04404</id><created>2015-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Novel valley depolarization dynamics and valley Hall effect of exciton
  in mono- and bilayer MoS$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 045414 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.045414</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the valley depolarization dynamics and valley Hall effect of
exciton due to the electron-hole exchange interaction in mono- and bilayer
MoS$_2$ by solving the kinetic spin Bloch equations. The effect of the exciton
energy spectra by the electron-hole exchange interaction is explicitly
considered. For the valley depolarization dynamics, in the monolayer MoS$_2$,
it is found that in the strong scattering regime, the conventional motional
narrowing picture is no longer valid, and a novel valley depolarization channel
is opened. For the valley Hall effect of exciton, in both the mono- and bilayer
MoS$_2$, with the exciton equally pumped in the K and K' valleys, the system
can evolve into the equilibrium state where the valley polarization is parallel
to the effective magnetic field due to the exchange interaction. With the drift
of this equilibrium state by applied uniaxial strain, the exchange interaction
can induce the {\it momentum-dependent} valley/photoluminesence polarization,
which leads to the valley/photoluminesence Hall current. Specifically, the
disorder strength dependence of the valley Hall conductivity is revealed. In
the strong scattering regime, the valley Hall conductivity decreases with the
increase of the disorder strength; whereas in the weak scattering regime, it
saturates to a constant, which can be much larger than the one in Fermi system
due to the absence of the Pauli blocking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05613</id><created>2015-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>Morten Hannibal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Poul-Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging Scatterometry</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1364/OE.24.001109</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an optical metrology system for characterization of topography of
micro/nano-structures on a surface or embedded in a semi-transparent material.
Based on the principles of scatterometry, where the intensity of scattered
light is used as a 'fingerprint' to reconstruct a surface, this new imaging
scatterometer can easily find areas of interest on the cm scale and measure
multiple segments simultaneously. The imaging scatterometer measures structural
features, such as height, width, and sidewall angle of a grating locally on few
um2 areas with nm resolution. We demonstrate two imaging scatterometers, one
built into an optical microscope and one in a split configuration. The two
scatterometers are targeted characterization of mm2 and cm2 areas,
respectively, and both setups are validated using nano-textured samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05784</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2015-11-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenting</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham, South Road, DH1 3LE Durham, UK</affiliation></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institut fur Astrophysik, Karl-Schwarzschild-Str. 1, 85741 Garching b. M&#xfc;nchen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mandelbaum</keyname><forenames>Rachel</forenames><affiliation>McWilliams Center for Cosmology, Department of Physics, Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA 15213, USA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Henriques</keyname><forenames>Bruno</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institut fur Astrophysik, Karl-Schwarzschild-Str. 1, 85741 Garching b. M&#xfc;nchen, Germany</affiliation><affiliation>Institute for Astronomy, Department of Physics, ETH Zurich, 8093 Zurich, Switzerland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames><affiliation>Max Planck Institut fur Astrophysik, Karl-Schwarzschild-Str. 1, 85741 Garching b. M&#xfc;nchen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jiaxin</forenames><affiliation>Institute for Computational Cosmology, University of Durham, South Road, DH1 3LE Durham, UK</affiliation></author></authors><title>A weak gravitational lensing recalibration of the scaling relations
  linking the gas properties of dark halos to their mass</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>22 pages, 11 figures, accepted by MNRAS</comments><report-no>DURAST/2015/0004</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2809</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use weak gravitational lensing to measure mean mass profiles around
Locally Brightest Galaxies (LBGs). These are selected from the SDSS/DR7
spectroscopic and photometric catalogues to be brighter than any neighbour
projected within 1.0 Mpc and differing in redshift by $&lt;1000$ km/s. Most ($&gt;
83\%$) are expected to be the central galaxies of their dark matter halos.
Previous stacking analyses have used this LBG sample to measure mean
Sunyaev-Zeldovich flux and mean X-ray luminosity as a function of LBG stellar
mass. In both cases, a simulation of the formation of the galaxy population was
used to estimate effective halo mass for LBGs of given stellar mass, allowing
the derivation of scaling relations between the gas properties of halos and
their mass. By comparing results from a variety of simulations to our lensing
data, we show that this procedure has significant model dependence reflecting:
(i) the failure of any given simulation to reproduce observed galaxy abundances
exactly; (ii) a dependence on the cosmology underlying the simulation; and
(iii) a dependence on the details of how galaxies populate halos. We use our
lensing results to recalibrate the scaling relations, eliminating most of this
model dependence and explicitly accounting both for residual modelling
uncertainties and for observational uncertainties in the lensing results. The
resulting scaling relations link the mean gas properties of dark halos to their
mass over an unprecedentedly wide range, $10^{12.5}&lt;M_{500}/
\mathrm{M_\odot}&lt;10^{14.5}$, and should fairly and robustly represent the full
halo population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07335</id><created>2015-09-24</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of four-jet differential cross sections in $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV
  proton-proton collisions using the ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>59 pages plus author list (75 pages total), 19 figures, 49 tables,
  published version, all figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2014-14/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-181</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 12 (2015) 105</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2015)105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Differential cross sections for the production of at least four jets have
been measured in proton-proton collisions at $\sqrt{s} = 8$ TeV at the Large
Hadron Collider using the ATLAS detector. Events are selected if the four
anti-$k_{t}$ R=0.4 jets with the largest transverse momentum ($p_{T}$) within
the rapidity range $|y|&lt;2.8$ are well separated ($dR^{\rm min}_{4j}&gt;0.65$), all
have $p_{T}&gt;64$ GeV, and include at least one jet with $p_{T} &gt;100$ GeV. The
dataset corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 20.3 $fb^{-1}$. The cross
sections, corrected for detector effects, are compared to leading-order and
next-to-leading-order calculations as a function of the jet momenta, invariant
masses, minimum and maximum opening angles and other kinematic variables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07623</id><created>2015-09-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>Morten Hannibal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boher</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>Poul-Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>J&#xf8;rgensen</keyname><forenames>Jan Friis</forenames></author></authors><title>Alignment free characterization of 2D gratings</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1364/AO.55.000317</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fast characterization of 2-dimensional gratings is demonstrated using a
Fourier lens optical system and a differential optimization algorithm. It is
shown that both the grating specific parameters such as the basis vectors and
the angle between them and the alignment of the sample, such as the rotation of
the sample around the x-, y-, and z-axis, can be deduced from a single
measurement. More specifically, the lattice vectors and the angle between them
have been measured, while the corrections of the alignment parameters are used
to improve the quality of the measurement, and hence reduce the measurement
uncertainty. Alignment free characterization is demonstrated on both a 2D
hexagonal grating with a period of 700 nm and a checkerboard grating with a
pitch of 3000 nm. The method can also be used for both automatic alignment and
in-line characterization of gratings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08928</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08928</id><created>2015-09-27</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frolov</keyname><forenames>Alexei M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Hamilton approach for the metric GR</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Basic principles of the Hamilton approach developed for the metric General
Relativity (Einstein`s GR) are discussed. In particular, we derive the
Hamiltonian of the metric GR in the explicit form. This Hamiltonian is a
quadratic function of the momenta $\pi^{mn}$ conjugate to the spatial
components $g_{mn}$ of the metric tensor $g_{\alpha\beta}$. The Hamilton
approach is used to analyze some problems of metric GR, including the internal
structure of propagating gravitational waves and quantization of the metric GR.
We also derive the Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation for the free Gravitational field
and show that actual gravitational field cannot propagate as pure harmonic
oscillations, or harmonic gravitational waves. A number of inequalities useful
in applications to the metric GR are derived.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01480</id><created>2015-10-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Bloch oscillations in non-Hermitian lattices with trajectories in
  complex plane</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, to appear in Phys. Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 042116 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.042116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bloch oscillations (BOs), i.e. the oscillatory motion of a quantum particle
in a periodic potential, are one of the most striking effects of coherent
quantum transport in the matter. In the semiclassical picture, it is well known
that BOs can be explained owing to the periodic band structure of the crystal
and the so-called 'acceleration' theorem: since in the momentum space the
particle wave packet drifts with a constant speed without being distorted, in
real space the probability distribution of the particle undergoes a periodic
motion following a trajectory which exactly reproduces the shape of the lattice
band. In non-Hermitian lattices with a complex (i.e. not real) energy band,
extension of the semiclassical model is not intuitive. Here we show that the
acceleration theorem holds for non-Hermitian lattices with a complex energy
band only {\it on average}, and that the periodic wave packet motion of the
particle in the real space is described by a trajectory in {\it complex} plane,
i.e. it generally corresponds to reshaping and breathing of the wave packet in
addition to a transverse oscillatory motion. The concept of BOs involving
complex trajectories is exemplified by considering two examples of
non-Hermitian lattices with a complex band dispersion relation, including the
Hatano-Nelson tight-binding Hamiltonian describing the hopping motion of a
quantum particle on a linear lattice with an imaginary vector potential and a
tight-binding lattice with imaginary hopping rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03360</id><created>2015-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goracke</keyname><forenames>Byron D.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Ground-level ozone following astrophysical ionizing radiation events: an
  additional biological hazard?</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.HE q-bio.PE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Astrobiology</comments><journal-ref>Astrobiology, Vol. 16, Num. 1, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1089/ast.2015.1311</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Astrophysical ionizing radiation events such as supernovae, gamma-ray bursts,
and solar proton events have been recognized as a potential threat to life on
Earth, primarily through depletion of stratospheric ozone and subsequent
increase in solar UV radiation at Earth's surface and in the upper levels of
the ocean. Other work has also considered the potential impact of nitric acid
rainout, concluding that no significant threat is likely. Not yet studied
to-date is the potential impact of ozone produced in the lower atmosphere
following an ionizing radiation event. Ozone is a known irritant to organisms
on land and in water and therefore may be a significant additional hazard.
Using previously completed atmospheric chemistry modeling we have examined the
amount of ozone produced in the lower atmosphere for the case of a gamma-ray
burst and find that the values are too small to pose a significant additional
threat to the biosphere. These results may be extended to other ionizing
radiation events, including supernovae and extreme solar proton events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04275</id><created>2015-10-14</created><updated>2015-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maksimov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyshev</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Field-induced dynamical properties of the $XXZ$ model on a honeycomb
  lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>19 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 014418 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.014418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comprehensive $1/S$ study of the field-induced dynamical
properties of the nearest-neighbor $XXZ$ antiferromagnet on a honeycomb lattice
using the formalism of the nonlinear spin-wave theory developed for this model.
The external magnetic field controls spin frustration in the system and induces
non-collinearity of the spin structure, which is essential for the two-magnon
decay processes. Our results include an intriguing field-evolution of the
regions of the Brillouin zone wherein decays of spin excitations are prominent,
a detailed classification of the decay channels involving magnons from both
excitation branches, and a thorough analysis of the singularities in the magnon
spectra due to coupling to the two magnon continuum, all of which are
illustrated for several field and anisotropy values. We highlight a number of
features related to either the non-Bravais nature of the lattice, or the
existence of the Dirac-like points in the spectrum. In addition, the asymptotic
behavior of the decay rates near high-symmetry points is analyzed in detail.
The inelastic neutron-scattering spin-spin structure factor is obtained in the
leading $1/S$ order and is shown to exhibit qualitatively distinct fingerprints
of the decay-induced magnon dynamics such as quasiparticle peaks broadened by
decays and strong spectral weight redistribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05506</id><created>2015-10-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Longhi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Half-spectral unidirectional invisibility in non-Hermitian periodic
  optical structures</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 40, 5694 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.40.005694</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phenomenon of half-spectral unidirectional invisibility is introduced for
one-dimensional periodic optical structures with tailored real and imaginary
refractive index distributions in a non-$\mathcal{PT}$-symmetric configuration.
The effect refers to the property that the optical medium appears to be
invisible, both in reflection and transmission, below the Bragg frequency when
probed from one side, and above the Bragg frequency when probed from the
opposite side. Half-spectral invisibility is obtained by a combination of
in-phase index and gain gratings whose spatial amplitudes are related each
other by a Hilbert transform.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08538</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08538</id><created>2015-10-28</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Yongkang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghimire</keyname><forenames>N. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ronning</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>&quot;Hard&quot; crystalline lattice in the Weyl semimetal NbAs</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 1 table</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 055502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/5/055502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the effect of hydrostatic pressure on the magnetotransport
properties of the Weyl semimetal NbAs. Subtle changes can be seen in the
$\rho_{xx}(T)$ profiles with pressure up to 2.31 GPa. The Fermi surfaces
undergo an anisotropic evolution under pressure: the extremal areas slightly
increase in the $\mathbf{k_x}$-$\mathbf{k_y}$ plane, but decrease in the
$\mathbf{k_z}$-$\mathbf{k_y}$($\mathbf{k_x}$) plane. The topological features
of the two pockets observed at atmospheric pressure, however, remain unchanged
at 2.31 GPa. No superconductivity can be seen down to 0.3 K for all the
pressures measured. By fitting the temperature dependence of specific heat to
the Debye model, we obtain a small Sommerfeld coefficient $\gamma_0=$ 0.09(1)
mJ/(mol$\cdot$K$^2$) and a large Debye temperature, $\Theta_D=$ 450(9) K,
confirming a &quot;hard&quot; crystalline lattice that is stable under pressure. We also
studied the Kadowaki-Woods ratio of this low-carrier-density massless system,
$R_{KW}=$ 3.2$\times 10^4$ $\mu\Omega$ cm mol$^2$ K$^2$ J$^{-2}$. After
accounting for the small carrier density in NbAs, this $R_{KW}$ indicates a
suppressed transport scattering rate relative to other metals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01415</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01415</id><created>2015-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Campagne-Ibarcq</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Six</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bretheau</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarlette</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirrahimi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouchon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huard</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Observing quantum state diffusion by heterodyne detection of
  fluorescence</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Supplementary material can be found in the ancillary section</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 011002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.011002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A qubit can relax by fluorescence, which prompts the release of a photon into
its electromagnetic environment. By counting the emitted photons, discrete
quantum jumps of the qubit state can be observed. The succession of states
occupied by the qubit in a single experiment, its quantum trajectory, depends
in fact on the kind of detector. How are the quantum trajectories modified if
one measures continuously the amplitude of the fluorescence field instead?
Using a superconducting parametric amplifier, we have performed heterodyne
detection of the fluorescence of a superconducting qubit. For each realization
of the measurement record, we can reconstruct a different quantum trajectory
for the qubit. The observed evolution obeys quantum state diffusion, which is
characteristic of quantum measurements subject to zero point fluctuations.
Independent projective measurements of the qubit at various times provide a
quantitative validation of the reconstructed trajectories. By exploring the
statistics of quantum trajectories, we demonstrate that the qubit states span a
deterministic surface in the Bloch sphere at each time in the evolution.
Additionally, we show that when monitoring fluorescence, coherent
superpositions are generated during the decay from excited to ground state.
Counterintuitively, measuring light emitted during relaxation can give rise to
trajectories with increased excitation probability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01890</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Correia</keyname><forenames>Alexandre C. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cassini states for black hole binaries</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.EP astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 457, L49-L53 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slv198</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cassini states correspond to the equilibria of the spin axis of a body when
its orbit is perturbed. They were initially described for planetary satellites,
but the spin axes of black hole binaries also present this kind of equilibria.
In previous works, Cassini states were reported as spin-orbit resonances, but
actually the spin of black hole binaries is in circulation and there is no
resonant motion. Here we provide a general description of the spin dynamics of
black hole binary systems based on a Hamiltonian formalism. In absence of
dissipation the problem is integrable and it is easy to identify all possible
trajectories for the spin for a given value of the total angular momentum. As
the system collapses due to radiation reaction, the Cassini states are shifted
to different positions, which modifies the dynamics around them. This is why
the final spin distribution may differ from the initial one. Our method
provides a simple way of predicting the distribution of the spin of black hole
binaries at the end of the inspiral phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07828</id><created>2015-11-24</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Behrndt</keyname><forenames>Jussi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rohleder</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stadler</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenvalue inequalities for Schr\&quot;odinger operators on unbounded
  Lipschitz domains</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>revised version; to appear in J. Spectr. Theory</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Given a Schr\&quot;odinger differential expression on an exterior Lipschitz domain
we prove strict inequalities between the eigenvalues of the corresponding
selfadjoint operators subject to Dirichlet and Neumann or Dirichlet and mixed
boundary conditions, respectively. Moreover, we prove a strict inequality
between the eigenvalues of two different elliptic differential operators on the
same domain with Dirichlet boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08269</id><created>2015-11-25</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>McBride</keyname><forenames>R. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slutz</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vesey</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sefkow</keyname><forenames>A. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knapp</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmit</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geissel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harvey-Thompson</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jennings</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harding</keyname><forenames>E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awe</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rovang</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hahn</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cochrane</keyname><forenames>K. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peterson</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rochau</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porter</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stygar</keyname><forenames>W. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakhleh</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuneo</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinars</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring magnetized liner inertial fusion with a semi-analytic model</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Published in Physics of Plasmas [http://dx.doi.org/10.1063/1.4939479]</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Plasmas 23, 012705 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939479</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we explore magnetized liner inertial fusion (MagLIF) [S. A.
Slutz et al., Phys. Plasmas 17, 056303 (2010)] using a semi-analytic model [R.
D. McBride and S. A. Slutz, Phys. Plasmas 22, 052708 (2015)]. Specifically, we
present simulation results from this model that: (a) illustrate the parameter
space, energetics, and overall system efficiencies of MagLIF; (b) demonstrate
the dependence of radiative loss rates on the radial fraction of the fuel that
is preheated; (c) explore some of the recent experimental results of the MagLIF
program at Sandia National Laboratories [M. R. Gomez et al., Phys. Rev. Lett.
113, 155003 (2014)]; (d) highlight the experimental challenges presently facing
the MagLIF program; and (e) demonstrate how increases to the preheat energy,
fuel density, axial magnetic field, and drive current could affect future
MagLIF performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08421</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08421</id><created>2015-11-26</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fedorenko</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Major</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pressman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durose</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic Properties of CdS/CdTe Solar Cells as Influenced by a Buffer
  Layer</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This article gives an overview of results presented at 2015 MRS Fall
  Meeting</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We considered modification of the defect density of states in CdTe as
influenced by a buffer layer in ZnO(ZnS, SnSe)/CdS/CdTe solar cells. Compared
to the solar cells employing ZnO buffer layers, implementation of ZnSe and ZnS
resulted in the lower net ionized acceptor concentration and the energy shift
of the dominant deep trap levels to the midgap of CdTe. The results clearly
indicated that the same defect was responsible for the inefficient doping and
the formation of recombination centers in CdTe. This observation can be
explained taking into account the effect of strain on the electronic properties
of the grain boundary interface states in polycrystalline CdTe. In the
conditions of strain, interaction of chlorine with the grain boundary point
defects can be altered.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08693</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Posik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surrow</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>R&amp;D of Commercially Manufactured Large GEM Foils</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures, Submitted as conference record to IEEE Nucl. Sci.
  Symposium, San Diego, CA. Version 2: Updated reference [5]</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many experiments are currently using or proposing to use large area GEM foils
in their detectors, which is creating a need for commercially available GEM
foils. Currently CERN is the only main distributor of GEM foils, however with
the growing interest in GEM technology keeping up with the increasing demand
for GEM foils will be difficult. Thus the commercialization of GEM foils has
been established by Tech-Etch Inc. of Plymouth, MA, USA using the single-mask
technique, which is capable of producing GEM foils over a meter long.
  To date Tech-Etch has successfully manufactured 10 $\times$ 10 cm$^2$ and 40
$\times$ 40 cm$^2$ GEM foils. We will report on the electrical and geometrical
properties, along with the inner and outer hole diameter size uniformity of
these foils. Furthermore, Tech-Etch has now begun producing even larger GEM
foils of 50 $\times$ 50 cm$^2$, and are currently looking into how to
accommodate GEM foils on the order of one meter long.
  The Tech-Etch foils were found to have excellent electrical properties. The
measured mean optical properties were found to reflect the desired parameters
and are consistent with those measured in double-mask GEM foils, as well as
single-mask GEM foils produced at CERN. They also show good hole diameter
uniformity over the active area.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04009</id><created>2015-12-13</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ying</keyname><forenames>Shenggang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ying</keyname><forenames>Mingsheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Privacy-Preserving Data Mining</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR cs.DB cs.LG</categories><comments>5 pages. Comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Data mining is a key technology in big data analytics and it can discover
understandable knowledge (patterns) hidden in large data sets. Association rule
is one of the most useful knowledge patterns, and a large number of algorithms
have been developed in the data mining literature to generate association rules
corresponding to different problems and situations. Privacy becomes a vital
issue when data mining is used to sensitive data sets like medical records,
commercial data sets and national security. In this Letter, we present a
quantum protocol for mining association rules on vertically partitioned
databases. The quantum protocol can improve the privacy level preserved by
known classical protocols and at the same time it can exponentially reduce the
computational complexity and communication cost.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05646</id><created>2015-12-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal conductivity of the diamond-chain compound Cu_3(CO_3)_2(OH)_2</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in J. Phys.: Condens.
  Matt</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matt. 28, 056002 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/5/056002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermal conductivity (\kappa) of a distorted spin diamond-chain system,
Cu_3(CO_3)_2(OH)_2, is studied at low temperatures down to 0.3 K and in
magnetic fields up to 14 T. In zero field, the \kappa(T) curve with heat
current along the chain direction has very small magnitudes and shows a
pronounced three-peak structure. The magnetic fields along and perpendicular to
the chains change the \kappa strongly in a way having good correspondence to
the changes of magnetic specific heat in fields. The data analysis based on the
Debye model for phononic thermal conductivity indicates that the heat transport
is due to phonons and the three-peak structure is caused by two resonant
scattering processes by the magnetic excitations. In particular, the spin
excitations of the chain subsystem are strongly scattering phonons rather than
transporting heat.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07389</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07389</id><created>2015-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Miyazono</keyname><forenames>Evan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Tian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craiciu</keyname><forenames>Ioana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kindem</keyname><forenames>Jonathan M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faraon</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author></authors><title>Coupling of erbium dopants to yttrium orthosilicate photonic crystal
  cavities for on-chip optical quantum memories</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 108, 011111 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939651</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Erbium dopants in crystals exhibit highly coherent optical transitions well
suited for solid-state optical quantum memories operating in the telecom band.
Here we demonstrate coupling of erbium dopant ions in yttrium orthosilicate to
a photonic crystal cavity fabricated directly in the host crystal using focused
ion beam milling. The coupling leads to reduction of the photoluminescence
lifetime and enhancement of the optical depth in microns-long devices, which
will enable on-chip quantum memories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00324</id><created>2016-01-03</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fily</keyname><forenames>Yaouen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baskaran</keyname><forenames>Aparna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagan</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Active Particles on Curved Surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies have highlighted the sensitivity of active matter to
boundaries and their geometries. Here we develop a general theory for the
dynamics and statistics of active particles on curved surfaces and illustrate
it on two examples. We first show that active particles moving on a surface
with no ability to probe its curvature only exhibit steady-state
inhomogeneities in the presence of orientational order. We then consider a
strongly confined 3D ideal active gas and compute its steady-state density
distribution in a box of arbitrary convex shape.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01522</id><created>2016-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Meinert</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Exchange interactions and Curie temperatures of the tetrametal nitrides
  Cr4N, Mn4N, Fe4N, Co4N, and Ni4N</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 056006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/5/056006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exchange interactions of Cr4N, Mn4N, Fe4N, Co4N, and Ni4N compounds with
perovskite structure were calculated to obtain the Curie temperatures for these
compounds from Monte Carlo calculations. Contrary to naive expectation, the
exchange interactions vary markedly among these five compounds. In Fe4N, the
intra-sublattice interaction of the Fe 3c atoms is strongly negative, leading
to a significant reduction of the Curie temperature. The calculated Curie
temperatures are 291K (Cr4N), 710K (Mn4N), 668K (Fe4N), 827K (Co4N), and 121K
(Ni4N), in good agreement with experimental observations where available. The
much lower Curie temperature of Ni4N compared to fcc Ni is explained on the
basis of the exchange interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01668</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sola</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author></authors><title>Running Vacuum in the Universe: current phenomenological status</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 Figures, references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I review the excellent phenomenological status of a class of dynamical vacuum
models in which the vacuum energy density, $\rho_{\Lambda}=\rho_{\Lambda}(H)$,
as a function of the Hubble rate, evolves through its interaction with dark
matter and/or through the accompanying running of the gravitational coupling
$G$, including the possibility of being self-conserved with a nontrivial
effective equation of state. Some of these models have been used to incorporate
into a single vacuum structure the rapid stage of inflation, followed by the
standard radiation and cold dark matter epochs all the way down until the dark
energy era. Remarkably, the running vacuum models (RVM's) render an outstanding
phenomenological description of the main cosmological data at a level that is
currently challenging the concordance $\Lambda$CDM model, thereby implying that
present observations seem to point to a running vacuum rather than to a rigid
cosmological constant $\Lambda$ in our Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02585</id><created>2016-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kerner</keyname><forenames>Boris S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Failure of classical traffic flow theories: Stochastic highway capacity
  and automatic driving</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>109 pages, 27 figures, Physica A (in press)</comments><journal-ref>Physica A (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.01.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a mini-review [Physica A {\bf 392} (2013) 5261--5282] it has been shown
that classical traffic flow theories and models failed to explain empirical
traffic breakdown -- a phase transition from metastable free flow to
synchronized flow at highway bottlenecks. The main objective of this
mini-review is to study the consequence of this failure of classical
traffic-flow theories for an analysis of empirical stochastic highway capacity
as well as for the effect of automatic driving vehicles and cooperative driving
on traffic flow. To reach this goal, we show a deep connection between the
understanding of empirical stochastic highway capacity and a reliable analysis
of automatic driving vehicles in traffic flow. With the use of simulations in
the framework of three-phase traffic theory, a probabilistic analysis of the
effect of automatic driving vehicles on a mixture traffic flow consisting of a
random distribution of automatic driving and manual driving vehicles has been
made. We have found that the parameters of automatic driving vehicles can
either decrease or increase the probability of traffic breakdown. The increase
in the probability of traffic breakdown, i.e., the deterioration of the
performance of the traffic system can occur already at a small percentage
(about 5$\%$) of automatic driving vehicles. The increase in the probability of
traffic breakdown through automatic driving vehicles can be realized, even if
any platoon of automatic driving vehicles satisfies condition for string
stability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02809</id><created>2016-01-12</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sahin</keyname><forenames>Mehmet &#xd6;zg&#xfc;r</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kr&#xfc;cker</keyname><forenames>Dirk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melzer-Pellmann</keyname><forenames>Isabell-Alissandra</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance and optimization of support vector machines in high-energy
  physics classification problems</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>20 pages, 6 figures</comments><report-no>DESY 16-004</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we promote the use of Support Vector Machines (SVM) as a
machine learning tool for searches in high-energy physics. As an example for a
new- physics search we discuss the popular case of Supersymmetry at the Large
Hadron Collider. We demonstrate that the SVM is a valuable tool and show that
an automated discovery- significance based optimization of the SVM
hyper-parameters is a highly efficient way to prepare an SVM for such
applications. A new C++ LIBSVM interface called SVM-HINT is developed and
available on Github.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02827</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02827</id><created>2016-01-12</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wyrzykowski</keyname><forenames>&#x141;ukasz</forenames></author></authors><title>First year of the Gaia Science Alerts</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>to be published in the Proceedings of the XXXVII Meeting of the
  Polish Astronomical Society</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since mid 2014 Gaia mission delivers daily millions of observations of the
whole sky. Among them we search for transient events, e.g., supernovae,
microlensing events, cataclysmic variables, etc. In my talk I describe the
near-real-time Gaia data processing pipeline for anomaly detection, show first
scientific results from years 2014/2015 and describe the organization of the
ground-based network for the photometric and spectroscopic follow-up of Gaia
alerts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03416</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sussman</keyname><forenames>Daniel M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodrich</keyname><forenames>Carl P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Andrea J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spatial structure of states of self stress in jammed systems</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>21 pages (single column), 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  States of self stress, organizations of internal forces in many-body systems
that are in equilibrium with an absence of external forces, can be thought of
as the constitutive building blocks of the elastic response of a material. In
overconstrained disordered packings they have a natural mathematical
correspondence with the zero-energy vibrational modes in underconstrained
systems. While substantial attention in the literature has been paid to
diverging length scales associated with zero- and finite-energy vibrational
modes in jammed systems, less is known about the spatial structure of the
states of self stress. In this work we define a natural way in which a unique
state of self stress can be associated with each bond in a disordered spring
network derived from a jammed packing, and then investigate the spatial
structure of these bond-localized states of self stress. This allows for an
understanding of how the elastic properties of a system would change upon
changing the strength or even existence of any bond in the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03429</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xing</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin Chern Pumping from the Bulk of Two-Dimensional Topological
  Insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 125117 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.125117</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological insulators (TIs) are a new quantum state of matter discovered
recently, which are characterized by unconventional bulk topological
invariants. Proposals for practical applications of the TIs are mostly based
upon their metallic surface or edge states. Here, we report the theoretical
discovery of a bulk quantum pumping effect in a two-dimensional TI electrically
modulated in adiabatic cycles. In each cycle, an amount of spin proportional to
the sample width can be pumped into a nonmagnetic electrode, which is
attributed to nonzero spin Chern numbers $C_{\pm}$. Moreover, by using a
half-metallic electrode, universal quantized charge pumping conductivities
$-C_{\pm}e^2/h$ can be measured. This discovery paves the way for direct
investigation of the robust topological properties of the TIs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03452</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbiellini</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orikasa</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaprzyk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itou</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yung Jui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafiz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchimoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bansil</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakurai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-destructive measurement of in-operando lithium concentration in
  batteries via x-ray Compton scattering</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 119, 025103 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-destructive determination of lithium distribution in a working battery is
key for addressing both efficiency and safety issues. Although various
techniques have been developed to map the lithium distribution in electrodes,
these methods are mostly applicable to test cells. Here we propose the use of
high-energy x-ray Compton scattering spectroscopy to measure the local lithium
concentration in closed electrochemical cells. A combination of experimental
measurements and parallel first-principles computations is used to show that
the shape parameter S of the Compton profile is linearly proportional to
lithium concentration and thus provides a viable descriptor for this important
quantity. The merits and applicability of our method are demonstrated with
illustrative examples of LixMn2O4 cathodes and a working commercial lithium
coin battery CR2032.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03454</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Imai</keyname><forenames>Yoshiki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wakabayashi</keyname><forenames>Katsunori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigrist</keyname><forenames>Manfred</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal Hall conductivity and topological transition in a chiral p-wave
  superconductor for Sr2RuO4</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 024510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.024510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The interplay between the thermal transport property and the topological
aspect is investigated in a spin-triplet chiral p-wave superconductor Sr2RuO4
with the strong two-dimensionality. We show the thermal Hall conductivity is
well described by the temperature linear term and the exponential term in the
low temperature region. While the former term is proportional to the so-called
Chern number directly, the latter is associated with the superconducting gap
amplitude of the gamma band. We also demonstrate that the coefficient of the
exponential term changes the sign around Lifshitz transition. Our obtained
result may enable us access easily the physical quantities and the topological
property of Sr2RuO4 in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03457</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerrieri</keyname><forenames>Andrea L.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the soft limit of tree-level string amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, to appear in Fourteenth Marcel Grossmann Meeting - MG 14
  proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the soft behavior of string scattering amplitudes at three level
with massless and massive external insertions, relying on different techniques
to compute 4-points amplitudes respectively with open or closed strings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03459</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Fluke</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Ultimate Display</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, to appear in Proceedings of ADASS XXV (Sydney,
  Australia; 2015), edited by N. P. F. Lorente &amp; K. Shortridge (San Francisco:
  ASP), ASP Conf. Series</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Astronomical images and datasets are increasingly high-resolution and
multi-dimensional. The vast majority of astronomers perform all of their
visualisation and analysis tasks on low-resolution, two-dimensional desktop
monitors. If there were no technological barriers to designing the ultimate
stereoscopic display for astronomy, what would it look like? What capabilities
would we require of our compute hardware to drive it? And are existing
technologies even close to providing a true 3D experience that is compatible
with the depth resolution of human stereoscopic vision? We consider the CAVE2
(an 80 Megapixel, hybrid 2D and 3D virtual reality environment directly
integrated with a 100 Tflop/s GPU-powered supercomputer) and the Oculus Rift (a
low- cost, head-mounted display) as examples at opposite financial ends of the
immersive display spectrum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03460</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaneko</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murai</keyname><forenames>Daigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marqu&#xe9;s-Gonz&#xe1;lez</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>Hisao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komoto</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishino</keyname><forenames>Tomoaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Katsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsukagoshi</keyname><forenames>Kazuhito</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiguchi</keyname><forenames>Manabu</forenames></author></authors><title>Site selection in single-molecule junction for highly reproducible
  molecular electronics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 figures, J. Am. Chem. Soc., in press</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Adsorption sites of molecules critically determine the electric/photonic
properties and its stability of heterogeneous molecule-metal interfaces. Then,
selectivity of adsorption site is essential for development of the fields
including organic electronics, catalysis, and biology. However, due to current
technical limitations, site-selectivity remains a major challenge because of
difficulty in precise selection of meaningful one among the sites. Here, we
report the single site-selection at a single-molecule junction by performing
newly developed hybrid technique: simultaneous characterization of surface
enhanced Raman scattering (SERS) and current-voltage (I-V) measurements. The
I-V response of 1,4-benzenedithiol junctions, reveals the existence of three
meta-stable states arising from different adsorption sites. Notably, correlated
SERS measurements show selectivity towards one of the adsorption sites, bridge
sites. This site-selectivity represents an essential step towards the reliable
integration of individual molecules on metallic surfaces. Furthermore, the
hybrid spectro-electric technique reveals the dependence of the SERS intensity
on the strength of the molecule-metal interaction, showing the interdependence
between the optical and electronic properties in single-molecule junctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03462</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03462</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Melendez</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Placco</keyname><forenames>Vinicius M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucci-Maia</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramirez</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ting S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perez</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author></authors><title>2MASS J18082002-5104378: The brightest (V=11.9) ultra metal-poor star</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>A&amp;A Letters</comments><journal-ref>2016 A&amp;A 585, L5</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201527456</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Context. The most primitive metal-poor stars are important for studying the
conditions of the early galaxy and are also relevant to big bang
nucleosynthesis. Aims. Our objective is to find the brightest (V&lt;14) most
metal-poor stars. Methods. Candidates were selected using a new method, which
is based on the mismatch between spectral types derived from colors and
observed spectral types. They were observed first at low resolution with EFOSC2
at the NTT/ESO to obtain an initial set of stellar parameters. The most
promising candidate, 2MASS J18082002-5104378 (V=11.9), was observed at high
resolution (R=50 000) with UVES at the VLT/ESO, and a standard abundance
analysis was performed. Results. We found that 2MASS J18082002-5104378 is an
ultra metal-poor star with stellar parameters Teff = 5440 K, log g = 3.0 dex,
vt = 1.5 km/s, [Fe/H] = -4.1 dex. The star has [C/Fe]&lt;+0.9 in a 1D analysis, or
[C/Fe]&lt;=+0.5 if 3D effects are considered; its abundance pattern is typical of
normal (non-CEMP) ultra metal-poor stars. Interestingly, the star has a binary
companion. Conclusions. 2MASS J1808-5104 is the brightest (V=11.9) metal-poor
star of its category, and it could be studied further with even higher S/N
spectroscopy to determine additional chemical abundances, thus providing
important constraints to the early chemical evolution of our Galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03486</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Takada</keyname><forenames>Yasutami</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory for Reliable First-Principles Prediction of the Superconducting
  Transition Temperature</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures, published in &quot;Carbon-based superconductors:
  Toward high-Tc superconductivity&quot;, edited by J. Haruyama (Pan Stanford,
  Singapore,2015), pp. 193-230; ISBN: 978-981-4303-30-9 (Hardcover),
  978-981-4303-31-6 (eBook). arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1601.02753</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A review is given for the theoretical framework to give a reliable prediction
of the superconducting transition temperature Tc from first principles,
together with a practical strategy for its application to actual materials with
illustrations of the results of Tc calculated for superconductors in the
weak-coupling region like the alkali and alkaline-earth intercalated graphites
as well as those in the strong-coupling region like the alkali-doped
fullerides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03500</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lueng</keyname><forenames>Chris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metaxas</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostylev</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensitivity Enhancement of Pd/Co Bi-layer Film for Hydrogen Gas Sensing
  using Perpendicular-to-Plane Ferromagnetic Resonance Configuration</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures, 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previously, it has been shown that the strength of the perpendicular magnetic
anisotropy (PMA) of thin Palladium-Cobalt bi-layer films can be modified when
hydrogen gas is absorbed by the Palladium (Pd) layer. In our recent work we
showed that the ferromagnetic resonance (FMR) response of this material is
sensitive to changes in PMA upon exposure of Pd to hydrogen gas. As such, a
simple, compact and contactless hydrogen gas sensor could exploit FMR-based
detection, of the reversible hydrogen-gas-induced changes in PMA. The magnitude
of the FMR peak shift is critical in determining the sensor's sensitivity: the
higher the FMR peak shift at a given hydrogen gas concentration, the higher the
sensitivity. In the present work we demonstrate that the detection sensitivity
is enhanced when the static magnetic field is applied perpendicular to the film
plane. A factor of eight times improvement is observed with respect to the
in-plane FMR configuration studied previously. An analysis based on the Kittel
equation for FMR frequencies of a ferromagnetic film is carried out in order to
understand the mechanism of sensitivity enhancement. The result is important
for optimizing Pd/Co bi-layered thin films for use in novel platforms for
hydrogen gas sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03504</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Liyanage</keyname><forenames>D D</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thamali</keyname><forenames>Rajika J K A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumbalatara</keyname><forenames>A A K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weliwita</keyname><forenames>J A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witharana</keyname><forenames>S</forenames></author></authors><title>An Analysis of Nanoparticle Settling Times in Liquids</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Journal of Nanomaterials 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aggregation and settling are crucial phenomena that involve particulate
systems. For particle sizes of millimetre and above, there are reasonable
accurate predicting tools. However for smaller particle sizes, there appears to
be a void in knowledge. This paper presents an analytical model to predict the
settling rates of nano-to-micro size particulate systems. The model was
developed as a combination of modified classical equations and graphical
methods. A calculation sequence also is presented. By validation with available
experimental data for settling nano-to-micro systems, it was found that the two
schemes show order of magnitude agreement. A significant feature of this model
is its ability to accommodate non-spherical particles and different fractal
dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03545</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03545</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Champneys</keyname><forenames>Alan R</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varkonyi</keyname><forenames>Peter L</forenames></author></authors><title>The Painleve paradox in contact mechanics</title><categories>physics.class-ph cs.RO math.DS</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The 120-year old so-called Painleve paradox involves the loss of determinism
in models of planar rigid bodies in point contact with a rigid surface, subject
to Coulomb-like dry friction. The phenomenon occurs due to coupling between
normal and rotational degrees-of-freedom such that the effective normal force
becomes attractive rather than repulsive. Despite a rich literature, the
forward evolution problem remains unsolved other than in certain restricted
cases in 2D with single contact points. Various practical consequences of the
theory are revisited, including models for robotic manipulators, and the
strange behaviour of chalk when pushed rather than dragged across a blackboard.
  Reviewing recent theory, a general formulation is proposed, including a
Poisson or energetic impact law. The general problem in 2D with a single point
of contact is discussed and cases or inconsistency or indeterminacy enumerated.
Strategies to resolve the paradox via contact regularisation are discussed from
a dynamical systems point of view. By passing to the infinite stiffness limit
and allowing impact without collision, inconsistent and indeterminate cases are
shown to be resolvable for all open sets of conditions. However, two
unavoidable ambiguities that can be reached in finite time are discussed in
detail, so called dynamic jam and reverse chatter. A partial review is given of
2D cases with two points of contact showing how a greater complexity of
inconsistency and indeterminacy can arise. Extension to fully three-dimensional
analysis is briefly considered and shown to lead to further possible
singularities. In conclusion, the ubiquity of the \pain paradox is highlighted
and open problems are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03557</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03557</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuraptsev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous decay of an atom excited in a dense and disordered atomic
  ensemble: quantum microscopic approach</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 90, 012511 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.90.012511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the basis of general theoretical results developed previously in [I. M.
Sokolov et al., J. Exp. Theor. Phys. 112, 246 (2011)], we analyze spontaneous
decay of a single atom inside cold atomic clouds under conditions when the
averaged interatomic separation is less or comparable with the wavelength of
quasi resonant radiation. Beyond the decay dynamics we analyze shifts of
resonance as well as distortion of the spectral shape of the atomic transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03563</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robens</keyname><forenames>Tania</forenames></author></authors><title>W+W- + jet: compact analytic results</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures; contribution to Proceedings of Radcor-Loopfest
  2015</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-CONF-16-006-T</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the second run of the LHC, which started in April 2015, an accurate
understanding of Standard Model processes is more crucial than ever. Processes
including electroweak gauge bosons serve as standard candles for SM
measurements, and equally constitute important background for BSM searches. We
here present the NLO QCD virtual contributions to W+W- + jet in an analytic
format obtained through unitarity methods and show results for the full process
using an implementation into the Monte Carlo event generator MCFM.
Phenomenologically, we investigate total as well as differential cross sections
for the LHC with 14 TeV center-of-mass energy, as well as a future 100 TeV
proton-proton machine. In the format presented here, the one-loop virtual
contributions also serve as important ingredients in the calculation of W+W-
pair production at NNLO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03565</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>O'Naraigh</keyname><forenames>Lennon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barros</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle-laden viscous channel flows - model regularization and
  parameter study</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize the flow of a viscous suspension in an inclined channel where
the flow is maintained in a steady state under the competing influences of
gravity and an applied pressure drop. The basic model relies on a
diffusive-flux formalism. Such models are common in the literature, yet many of
them possess an unphysical singularity at the channel centreline where the
shear rate vanishes. We therefore present a regularization of the basic
diffusive-flux model that removes this singularity. This introduces an explicit
(physical) dependence on the particle size into the model equations. This
approach enables us to carry out a detailed parameter study showing in
particular the opposing effects of the pressure drop and gravity. Conditions
for counter-current flow and complete flow reversal are obtained from numerical
solutions of the model equations. These are supplemented by an analytic lower
bound on the ratio of the gravitational force to the applied pressure drop
necessary to bring about complete flow reversal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03568</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bolmatov</keyname><forenames>Dima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhernenkov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zav'yalov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoupin</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunsolo</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yong Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermally triggered phononic gaps in liquids at THz scale</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1512.07202</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 19469 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep19469</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present inelastic X-ray scattering experiments in a diamond
anvil cell and molecular dynamic simulations to investigate the behavior of
phononic excitations in liquid Ar. The spectra calculated using molecular
dynamics were found to be in a good agreement with the experimental data.
Furthermore, we observe that, upon temperature increases, a low-frequency
transverse phononic gap emerges while high-frequency propagating modes become
evanescent at the THz scale. The effect of strong localization of a
longitudinal phononic mode in the supercritical phase is observed for the first
time. The evidence for the high-frequency transverse phononic gap due to the
transition from an oscillatory to a ballistic dynamic regimes of motion is
presented and supported by molecular dynamics simulations. This transition
takes place across the Frenkel line thermodynamic limit which demarcates
compressed liquid and non-compressed fluid domains on the phase diagram and is
supported by calculations within the Green-Kubo phenomenological formalism.
These results are crucial to advance the development of novel terahertz thermal
devices, phononic lenses, mirrors, and other THz metamaterials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03573</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuraptsev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>I. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reflection of resonant light from a plane surface of an ensemble of
  motionless point scatters: Quantum microscopic approach</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 91, 053822 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.91.053822</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  On the basis of general theoretical results developed previously in [JETP
112, 246 (2011)], we analyze the reflection of quasiresonant light from a plane
surface of dense and disordered ensemble of motionless point scatters. Angle
distribution of the scattered light is calculated both for s and p
polarizations of the probe radiation. The ratio between coherent and incoherent
(diffuse) components of scattered light is calculated. We analyze the
contributions of scatters located at different distances from the surface and
determine on this background the thickness of surface layer responsible for
reflected beam generation. The inhomogeneity of dipole-dipole interaction near
the surface is discussed.We study also dependence of total reflected light
power on the incidence angle and compare the results of the microscopic
approach with predictions of the Fresnel reflection theory. The calculations
are performed for different densities of scatters and different frequencies of
a probe radiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03587</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Song-Ju</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naruse</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aono</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hori</keyname><forenames>Hirokazu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akimoto</keyname><forenames>Takuma</forenames></author></authors><title>Accelerated diffusion by chaotic fluctuation in probability in
  photoexcitation transfer system</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>17 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a new accelerated diffusion phenomenon that is produced by a
one-dimensional ran- dom walk in which the flight probability to one of the two
directions (i.e., bias) oscillates dynam- ically in periodic, quasiperiodic,
and chaotic manners. The probability oscillation dynamics can be physically
observed in nanoscale photoexcitation transfer in a quantum-dot network, where
the existence probability of an exciton at the bottom energy level of a quantum
dot fluctuates dif- ferently with a parameter setting. We evaluate the ensemble
average of the time-averaged mean square displacement (ETMSD) of the time
series obtained from the quantum-dot network model that generates various
oscillatory behaviors because the ETMSD exhibits characteristic changes
depending on the fluctuating bias; in the case of normal diffusion, the
asymptotic behavior of the ETMSD is proportional to the time (i.e., a linear
growth function), whereas it grows nonlinearly with an exponent greater than 1
in the case of superdiffusion. We find that the diffusion can be accelerated
significantly when the fluctuating bias is characterized as weak chaos owing to
the transient nonstationarity of its biases, in which the spectrum contains
high power at low frequen- cies. By introducing a simplified model of our
random walk, which exhibits superdiffusion as well as normal diffusion, we
explain the mechanism of the accelerated diffusion by analyzing the mean square
displacement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03588</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lustikova</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiomi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saitoh</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Vector spectroscopy for spin pumping</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 224436 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.224436</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to separate the inverse spin Hall effect (ISHE) from
galvanomagnetic effects in spin pumping experiments on metallic bilayer systems
by measuring the dc electromotive force in two orthogonal directions.
Calculations of dc voltages in longitudinal and Hall directions induced in
Ni81Fe19 and Ni81Fe19/Pt films at ferromagnetic resonance in a microwave cavity
predict that contributions from ISHE and from the galvanomagnetic effects, i.e.
the anisotropic magnetoresistance and the anomalous Hall effect, exhibit
distinct signal symmetry as well as angular dependence when changing the
direction of the external field with respect to the film plane. According to
measurements on Ni81Fe19/Pt, only that dc voltage component which includes ISHE
is more than five times larger than purely galvanomagnetic components. This is
corroborated by results on La0.67Sr0.33MnO3/Pt samples, demonstrating
universality of this method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03589</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Pavlyuk</keyname><forenames>Anatoliy M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polynomial Invariants of Torus Knots and (p,q)-Calculus</title><categories>math.GT hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages; based on invited talks given at the 6th Petrov International
  Symposium on High Energy Physics, Cosmology and Gravity, Kyiv (Ukraine),
  September 5-8, 2013</comments><msc-class>57M27, 17B37, 81R50</msc-class><journal-ref>Algebras, Groups and Geometries Vol.31, No.2 (2014) 175-182</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce the deformed fermionic numbers, corresponding to the skein
relations, the main characteristics of knots and links. These fermionic numbers
allow one to restore the skein relations. For the Alexander (Jones) skein
relation we introduce corresponding Alexander (Jones) fermionic q-numbers, and
for the HOMFLY skein relation - the HOMFLY deformed (p,q)-numbers with one
fermionic parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03590</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03590</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Schranz</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabelka</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarras</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burock</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Giant domain wall response of highly twinned ferroelastic materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 101, 141913 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4757992</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many ferroelastic crystals display at sufficiently low measurement
frequencies a huge elastic softening below Tc which is caused by domain wall
motion. Materials range from perovskites to iron based superconductors and
shape memory materials. We present a model - based on Landau-Ginzburg theory
including long range elastic interaction between needle shaped ferroelastic
domains - to describe the observed superelastic softening. The theory predicts
that the domain wall contribution to the elastic susceptibility is different
for improper and proper ferroelastic materials. A test of the theory against
experimental data on SrTiO3, KMnF3, LaAlO3, La1-xNdxP5O14 and NH4HC2O4.1/2H2O
yields excellent agreement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03592</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fen</keyname><forenames>Mehmet Onur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fen</keyname><forenames>Fatma Tokmak</forenames></author></authors><title>Homoclinic and Heteroclinic Motions in Hybrid Systems with Impacts</title><categories>nlin.CD math.DS</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present a method to generate homoclinic and heteroclinic
motions in impulsive systems. We rigorously prove the presence of such motions
in the case that the systems are under the influence of a discrete map that
possesses homoclinic and heteroclinic orbits. Simulations that support the
theoretical results are represented by means of a Duffing equation with
impacts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03612</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Henrichs</keyname><forenames>L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Choice of tip, signal stability and practical aspects of
  Piezoresponse-Force-Microscopy</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Review of Scientific Instruments 86, 083707 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4929572</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Piezoresponse force-microscopy (PFM) has become the standard tool to
investigate ferroelectrics on the micro- and nanoscale. However, reliability of
PFM signals is often problematic and their quantification is challenging and
thus not widely applied. Here, we present a study of the reproducibility of PFM
signals and of the so-called PFM background signal which has been reported in
literature. We find that PFM signals are generally reproducible to certain
extents. The PFM signal difference between 180{\deg} domains on
periodically-poled lithium niobate (PPLN) is taken as the reference signal in a
large number of measurements, carried out in a low frequency regime (30-70
kHz). We show that in comparison to Pt coated tips, diamond coated tips exhibit
improved signal stability, lower background signal and less imaging artifacts
related to PFM which is reflected in the spread of measurements. This is
attributed to the improved mechanical stability of the conductive layer. The
average deviation of the mean PFM signal is 38.3%, for a diamond coated tip.
Although this deviation is relatively high, it is far better than values from
literature which showed a deviation of approx. 73.1%. Additionally, we find
that the average deviation of the background signal from 0 is 11.6% of the PPLN
domain contrast. Thus, the background signal needs to be taken into account
when quantifying PFM signals and should be subtracted from PFM signals. Those
results are important for quantification of PFM signals, since PPLN might be
used for this purpose when PFM signals measured on PPLN are related to its
macroscopic d33 coefficient. Finally, the crucial influence of sample polishing
on PFM signals is shown and we recommend to use a multistep polishing route
with a final step involving 200 nm sized colloidal silica particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03626</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gori</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donato</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Floriani</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nardecchia</keyname><forenames>Ilaria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Random walk of passive tracers among randomly moving obstacles</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>29 pages; 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: This study is mainly motivated by the need of understanding how
the diffusion behaviour of a biomolecule (or even of a larger object) is
affected by other moving macromolecules, organelles, and so on, inside a living
cell, whence the possibility of understanding whether or not a randomly walking
biomolecule is also subject to a long-range force field driving it to its
target. Method: By means of the Continuous Time Random Walk (CTRW) technique
the topic of random walk in random environment is here considered in the case
of a passively diffusing particle in a crowded environment made of randomly
moving and interacting obstacles. Results: The relevant physical quantity which
is worked out is the diffusion cofficient of the passive tracer which is
computed as a function of the average inter-obstacles distance. Coclusions: The
results reported here suggest that if a biomolecule, let us call it a test
molecule, moves towards its target in the presence of other independently
interacting molecules, its motion can be considerably slowed down. Hence, if
such a slowing down could compromise the efficiency of the task to be performed
by the test molecule, some accelerating factor would be required.
Intermolecular electrodynamic forces are good candidates as accelerating
factors because they can act at a long distance in a medium like the cytosol
despite its ionic strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03627</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Manzoni</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sterzi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crepaldi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diego</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cilento</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zacchigna</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bugnon</keyname><forenames>Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magrez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grioni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parmigiani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast Optical Control of the Electronic Properties of $ZrTe_5$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review Letters 115, 207402 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.207402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the temperature dependence of the $ZrTe_5$ electronic
properties, studied at equilibrium and out of equilibrium, by means of time and
angle resolved photoelectron spectroscopy. Our results unveil the dependence of
the electronic band structure across the Fermi energy on the sample
temperature. This finding is regarded as the dominant mechanism responsible for
the anomalous resistivity observed at T* $\sim$ 160 K along with the change of
the charge carrier character from holelike to electronlike. Having addressed
these long-lasting questions, we prove the possibility to control, at the
ultrashort time scale, both the binding energy and the quasiparticle lifetime
of the valence band. These experimental evidences pave the way for optically
controlling the thermoelectric and magnetoelectric transport properties of
$ZrTe_5$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03646</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Adams</keyname><forenames>Luise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogner</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weinzierl</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>A walk on sunset boulevard</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>10 pages, talk given at Radcor 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A walk on sunset boulevard can teach us about transcendental functions
associated to Feynman diagrams. On this guided tour we will see multiple
polylogarithms, differential equations and elliptic curves. A highlight of the
tour will be the generalisation of the polylogarithms to the elliptic setting
and the all-order solution for the sunset integral in the equal mass case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03657</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gituliar</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-order corrections to the splitting functions from differential
  equations in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings of The 12th International Symposium on Radiative
  Corrections (Radcor 2015) and LoopFest XIV (Radiative Corrections for the LHC
  and Future Colliders), Los Angeles, CA, USA. Based on arXiv:1512.02045. 9
  pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>IFJPAN-IV-2016-1</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the status an ab initio computation of the time-like splitting
functions at next-to-next-to-leading order in QCD. Time-like splitting
functions govern the collinear kinematics of inclusive hadron production in
$e^+e^-$ annihilation and the evolution of the parton fragmentation
distributions. Current knowledge about them at three loops has been inferred by
means of crossing symmetry from their related space-like counterparts, the
deep-inelastic structure functions and parton densities. In this approach
certain parts of the off-diagonal quark-gluon splitting function are left
undetermined, which calls for an independent calculation from first principles.
We outline the method for calculating master integrals from differential
equations which are required to attack the problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03686</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03686</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Tianqi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Novel Method to Obtain Wires Distribution Considering the Shape of
  Generated Electromagnetic Field</title><categories>physics.comp-ph math.OC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proposes a method to calculate the wires distribution for
generating required electromagnetic field. Instead of solving the distribution
of wires directly, we formulate the problem into zero-one programming form. By
applying the proposed algorithm to solve the zero-one programming problem, a
practical solution can be obtained. Two practical examples are proposed to
illustrate detailed calculation steps of the novel method. The comparison
between binary particle swarm optimization searching algorithm and the
pro-posed algorithm is provided and discussed. All the design results are
validated with FEM calculation results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03701</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sz&#xe9;kely</keyname><forenames>Gergely</forenames></author></authors><title>On some Symmetry Axioms in Relativity Theories</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.LO math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>03B30, 83A02, 83C02</msc-class><journal-ref>Symmetry: Cutlure and Science, Vol. 26. No. 4, 405-420, 2015</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we review two symmetry axioms of special relativity and their
connections to each other together with their role in some famous predictions
of relativity theory, such as time dilation, length contraction, and the twin
paradox. We also discuss briefly counterparts of these symmetry axioms in
general relativity and formulate a conjecture, namely that without them the
axioms of general relativity would capture general relativistic spacetimes only
up to conformal equivalence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03715</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Tumulka</keyname><forenames>Roderich</forenames></author></authors><title>Distribution of the Time at Which an Ideal Detector Clicks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages LaTeX, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the problem of computing, for a detector waiting for a quantum
particle to arrive, the probability distribution of the time at which the
detector clicks, from the initial wave function of the particle in the
non-relativistic regime. Although the standard rules of quantum mechanics offer
no operator for the time of arrival, quantum mechanics makes an unambiguous
prediction for this distribution, defined by first solving the Schrodinger
equation for the big quantum system formed by the particle of interest, the
detector, a clock, and a device that records the time when the detector clicks,
then making a quantum measurement of the record at a very late time, and
finally using the distribution of the recorded time. This leads to question
whether there is also a practical, simple rule for computing this distribution,
at least approximately (i.e., for an idealized detector). We argue here in
favor of a rule based on a 1-particle Schrodinger equation with a certain
(absorbing) boundary condition at the ideal detecting surface, first considered
by Werner in 1987. We present a novel derivation of this rule and describe how
it arises as a limit of a &quot;soft&quot; detector represented by an imaginary
potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03722</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoeche</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luisoni</keyname><forenames>Gionata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schonherr</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Jan-Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yundin</keyname><forenames>Valery</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs + Multi-jets in Gluon Fusion</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures, Contribution to appear in the proceedings of
  {12th International Symposium on Radiative Corrections (Radcor 2015) and
  LoopFest XIV</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed phenomenological analysis of the production of a
Standard Model Higgs boson in association with up to three jets. The Higgs is
produced via gluon fusion, which is an irreducible background to the vector
boson fusion mechanism. We calculate the next-to-leading order corrections in
QCD in the limit of an infinitely heavy top quark. Numerical results are
presented for a large variety of observables, for different selection cuts, and
for different choices of the jet tagging scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
