<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:27:49Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-01-18" from="2016-01-17" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.3128</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.3128</id><created>2012-05-14</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Foschini</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author></authors><title>The Blandford-Znajek theory revisited</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure. Poster presented at the 28th Texas Symposium
  (Geneva, Switzerland, Dec 13-18, 2015). Revised according to the LaTeX
  template for the proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Blandford-Znajek theory (1977) is generally studied to understand the
generation of powerful relativistic jets. However, it could also give important
insights about the feedback between a rotating black hole, its ergosphere, and
a surrounding accretion disk. The energy flow between these systems could be
understood by studying the BZ power as a function of a slip factor, which in
turn is defined as a function of the angular velocity of the black hole and the
angular velocity of the magnetic field lines (generally anchored to the disk).
The distinct stages could explain the different types of observed AGN
(with/without jets), but could also help understanding the evolution of the
merging of binary AGN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.7259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.7259</id><created>2013-03-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medhekar</keyname><forenames>Nikhil V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shenoy</keyname><forenames>Vivek B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bonding Charge Density and Ultimate Strength of Monolayer Transition
  Metal Dichalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1021/jp403986v</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional (2D) semiconducting transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDs)
can withstand a large deformation without fracture or inelastic relaxation,
making them attractive for application in novel strain-engineered and flexible
electronic and optoelectronic devices. In this study, we characterize the
mechanical response of monolayer group VI TMDs to large elastic deformation
using first-principles density functional theory calculations. We find that the
ultimate strength and the overall stress response of these 2D materials is
strongly influenced by their chemical composition and loading direction. We
demonstrate that differences in the observed mechanical behavior can be
attributed to the spatial redistribution of the occupied hybridized electronic
states in the region between the transition metal atom and the chalcogens. In
spite of the strong covalent bonding between the transition metal and the
chalcogens, we find that a simple linear relationship can be established to
describe the dependence of the mechanical strength on the charge transfer from
the transition metal atom to the chalcogens.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.7089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.7089</id><created>2013-04-26</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Chuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komatsu</keyname><forenames>Katsuyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clave</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campidelli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filoramo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gueron</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouchiat</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Signature of gate-tunable magnetism in graphene grafted with
  Pt-porphyrins</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 045403 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.045403</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inducing magnetism in graphene holds great promises, such as controlling the
exchange interaction with a gate electrode and generating exotic magnetic
phases. Coating graphene with magnetic molecules or atoms has so far mostly
lead to decreased graphene mobility. In the present work, we show that
Pt-porphyrins adsorbed on graphene lead to an enhanced mobility and to
gate-dependent magnetism. We report that porphyrins can be donor or acceptor,
depending on graphene s initial doping. The porphyrins transfer charge and
ionize around the charged impurities on graphene, decreasing the graphene
doping and increasing its mobility. In addition, ionized porphyrins carry a
magnetic moment. Using the sensitivity of mesoscopic transport to magnetism, in
particular the superconducting proximity effect and conductance fluctuations,
we explore the magnetic order induced in graphene by the interacting magnetic
moments of the ionized porphyrins. Among the signatures of magnetism, we find
two-terminal-magnetoresistance fluctuations with an odd component, a tell-tale
sign of time reversal symmetry breaking at zero field, that does not exist in
uncoated graphene sample. When graphene is connected to superconducting
electrodes, the induced magnetism leads to a gate-voltage-dependent suppression
of the supercurrent, modified magnetic interference patterns, and
gate-voltage-dependent magnetic hysteresis. The magnetic signatures are
greatest for long superconductor graphene superconductor junctions and for
samples with the highest initial doping, compatible with a greater number of
ionized and thus magnetic porphyrins. Our findings suggest that long-range
magnetism is induced through graphene by the ionized porphyrins magnetic
moment. This magnetic interaction is controlled by the density of carriers in
graphene, a tunability that could be exploited in spintronic applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1305.6261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1305.6261</id><created>2013-05-27</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Shigeji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Akira</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of the Room-Temperature QHE in Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1304.7631</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The unusual quantum Hall effect (QHE) in graphene is often discussed in terms
of Dirac fermions moving with a linear dispersion relation. The same phenomenon
will be explained in terms of the more traditional composite bosons, which move
with a linear dispersion relation. The &quot;electron&quot; (wave packet) moves easier in
the direction [1,1,0,c-axis] = [1,1,0] of the honeycomb lattice than
perpendicular to it, while the &quot;hole&quot; moves easier in [0,0,1]. Since
&quot;electrons&quot; and &quot;holes&quot; move in different channels, the number densities can be
high especially when the Fermi surface has &quot;necks&quot;. The strong QHE arises from
the phonon exchange attraction in the neighborhood of the &quot;neck&quot; Fermi
surfaces. The plateau observed for the Hall conductivity and the accompanied
resistivity drop is due to the Bose-Einstein condensation of the c-bosons, each
forming from a pair of one-electron--two-fluxons c-fermions by phonon-exchange
attraction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.6610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.6610</id><created>2014-01-26</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Peizhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheung</keyname><forenames>Yeuk-Kwan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Permutation Relations of Yangian Invariants, Unitarity Cuts, and
  Scattering Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>references added; 61 pages &amp; 26 figures; final version on JHEP</comments><report-no>NITS-PHY-2014003</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1409 (2014) 115</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2014)115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find a permutation relation among Yangian Invariants -- two Yangian
Invariants with adjacent external lines exchanged are related by a simple
kinematic factor. This relation is shown to be equivalent to U(1) decoupling
and Bern-Carrasco-Johansson (BCJ) relation at the level of maximal helicity
violating (MHV) amplitudes. Together with the newly found permutation relation
and using unitarity cuts to remove ambiguity in the definition of loop momenta
of cut amplitudes due to the nonplanar legs, we propose a systematic way of
reconstructing the the integrands of nonplanar MHV amplitudes up to a rational
function which vanishes under all possible unitarity cuts. This method when
applied to planar diagrams reproduces results from the single cut method. As
explicit examples the construction of one-loop double-trace MHV amplitudes of
4- and 5-point interactions are presented using on-shell diagrams. The
kinematic factors and the resultant planar diagrams are carefully dealt with
using the unitarity cut condition. The first next-to-MHV amplitudes are
addressed using generalized unitarity cuts. Their leading singularities can be
identified as residues of the Grassmanian integral. This example also serve to
demonstrate the power of the newly found relation of Yangian Invariants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.5625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.5625</id><created>2014-03-22</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Changhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandenberger</keyname><forenames>Robert H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheung</keyname><forenames>Yeuk-Kwan E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Big Bounce Genesis</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages; 2 figures; published version</comments><report-no>NITS-PHY-2014004</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 90, 123535 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.90.123535</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the possibility to use dark matter particle's mass and its cross
section as a smoking gun signal of the existence of a Big Bounce at the early
stage in the evolution of our currently observed universe. A model independent
study of dark matter production in the pre-bounce contraction and the
post-bounce expansion epochs of the bounce universe reveals a new venue for
achieving the observed relic abundance of our present universe, in which a
significantly smaller amount of dark matter with a smaller cross section -- as
compared to the prediction of Standard Cosmology -- is produced and carries the
information about the bounce universe evolution. Once the values of dark matter
mass and cross section are obtained by direct detection in laboratories, this
alternative route becomes a signature of the bounce universe scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.6450</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.6450</id><created>2014-03-25</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Keelan</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Emma M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hague</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulated annealing approach to vascular structure with application to
  the coronary arteries</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.TO</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Does the complex processes of angiogenesis during organism development
ultimately lead to a near optimal coronary vasculature in the organs of adult
mammals? We examine this hypothesis using a powerful and universal method,
built on physical and physiological principles, for the determination of
globally energetically optimal arterial trees. The method is based on simulated
annealing, and can be used to examine arteries in hollow organs with arbitrary
tissue geometries. We demonstrate that the approach can generate in-silico
vasculatures which closely match porcine anatomical data for the coronary
arteries on all length scales, and that the optimised arterial trees improve
systematically as computational time increases. The method presented here is
general, and could in principle be used to examine the arteries of other
organs. Potential applications include improvement of medical imaging analysis
and the design of vascular trees for artificial organs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.7188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.7188</id><created>2014-06-27</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kondo</keyname><forenames>Yasushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuzaki</keyname><forenames>Yuichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsushima</keyname><forenames>Kei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filgueiras</keyname><forenames>Jefferson G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using the Quantum Zeno Effect for Suppression of Decoherence</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures, largely rewritten</comments><journal-ref>Yasushi Kondo et al 2016 New J. Phys. 18 013033</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/1/013033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Projective measurements are an essential element of quantum mechanics. In
most cases, they cause an irreversible change of the quantum system on which
they act. However, measurements can also be used to stabilize quantum states
from decay processes, which is known as the quantum Zeno effect (QZE). Here, we
demonstrate this effect for the case of a superposition state of a nuclear spin
qubit, using an ancilla to perform the measurement. As a result, the quantum
state of the qubit is protected against dephasing without relying on an
ensemble nature of NMR experiments. We also propose a scheme to protect an
arbitrary state by using QZE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2656</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2656</id><created>2014-09-09</created><updated>2015-03-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Shu-Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Wolung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>Kin-Wang</forenames></author></authors><title>Inflationary dilaton-axion magnetogenesis</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages with 6 figures using revtex4</comments><journal-ref>Chin.J.Phys. 53 (2015) 110105</journal-ref><doi>10.6122/CJP.20150909</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the generation of primordial magnetic fields during inflation in
the dilaton-axion electromagnetism, in which the dilaton and axion dynamics are
introduced in terms of two time dependent functions of the cosmic scale factor,
$I(a) F^2/4$ and $J(a) F\tilde{F}/4$, respectively, where $F$ is the
electromagnetic field strength and $\tilde{F}$ is its dual. We study the form
of $J(a)$ that can generate a large seed magnetic field in the weak coupling
regime, $I(a)&lt;1$. Although the $J(a)$ function is model dependent, the
axion-photon coupling indeed opens up a new window for a successful
inflationary magnetogenesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.8262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.8262</id><created>2014-09-29</created><updated>2015-12-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uzdensky</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerutti</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nalewajko</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Begelman</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>The extent of power-law energy spectra in collisionless relativistic
  magnetic reconnection in pair plasmas</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys. J. Lett. 816, L8 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/816/1/L8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using two-dimensional particle-in-cell simulations, we characterize the
energy spectra of particles accelerated by relativistic magnetic reconnection
(without guide field) in collisionless electron-positron plasmas, for a wide
range of upstream magnetizations $\sigma$ and system sizes $L$. The particle
spectra are well-represented by a power law $\gamma^{-\alpha}$, with a
combination of exponential and super-exponential high-energy cutoffs,
proportional to $\sigma$ and $L$, respectively. For large $L$ and $\sigma$, the
power-law index $\alpha$ approaches about 1.2.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.1484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.1484</id><created>2014-10-06</created><updated>2015-05-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takimi</keyname><forenames>Tomohisa</forenames></author></authors><title>Prescription for choosing an interpolating function</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.str-el hep-lat hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages, 27 figures, 3 tables, v2: typos corrected, v3: minor
  corrections</comments><report-no>HRI/ST/1413</report-no><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 022301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939710</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interpolating functional method is a powerful tool for studying the behavior
of a quantity in the intermediate region of the parameter space of interest by
using its perturbative expansions at both ends. Recently several interpolating
functional methods have been proposed, in addition to the well-known Pade
approximant, namely the &quot;Fractional Power of Polynomial&quot; (FPP) and the
&quot;Fractional Power of Rational functions&quot; (FPR) methods. Since combinations of
these methods also give interpolating functions, we may end up with multitudes
of the possible approaches. So a criterion for choosing an appropriate
interpolating function is very much needed. In this paper, we propose reference
quantities which can be used for choosing a good interpolating function. In
order to validate the prescription based on these quantities, we study the
degree of correlation between &quot;the reference quantities&quot; and the &quot;actual degree
of deviation between the interpolating function and the true function&quot; in
examples where the true functions are known.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.2691</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.2691</id><created>2014-10-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>Koichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakatsukasa</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satu&#x142;a</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Mean-Field Calculation Based on Proton-Neutron Mixed Energy Density
  Functionals</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures, talk given at the 2nd Conference on &quot;Advances in
  Radioactive Isotope Science 2014&quot; (ARIS 2014), Tokyo, Japan, Jun. 1-6, 2014</comments><journal-ref>JPS Conf. Proc. 6 (2015) 020051</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed calculations based on the Skyrme energy density functional
(EDF) that includes arbitrary mixing between protons and neutrons. In this
framework, single-particle states are generalized as mixtures of proton and
neutron components. The model assumes that the Skyrme EDF is invariant under
the rotation in isospin space and the Coulomb force is the only source of the
isospin symmetry breaking. To control the isospin of the system, we employ the
isocranking method, which is analogous to the standard cranking approach used
for describing high-spin states. Here, we present results of the isocranking
calculations performed for the isobaric analog states in $A = 40$ and $A = 54$
nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.3983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.3983</id><created>2014-11-14</created><updated>2015-11-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zavjalov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Autti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eltsov</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heikkinen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volovik</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Light Higgs channel of the resonant decay of magnon condensate in
  superfluid $^3$He-B</title><categories>cond-mat.other hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat.Comm. 7, 10294 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms10294</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In superfluids the order parameter, which describes spontaneous symmetry
breaking, is an analogue of the Higgs field in the Standard Model of particle
physics. Oscillations of the field amplitude are massive Higgs bosons, while
oscillations of the orientation are massless Nambu-Goldstone bosons. The
125~GeV Higgs boson, discovered at Large Hadron Collider, is light compared to
electroweak energy scale, which led to a suggestion of the ``little Higgs''
extension of the Standard Model, in which the light Higgs appears as a NG mode
acquiring mass due to violation of a hidden symmetry. Here we show that such
light Higgs exists in superfluid $^3$He-B, where one of three Nambu-Goldstone
spin-wave modes acquires small mass due to the spin-orbit interaction. Other
modes become optical and acoustic magnons. We observe parametric decay of
Bose-Einstein condensate of optical magnons to light Higgs modes and decay of
optical to acoustic magnons. Formation of a light Higgs from a Nambu-Goldstone
mode observed in $^3$He-B opens a possibility that such scenario can be
realized in other systems, where violation of some hidden symmetry is possible,
including the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.1120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.1120</id><created>2014-12-02</created><updated>2015-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poddubny</keyname><forenames>Alexander N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miroshnichenko</keyname><forenames>Andrey E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kivshar</keyname><forenames>Yuri S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Circular dichroism induced by Fano resonances in planar chiral oligomers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Laser Photonics Rev. 10, No. 1, 137-146 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/lpor.201500222</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a general theory of circular dichroism in planar chiral
nanostructures with rotational symmetry. It is demonstrated, analytically, that
the handedness of the incident field's polarization can control whether a
nanostructure induces either absorption or scattering losses, even when the
total optical loss (extinction) is polarization-independent. We show that this
effect is a consequence of modal interference so that strong circular dichroism
in absorption and scattering can be engineered by combining Fano resonances
with planar chiral nanoparticle clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.4625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.4625</id><created>2014-12-15</created><updated>2015-09-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maslovski</keyname><forenames>Stanislav I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simovski</keyname><forenames>Constantin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tretyakov</keyname><forenames>Sergei A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Overcoming black body radiation limit in free space: metamaterial
  superemitter</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>34 pages, 7 figures (largely revised version with new numerical
  results added)</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys., vol. 18, p. 013034, Jan 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here, we demonstrate that the power spectral density of thermal radiation at
a specific wavelength produced by a body of finite dimensions set up in free
space under a fixed temperature could be made theoretically arbitrary high, if
one could realize double negative metamaterials with arbitrary small loss and
arbitrary high absolute values of permittivity and permeability (at a given
frequency). This result refutes the widespread belief that Planck's law itself
sets a hard upper limit on the spectral density of power emitted by a finite
macroscopic body whose size is much greater that the wavelength. Here we
propose a physical realization of a metamaterial emitter whose spectral
emissivity can be greater than that of the ideal black body under the same
conditions. Due to the reciprocity between the heat emission and absorption
processes such cooled down superemitter also acts as an optimal sink for the
thermal radiation --- the &quot;thermal black hole&quot; --- which outperforms
Kirchhoff-Planck's black body which can absorb only the rays directly incident
on its surface. The results may open a possibility to realize narrowband
super-Planckian thermal radiators and absorbers for future thermo-photovoltaic
systems and other devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02135</id><created>2015-01-09</created><updated>2015-03-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Charnukha</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rienks</keyname><forenames>E. D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thirupathaiah</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avigo</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeevan</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gegenwart</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roslova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wurmehl</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bovensiepen</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borisenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vojta</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buechner</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Fermi-liquid scattering rates and anomalous band dispersion in
  ferropnictides</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures Supplement 4 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92. 201106 (R) (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.201106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Angle-resolved photoemission spectroscopy (ARPES) is used to study the band
dispersion and the quasiparticle scattering rates in two ferropnictides
systems. Our ARPES results show linear-in-energy dependent scattering rates
which are constant in a wide range of control parameter and which depend on the
orbital character of the bands. We demonstrate that the linear energy
dependence gives rise to weakly dispersing band with a strong mass enhancement
when the band maximum crosses the chemical potential. In the superconducting
phase the related small effective Fermi energy favors a
Bardeen-Cooper-Schrieffer (BCS)\,\cite{Bardeen1957}-Bose-Einstein
(BE)\,\cite{Bose1924} crossover state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.03765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.03765</id><created>2015-03-12</created><updated>2015-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wadley</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howells</keyname><forenames>Bryn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zelezny</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrews</keyname><forenames>Carl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hills</keyname><forenames>Victoria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campion</keyname><forenames>Richard P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novak</keyname><forenames>Vit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freimuth</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokrousov</keyname><forenames>Yuriy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rushforth</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edmonds</keyname><forenames>Kevin W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>Bryan L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jungwirth</keyname><forenames>Tomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrical switching of an antiferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>P. Wadley et al., Science 10.1126/science.aab1031 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aab1031</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Louis Neel pointed out in his Nobel lecture that while abundant and
interesting from a theoretical viewpoint, antiferromagnets did not seem to have
any applications. Indeed, the alternating directions of magnetic moments on
individual atoms and the resulting zero net magnetization make antiferromagnets
hard to control by tools common in ferromagnets. Remarkably, Neel in his
lecture provides the key which, as we show here, allows us to control
antiferromagnets by electrical means analogous to those which paved the way to
the development of ferromagnetic spintronics applications. The key noted by
Neel is the equivalence of antiferromagnets and ferromagnets for effects that
are an even function of the magnetic moment. Based on even-in-moment
relativistic transport phenomena, we demonstrate room-temperature electrical
switching between two stable configurations combined with electrical read-out
in antiferromagnetic CuMnAs thin film devices. Our magnetic memory is
insensitive to and produces no magnetic field perturbations which illustrates
the unique merits of antiferromagnets for spintronics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.00575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.00575</id><created>2015-04-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Mailybaev</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous stochasticity of velocity in turbulence models</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Multiscale Model. Simul. 14 (2016), 96-112</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/15M1012451</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the phenomenon of spontaneous stochasticity in fluid dynamics
formulated as the nonuniqueness of solutions resulting from viscosity at
infinitesimal scales acting through intermediate on large scales of the flow.
We study the finite-time onset of spontaneous stochasticity in a real version
of the GOY shell model of turbulence. This model allows high-accuracy numerical
simulations for a wide range of scales (up to ten orders of magnitude) and
demonstrates non-chaotic dynamics, but leads to an infinite number of solutions
in the vanishing viscosity limit after the blowup time. Thus, the spontaneous
stochasticity phenomenon is clearly distinguished from the chaotic behavior in
turbulent flows. We provide the numerical and theoretical description of the
system dynamics at all stages. This includes the asymptotic analysis before and
after the blowup leading to universal (periodic and quasi-periodic)
renormalized solutions, followed by nonunique stationary states at large times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.00697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.00697</id><created>2015-04-02</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berg-Johansen</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xf6;ppel</keyname><forenames>Falk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stiller</keyname><forenames>Birgit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banzer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ornigotti</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giacobino</keyname><forenames>Elisabeth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aiello</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquardt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Classically entangled optical beams for high-speed kinematic sensing</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>v2 includes the real-time measurement from the published version.
  Reference [29] added. Minor experimental details added on page 6</comments><journal-ref>Optica 2(10), 864-868 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.2.000864</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tracking the kinematics of fast-moving objects is an important diagnostic
tool for science and engineering. Existing optical methods include high-speed
CCD/CMOS imaging, streak cameras, lidar, serial time-encoded imaging and
sequentially timed all-optical mapping. Here, we demonstrate an entirely new
approach to positional and directional sensing based on the concept of
classical entanglement in vector beams of light. The measurement principle
relies on the intrinsic correlations existing in such beams between transverse
spatial modes and polarization. The latter can be determined from intensity
measurements with only a few fast photodiodes, greatly outperforming the
bandwidth of current CCD/CMOS devices. In this way, our setup enables
two-dimensional real-time sensing with temporal resolution in the GHz range. We
expect the concept to open up new directions in photonics-based metrology and
sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04570</id><created>2015-04-17</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gallais</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chauviere</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmalian</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nematic resonance in the Raman response of iron-based superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 017001 (2016)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 017001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.017001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a fully-gapped superconductor the electronic Raman response has a
pair-breaking peak at twice the superconducting gap $\Delta$, if the Bogoliubov
excitations are uncorrelated. Motivated by the iron based superconductors, we
study how this peak is modified if the superconducting phase hosts a
nematic-structural quantum critical point. We show that, upon approaching this
point by tuning, e.g., doping, the growth of nematic correlations between the
quasiparticles transforms the pair-breaking peak into a nematic resonance. The
mode energy is below 2$\Delta$, and stays finite at the quantum critical point,
where its spectral weight is sharply enhanced. The latter is consistent with
recent experiments on electron-doped iron based superconductors and provides
direct evidence of nematic correlations in their superconducting phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04964</id><created>2015-04-20</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuneo</keyname><forenames>No&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eckmann</keyname><forenames>Jean-Pierre</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium steady states for chains of four rotors</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Minor changes to reflect the published version</comments><doi>10.1007/s00220-015-2550-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a chain of four interacting rotors (rotators) connected at both ends
to stochastic heat baths at different temperatures. We show that for
non-degenerate interaction potentials the system relaxes, at a stretched
exponential rate, to a non-equilibrium steady state (NESS). Rotors with high
energy tend to decouple from their neighbors due to fast oscillation of the
forces. Because of this, the energy of the central two rotors, which interact
with the heat baths only through the external rotors, can take a very long time
to dissipate. By appropriately averaging the oscillatory forces, we estimate
the dissipation rate and construct a Lyapunov function. Compared to the chain
of length three (considered previously by C. Poquet and the current authors),
the new difficulty with four rotors is the appearance of resonances when both
central rotors are fast. We deal with these resonances using the rapid
thermalization of the two external rotors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06769</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06769</id><created>2015-04-25</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Kush</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parameswaran</keyname><forenames>Siddharth A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weld</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fibonacci optical lattices for tunable quantum quasicrystals</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 063426 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.063426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a quasiperiodic optical lattice, created by a physical
realization of the abstract cut-and-project construction underlying all
quasicrystals. The resulting potential is a generalization of the Fibonacci
tiling. Calculation of the energies and wavefunctions of ultracold atoms loaded
into such a lattice demonstrate a multifractal energy spectrum, a singular
continuous momentum-space structure, and the existence of controllable edge
states. These results open the door to cold atom quantum simulation experiments
in tunable or dynamic quasicrystalline potentials, including topological
pumping of edge states and phasonic spectroscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.08171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.08171</id><created>2015-04-30</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Ushasi</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Basu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>a</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bemmerer</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boretzky</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>c</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Elekes</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kempe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Munzenberg</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames><affiliation>c</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>c</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sobiella</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Stach</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yakorev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames><affiliation>b</affiliation></author></authors><title>Response of Multi-strip Multi-gap Resistive Plate Chamber</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>19 pages, 26 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation 10 (2015) 7005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/10/07/P07005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A prototype of Multi-strip Multi-gap Resistive Plate chamber (MMRPC) with
active area 40 cm $\times$ 20 cm has been developed at SINP, Kolkata. Detailed
response of the developed detector was studied with the pulsed electron beam
from ELBE at Helmholtz-Zentrum Dresden-Rossendorf. In this report the response
of SINP developed MMRPC with different controlling parameters is described in
details. The obtained time resolution ($\sigma_t$) of the detector after slew
correction was 91.5$ \pm $3 ps. Position resolution measured along ($\sigma_x$)
and across ($\sigma_y$) the strip was 2.8$\pm$0.6 cm and 0.58 cm, respectively.
The measured absolute efficiency of the detector for minimum ionizing particle
like electron was 95.8$\pm$1.3 $\%$. Better timing resolution of the detector
can be achieved by restricting the events to a single strip. The response of
the detector was mainly in avalanche mode but a few percentage of streamer mode
response was also observed. A comparison of the response of these two modes
with trigger rate was studied
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00498</id><created>2015-05-03</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Johnston</keyname><forenames>David C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Dipole Interactions in Crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>51 pages, 30 figures, 19 tables and 64 references, including attached
  Supplementary Information; v2: published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 014421 (2016); 33 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.014421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of magnetic dipole interactions (MDIs) on the magnetic
properties of local-moment spin systems is investigated. The eigenvalues and
eigenvectors of the MDI tensor are determined for a wide variety of spin
lattices and magnetic wavevectors in the magnetically ordered state with
collinear moment alignments. The predicted easy axes in the ordered state are
compared with experimental results for antiferromagnetic (AFM) compounds. The
theory is generalized to include noncollinear AFM structures and compared with
experiments. Many properties caused or influenced by MDIs in the ordered and
paramagnetic states are calculated within Weiss molecular field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04192</id><created>2015-05-15</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chacko</keyname><forenames>Zackaria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Yanou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hong</keyname><forenames>Sungwoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okui</keyname><forenames>Takemichi</forenames></author></authors><title>A Hidden Dark Matter Sector, Dark Radiation, and the CMB</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures. Version published in PRD</comments><report-no>UMD-PP-014-018</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 055033 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.055033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider theories where dark matter is composed of a thermal relic of weak
scale mass, whose couplings to the Standard Model (SM) are however too small to
give rise to the observed abundance. Instead, the abundance is set by
annihilation to light hidden sector states that carry no charges under the SM
gauge interactions. In such a scenario the constraints from direct and indirect
detection, and from collider searches for dark matter, can easily be satisfied.
The masses of such light hidden states can be protected by symmetry if they are
Nambu-Goldstone bosons, fermions, or gauge bosons. These states can then
contribute to the cosmic energy density as dark radiation, leading to
observable signals in the cosmic microwave background (CMB). Furthermore,
depending on whether or not the light hidden sector states self-interact, the
fraction of the total energy density that free-streams is either decreased or
increased, leading to characteristic effects on both the scalar and tensor
components of the CMB anisotropy that allows these two cases to be
distinguished. The magnitude of these signals depends on the number of light
degrees of freedom in the hidden sector, and on the temperature at which it
kinetically decouples from the SM. We consider a simple model that realizes
this scenario, based on a framework in which the SM and hidden sector are
initially in thermal equilibrium through the Higgs portal, and show that the
resulting signals are compatible with recent Planck results, while large enough
to be detected in upcoming experiments such as CMBPol and CMB Stage-IV.
Invisible decays of the Higgs into hidden sector states at colliders can offer
a complementary probe of this model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05078</id><created>2015-05-19</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kraus</keyname><forenames>Per</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathur</keyname><forenames>Samir D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nature abhors a horizon</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, Essay awarded third prize in the Gravity Research
  Foundation 2015 essay competition (some typographical errors corrected)</comments><doi>10.1142/S0218271815430038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The information paradox can be resolved if we recognize that the
wavefunctional in gravity $\Psi[g]$ should be considered on the {\it whole} of
superspace, the space of possible $g$. The largeness of the Bekenstein entropy
implies a vast space of gravitational solutions, which are conjectured to be
fuzzball configurations. In the WKB approximation, the wavefunctional for a
collapsing shell is oscillatory in a small region of superspace, and the
classical approximation picks out this part. But the wavefunctional will be
damped (`under the barrier') in the remainder of this vast superspace. We
perform a simple computation to show that at the threshold of black hole
formation, the barrier is lowered enough to make the latter part oscillatory;
this alters the classical evolution and avoids horizon formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06420</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06420</id><created>2015-05-24</created><updated>2016-01-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoehn</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey</forenames></author></authors><title>The 290 fixed-point sublattices of the Leech lattice</title><categories>math.GR hep-th math.AG</categories><comments>22 pages, 1 table, latex; 2 supplemental tables (pdf) and 1 data file
  (text) included in the source file. Version 2 adds a note describing the
  situation for the E_8 lattice. Version 3 adds data for the lattices as text
  file readable by the computer algebra system Magma</comments><journal-ref>J. of Algebra, 448 (2016), 618-637</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jalgebra.2015.08.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We determine the orbits of fixed-point sublattices of the Leech lattice with
respect to the action of the Conway group Co_0. There are 290 such orbits.
Detailed information about these lattices, the corresponding coinvariant
lattices, and the stabilizing subgroups, is tabulated in several tables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.07914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.07914</id><created>2015-05-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Takesue</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Toshihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamaki</keyname><forenames>Kiyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koashi</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental quantum key distribution without monitoring signal
  disturbance</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photonics 9, 827-831 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2015.173</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the invention of Bennett-Brassard 1984 (BB84) protocol, many quantum
key distribution (QKD) protocols have been proposed and some protocols are
operated even in field environments. One of the striking features of QKD is
that QKD protocols are provably secure unlike cryptography based on
computational complexity assumptions. It has been believed that, to guarantee
the security of QKD, Alice and Bob have to monitor the statistics of the
measurement outcomes which are used to determine the amount of the privacy
amplification to generate a key. Recently a new type of QKD protocol, called
round robin differential phase shift (RRDPS) protocol, was proposed, and
remarkably this protocol can generate a key without monitoring any statistics
of the measurement outcomes. Here we report an experimental realization of the
RRDPS protocol. We used a setup in which Bob randomly chooses one from four
interferometers with different pulse delays so that he could implement phase
difference measurements for all possible combinations with five-pulse time-bin
states. Using the setup, we successfully distributed keys over 30 km of fiber,
making this the first QKD experiment that does not rely on signal disturbance
monitoring.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01636</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01636</id><created>2015-06-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Nagel</keyname><forenames>Hannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Labavic</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer-Ortmanns</keyname><forenames>Hildegard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janke</keyname><forenames>Wolfhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Open boundary conditions in stochastic transport processes with
  pair-factorized steady states</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>conference contribution for the 27th Annual CSP Workshop on &quot;Recent
  Developments in Computer Simulation Studies in Condensed Matter Physics&quot;, CSP
  2014 5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Procedia 57 77-81 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.phpro.2014.08.136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using numerical methods we discuss the effects of open boundary conditions on
condensation phenomena in the zero-range process (ZRP) and transport processes
with pair-factorized steady states (PFSS), an extended model of the ZRP with
nearest-neighbor interaction. For the zero-range process we compare to
analytical results in the literature with respect to criticality and
condensation. For the extended model we find a similar phase structure, but
observe supercritical phases with droplet formation for strong boundary drives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03052</id><created>2015-06-09</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Much</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Adjointness of Deformed Unbounded Operators</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1307.2609</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics (Vol.56, Issue 9), 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4929662</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider deformations of unbounded operators by using the novel
construction tool of warped convolutions. By using the Kato-Rellich theorem we
show that unbounded self-adjoint deformed operators are self-adjoint if they
satisfy a certain condition. This condition proves itself to be necessary for
the oscillatory integral to be well-defined. Moreover, different proofs are
given for self-adjointness of deformed unbounded operators in the context of
quantum mechanics and quantum field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03062</id><created>2015-06-09</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for resonant t t-bar production in proton-proton collisions at
  sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added journal reference and DOI</comments><report-no>CMS-B2G-13-008, CERN-PH-EP-2015-126</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93 (2016) 012001</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.012001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is performed for the production of heavy resonances decaying into
top-antitop quark pairs in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV. Data
used for the analyses were collected with the CMS detector and correspond to an
integrated luminosity of 19.7 inverse femtobarns. The search is performed using
events with three different final states, defined by the number of leptons
(electrons and muons) from the t t-bar to W b W b decay. The analyses are
optimized for reconstruction of top quarks with high Lorentz boosts, where jet
substructure techniques are used to enhance the sensitivity. Results are
presented for all channels and a combination is performed. No significant
excess of events relative to the expected yield from standard model processes
is observed. Upper limits on the production cross section of heavy resonances
decaying to t t-bar are calculated. A narrow leptophobic topcolor Z' resonance
with a mass below 2.4 TeV is excluded at 95% confidence level. Limits are also
derived for a broad Z' resonance with a 10% width relative to the resonance
mass, and a Kaluza-Klein excitation of the gluon in the Randall-Sundrum model.
These are the most stringent limits to date on heavy resonances decaying into
top-antitop quark pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01714</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Baumeler</keyname><forenames>&#xc4;min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolf</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>The space of logically consistent classical processes without causal
  order</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 12 figures, 1 table, improved, references updated</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 013036, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/1/013036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical correlations without predefined causal order arise from processes
where parties manipulate random variables, and where the order of these
interactions is not predefined. No assumption on the causal order of the
parties is made, but the processes are restricted to be logically consistent
under any choice of the parties' operations. It is known that for three parties
or more, this set of processes is larger than the set of processes achievable
in a predefined ordering of the parties. Here, we model all classical processes
without predefined causal order geometrically and find that the set of such
processes forms a polytope. Additionally, we model a smaller polytope --- the
deterministic-extrema polytope --- where all extremal points represent
deterministic processes. This polytope excludes probabilistic processes that
must be --- quite unnaturally --- fine-tuned, because any variation of the
weights in a decomposition into deterministic processes leads to a logical
inconsistency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02527</id><created>2015-07-09</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Ken-Ichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uoi</keyname><forenames>Hidenari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Masatoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional renormalization group study of the Nambu--Jona-Lasinio model
  at finite temperature and density in an external magnetic field</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures, published version</comments><report-no>KANAZAWA-15-12</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B753 (2016) 580-585</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.12.063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, we investigate the Nambu--Jona-Lasinio (NJL) model at finite
temperature and finite density in an external magnetic field using the
functional renormalization group. We investigate the dependence of the position
of the ultraviolet fixed point (UVFP) of the four-Fermi coupling constant on
the temperature, density, and external magnetic field, and we obtain the chiral
phase structure. The UVFP at low temperature and finite chemical potential
oscillates in a small external magnetic field, which can be interpreted as the
de Haas--van Alphen effect. We also obtain phase diagrams with complex
structures, where the phase boundary moves back and forth as the external
magnetic field increases in the low temperature and high density region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03320</id><created>2015-07-13</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maheshwari</keyname><forenames>P. K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jha</keyname><forenames>Rajveer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gahtori</keyname><forenames>Bhasker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awana</keyname><forenames>V. P. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural, and Magnetic properties of flux free large FeTe Single
  crystal</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages Text+Figs</comments><journal-ref>J. Supecond. &amp; Novel Mag. 28, L2893-2897 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report synthesis of non superconducting parent compound of iron
chalcogenide, i.e., FeTe single crystal by self flux method. The FeTe single
crystal is crystallized in tetragonal structure with the P4/nmm space group.
The detailed SEM (scanning electron microscopy) results showed that the
crystals are formed in slab like morphology and are near (slight deficiency of
Te) stoichiometric with homogenous distribution of Fe and Te. The coupled
structural and magnetic phase transition is seen at around 70K in both
electrical resistivity and magnetization measurements, which is hysteric
(deltaT = 5K) in nature with cooling and warming cycles. Magnetic
susceptibility (chi-T) measurements showed the magnetic transition to be of
antiferromagnetic nature, which is substantiated by isothermal magnetization
(M-H) plots as well. The temperature dependent electrical resistivity measured
in 10kOe field in both in plane and out of plane field directions showed that
the hysteric width nearly becomes double to deltaT = 10K, and is maximum for
the out of plane field direction for the studied FeTe single crystal. We also
obtained a sharp spike like peak in heat capacity Cp(T) measurement due to the
coupled structural and magnetic order phase transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04983</id><created>2015-07-17</created><updated>2015-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sigl</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leite</keyname><forenames>Natacha</forenames></author></authors><title>Chiral Magnetic Effect in Protoneutron Stars and Magnetic Field Spectral
  Evolution</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 10 figures; Accepted for publication in JCAP</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)025</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the evolution of the chiral magnetic instability in a
protoneutron star and compute the resulting magnetic power and helicity
spectra. The instability may act during the early cooling phase of the hot
protoneutron star after supernova core collapse, where it can contribute to the
buildup of magnetic fields of strength up to the order of $10^{14}$ G. The
maximal field strengths generated by this instability, however, depend
considerably on the temperature of the protoneutron star, on density
fluctuations and turbulence spectrum of the medium. At the end of the hot
cooling phase the magnetic field tends to be concentrated around the
submillimeter to cm scale, where it is subject to slow resistive damping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01325</id><created>2015-08-06</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eissing</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meden</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kennes</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization in periodically driven quantum dots</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 026801 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.026801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on strong renormalization encountered in periodically driven
interacting quantum dots in the non-adiabatic regime. Correlations between lead
and dot electrons enhance or suppress the amplitude of driving depending on the
sign of the interaction. Employing a newly developed flexible renormalization
group based approach for periodic driving to an interacting resonant level we
show analytically that the magnitude of this effect follows a power law. Our
setup can act as a non-Markovian, single-parameter quantum pump.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.01795</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.01795</id><created>2015-08-07</created><updated>2015-12-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Teruyoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Trend-driven information cascades on random networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Physical Review E, in press</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.92.062823</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Threshold models of global cascades have been extensively used to model
real-world collective behavior, such as the contagious spread of fads and the
adoption of new technologies. A common property of those cascade models is that
a vanishingly small seed fraction can spread to a finite fraction of an
infinitely large network through local infections.
  In social and economic networks, however, individuals' behavior is often
influenced not only by what their direct neighbors are doing, but also by what
the majority of people are doing as a trend. A trend affects individuals'
behavior while individuals' behavior creates a trend.
  To analyze such a complex interplay between local- and global-scale
phenomena, I generalize the standard threshold model by introducing a new type
of node, called \textit{global nodes} (or \textit{trend followers}), whose
activation probability depends on a global-scale trend; specifically the
percentage of activated nodes in the population. The model shows that global
nodes play a role as accelerating cascades once a trend emerges while reducing
the probability of a trend emerging. Global nodes thus either facilitate or
inhibit cascades, suggesting that a moderate share of trend followers may
maximize the average size of cascades.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02325</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02325</id><created>2015-08-10</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Franco</keyname><forenames>Rosario Lo</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlocality threshold for entanglement under general dephasing
  evolutions: A case study</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures. Revised version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Determining relationships between different types of quantum correlations in
open composite quantum systems is important since it enables the exploitation
of a type by knowing the amount of another type. We here review, by giving a
formal demonstration, a closed formula of the Bell function, witnessing
nonlocality, as a function of the concurrence, quantifying entanglement, valid
for a system of two noninteracting qubits initially prepared in extended
Werner-like states undergoing any local pure-dephasing evolution. This formula
allows for finding nonlocality thresholds for the concurrence depending only on
the purity of the initial state. We then utilize these thresholds in a
paradigmatic system where the two qubits are locally affected by a quantum
environment with an Ohmic class spectrum. We show that steady entanglement can
be achieved and provide the lower bound of initial state purity such that this
stationary entanglement is above the nonlocality threshold thus guaranteeing
the maintenance of nonlocal correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03646</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03646</id><created>2015-08-14</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gulden</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janas</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuting</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamenev</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal Finite-Size Scaling around Topological Quantum Phase
  Transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures. Supplement: 2 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 026402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.026402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The critical point of a topological phase transition is described by a
conformal field theory, where finite-size corrections to energy are uniquely
related to its central charge. We investigate the finite-size scaling away from
criticality and find a scaling function, which discriminates between phases
with different topological indexes. This function appears to be universal for
all five Altland-Zirnbauer symmetry classes with non-trivial topology in one
spatial dimension. We obtain an analytic form of the scaling function and
compare it with numerical results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07819</id><created>2015-08-31</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of differential cross sections for Higgs boson production in
  the diphoton decay channel in pp collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added journal reference and DOI</comments><report-no>CMS-HIG-14-016, CERN-PH-EP-2015-195</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 13</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-015-3853-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A measurement is presented of differential cross sections for the Higgs boson
(H) production in pp collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV. The analysis exploits the H
to gamma gamma decay in data corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 19.7
inverse femtobarns collected by the CMS experiment at the LHC. The cross
section is measured as a function of the kinematic properties of the diphoton
system and of the associated jets. Results corrected for detector effects are
compared with predictions at next-to-leading order and next-to-next-to-leading
order in perturbative quantum chromodynamics, as well as with predictions
beyond the standard model. For isolated photons with pseudorapidities abs(eta)
&lt; 2.5, and with the photon of largest and next-to-largest transverse momentum
(pt[gamma]) divided by the diphoton mass m[gamma-gamma] satisfying the
respective conditions of pt[gamma] / m[gamma-gamma] &gt; 1/3 and &gt; 1/4, the total
fiducial cross section is 32 +/- 10 fb.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00160</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00160</id><created>2015-09-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Stoecker</keyname><forenames>Horst</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senzel</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greiner</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beitel</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallmeister</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorenstein</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishustin</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasak</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinheimer</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Struckmeier</keyname><forenames>Juergen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vovchenko</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satarov</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>Pengfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csernai</keyname><forenames>Laszlo P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Bikash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raha</keyname><forenames>Sibaji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bir&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Tam&#xe1;s S&#xe1;ndor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panero</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Glueballs amass at RHIC and LHC Colliders! - The early quarkless 1st
  order phase transition at $T=270$ MeV - from pure Yang-Mills glue plasma to
  GlueBall-Hagedorn states</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures;</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. G 43 (2016) 1, 015105</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0954-3899/43/1/015105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The early stage of high multiplicity pp, pA and AA collider is represented by
a nearly quarkless, hot, deconfined pure gluon plasma. According to pure
Yang-Mills Lattice Gauge Theory, this hot pure glue matter undergoes, at a high
temperature, $T_c = 270$ MeV, a first order phase transition into a confined
Hagedorn-GlueBall fluid. These new scenario should be characterized by a
suppression of high $p_T$ photons and dileptons, baryon suppression and
enhanced strange meson production. We propose to observe this newly predicted
class of events at LHC and RHIC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01322</id><created>2015-09-03</created><updated>2016-01-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mantz</keyname><forenames>Adam B.</forenames><affiliation>KIPAC Stanford/SLAC</affiliation><affiliation>KICP Chicago</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>Steven W.</forenames><affiliation>KIPAC Stanford/SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Morris</keyname><forenames>R. Glenn</forenames><affiliation>KIPAC Stanford/SLAC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Robert W.</forenames><affiliation>Heidelberg</affiliation></author></authors><title>Cosmology and Astrophysics from Relaxed Galaxy Clusters III:
  Thermodynamic Profiles and Scaling Relations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Accepted version. 16 pages (+5 pages of appendix), 12 figures, 5
  tables</comments><journal-ref>Mon. Not. Roy. Astron. Soc. 456:4020-4039, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2899</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the third in a series of papers studying the astrophysics and
cosmology of massive, dynamically relaxed galaxy clusters. Our sample comprises
40 clusters identified as being dynamically relaxed and hot (i.e., massive) in
Papers I and II of this series. Here we consider the thermodynamics of the
intracluster medium, in particular the profiles of density, temperature and
related quantities, as well as integrated measurements of gas mass, average
temperature, total luminosity and center-excluded luminosity. We fit power-law
scaling relations of each of these quantities as a function of redshift and
cluster mass, which can be measured precisely and with minimal bias for these
relaxed clusters using hydrostatic arguments. For the thermodynamic profiles,
we jointly model the density and temperature and their intrinsic scatter as a
function of radius, thus also capturing the behavior of the gas pressure and
entropy. For the integrated quantities, we also jointly fit a multidimensional
intrinsic covariance. Our results reinforce the view that simple hydrodynamical
models provide a good description of relaxed clusters outside their centers,
but that additional heating and cooling processes are important in the inner
regions (radii $r &lt; 0.5r_{2500} \approx 0.15r_{500}$). The thermodynamic
profiles remain regular, with small intrinsic scatter, down to the smallest
radii where deprojection is straightforward ($\sim 20$ kpc); within this
radius, even the most relaxed systems show clear departures from spherical
symmetry. Our results suggest that heating and cooling are continuously
regulated in a tight feedback loop, allowing the cluster atmosphere to remain
stratified on these scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.01808</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.01808</id><created>2015-09-06</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gregersen</keyname><forenames>Kristian Damlund</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>J&#xf8;rgen Beck</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequentist limit setting in effective field theories</title><categories>physics.data-an hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 15 figures, the text is edited and more figures are added
  to improve readability</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The original frequentist approach for computing confidence intervals involves
the construction of the confidence belt which provides a mapping of the
observation in data into a subset of values for the parameter. There are
different prescriptions for constructing the confidence belt, here we use the
one provided by Feldman and Cousins. Alternative methods based on the
frequentist idea exist, including the delta likelihood method, the $CL_s$
method and a method here referred to as the $p$-value method, which have all
been commonly used in high energy experiments. The purpose of this article is
to draw attention to a series of potential problems when applying these
alternative methods to the important case where the predicted signal depends
quadratically on the parameter of interest, a situation which is common in high
energy physics as it covers scenarios encountered in effective theories. These
include anomalous Higgs couplings and anomalous trilinear and quartic gauge
couplings. It is found that the alternative methods, contrary to the original
method using the confidence belt, encode the goodness-of-fit into the
confidence intervals and potentially over-constrain the parameter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04152</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Theis</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motzoi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilhelm</keyname><forenames>F. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simultaneous gates in frequency-crowded multilevel systems using fast,
  robust, analytic control shapes</title><categories>quant-ph math.OC</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 012324 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.012324</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a few-parameter ansatz for pulses to implement a broad set of
simultaneous single-qubit rotations in frequency-crowded multilevel systems.
Specifically, we consider a system of two qutrits whose working and leakage
transitions suffer from spectral crowding (detuned by $\delta$). In order to
achieve precise controllability, we make use of two driving fields (each having
two quadratures) at two different tones to implement arbitrary simultaneous
rotations. Expanding the waveforms in terms of Hanning windows, we show how
analytic pulses containing smooth and composite-pulse features can easily
achieve gate errors less than $10^{-4}$ and considerably outperform known
adiabatic techniques. Moreover, we find a generalization of the WahWah method
by Schutjens et al. [Phys. Rev. A 88, 052330 (2013)] that allows precise
separate single-qubit rotations for all gate times beyond a quantum speed
limit. We find in all cases a quantum speed limit slightly below $2\pi/\delta$
for the gate time and show that our pulses are robust against variations in
system parameters and filtering due to transfer functions, making them suitable
for experimental implementations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04246</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-01-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tabia</keyname><forenames>Gelo Noel M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Recursive multiport schemes for implementing quantum algorithms with
  photonic integrated circuits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures; v2, version accepted for publication</comments><msc-class>81V80</msc-class><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 012323 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.012323</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present recursive multiport schemes for implementing quantum Fourier
transforms and the inversion step in Grover's algorithm on an integrated linear
optics device. In particular, each scheme shows how to execute a quantum
operation on $2d$ modes using a pair of circuits for the same operation on $d$
modes. The circuits operate on path-encoded qudits and realize $d$-dimensional
unitary transformations on these states using linear optical networks with
$O\left(d^2\right)$ optical elements. To evaluate the schemes against realistic
errors, we ran simulations of proof-of-principle experiments using a simple
fabrication model of silicon-based photonic integrated devices that employ
directional couplers and thermo-optic modulators for beam splitters and phase
shifters, respectively. We find that high-fidelity performance is achievable
with our multiport circuits for $2$-qubit and $3$-qubit quantum Fourier
transforms, and for quantum search on four-item and eight-item databases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05423</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05423</id><created>2015-09-17</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kannike</keyname><forenames>Kristjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Racioppi</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raidal</keyname><forenames>Martti</forenames></author></authors><title>Linear inflation from quartic potential</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, revised version published on JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1601 (2016) 035</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2016)035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that if the inflaton has a non-minimal coupling to gravity and the
Planck scale is dynamically generated, the results of Coleman-Weinberg
inflation are confined in between two attractor solutions: quadratic inflation,
which is ruled out by the recent measurements, and linear inflation which,
instead, is in the experimental allowed region. The minimal scenario has only
one free parameter -- the inflaton's non-minimal coupling to gravity -- that
determines all physical parameters such as the tensor-to-scalar ratio and the
reheating temperature of the Universe. Should the more precise future
measurements of inflationary parameters point towards linear inflation, further
interest in scale-invariant scenarios would be motivated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05606</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dar&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lombardo</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent thermoelectric transport for nanoscale thermal machines</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 035303 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.035303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze an electronic nanoscale thermal machine driven by time-dependent
environment: besides bias and gate voltage variations, we consider also the
less prevailing time modulation of the couplings between leads and dot. We
provide energy and heat current expressions in such situations, as well as
expressions for the power exchanged between the dot+leads system and its
outside. Calculations are made in the Keldysh nonequilibrium Green's function
framework. We apply these results to design a cyclic refrigerator,
circumventing the ambiguity of defining energy flows between subsystems in the
case of strong coupling. For fast lead-dot coupling modulation, we observe
transient currents which cannot be ascribed to charge tunneling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06409</id><created>2015-09-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Gim</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sethi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Isotropic and Anisotropic Regimes of the Field-Dependent Spin Dynamics
  in Sr2IrO4: Raman Scattering Studies</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures, submitted</comments><report-no>Phys. Rev. B 93, 024405</report-no><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.024405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A major focus of experimental interest in Sr2IrO4 has been to clarify how the
magnetic excitations of this strongly spin-orbit coupled system differ from the
predictions of anisotropic 2D spin-1/2 Heisenberg model and to explore the
extent to which strong spin-orbit coupling affects the magnetic properties of
iridates. Here, we present a high-resolution inelastic light (Raman) scattering
study of the low energy magnetic excitation spectrum of Sr2IrO4 and doped
Eu-doped Sr2IrO4 as functions of both temperature and applied magnetic field.
We show that the high-field (H&gt;1.5 T) in-plane spin dynamics of Sr2IrO4 are
isotropic and governed by the interplay between the applied field and the small
in-plane ferromagnetic spin components induced by the Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya
interaction. However, the spin dynamics of Sr2IrO4 at lower fields (H&lt;1.5 T)
exhibit important effects associated with interlayer coupling and in-plane
anisotropy, including a spin-flop transition at Hc in Sr2IrO4 that occurs
either discontinuously or via a continuous rotation of the spins, depending
upon the in-plane orientation of the applied field. These results show that
in-plane anisotropy and interlayer coupling effects play important roles in the
low-field magnetic and dynamical properties of Sr2IrO4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06497</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>T&#xf6;rek</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>Axel</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards the spectrum of a GUT from gauge invariance</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>Poster presented at the &quot;27th International Symposium on Lepton
  Photon Interactions at High Energies&quot;, Ljubljana, August 2015. Final version
  with minor changes, PoS(LeptonPhoton2015)073</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The description of electroweak physics using perturbation theory is highly
successful. Though not obvious, this is due to a subtle field-theoretical
effect, the Fr\&quot;ohlich-Morchio-Strocchi mechanism, which links the physical
spectrum to that of the elementary particles. This works because of the special
structure of the standard model, and it is not a priori clear whether it works
for structurally different theories. Candidates for conflicts are, e.g., grand
unified theories. We study this situation in a toy model, a $SU(3)$ gauge
theory with two Higgs fields and a breaking pattern $SU(3) \rightarrow SU(2)
\rightarrow 1$. This mimics the weak-Higgs sector of the standard model. We
determine the leading order predictions for the gauge invariant spectrum in
this theory, and discuss a setup to test them using lattice gauge theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.06614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.06614</id><created>2015-09-22</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alishahiha</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Complexity</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>revtex, 6 pages, V2: Typos corrected, Comments added, V3: Typos
  corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 126009 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.126009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For a field theory with a gravitational dual, following Susskind's proposal
we define holographic complexity for a subsystem. The holographic complexity is
proportional to the volume of a co-dimension one time slice in the bulk
geometry enclosed by the extremal co-dimension two hyper-surface appearing in
the computation of the holographic entanglement entropy. The proportionally
constant, up to a numerical order of one factor is G R where G is the Newton
constant and R is the curvature of the space time. We study this quantity in
certain holographic model. We also explore a possible relation between the
defined quantity and fidelity appearing in quantum information literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01566</id><created>2015-10-06</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adamek</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Durrer</keyname><forenames>Ruth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tansella</keyname><forenames>Vittorio</forenames></author></authors><title>Lensing signals from Spin-2 perturbations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures; v2: discussions about non-linear contributions
  and quadrupole regularization extended, minor typos corrected, references
  added, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP01(2016)024</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/01/024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the angular power spectra of the E-type and B-type lensing
potentials for gravitational waves from inflation and for tensor perturbations
induced by scalar perturbations. We derive the tensor-lensed CMB power spectra
for both cases. We also apply our formalism to determine the linear lensing
potential for a Bianchi I spacetime with small anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02152</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02152</id><created>2015-10-07</created><updated>2015-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Kent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stein</keyname><forenames>Leo C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunes</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Challenging the Presence of Scalar Charge and Dipolar Radiation in
  Binary Pulsars</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, 6 figures; references updated, matches PRD version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93 (2016) 2, 024010</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.024010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Corrections to general relativity that introduce long-ranged scalar fields
which are non-minimally coupled to curvature typically predict that neutron
stars possess a non-trivial scalar field profile. An observer far from a star
is most sensitive to the spherically-symmetric piece of this profile that
decays linearly with the inverse of the distance, the so-called scalar charge,
which is related to the emission of dipolar radiation from compact binaries.
The presence of dipolar radiation has the potential to very strongly constrain
extended theories of gravity. These facts may lead people to believe that
gravitational theories with long-ranged scalar fields have already been
constrained strongly from binary pulsar observations. Here we challenge this
&quot;lore&quot; by investigating the decoupling limit of Gauss-Bonnet gravity as an
example, in which the scalar field couples linearly to the Gauss-Bonnet density
in the action. We prove a theorem that neutron stars in this theory cannot
possess a scalar charge. Thus Gauss-Bonnet gravity evades the strong binary
pulsar constraints on dipole radiation. We discuss the astrophysical systems
yielding the best constraints on Gauss-Bonnet gravity and related quadratic
gravity theories. To achieve this we explicitly compute the scalar charge for
slowly-rotating neutron stars in quadratic gravity theories. In generic case,
either neutron star-binary or neutron star-black hole systems can be used to
constrain the theory, but Gauss-Bonnet gravity evades the neutron star-binary
constraints. However, black holes in Gauss-Bonnet gravity do anchor scalar
charge. The best constraints on Gauss-Bonnet gravity will thus come from black
hole observations, for example via pulsar-black hole binaries. We estimate
these constraints to be ten times better than the current estimated bound, and
also include estimated constraints on generic quadratic gravity theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02607</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutsche</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hammerschmidt</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pomplun</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohlfeil</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zschiedrich</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>hp-finite-elements for simulating electromagnetic fields in optical
  devices with rough textures</title><categories>physics.optics physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings article, SPIE conference &quot;Optical Systems Design 2015:
  Computational Optics&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Proc. SPIE Vol. 9630 (2015) 96300S</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2190119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The finite-element method is a preferred numerical method when
electromagnetic fields at high accuracy are to be computed in nano-optics
design. Here, we demonstrate a finite-element method using hp-adaptivity on
tetrahedral meshes for computation of electromagnetic fields in a device with
rough textures. The method allows for efficient computations on meshes with
strong variations in element sizes. This enables to use precise geometry
resolution of the rough textures. Convergence to highly accurate results is
observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04687</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04687</id><created>2015-10-15</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gwynne</keyname><forenames>Ewain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holden</keyname><forenames>Nina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Jason</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Xin</forenames></author></authors><title>Brownian motion correlation in the peanosphere for $\kappa &gt; 8$</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.CV math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages and 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The peanosphere (or &quot;mating of trees&quot;) construction of Duplantier, Miller,
and Sheffield encodes certain types of $\gamma$-Liouville quantum gravity (LQG)
surfaces ($\gamma \in (0,2)$) decorated with an independent SLE$_{\kappa}$
($\kappa = 16/\gamma^2 &gt; 4$) in terms of a correlated two-dimensional Brownian
motion and provides a framework for showing that random planar maps decorated
with statistical physics models converge to LQG decorated with an SLE.
Previously, the correlation for the Brownian motion was only explicitly
identified as $-\cos(4\pi/\kappa)$ for $\kappa \in (4,8]$ and unknown for
$\kappa &gt; 8$. The main result of this work is that this formula holds for all
$\kappa &gt; 4$. This supplies the missing ingredient for proving convergence
results of the aforementioned type for $\kappa &gt; 8$. Our proof is based on the
calculation of a certain tail exponent for SLE$_{\kappa}$ on a quantum wedge
and then matching it with an exponent which is well-known for Brownian motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.04831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.04831</id><created>2015-10-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Baczyk</keyname><forenames>Pawel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobaczewski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konieczka</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Satula</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong-interaction isospin-symmetry breaking within the density
  functional theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>talk presented at the XXII Nuclear Physics Workshop, Kazimierz Dolny,
  Poland, September 22-27, 2015</comments><journal-ref>Acta Phys. Pol. B Proc. Supp.8 (2015) 539</journal-ref><doi>10.5506/APhysPolBSupp.8.539</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conventional Skyrme interaction is generalized by adding zero-range
charge-symmetry-breaking and charge-independence-breaking terms, and the
corresponding energy density functional is derived. It is shown that the
extended model accounts for experimental values of mirror and triplet
displacement energies (MDEs and TDEs) in sd-shell isospin triplets with, on
average, about 100~keV precision using only two additional adjustable coupling
constants. Moreover, the model is able to reproduce, for the first time, the
A=4n versus A=4n+2 staggering of the TDEs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06610</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06610</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wo&#x17a;niak</keyname><forenames>Pawe&#x142;</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;flich</keyname><forenames>Katja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xf6;nstrup</keyname><forenames>Gerald</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banzer</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christiansen</keyname><forenames>Silke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author></authors><title>Unveiling the optical properties of a metamaterial synthesized by
  electron-beam-induced deposition</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 025705 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/2/025705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The direct writing using a focused electron beam allows for fabricating truly
three-dimensional structures of sub-wavelength dimensions in the visible
spectral regime. The resulting sophisticated geometries are perfectly suited
for studying light-matter interaction at the nanoscale. Their overall optical
response will strongly depend not only on geometry but also on the optical
properties of the deposited material. In case of the typically used
metal-organic precursors, the deposits show a substructure of metallic
nanocrystals embedded in a carbonaceous matrix. Since gold-containing precursor
media are especially interesting for optical applications, we experimentally
determine the effective permittivity of such an effective material. Our
experiment is based on spectroscopic measurements of planar deposits. The
retrieved permittivity shows a systematic dependence on the gold particle
density and cannot be sufficiently described using the common Maxwell-Garnett
approach for effective medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07593</id><created>2015-10-26</created><updated>2016-01-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Menzel</keyname><forenames>Andreas M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoell</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xf6;wen</keyname><forenames>Hartmut</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Density Functional Theory For Microswimmers</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 024115 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939630</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical density functional theory (DDFT) has been successfully derived and
applied to describe on the one hand passive colloidal suspensions, including
hydrodynamic interactions between individual particles. On the other hand,
active &quot;dry&quot; crowds of self-propelled particles have been characterized using
DDFT. Here we go one essential step further and combine these two approaches.
We establish a DDFT for active microswimmer suspensions. For this purpose,
simple minimal model microswimmers are introduced. These microswimmers
self-propel by setting the surrounding fluid into motion. They hydrodynamically
interact with each other through their actively self-induced fluid flows and
via the common &quot;passive&quot; hydrodynamic interactions. An effective soft steric
repulsion is also taken into account. We derive the DDFT starting from common
statistical approaches. Our DDFT is then tested and applied by characterizing a
suspension of microswimmers the motion of which is restricted to a plane within
a three-dimensional bulk fluid. Moreover, the swimmers are confined by a
radially symmetric trapping potential. In certain parameter ranges, we find
rotational symmetry breaking in combination with the formation of a
&quot;hydrodynamic pumping state&quot;, which has previously been observed in the
literature as a result of particle-based simulations. An additional instability
of this pumping state is revealed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08221</id><created>2015-10-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Loos</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloomfield</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gill</keyname><forenames>Peter M. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three-electron coalescence points in two and three dimensions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, accepted for publication as a Communication in the
  Journal of Chemical Physics</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 181101 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4935374</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The form of the wave function at three-electron coalescence points is
examined for several spin states using an alternative method to the usual Fock
expansion. We find that, in two- and three-dimensional systems, the
non-analytical nature of the wave function is characterized by the appearance
of logarithmic terms, reminiscent of those that appear as both electrons
approach the nucleus of the helium atom. The explicit form of these
singularities is given in terms of the interelectronic distances for a doublet
and two quartet states of three electrons in a harmonic well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08785</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ungureanu</keyname><forenames>Bogdan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achaoui</keyname><forenames>Younes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enoch</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xfb;l&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>St&#xe9;phane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guenneau</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Auxetic-like metamaterials as novel earthquake protections</title><categories>physics.class-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose that wave propagation through a class of mechanical metamaterials
opens unprecedented avenues in seismic wave protection based on spectral
properties of auxetic-like metamaterials. The elastic parameters of these
metamaterials like the bulk and shear moduli, the mass density, and even the
Poisson ratio, can exhibit negative values in elastic stop bands. We show here
that the propagation of seismic waves with frequencies ranging from 1Hz to 40Hz
can be influenced by a decameter scale version of auxetic-like metamaterials
buried in the soil, with the combined effects of impedance mismatch, local
resonances and Bragg stop bands. More precisely, we numerically examine and
illustrate the markedly different behaviors between the propagation of seismic
waves through a homogeneous isotropic elastic medium (concrete) and an
auxetic-like metamaterial plate consisting of 64 cells (40mx40mx40m), utilized
here as a foundation of a building one would like to protect from seismic site
effects. This novel class of seismic metamaterials opens band gaps at
frequencies compatible with seismic waves when they are designed appropriately,
what makes them interesting candidates for seismic isolation structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00621</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arnaud</keyname><forenames>Ludovic</forenames></author></authors><title>All possible permutational symmetries of a quantum system</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 012320 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.012320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the intermediate permutational symmetries of a system of
qubits, that lie in between the perfect symmetric and antisymmetric cases. We
prove that, on average, pure states of qubits picked at random with respect to
the uniform measure on the unit sphere of the Hilbert space are almost as
antisymmetric as they are allowed to be. We then observe that multipartite
entanglement, measured by the generalized Meyer- Wallach measure, tends to be
larger in subspaces that are more antisymmetric than the complete symmetric
one. Eventually, we prove that all states contained in the most antisymmetric
subspace are relevant multipartite entangled states in the sense that their
1-qubit reduced states are all maximally mixed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01929</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mazoyer</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pueyo</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norman</keyname><forenames>Colin</forenames></author><author><keyname>N'Diaye</keyname><forenames>Mamadou</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Marel</keyname><forenames>Roeland P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soummer</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;mi</forenames></author></authors><title>Active compensation of aperture discontinuities for WFIRST-AFTA:
  analytical and numerical comparison of propagation methods and preliminary
  results with a WFIRST-AFTA-like pupil</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>16 pages, 5 figures, Accepted for publication (Oct. 23, 2015) in
  Journal of Astronomical Telescopes, Instruments, and Systems, special
  WFIRST-AFTA coronagraph</comments><journal-ref>J. Astron. Telesc. Instrum. Syst. 2(1), 011008 (Nov 23, 2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/1.JATIS.2.1.011008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The new frontier in the quest for the highest contrast levels in the focal
plane of a coronagraph is now the correction of the large diffractive artifacts
effects introduced at the science camera by apertures of increasing complexity.
The coronagraph for the WFIRST/AFTA mission will be the first of such
instruments in space with a two Deformable Mirrors wavefront control system.
Regardless of the control algorithm for these multi Deformable Mirrors, they
will have to rely on quick and accurate simulation of the propagation effects
introduced by the out-of-pupil surface. In the first part of this paper, we
present the analytical description of the different approximations to simulate
these propagation effects. In Annex A, we prove analytically that, in the
special case of surfaces inducing a converging beam, the Fresnel method yields
high fidelity for simulations of these effects. We provide numerical
simulations showing this effect. In the second part, we use these tools in the
framework of the Active Compensation of Aperture Discontinuities technique
(ACAD) applied to pupil geometries similar to WFIRST-AFTA. We present these
simulations in the context of the optical layout of the High-contrast imager
for Complex Aperture Telescopes, which will test ACAD on a optical bench. The
results of this analysis show that using the ACAD method, an apodized pupil
lyot coronagraph and the performance of our current deformable mirrors, we are
able to obtain, in numerically simulations, a dark hole with an AFTA-like
pupil. Our numerical simulation shows that we can obtain contrast better than
$2.10^{-9}$ in monochromatic light and better than 3.e-8 with 10% bandwidth
between 5 and 14 lambda/D.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03307</id><created>2015-11-10</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian-Xun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Hui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weiss</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Inversion of Tsunamis Characteristics from Sediment Deposits Based on
  Ensemble Kalman Filtering</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Sediment deposits are the only leftover records from paleo tsunami events.
Therefore, inverse modeling method based on the information contained in the
deposit is an indispensable way of deciphering the quantitative characteristics
of the tsunamis, e.g., the flow speed and the flow depth. While several models
have been proposed to perform tsunami inversion, i.e., to infer the tsunami
characteristics based on the sediment deposits, the existing methods lack
mathematical rigorousness and are not able to account for uncertainties in the
inferred quantities. In this work, we propose an inversion scheme based on
Ensemble Kalman Filtering (EnKF) to infer tsunami characteristics from sediment
deposits. In contrast to traditional data assimilation methods using EnKF, a
novelty of the current work is that we augment the system state to include both
the physical variables (sediment fluxes) that are observable and the unknown
parameters (flow speed and flow depth) to be inferred. Based on the rigorous
Bayesian inference theory, the inversion scheme provides quantified
uncertainties on the inferred quantities, which clearly distinguishes the
present method with existing schemes for tsunami inversion. Two test cases with
synthetic observation data are used to verify the proposed inversion scheme.
Numerical results show that the tsunami characteristics inferred from the
sediment deposit information have a favorable agreement with the truths, which
demonstrated the merits of the proposed tsunami inversion scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03674</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03674</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dror</keyname><forenames>Jeff Asaf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvioni</keyname><forenames>Ennio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra</keyname><forenames>Javi</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong tW Scattering at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>37 pages, 10 figures; v2: minor improvements in the discussion,
  references added. Matches version published in JHEP</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2016)071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deviations of the top electroweak couplings from their Standard Model values
imply that certain amplitudes for the scattering of third generation fermions
and longitudinally polarized vector bosons or Higgses diverge quadratically
with momenta. This high-energy growth is a genuine signal of models where the
top quark is strongly coupled to the sector responsible for electroweak
symmetry breaking. We propose to profit from the high energies accessible at
the LHC to enhance the sensitivity to non-standard top-$Z$ couplings, which are
currently very weakly constrained. To demonstrate the effectiveness of the
approach, we perform a detailed analysis of $tW \to tW$ scattering, which can
be probed at the LHC via $pp\to t\bar{t}Wj$. By recasting a CMS analysis at 8
TeV, we derive the strongest direct bounds to date on the $Ztt$ couplings. We
also design a dedicated search at 13 TeV that exploits the distinctive features
of the $t\bar{t}Wj$ signal. Finally, we present other scattering processes in
the same class that could provide further tests of the top-Higgs sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05668</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05668</id><created>2015-11-18</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maeda</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tajitsu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawabata</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foley</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honda</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moritani</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hashimoto</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishigaki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simon</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamanaka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogami</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arai</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milisavljevic</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzali</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soderberg</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schramm</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sato</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harakawa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrell</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arimoto</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sodium Absorption Systems toward SN Ia 2014J Originate on Interstellar
  Scales</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>20 pages, 17 figures, 1 table. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/816/2/57</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Na I D absorbing systems toward Type Ia supernovae (SNe Ia) have been
intensively studied over the last decade with the aim of finding circumstellar
material (CSM), which is an indirect probe of the progenitor system. However,
it is difficult to deconvolve CSM components from non-variable, and often
dominant, components created by interstellar material (ISM). We present a
series of high-resolution spectra of SN Ia 2014J from before maximum brightness
to ~250 days after maximum brightness. The late-time spectrum provides unique
information for determining the origin of the Na I D absorption systems. The
deep late-time observation allows us to probe the environment around the SN at
a large scale, extending to ~40 pc. We find that a spectrum of diffuse light in
the vicinity, but not directly in the line-of-sight, of the SN has absorbing
systems nearly identical to those obtained for the &quot;pure&quot; SN line-of-sight.
Therefore, basically all Na I D systems seen toward SN 2014J must originate
from foreground material that extends to at least ~40 pc in projection and none
at the CSM scale. A fluctuation in the column densities at a scale of ~20 pc is
also identified. After subtracting the diffuse, &quot;background&quot; spectrum, the
late-time SN Na I D profile along the SN line-of-sight is consistent with the
profile in the near-maximum brightness spectra. The lack of variability on a ~1
year timescale is consistent with the ISM interpretation for the gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06511</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Viaggiu</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Planckian corrections to the Friedmann flat equations from
  thermodynamics at the apparent horizon</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>Final version published on Mod. Phys. Lett. A</comments><journal-ref>Mod. Phys. Lett. A, Vol. 31, No. 4 (2016) 1650016</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316500164</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we use our recently generalized black hole entropy formula to
propose a quantum version of the Friedmann equations. In particular, starting
from the differential version of the first law of thermodynamics, we are able
to find planckian (non commutative) corrections to the Friedmann flat
equations. The so modified equations are formally similar to the ones present
in Gauss-Bonnet gravity, but in the ordinary 3+1 dimensions. As a consequence
of these corrections, by considering negative fluctuations in the internal
energy that are allowed by quantum field theory, our equations imply a maximum
value both for the energy density $\rho$ and for the Hubble flow $H$, i.e. the
big bang is ruled out. Conversely, by considering positive quantum
fluctuations, we found no maximum for $\rho$ and $H$. Nevertheless, by starting
with an early time energy density $\rho\sim 1/t^2$, we obtain a value for the
scale factor $a(t)\sim e^{\sqrt{t}}$, implying a finite planckian universe at
$t=0$, i.e. the point-like big bang singularity is substituted by a universe of
planckian size at $t=0$. Finally, we found possible higher order planckian
terms to our equations together with the related corrections of our generalized
Bekenstein-Hawking entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08298</id><created>2015-11-26</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Ji-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Yuan-Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Long-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Ke-Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Guo-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>Lun-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ren-Xin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yue</keyname><forenames>You-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhi</keyname><forenames>Qi-Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-frequency Radio Profiles of PSR B1133+16: radiation location and
  particle energy</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 18 figures, ApJ, 816, 76</comments><proxy>Jiguang Lu</proxy><journal-ref>J. G. Lu et al., 2016, ApJ, 816, 76</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/816/2/76</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pulse profile of PSR B1133+16 is usually regarded as a conal-double
structure. However, its multifrequency profiles cannot simply be fitted with
two Gaussian functions, and a third component is always needed to fit the
bridge region (between two peaks). This would introduce additional, redundant
parameters. In this paper, through a comparison of five fitting functions
(Gaussian, von Mises, hyperbolic secant, square hyperbolic secant, and
Lorentz), it is found that the square hyperbolic secant function can best
reproduce the profile, yielding an improved fit. Moreover, a symmetric 2D
radiation beam function, instead of a simple 1D Gaussian function, is used to
fit the profile. Each profile with either well-resolved or not-so-well-resolved
peaks could be fitted adequately using this beam function, and the bridge
emission between the two peaks does not need to be a new component. Adopting
inclination and impact angles based on polarization measurements, the opening
angle ({\theta}_{\mu}0) of the radiation beam in a certain frequency band is
derived from beam-function fitting. The corresponding radiation altitudes are
then calculated. Based on multi-frequency profiles, we also computed the
Lorentz factors of the particles and their dispersion at those locations in
both the curvature-radiation (CR) and inverse-Compton-scattering (ICS) models.
We found that the Lorentz factors of the particles decrease rapidly as the
radiation altitude increases. Besides, the radiation prefers to be generated in
annular region rather than core region, and this needs further validation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08803</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Velzen</keyname><forenames>Sjoert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Gemma E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stone</keyname><forenames>Nicholas C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraser</keyname><forenames>Morgan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wevers</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>Brian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonker</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Horst</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staley</keyname><forenames>Tim D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendez</keyname><forenames>Alexander J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller-Jones</keyname><forenames>James C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hodgkin</keyname><forenames>Simon T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Heather C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fender</keyname><forenames>Rob P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A radio jet from the optical and x-ray bright stellar tidal disruption
  flare ASASSN-14li</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA</categories><doi>10.1126/science.aad1182</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The tidal disruption of a star by a supermassive black hole leads to a
short-lived thermal flare. Despite extensive searches, radio follow-up
observations of known thermal stellar tidal disruption flares (TDFs) have not
yet produced a conclusive detection. We present a detection of variable radio
emission from a thermal TDF, which we interpret as originating from a
newly-launched jet. The multi-wavelength properties of the source present a
natural analogy with accretion state changes of stellar mass black holes,
suggesting all TDFs could be accompanied by a jet. In the rest frame of the
TDF, our radio observations are an order of magnitude more sensitive than
nearly all previous upper limits, explaining how these jets, if common, could
thus far have escaped detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08812</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08812</id><created>2015-11-27</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Candlish</keyname><forenames>G. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bidin</keyname><forenames>C. Moni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gibson</keyname><forenames>B. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Weighing the Galactic disk using the Jeans equation: lessons from
  simulations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>20 pages, 11 figures. Accepted to MNRAS. References added, plots made
  B&amp;W print-friendly</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2792</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using three-dimensional stellar kinematic data from simulated galaxies, we
examine the efficacy of a Jeans equation analysis in reconstructing the total
disk surface density, including the dark matter, at the &quot;Solar&quot; radius. Our
simulation dataset includes galaxies formed in a cosmological context using
state-of-the-art high resolution cosmological zoom simulations, and other
idealised models. The cosmologically formed galaxies have been demonstrated to
lie on many of the observed scaling relations for late-type spirals, and thus
offer an interesting surrogate for real galaxies with the obvious advantage
that all the kinematical data are known perfectly. We show that the vertical
velocity dispersion is typically the dominant kinematic quantity in the
analysis, and that the traditional method of using only the vertical force is
reasonably effective at low heights above the disk plane. At higher heights the
inclusion of the radial force becomes increasingly important. We also show that
the method is sensitive to uncertainties in the measured disk parameters,
particularly the scale lengths of the assumed double exponential density
distribution, and the scale length of the radial velocity dispersion. In
addition, we show that disk structure and low number statistics can lead to
significant errors in the calculated surface densities. Finally we examine the
implications of our results for previous studies of this sort, suggesting that
more accurate measurements of the scale lengths may help reconcile conflicting
estimates of the local dark matter density in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08896</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08896</id><created>2015-11-28</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hakobyan</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karapetyan</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barkhudaryan</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamon</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunth</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrosian</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adibekyan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aramyan</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turatto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Supernovae and their host galaxies - III. The impact of bars and bulges
  on the radial distribution of supernovae in disc galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures, 7 tables, online data</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society, Volume 456,
  Issue 3, pp.2848-2860, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2853</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an analysis of the impact of bars and bulges on the radial
distributions of the different types of supernovae (SNe) in the stellar discs
of host galaxies with various morphologies. We use a well-defined sample of 500
nearby (&lt; 100 Mpc) SNe and their low-inclined (i &lt; 60 deg) and morphologically
non-disturbed S0-Sm host galaxies from the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. We find
that in Sa-Sm galaxies, all core-collapse (CC) and vast majority of SNe Ia
belong to the disc, rather than the bulge component. The radial distribution of
SNe Ia in S0-S0/a galaxies is inconsistent with their distribution in Sa-Sm
hosts, which is probably due to the contribution of the outer bulge SNe Ia in
S0-S0/a galaxies. In Sa-Sbc galaxies, the radial distribution of CC SNe in
barred hosts is inconsistent with that in unbarred ones, while the
distributions of SNe Ia are not significantly different. At the same time, the
radial distributions of both types of SNe in Sc-Sm galaxies are not affected by
bars. We propose that the additional mechanism shaping the distributions of
Type Ia and CC SNe can be explained within the framework of substantial
suppression of massive star formation in the radial range swept by strong bars,
particularly in early-type spirals. The radial distribution of CC SNe in
unbarred Sa-Sbc galaxies is more centrally peaked and inconsistent with that in
unbarred Sc-Sm hosts, while the distribution of SNe Ia in unbarred galaxies is
not affected by host morphology. These results can be explained by the distinct
distributions of massive stars in the discs of early- and late-type spirals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01550</id><created>2015-12-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Smolec</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Survey of non-linear hydrodynamic models of type-II Cepheids</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 456(4): 3475-3493 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2868</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a grid on non-linear convective type-II Cepheid models. The dense
model grids are computed for 0.6M_Sun and a range of metallicities
([Fe/H]=-2.0,-1.5,-1.0), and for 0.8M_Sun ([Fe/H]=-1.5). Two sets of convective
parameters are considered. The models cover the full temperature extent of the
classical instability strip, but are limited in luminosity; for the most
luminous models violent pulsation leads to the decoupling of the outermost
model shell. Hence, our survey reaches only the shortest period RV Tau domain.
  In the Hertzsprung-Russel diagram we detect two domains in which period
doubled pulsation is possible. The first extends through the BL Her domain and
low luminosity W Vir domain (pulsation periods ~2-6.5 d). The second domain
extends at higher luminosities (W Vir domain; periods &gt;9.5d). Some models
within these domains display period-4 pulsation. We also detect very narrow
domains (~10 K wide) in which modulation of pulsation is possible. Another
interesting phenomenon we detect is double-mode pulsation in the fundamental
mode and in the fourth radial overtone. Fourth overtone is a surface mode,
trapped in the outer model layers. Single-mode pulsation in the fourth overtone
is also possible on the hot side of the classical instability strip. The origin
of the above phenomena is discussed. In particular, the role of resonances in
driving different pulsation dynamics as well as in shaping the morphology of
the radius variation curves is analysed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01561</id><created>2015-12-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Contini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Lucia</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatch</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borgani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Semi-Analytic Model Predictions of the Galaxy Population in
  Proto-clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2852</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the galaxy population in simulated proto-cluster regions using
a semi-analytic model of galaxy formation, coupled to merger trees extracted
from N-body simulations. We select the most massive clusters at redshift $z=0$
from our set of simulations, and follow their main progenitors back in time.
The analysis shows that proto-cluster regions are dominated by central galaxies
and their number decreases with time as many become satellites, clustering
around the central object. In agreement with observations, we find an
increasing velocity dispersion with cosmic time, the increase being faster for
satellites. The analysis shows that proto-clusters are very extended regions,
$\gtrsim 20 \, Mpc$ at $z \gtrsim 1$. The fraction of galaxies in proto-cluster
regions that are not progenitor of cluster galaxies varies with redshift,
stellar mass and area considered. It is about 20-30 per cent for galaxies with
stellar mass $\sim 10^9\,{\rm M}_{\sun}$, while negligible for the most massive
galaxies considered. Nevertheless, these objects have properties similar to
those of progenitors. We investigate the building-up of the passive-sequence in
clusters, and find that their progenitors are on average always active at any
redshift of interest of proto-clusters. The main mechanism which quenches their
star formation is the removal of the hot gas reservoir at the time of
accretion. The later galaxies are accreted (become satellite), and the more the
cold gas available, the longer the time spent as active. Central galaxies are
active over all redshift range considered, although a non-negligible fraction
of them become passive at redshift $z&lt;1$, due to strong feedback from Active
Galactic Nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03435</id><created>2015-12-10</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Michaeli</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naaman</keyname><forenames>Ron</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of spin dependent tunneling through chiral molecules</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The functionality of many biological systems depends on reliable electron
transfer with minimal heating. Unlike man-made electric circuits, nature
realizes electron transport via insulating chiral molecules. Here we include
spin into the analysis of tunneling through these molecules, and demonstrate
its importance for efficient transport. We show that the helical geometry
induces robust spin filtering accompanied by, and intimately related to,
strongly enhanced transmission. Thus, we resolve two key questions posed by
transport measurements through organic molecules, demonstrating their common
origin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03554</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-01-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Marika</forenames></author></authors><title>Lifshitz holography</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>58 pages; invited topical review for Classical and Quantum Gravity;
  v2 references and comments added (published version)</comments><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/3/033001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we review recent progress on the holographic modelling of
field theories with Lifshitz symmetry. We focus in particular on the
holographic dictionary for Lifshitz backgrounds - the relationship between bulk
fields and boundary operators, operator correlation functions and underlying
geometrical structure. The holographic dictionary is essential in identifying
the universality class of strongly coupled Lifshitz theories described by
gravitational models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07692</id><created>2015-12-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lingwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Review of magnetic properties and magnetocaloric effect in the
  intermetallic compounds of rare earth with low boiling point metal(s)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Invited review. Including 56 pages, 23 figures, 2 tables. Chinese
  Physics B 2016</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B Vol. 25, No. 3 (2016) 037502</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/25/3/037502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The magnetocaloric effect (MCE) in many rare earth (RE) based intermetallic
compounds has been extensively investigated during last two decades, not only
due to their potential applications for magnetic refrigeration but also for
better understanding of the fundamental problems of the materials. This paper
reviews our recent progress of magnetic properties and MCE in some binary or
ternary intermetallic compounds of RE with low boiling point metal(s) (Zn, Mg,
and Cd). Some of them are exhibiting promising MCE properties which make them
also attractive for low temperature magnetic refrigeration. Characteristics of
the magnetic transition, origin of large MCE as well as the potential
application of these compounds were thoroughly discussed. Additionally, a brief
review of the magnetic and magnetocaloric properties in the quaternary rare
earth nickel boroncarbides RENi2B2C superconductors is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02612</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02612</id><created>2016-01-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Martinez-Medina</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pichardo</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moreno</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peimbert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Velazquez</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Origin of High-Altitude Open Clusters in the Milky Way</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ Letters</comments><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/817/1/L3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a dynamical study of the effect of the bar and spiral arms on the
simulated orbits of open clusters in the Galaxy. Specifically, this work is
devoted to the puzzling presence of high-altitude open clusters in the Galaxy.
For this purpose we employ a very detailed observationally motivated potential
model for the Milky Way and a careful set of initial conditions representing
the newly born open clusters in the thin disk. We find that the spiral arms are
able to raise an important percentage of open clusters (about one-sixth of the
total employed in our simulations, depending on the structural parameters of
the arms) above the Galactic plane to heights beyond 200 pc, producing a
bulge-shaped structure toward the center of the Galaxy. Contrary to what was
expected, the spiral arms produce a much greater vertical effect on the
clusters than the bar, both in quantity and height; this is due to the sharper
concentration of the mass on the spiral arms, when compared to the bar. When a
bar and spiral arms are included, spiral arms are still capable of raising an
important percentage of the simulated open clusters through chaotic diffusion
(as tested from classification analysis of the resultant high-z orbits), but
the bar seems to restrain them, diminishing the elevation above the plane by a
factor of about two.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02746</id><created>2016-01-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Baodong</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Junmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of two-color magneto-optical trap with cesium
  6S1/2-6P3/2-7S1/2 ladder-type system</title><categories>physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><acm-class>J.2; G.1.8</acm-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  A novel cesium (Cs) two-color magneto-optical trap (TC-MOT), which partially
employs the optical radiation forces due to photon scattering of the 6P3/2
(F'=5) - 7S1/2 (F&quot;=4) excited-state transition in the Cs 6S1/2 - 6P3/2 - 7S1/2
(852 + 1470 nm) ladder-type system, has been proposed and experimentally
investigated. One of the three pairs of 852 nm cooling/trapping beams (CTBs) in
a conventional Cs MOT is replaced with a pair of the 1470 nm CTBs (type-I) or
with one 852 nm CTB plus another counter-propagating 1470 nm CTB (type-II).
Both the type-I and type-II Cs TC-MOTs can cool and trap atoms on both the red-
and blue-detuning sides of the two-photon resonance. The Cs TC-MOT demonstrated
in this work may have applications in the background-free detection of cooled
and trapped atoms, and the photon-pair sources compatible with the
ensemble-based quantum memory and the long-distance quantum communication via
optical fiber.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03645</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03645</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Mastrandrea</keyname><forenames>Rossana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soto-Aladro</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brouqui</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barrat</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing the evaluation of pathogen transmission risk in a hospital by
  merging hand-hygiene compliance and contact data: a proof-of-concept study</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-bio.PE</categories><journal-ref>BMC Research Notes 8:426 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1186/s13104-015-1409-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hand-hygiene compliance and contacts of health-care workers largely determine
the potential paths of pathogen transmission in hospital wards. We explored how
the combination of data collected by two automated infrastructures based on
wearable sensors and recording (i) use of hydro-alcoholic solution and (ii)
contacts of health-care workers provide an enhanced view of the risk of
transmission events in the ward. We perform a proof-of-concept observational
study. Detailed data on contact patterns and hand-hygiene compliance of
health-care workers were collected by wearable sensors over 12 days in an
infectious disease unit of a hospital in Marseilles, France. 10837 contact
events among 10 doctors, 4 nurses, 4 nurses' aids and 4 housekeeping staff were
recorded during the study. Most contacts took place among medical doctors.
Aggregate contact durations were highly heterogeneous and the resulting contact
network was highly structured. 510 visits of health-care workers to patients'
rooms were recorded, with a low rate of hand-hygiene compliance. Both data sets
were used to construct histories and statistics of contacts informed by the use
of hydro-alcoholic solution, or lack thereof, of the involved health-care
workers. Hand-hygiene compliance data strongly enrich the information
concerning contacts among health-care workers, by assigning a 'safe' or
'at-risk' value to each contact. The global contact network can thus be divided
into 'at-risk' and 'safe' contact networks. The combined data could be of high
relevance for outbreak investigation and to inform data-driven models of
nosocomial disease spread.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03740</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Tanoglidis</keyname><forenames>Dimitrios</forenames><affiliation>U. Crete</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pavlidou</keyname><forenames>Vasiliki</forenames><affiliation>U. Crete</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tomaras</keyname><forenames>Theodore</forenames><affiliation>U. Crete</affiliation></author></authors><title>Turnaround overdensity as a cosmological observable: the case for a
  local measurement of $\Lambda$</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that, in the context of the $\Lambda$CDM model, it is in
principle possible to measure the value of the cosmological constant by
tracing, across cosmic time, the evolution of the turnaround radius of cosmic
structures. The novelty of the presented method is that it is local, in the
sense that it uses the effect of the cosmological constant on the relatively
short scales of cosmic structures and not on the dynamics of the Universe at
its largest scales. In this way, it can provide an important consistency check
for the standard cosmological model and can give signs of new physics, beyond
$\Lambda$CDM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03748</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Marquard</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinhauser</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Four-loop relation between the $\bar{\rm MS}$ and on-shell quark mass</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the 12th
  International Symposium on Radiative Corrections (Radcor 2015) and LoopFest
  XIV (Radiative Corrections for the LHC and Future Colliders)</comments><report-no>TTP16-003, HU-EP-16/03, DESY 16-006</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this contribution we discuss the four-loop relation between the on-shell
and $\bar{\rm MS}$ definition of heavy quark masses which is applied to the
top, bottom and charm case. We also present relations between the $\bar{\rm
MS}$ quark mass and various threshold mass definitions and discuss the
uncertainty at next-to-next-to-next-to-leading order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03750</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03750</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>F. R. de S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Souza</keyname><forenames>J. J. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viana</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>O. P. de S&#xe1;</forenames></author></authors><title>A Simple Scheme for Quantum Non Demolition of Phonons Number of the
  Nanoelectromechanics Systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we describe a scheme to perform a continuous over time quantum
non demolition (QND) mea- surement of the number of phonons of a
nanoelectromechanical system (NEMS). Our scheme also allows us to describe the
statistics of the number of phonons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03753</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Reeves</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadler</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allison</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koribalski</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curran</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pracy</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bignall</keyname><forenames>H. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>HI emission and absorption in nearby, gas-rich galaxies II. -- sample
  completion and detection of intervening absorption in NGC 5156</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>31 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv3011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of a survey for intervening 21cm HI absorption in a
sample of 10 nearby, gas-rich galaxies selected from the HI Parkes All-Sky
Survey (HIPASS). This follows the six HIPASS galaxies searched in previous work
and completes our full sample. In this paper we searched for absorption along
17 sightlines with impact parameters between 6 and 46 kpc, making one new
detection. We also obtained simultaneous HI emission-line data, allowing us to
directly relate the absorption-line detection rate to the HI distribution. From
this we find the majority of the non-detections in the current sample are
because sightline does not intersect the HI disc of the galaxy at sufficiently
high column density, but that source structure is also an important factor.
  The detected absorption-line arises in the galaxy NGC 5156 ($z = 0.01$) at an
impact parameter of 19 kpc. The line is deep and narrow with an integrated
optical depth of 0.82 km s$^{-1}$. High resolution Australia Telescope Compact
Array (ATCA) images at 5 and 8 GHz reveal that the background source is
resolved into two components with a separation of 2.6 arcsec (500 pc at the
redshift of the galaxy), with the absorption likely occurring against a single
component. We estimate that the ratio of the spin temperature and covering
factor, $T_{\mathrm{S}}/f$, is approximately 950 K in the outer disc of NGC
5156, but further observations using VLBI would allow us to accurately measure
the covering factor and spin temperature of the gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03774</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ulmer</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames><affiliation>CMS and ATLAS Collaborations</affiliation></author></authors><title>Supersymmetry: Experimental Status</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 16 figures, proceedings prepared for LHCP2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This talk presents results from the CMS and ATLAS Collaborations from
searches for physics beyond the Standard Model motivated by supersymmetry from
Run 1 of the LHC. Representative searches are described to illustrate the
diverse nature of the search program in both background estimation techniques
and final state topologies. The status of preparation for Run 2 searches at 13
TeV is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03789</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Rivera</keyname><forenames>Alexander Bonilla</forenames></author></authors><title>Theoretical Foundations of PGWs Printed in the CMB and its Observational
  Status</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, presented in the Second Workshop on Numerical and
  Observational Astrophysics: From the First Structures to the Universe Today,
  2011. Updated version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The anisotropy study cosmic microwave background (CMB) is one of the main
observational tools for modern cosmology. However, alongside the study of the
thermal fluctuations of the CMB are other equally important information, which
is known as the polarization of the CMB. The inflationary model predicts that
the CMB is linearly polarized and the physical mechanism of this polarization
is studied from the Thompson scattering, the dominant process on the surface of
last scattering. There are basically two types of polarization called E and B
modes, the first produced by scalar perturbations and the latter by tensor
perturbations, such as those due to gravitational waves in the primordial
universe. So if we are able to measure these types of polarization will have an
entry to the study of the inflationary epoch. This paper presents the main
physical mechanisms that support theoretically the polarization of the CMB due
to primordial gravitational waves (PGW) and the revision of the main
observables, grouped in so-called Stokes parameters (Q, U, I), Which brings us
information to achieve the contrast the angular power spectrum produced by the
polarization of the CMB, which shows to be in excellent agreement with the
$\Lambda$CDM model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03794</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ferrario</keyname><forenames>Lilia</forenames></author></authors><title>Observational properties of magnetic white dwarfs</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>1p pages, 4 figures, to appear in the Proceedings of the &quot;14th Marcel
  Grossmann Meeting&quot; (Rome, July 12 - 18, 2015)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There are no known examples of magnetic white dwarfs with fields larger than
about 3MG paired with a non-degenerate companion in detached binary systems.
The suggestion is that highly magnetic, isolated white dwarfs may originate
from stars that coalesce during common envelope evolution while those stars
that emerge from a common envelope on a close orbit may evolve into double
degenerate systems consisting of two white dwarfs, one or both magnetic.
  The presence of planets or planetary debris around white dwarfs is also a new
and exciting area of research that may give us important clues on the formation
of first and second generation planetary systems, since these place unique
signatures in the spectra of white dwarfs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03814</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Noda</keyname><forenames>C. Quintero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suematsu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of horizontal flows in the solar granulation</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw090</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solar limb observations sometimes reveal the presence of a satellite lobe in
the blue wing of the Stokes I profile from pixels belonging to granules. The
presence of this satellite lobe has been associated in the past to strong line
of sight gradients and, as the line of sight component is almost parallel to
the solar surface, to horizontal granular flows. We aim to increase the
knowledge about these horizontal flows studying a spectropolarimetric
observation of the north solar pole. We will make use of two state of the art
techniques, the spatial deconvolution procedure that increases the quality of
the data removing the stray light contamination, and spectropolarimetric
inversions that will provide the vertical stratification of the atmospheric
physical parameters where the observed spectral lines form. We inverted the
Stokes profiles using a two component configuration, obtaining that one
component is strongly blueshifted and displays a temperature enhancement at
upper photospheric layers while the second component has low redshifted
velocities and it is cool at upper layers. In addition, we examined a large
number of cases located at different heliocentric angles, finding smaller
velocities as we move from the centre to the edge of the granule. Moreover, the
height location of the enhancement on the temperature stratification of the
blueshifted component also evolves with the spatial location on the granule
being positioned on lower heights as we move to the periphery of the granular
structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03816</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03816</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Subhra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Model of Emergent Universe in Inhomogeneous Space-Time</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><msc-class>83F05</msc-class><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 035013</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/3/035013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A scenario of an emergent universe is constructed in the background of an
inhomogeneous space-time model which is asymptotically (at spatial infinity)
FRW space-time. The cosmic substratum consists of non-interacting two
components, namely {\bf a)} homogeneous and isotropic fluid but dissipative in
nature and {\bf b)} an inhomogeneous and anisotropic barotropic fluid. In
non-equilibrium thermodynamic prescription (second order deviations), particle
creation mechanism is considered the cause for the dissipative phenomena. It is
found that for constant value of the particle creation rate parameter there
exists a scenario of emergent universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03820</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03820</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Seho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Hunpyo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Jin-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Jun-Hyung</forenames></author></authors><title>Mott- versus Slater-type Insulating Nature of Two-Dimensional Sn Atom
  Lattice on SiC(0001)</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures + supplementary material</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Semiconductor surfaces with narrow surface bands provide unique playgrounds
to search for Mott-insulating state. Recently, a combined experimental and
theoretical study [Phys. Rev. Lett. 114, 247602 (2015)] of the two-dimensional
(2D) Sn atom lattice on a wide-gap SiC(0001) substrate proposed a Mott-type
insulator driven by strong on-site Coulomb repulsion U. Our systematic
density-functional theory (DFT) study with local, semilocal, and hybrid
exchange-correlation functionals shows that the Sn dangling-bond state largely
hybridizes with the substrate Si 3p and C 2p states to split into three surface
bands due to the crystal field. Such a hybridization gives rise to the
stabilization of the antiferromagnetic order via superexchange interactions.
The band gap and the density of states predicted by the hybrid DFT calculation
agree well with photoemission data. Our findings not only suggest that the
Sn/SiC(0001) system can be represented as a Slater-type insulator driven by
long-range magnetism, but also have an implication that taking into account
long-range interactions beyond the on-site interaction would be of importance
for properly describing the insulating nature of Sn/SiC(0001).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03823</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Huei-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soo</keyname><forenames>Chopin</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic time geometrodynamics: explicit examples</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages. This article is an extension of `Intrinsic time
  geometrodynamics: explicit examples', Huei-Chen Lin and Chopin Soo, Chin. J.
  Phys. 53, 110102 (2015), published in Chinese Journal of Physics (Volume 53,
  Number 6 (November 2015)), Special Issue On the occasion of 100 years since
  the birth of Einstein's General Relativity</comments><journal-ref>Chin. J. Phys. 53, 110102 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Intrinsic time quantum geometrodynamics resolved `the problem of time' and
bridged the deep divide between quantum mechanics and canonical quantum gravity
with a Schrodinger equation which describes evolution in intrinsic time
variable. In this formalism, Einstein's general relativity is a particular
realization of a wider class of theories. Explicit classical black hole and
cosmological solutions and the motion of test particles are derived and
analyzed in this work in the context of constant three-curvature solutions in
intrinsic time geometrodynamics; and we exemplify how this formalism yields
results which agree with the predictions of Einstein's theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03824</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Soo</keyname><forenames>Chopin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Hoi-Lai</forenames></author></authors><title>New commutation relations for quantum gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages. Published as `New commutation relations for quantum
  gravity', Chopin Soo and Hoi-Lai Yu, Chin. J. Phys. 53, 110106 (2015),
  Chinese Journal of Physics (Volume 53, Number 6 (November 2015)) Special
  Issue On the occasion of 100 years since the birth of Einstein's General
  Relativity</comments><journal-ref>Chin. J. Phys. 53, 110106 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new set of fundamental commutation relations for quantum gravity is
presented. The basic variables are the eight components of the unimodular part
of the spatial dreibein and eight SU(3) generators which correspond to
Klauder's momentric variables. The commutation relations are not canonical, but
they have well defined group theoretical meanings. All fundamental entities are
dimensionless; and quantum wave functionals are preferentially selected to be
in the dreibein representation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03832</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zankovich</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalenko</keyname><forenames>I. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant Amplification of Turbulence by the Blast Wawes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal,2015, Volume 800, Issue 1, article id.
  28, 10 pp</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/800/1/28</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss an idea whether spherical blast waves can amplify by a non-local
resonant hydrodynamic mechanism inhomogeneities formed by turbulence or phase
segregation in the interstellar medium. We consider the problem of a
blast-wave-turbulence interaction in the Linear Interaction Approximation.
Mathematically, this is an eigenvalue problem for finding the structure and
amplitude of eigenfunctions describing the response of the shock-wave flow to
forced oscillations by external perturbations in the ambient interstellar
medium. Linear analysis shows that the blast wave can amplify density and
vorticity perturbations for a wide range of length scales with amplification
coefficients of up to 20, with amplification the greater, the larger the
length. There also exist resonant harmonics for which the gain becomes formally
infinite in the linear approximation. Their orbital wavenumbers are within the
range of macro- ($l \sim 1$), meso- ($l \sim 20$) and microscopic ($l &gt; 200$)
scales. Since the resonance width is narrow: typically, $\Delta l &lt;1$,
resonance should select and amplify discrete isolated harmonics. We speculate
as to a possible explanation of an observed regular filamentary structure of
regular-shaped round supernova remnants such as SNR 1572, 1006 or 0509-67.5.
Resonant mesoscales found ($l \approx 18 $) are surprisingly close to the
observed scales ($l \approx 15$) of ripples in the shell's surface of SNR
0509-67.5.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03834</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Msezane</keyname><forenames>A. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baltenkov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Doubly-charged Negative Ion of C60 Molecule</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1408.4647</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the Dirac- and Lorentz-bubble potential models an electronic structure
of the doubly-charged negative ion has been studied by a variational method. It
is shown that even in the first approximation of this method when a trial wave
function of the two electrons is represented as a product of one-electron
functions the total energy of the system is negative, a manifestation of the
existence of a stable state of the doubly-charged negative ion in these models.
The second electron affinity of C60 according to estimation is about 1 eV. The
photodetachment cross sections of this ion have been calculated as well. Near
threshold behavior of cross section is found to exhibit peculiar and
interesting behavior. The first cross section accompanied by the transformation
of the doubly-charged negative ion into a singly-charged one is exponentially
small near the process threshold. The second cross section corresponds to the
photodetachment of a singly-charged ion; it increases at the threshold as a
power function of the kinetic energy of the photoelectron. These cross sections
are of the same order as the photodetachment cross sections of atomic ions with
the same electron affinity. AMS (MOS) Subject Classification. 70G75, 81V10,
81V55
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03841</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Gris-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Ras</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Birks</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Airy fibre: an optical fibre that guides light diffracted by a
  circular aperture</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have designed and made an optical fibre that guides an approximate Airy
pattern as one of its guided modes. The fibre's attenuation was 11.0 dB/km at
1550 nm wavelength, the match between the fibre's mode and the ideal infinite
Airy pattern was 93.7%, and the far field resembled a top-hat beam. The
guidance mechanism has strong similarities to photonic bandgap guidance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03842</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03842</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Manson</keyname><forenames>S. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baltenkov</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Msezane</keyname><forenames>A. Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Model Potentials for a C60 Shell</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1406.2165</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spatial distribution of electric charges forming a square well potential
has been analyzed. It is shown that this potential is created by two concentric
spheres with a double layer of charges. A C60 shell potential has been
calculated under the assumption that it is formed by the averaged charge
density of a neutral atom. It is further demonstrated that the phenomenological
potentials simulating the C60 shell potential belong to a family of potentials
with a non-flat bottom. Two possible types of C60 model potentials are proposed
and their parameters have been calculated. AMS (MOS) Subject Classification.
62P35, 81V55
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03843</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Werner</keyname><forenames>Reinhard F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uncertainty relations for general phase spaces</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>For the proceedings of QCMC 2014</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe a setup for obtaining uncertainty relations for arbitrary pairs
of observables related by Fourier transform. The physical examples discussed
here are standard position and momentum, number and angle, finite qudit
systems, and strings of qubits for quantum information applications. The
uncertainty relations allow an arbitrary choice of metric for the distance of
outcomes, and the choice of an exponent distinguishing e.g., absolute or root
mean square deviations. The emphasis of the article is on developing a unified
treatment, in which one observable takes values in an arbitrary locally compact
abelian group and the other in the dual group. In all cases the phase space
symmetry implies the equality of measurement uncertainty bounds and preparation
uncertainty bounds, and there is a straightforward method for determining the
optimal bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03849</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03849</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dam</keyname><forenames>Mogens</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision Electroweak measurements at the FCC-ee</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Because of a luminosity of up to five orders of magnitude larger than at LEP,
electroweak precision measurements at the FCC-ee -- the Future Circular
Collider with electron-positron beams -- would provide improvements by orders
of magnitude over the present status and constitute a broad search for the
existence of new, weakly interacting particles up to very high energy scales.
The FCC-ee will address centre-of-mass energies ranging from below the Z pole
to the $\mathrm{t\bar{t}}$ threshold and above. At energies around the Z pole,
the Z-boson mass and width can be measured to better than 100 keV each.
Asymmetry measurements at the Z pole allow improvements in the determination of
the weak mixing angle by at least a factor 30 to
$\delta\sin^2\theta\mathrm{_W^{eff}}\simeq 6\times 10^{-6}$. A determination of
the electromagnetic coupling constant at the Z energy scale,
$\alpha_\mathrm{QED}(m_\mathrm{Z}^2)$, to a relative precision of $3\times
10^{-5}$ can be obtained via measurement of the forward-backward asymmetry of
lepton pairs at two energy points $\pm 3.2\,\textrm{GeV}$ away from the Z peak.
At energies around the WW threshold, high-statistic cross section measurements
can provide a determination of the W mass to 300 keV. The key breakthrough
advantage of the FCC-ee in these achievements, beside the large luminosity, is
the possibility of a continous, precise determination of the beam energy by
resonant depolarization at the Z peak and at the WW threshold. Precise
measurements of the hadronic branching fractions of the Z and W bosons allow
for considerably improvements in the determination of the strong coupling
constant down to a precision of $\delta\alpha_\mathrm{s}(m_\mathrm{Z}^2)\simeq
0.0001$. An energy scan around the 350 GeV $\mathrm{t\bar{t}}$ threshold allows
a 10 MeV measurement of the top-quark mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03861</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zanker</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marthaler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;n</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoherence and Decay of Two-level Systems due to Non-equilibrium
  Quasiparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.supr-con</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is frequently observed that even at very low temperatures the number of
quasiparticles in superconducting materials is higher than predicted by
standard BCS-theory. These quasiparticles can interact with two-level systems,
such as superconducting qubits or two-level systems (TLS) in the amorphous
oxide layer of a Josephson junction. This interaction leads to decay and
decoherence of the TLS, with specific results, such as the time dependence,
depending on the distribution of quasiparticles and the form of the
interaction. We study the resulting decay laws for different experimentally
relevant protocols.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03864</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Kades</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schrauth</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Maximilian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinrichsen</keyname><forenames>Haye</forenames></author></authors><title>Characteristics of a random walk on a self-inflating support</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>LaTeX, 12 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-similar dynamical processes are characterized by a growing length scale
$\xi$ which increases with time as $\xi \sim t^{1/z}$, where z is the dynamical
exponent. The best known example is a simple random walk with z=2. Usually such
processes are assumed to take place on a static background. In this paper we
address the question what changes if the background itself evolves dynamically.
As an example we consider a random walk on an isotropically and homogeneously
inflating space. For an exponentially fast expansion it turns out that the
self-similar properties of the random walk are destroyed. For an inflation with
power-law characteristics, however, self-similarity is preserved provided that
the exponent controlling the growth is small enough. The resulting probability
distribution is analyzed in terms of cumulant ratios. Moreover, the dynamical
exponent z is found to change continuously with the control exponent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03871</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Tumulka</keyname><forenames>Roderich</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection Time Distribution for Several Quantum Particles</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages LaTeX, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the question of how to compute the probability distribution of the
time at which a detector clicks, in the situation of $n$ non-relativistic
quantum particles in a volume $\Omega\subset \mathbb{R}^3$ in physical space
and detectors placed along the boundary $\partial \Omega$ of $\Omega$. We have
recently [http://arxiv.org/abs/1601.03715] argued in favor of a rule for the
1-particle case that involves a Schr\&quot;odinger equation with an absorbing
boundary condition on $\partial \Omega$ introduced by Werner; we call this rule
the &quot;absorbing boundary rule.&quot; Here, we describe the natural extension of the
absorbing boundary rule to the $n$-particle case. A key element of this
extension is that, upon a detection event, the wave function gets collapsed by
inserting the detected position, at the time of detection, into the wave
function, thus yielding a wave function of $n-1$ particles. We also describe an
extension of the absorbing boundary rule to the case of moving detectors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03885</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Abanov</keyname><forenames>Ar.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beneteau</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khavinson</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teodorescu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>A free boundary problem associated with the isoperimetric inequality</title><categories>math.CV math-ph math.CA math.MP</categories><msc-class>30D05, 30E10, 30E25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proves a 30 year old conjecture that disks and annuli are the only
domains where analytic content - the uniform distance from $\bar{z}$ to
analytic functions - achieves its lower bound. This problem is closely related
to several well-known free boundary problems, in particular, Serrin's problem
about laminar flow of incompressible viscous fluid for multiply-connected
domains, and Garabedian's problem on the shape of electrified droplets. Some
further ramifications and open questions, including extensions to higher
dimensions, are also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03886</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03886</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Riaud</keyname><forenames>Antoine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baudoin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Jean-Louis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matar</keyname><forenames>Olivier Bou</forenames></author></authors><title>SAW synthesis with IDTs array and the inverse filter: toward a versatile
  SAW toolbox for microfluidics and biological applications</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface acoustic waves (SAWs) are versatile tools to manipulate fluids at
small scales for microfluidics and bio- logical applications. A non-exhaustive
list of operations that can be performed with SAW includes sessile droplet
displacement, atomization, division and merging but also the actuation of
fluids embedded in microchannels or the manipulation of suspended particles.
However, each of these operations requires a specific design of the wave
generation system, the so-called interdigitated transducers (IDTs). Depending
on the application, it might indeed be necessary to generate focused or plane,
propagating or standing, aligned or shifted waves. Furthermore, the
possibilities offered by more complex wave-fields such as acoustical vortices
for particle tweezing and liquid twisting cannot be explored with classical
IDTs. In this paper, we show that the inverse filter technique coupled with an
interdigitated transducers array (IDTA) enables to synthesize all classical
wave-fields used in microfluidics and biological applications with a single
multi- function platform. It also enables to generate swirling SAWs, whose
potential for the on-chip synthesis of tailored acoustical vortices has been
demonstrated lately. The possibilities offered by this platform is illustrated
by performing successively many operations on sessile droplets with the same
system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03895</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Ushasi</forenames><affiliation>Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Saha Institute of Nuclear Physics, India</affiliation></author></authors><title>Ultra-fast timing detectors to probe exotic properties of nuclei using
  RIB facility</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><comments>Submitted to EMIS 2015 conference proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the facilities of radioactive ion beam (RIB) combined with advanced
detector systems provide us unique opportunity to probe the exotic properties
of the nuclei with unusual neutron-to-proton ratio. In this article, a study of
characterization of different types of ultra-fast timing detectors: a special
type of gas detector (multi-strip multi-gap resistive plate chamber, MMRPC)
($\sigma$ $&lt;$100 ps), scintillators array ( viz., $LaBr_3:Ce$) (timing
resolution ($\sigma&lt;$250 ps) are being presented. A brief discussion on usage
of these different types of ultra-fast timing detector systems at radioactive
ion beam facilities is also included.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03898</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Seleznev</keyname><forenames>Anton F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Open-cluster density profiles derived using a kernel estimator</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>17 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016 456 (4):
  3757-3773</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2874</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface and spatial radial density profiles in open clusters are derived
using a kernel estimator method. Formulae are obtained for the contribution of
every star into the spatial density profile. The evaluation of spatial density
profiles is tested against open-cluster models from N-body experiments with N =
500. Surface density profiles are derived for seven open clusters (NGC 1502,
1960, 2287, 2516, 2682, 6819 and 6939) using Two-Micron All-Sky Survey data and
for different limiting magnitudes. The selection of an optimal kernel
half-width is discussed. It is shown that open-cluster radius estimates hardly
depend on the kernel half-width. Hints of stellar mass segregation and
structural features indicating cluster non-stationarity in the regular force
field are found. A comparison with other investigations shows that the data on
open-cluster sizes are often underestimated. The existence of an extended
corona around the open cluster NGC 6939 was confirmed. A combined function
composed of the King density profile for the cluster core and the uniform
sphere for the cluster corona is shown to be a better approximation of the
surface radial density profile.The King function alone does not reproduce
surface density profiles of sample clusters properly. The number of stars, the
cluster masses and the tidal radii in the Galactic gravitational field for the
sample clusters are estimated. It is shown that NGC 6819 and 6939 are extended
beyond their tidal surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03901</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Entem</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortega</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Partners of the $X(3872)$ and HQSS breaking</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, sent as contribution to the proceedings of the
  XVI International Conference on Hadron Spectroscopy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the discovery of the $X(3872)$ the study of heavy meson molecules has
been the subject of many investigations. On the experimental side different
experiments have looked for its spin partners and the bottom analogs. On the
theoretical side different approaches have been used to understand this state.
Some of them are EFT that impose HQSS and so they make predictions for the
partners of the $X(3872)$, suggesting the existence of a $J^{PC}=2^{++}$
partner in the charm sector or $J^{PC}=1^{++}$ or $2^{++}$ analogs in the
bottom.
  In our work, in order to understand the $X(3872)$, we use a Chiral quark
model in which, due to the proximity to the $DD^*$ threshold, we include $c\bar
c$ states coupled to $DD^*$ molecular components. In this coupled channel model
the relative position of the bare $c\bar c$ states with two meson thresholds
are very important. We have looked for the $X(3872)$ partners and we don't find
a bound state in the $D^*D^*$ $J^{PC}=2^{++}$. In the bottom sector we find the
opposite situation where the $B^*B^*$ with $J^{PC}=2^{++}$ is bounded while the
$J^{PC}=1^{++}$ is not bounded. These results shows how the coupling with
$c\bar c$ states can induced different results than those expected by HQSS. The
reason is that this symmetry is worse in the open heavy meson sector than in
the hidden heavy meson sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03913</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03913</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Houdek</keyname><forenames>G&#xfc;nter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dupret</keyname><forenames>Marc-Antoine</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction Between Convection and Pulsation</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Invited review article for Living Reviews in Solar Physics. 88 pages,
  14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Living Rev. Solar Phys., 12 (2015) 8</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/lrsp-2015-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article reviews our current understanding of modelling convection
dynamics in stars. Several semi-analytical time-dependent convection models
have been proposed for pulsating one-dimensional stellar structures with
different formulations for how the convective turbulent velocity field couples
with the global stellar oscillations. In this review we put emphasis on two,
widely used, time-dependent convection formulations for estimating pulsation
properties in one-dimensional stellar models. Applications to pulsating stars
are presented with results for oscillation properties, such as the effects of
convection dynamics on the oscillation frequencies, or the stability of
pulsation modes, in classical pulsators and in stars supporting solar-type
oscillations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03914</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03914</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Liang-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Wu-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Superfluidity of Spin-Orbit Coupled Bilayer Fermi Gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>34 pages, 5 figures, Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological superfluid, new quantum matter that possesses gapless exotic
excitations known as Majorana fermions, has attracted extensive attention
recently. These excitations, which can encode topological qubits, could be
crucial ingredients for fault-tolerant quantum computation. However, creating
and manipulating multiple Majorana fermions remain an ongoing challenge.
Loading a topologically protected system in multi-layer structures would be a
natural and simple way to achieve this goal. Here we investigate the system of
bilayer Fermi gases with spin-orbit coupling and show that the topological
condition is significantly influenced by the inter-layer tunneling, yielding
two novel topological phases, which support more Majorana Fermions. We
demonstrate the existence of such novel topological phases and associated
multiple Majorana fermions using bilayer Fermi gases trapped inside a harmonic
potential. This research pave a new way for generating multiple Majorana
fermions and would be a significant step towards topological quantum
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03933</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03933</id><created>2015-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Maganti</keyname><forenames>Lakshmi Sirisha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>Purbarun</forenames></author><author><keyname>sundararajan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Sarit K</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle and thermo-hydraulic maldistribution of nanofluids in parallel
  microchannel systems</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>37 pages 16 figures (Manuscript under review)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fluidic maldistribution in microscale multichannel devices requires deep
understanding to achieve optimized flow and heat transfer characteristics. A
thorough computational study has been performed to understand the concentration
and thermohydraulic maldistribution of nanofluids in parallel microchannel
systems using an Eulerian Lagrangian twin phase model. The study reveals that
nanofluids cannot be treated as homogeneous single phase fluids in such complex
flow domains and effective property models fail drastically to predict the
performance parameters. To comprehend the distribution of the particulate
phase, a novel concentration maldistribution factor has been proposed. It has
been observed that distribution of particles need not essentially follow the
flow pattern, leading to higher thermal performance than expected from
homogeneous models. Particle maldistribution has been conclusively shown to be
due to various migration and diffusive phenomena like Stokesian drag, Brownian
motion, thermophoretic drift, etc. The implications of particle distribution on
the cooling performance have been illustrated and smart fluid effects (reduced
magnitude of maximum temperature) have been observed and a mathematical model
to predict the enhanced cooling performance in such flow geometries has been
proposed. The article presents lucidly the effectiveness of discrete phase
approach in modelling nanofluid thermohydraulics and sheds insight on behavior
of nanofluids in complex flow domains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03940</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Geosciences, University of Trieste, Italy and Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author></authors><title>Theory of non-local point transformations - Part 1: Representation of
  Teleparallel Gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the extension of the functional setting customarily adopted in
General Relativity (GR) is considered. For this purpose, an explicit solution
of the so-called Einstein's\ Teleparallel problem is sought. This is achieved
by a suitable extension of the traditional concept of GR reference frame and is
based on the notion of non-local point transformation (NLPT). In particular, it
is shown that a solution to the said problem can be reached by introducing a
suitable subset of transformations denoted here as \textit{special}
\textit{NLPT}. These are found to realize a phase-space transformation
connecting\emph{\}the flat Minkowski space-time with, in principle, an
arbitrary curved space-time. The functional setting and basic properties of the
new transformations are investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03941</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Geosciences, University of Trieste, Italy and Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author></authors><title>Theory of non-local point transformations - Part 2: General form and
  Gedanken experiment</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem is posed of further extending the axiomatic construction proposed
in Part 1 for non-local point transformations mapping in each other different
curved space times. The new transformations apply to curved space times when
expressed in arbitrary coordinate systems. It is shown that the solution
permits to achieve an ideal (Gedanken) experiment realizing a suitable kind of
phase-space transformation on point-particle classical dynamical systems.
Applications of the theory are discussed both for diagonal and non-diagonal
metric tensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03942</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03942</id><created>2016-01-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames><affiliation>Department of Mathematics and Geosciences, University of Trieste, Italy and Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Physics, Faculty of Philosophy and Science, Silesian University in Opava, Bezru&#x10d;ovo n&#xe1;m.13, CZ-74601 Opava, Czech Republic</affiliation></author></authors><title>Theory of non-local point transformations - Part 3: Theory of
  NLPT-acceleration and the physical origin of acceleration effects in curved
  space-times</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is motivated by the introduction of a new functional setting of
General Relativity (GR) based on the adoption of suitable group non-local point
transformations (NLPT). Unlike the customary local point transformatyion
usually utilized in GR, these transformations map in each other intrinsically
different curved space-times. In this paper the problem is posed of determining
the tensor transformation laws holding for the $4-$% acceleration with respect
to the group of general NLPT. Basic physical implications are considered. These
concern in particular the identification of NLPT-acceleration effects, namely
the relationship established via general NLPT between the $4-$accelerations
existing in different curved-space times. As a further application the tensor
character of the EM Faraday tensor.with respect to the NLPT-group is
established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03953</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Siegel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>F-theory with zeroth-quantized ghosts</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages</comments><report-no>YITP-SB-16-2</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  F-theory in its most general sense should be a theory defined on a
worldvolume of higher dimension than the worldsheet, that reproduces string
results perturbatively but includes nonperturbative supergravity solutions at
the first-quantized level. This implies that in some sense it should contain
the same oscillator modes as the string but an enlarged set of zero-modes. In
this paper we concentrate on the higher-dimensional properties of the
worldvolume (rather than those of spacetime): &quot;Ghost&quot; dimensions are added to
the worldvolume, as might be expected in a &quot;zeroth-quantized&quot; approach to the
constraints on its higher bosonic dimensions, by adding equal numbers of
bosonic and fermionic dimensions to the worldsheet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03956</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03956</id><created>2016-01-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Sridip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grinstein</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>Zeno-Gravity Correspondence: Zeno's Dichotomy Paradox and Gravitational
  red-shift near Event Horizon</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We relate Zeno's Dichotomy paradox with gravitational red-shift near event
horizon in a spherically symmetric space-time. A dictionary of this connection,
henceforth called as Zeno-Gravity correspondence, has been built up. The
infinite sequence of Zeno's paradox gets mapped to the effect of infinite
gravitational red-shift near event horizon and the infinite amount of
co-ordinate time the light/particle takes to reach the horizon, starting from a
finite distance away from the horizon. Utilizing the dictionary, we elucidate
the concept of gravitational red-shift and co-ordinate chart, not covering the
whole manifold in a more transparent student-friendly manner without using
sophisticated machinery of differential geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03992</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Schulz-Baldes</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villegas-Blas</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Signatures for $J$-hermitians and $J$-unitaries on Krein spaces with
  Real structures</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>This paper contains and considerably extends the analysis of version
  1 of arXiv:1306.1816. The new version 2 of arXiv:1306.1816 only contains the
  applications</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For $J$-hermitian operators on a Krein space $(\mathcal{K},J)$ satisfying an
adequate Fredholm property, a global Krein signature is shown to be a homotopy
invariant. It is argued that this global signature is a generalization of the
Noether index. When the Krein space has a supplementary Real structure, the
sets of $J$-hermitian Fredholm operators with Real symmetry can be retracted to
certain of the classifying spaces of Atiyah and Singer. Secondary
$\mathbb{Z}_2$-invariants are introduced to label their connected components.
Related invariants are also analyzed for $J$-unitary operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03994</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Cen</forenames></author></authors><title>Automating Predictions for Standard Model Effective Field Theory in
  MadGraph5_aMC@NLO</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures, contribution to appear in the proceedings of the
  12th International Symposium on Radiative Corrections (Radcor 2015) and
  LoopFest XIV</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next-to-leading order event generation for the Standard Model effective field
theory has started to become available in the MadGraph5_aMC@NLO framework. In
this talk we discuss some of the recent progresses in this direction, with a
focus on the top-quark sector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04004</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bashindzhagyan</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korotkova</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractionally charged particles in cosmic rays</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The results of many experiments on a search of fractionally charged particles
in cosmic rays have been reviewed. The registered by ATIC and PAMELA
experiments change of the proton energy spectrum at about 250 GeV can be
explained if fractionally charged particles with another energy spectrum slope
actually mixed with protons but cannot be separated because of a strong dE/dx
fluctuations. The performed simulations show that multilayer detectors can
seriously help in such separation. In the Aragats experiment performed using
multilayer proportional counter combined with hadron calorimeter a group of
4e/3 like events with unexpectedly high average energy has been registered. It
could be explained by their different from regular hadrons energy spectrum. The
ATIC experiment ionization spectrum in single charged particle area has been
examined. An interesting bump in 2e/3 charge region was observed. The events in
the bump have very different from regular protons angular distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04006</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Bisnovatyi-Kogan</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolutions of Neutron Stars and their Magnetic Fields</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>29 pages, 5 figures, Chapter from &quot;Neutron Stars, Supernovae and
  Supernovae Remnants&quot;, Authors: A. Ankay, G. S. Bisnovatyi-Kogan, O. H.
  Guseinov, D. M. Sedrakian, K. M. Shahabasyan, S. O. Tagieva, Dejan Urosevic,
  E. Yazgan. : Nova Sci. Publ. 2007. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:astro-ph/0311031, arXiv:astro-ph/0401086 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Estimations of magnetic fields of neutron stars, observed as radio and X-ray
pulsars, are discussed. It is shown, that theoretical and observational values
for different types of radiopulsars are in good correspondence. Radiopulsars in
close binaries and millisecond pulsars, which have passed the stage of disk
accretion (recycled radiopulsars), have magnetic fields 2-4 orders of magnitude
smaller than ordinary single pulsars. Most probably, the magnetic field of the
neutron star was screened by the infalling material. Several screening models
are considered. Formation of single recycled pulsars loosing its companion is
discussed. Magnetic fields of some X-ray pulsars are estimated from the
cyclotron line energy. In the case of Her X-1 this estimation exceeds
considerably the value of its magnetic field obtained from long term
observational data related to the beam structure evolution. Another
interpretation of the cyclotron feature, based on the relativistic dipole
radiation mechanism, could remove this discrepancy. Observational data about
soft gamma repeaters and their interpretation as magnetars are critically
analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04019</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Dieterle</keyname><forenames>Paul B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalaee</keyname><forenames>Mahmoud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fink</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Painter</keyname><forenames>Oskar</forenames></author></authors><title>Superconducting cavity-electromechanics on silicon-on-insulator</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fabrication processes involving anhydrous hydrofluoric vapor etching are
developed to create high-$Q$ aluminum superconducting microwave resonators on
free-standing silicon membranes formed from a silicon-on-insulator wafer. Using
this fabrication process, a high-impedance $8.9$GHz coil resonator is coupled
capacitively with large participation ratio to a $9.7$MHz micromechanical
resonator. Two-tone microwave spectroscopy and radiation pressure back-action
are used to characterize the coupled system in a dilution refrigerator down to
temperatures of $T_f = 11$~mK, yielding a measured electromechanical vacuum
coupling rate of $g_{0}/2\pi \approx 24.6$~Hz and a mechanical resonator
$Q$-factor of $Q_{m}=1.7\times 10^7$. Microwave back-action cooling of the
mechanical resonator is also studied, with a minimum phonon occupancy of $n_{m}
\approx 16$ phonons being realized at an elevated fridge temperature of $T_f =
211$~mK.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04052</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04052</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Stubbs</keyname><forenames>Christopher W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Yorke J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Precise Astronomical Flux Calibration and its Impact on Studying the
  Nature of Dark Energy</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures. Accepted Modern Physics Letters A</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters A vol 30 number 40 1530030 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S021773231530030X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of the luminosity of type Ia supernovae vs. redshift provided
the original evidence for the accelerating expansion of the Universe and the
existence of dark energy. Despite substantial improvements in survey
methodology, systematic uncertainty in flux calibration dominates the error
budget for this technique, exceeding both statistics and other systematic
uncertainties. Consequently, any further collection of type Ia supernova data
will fail to refine the constraints on the nature of dark energy unless we also
improve the state of the art in astronomical flux calibration to the order of
1%. We describe how these systematic errors arise from calibration of
instrumental sensitivity, atmospheric transmission, and Galactic extinction,
and discuss ongoing efforts to meet the 1% precision challenge using white
dwarf stars as celestial standards, exquisitely calibrated detectors as
fundamental metrologic standards, and real-time atmospheric monitoring.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04056</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>W&#xfc;rger</keyname><forenames>Alois</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Curvature capillary migration of microspheres&quot; by N.
  Sharifi-Mood, I.B. Liu, K.J. Stebe, Soft Matter 11, 6768 (2015),
  arXiv:1502.01672</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>2 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2016, 12, 331</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c5sm01948f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper, Sharifi-Mood et al. study colloidal particles trapped at a
liquid interface with opposite principal curvatures $c_{1}=-c_{2}$. In the
theory part, they claim that the trapping energy vanishes at second order in
$\Delta c=c_{1}-c_{2}$, which would invalidate our previous result [Phys. Rev.
E 74, 041402 (2006)]. Here we show that this claim arises from an improper
treatment of the outer boundary condition on the deformation field. For both
pinned and moving contact lines, we find that the outer boundary is irrelevant,
which confirms our previous work. More generally, we show that the trapping
energy is determined by the deformation close to the particle and does not
depend on the far-field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04057</id><created>2016-01-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Green</keyname><forenames>Avery J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dey</keyname><forenames>Sonal</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Yong Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>Brendan</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Mullane</keyname><forenames>Samuel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiel</keyname><forenames>Bradley</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diebold</keyname><forenames>Alain C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Oxidation of the Topological Insulator Bi2Se3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages text, 1 table and 14 figures separate</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A comprehensive picture of the aging and oxidation of the (0001) surface of
Bi2Se3 is critical to understanding the physical origin of changes in its
topologically protected surface states. We find that surface aging in ambient
conditions occurs in two major steps. Within two hours of exfoliation, a series
of ~ 3.6 A high islands are observed by atomic force microscopy over
approximate 10% of the surface. Subsequently, patch growth stops, and oxidation
begins after the two hours and continues until one quintuple layer has been
oxidized. X-ray photoelectron spectroscopy shows no sign of oxidation before ~
120 minutes of exposure to air, and the oxygen 1s peak is clearly present after
~ 190 minutes of ambient exposure. Variable angle spectroscopic ellipsometry
also indicates that the oxidation of a full quintuple layer occurs on the time
scale of days. These results are in good agreement with the time dependent
changes previously observed in the surface crystal structure by second harmonic
generation. In addition to providing the ability to non-destructively measure
oxide on the surface of Bi2Se3 crystals, ellipsometry can be used to identify
the thickness of Bi2Se3 flakes. These results are consistent with non-linear
optical methods including rotational anisotropy second harmonic generation,
which follow the time dependence of the changes to the top quintuple layer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:nucl-th/0306078</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-18</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>nucl-th/0306078</id><created>2003-06-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Benayoun</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>David</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DelBuono</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leruste</keyname><forenames>Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Connell</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous $\eta/\eta^\prime$ Decays: The Triangle and Box Anomalies</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>47 pages</comments><report-no>LPNHE 03-07, FERMILAB-PUB-03-166</report-no><journal-ref>Eur.Phys.J.C31:525-547,2003</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s2003-01378-x</doi><abstract>  We examine the decay modes $\eta/\etp\ra \pi^+ \pi^- \gamma$ within the
context of the Hidden Local Symmetry (HLS) Model. Using numerical information
derived in previous fits to $VP\gamma$ and $Ve^+e^-$ decay modes in isolation
and the $\rho$ lineshape determined in a previous fit to the pion form factor,
we show that all aspects of these decays can be predicted with fair accuracy.
Freeing some parameters does not improve the picture. This is interpreted as a
strong evidence in favor of the box anomaly in the $\eta/\etp$ decays, which
occurs at precisely the level expected. We also construct the set of equations
defining the amplitudes for $\eta/\etp\ra \pi^+ \pi^- \gamma$ and $ \eta/\etp
\ra \ggam $ at the chiral limit, as predicted from the anomalous HLS Lagrangian
appropriately broken. This provides a set of four equations depending on only
one parameter, instead of three for the traditional set. This is also shown to
match the (two--angle, two--decay--constant) $\eta-\etp$ mixing scheme recently
proposed and is also fairly well fulfilled by the data. The information
returned from fits also matches expectations from previously published fits to
the $VP\gamma$ decay modes in isolation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
