<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:15:53Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-05-30" from="2016-05-29" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0902.1299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0902.1299</id><created>2009-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hirotada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gall</keyname><forenames>Francois Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roetteler</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Perfect Quantum Network Communication Protocol Based on Classical
  Network Coding</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>LaTeX2e, 10 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings 2010 IEEE International Symposium on Information
  Theory (ISIT 2010), pp. 2686-2690</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ISIT.2010.5513644</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper considers a problem of quantum communication between parties that
are connected through a network of quantum channels. The model in this paper
assumes that there is no prior entanglement shared among any of the parties,
but that classical communication is free. The task is to perfectly transfer an
unknown quantum state from a source subsystem to a target subsystem, where both
source and target are formed by ordered sets of some of the nodes. It is proved
that a lower bound of the rate at which this quantum communication task is
possible is given by the classical min-cut max-flow theorem of network coding,
where the capacities in question are the quantum capacities of the edges of the
network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0908.1457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0908.1457</id><created>2009-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hirotada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gall</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roetteler</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>General Scheme for Perfect Quantum Network Coding with Free Classical
  Communication</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures, generalizes some of the results in
  arXiv:0902.1299 to the k-pair problem and codes over rings. Appeared in the
  Proceedings of the 36th International Colloquium on Automata, Languages and
  Programming (ICALP'09), LNCS 5555, pp. 622-633, 2009</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the 36th International Colloquium on Automata,
  Languages and Programming (ICALP'09), LNCS 5555, pp. 622-633, 2009</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-642-02927-1_52</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper considers the problem of efficiently transmitting quantum states
through a network. It has been known for some time that without additional
assumptions it is impossible to achieve this task perfectly in general --
indeed, it is impossible even for the simple butterfly network. As additional
resource we allow free classical communication between any pair of network
nodes. It is shown that perfect quantum network coding is achievable in this
model whenever classical network coding is possible over the same network when
replacing all quantum capacities by classical capacities. More precisely, it is
proved that perfect quantum network coding using free classical communication
is possible over a network with $k$ source-target pairs if there exists a
classical linear (or even vector linear) coding scheme over a finite ring. Our
proof is constructive in that we give explicit quantum coding operations for
each network node. This paper also gives an upper bound on the number of
classical communication required in terms of $k$, the maximal fan-in of any
network node, and the size of the network.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1012.4583</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1012.4583</id><created>2010-12-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>Hirotada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gall</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Harumichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roetteler</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Constructing Quantum Network Coding Schemes from Classical Nonlinear
  Protocols</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings 2011 IEEE International Symposium on Information
  Theory (ISIT 2011), pp. 109-113</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/ISIT.2011.6033701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The k-pair problem in network coding theory asks to send k messages
simultaneously between k source-target pairs over a directed acyclic graph. In
a previous paper [ICALP 2009, Part I, pages 622--633] the present authors
showed that if a classical k-pair problem is solvable by means of a linear
coding scheme, then the quantum k-pair problem over the same graph is also
solvable, provided that classical communication can be sent for free between
any pair of nodes of the graph. Here we address the main case that remained
open in our previous work, namely whether nonlinear classical network coding
schemes can also give rise to quantum network coding schemes. This question is
motivated by the fact that there are networks for which there are no linear
solutions to the k-pair problem, whereas nonlinear solutions exist. In the
present paper we overcome the limitation to linear protocols and describe a new
communication protocol for perfect quantum network coding that improves over
the previous one as follows: (i) the new protocol does not put any condition on
the underlying classical coding scheme, that is, it can simulate nonlinear
communication protocols as well, and (ii) the amount of classical communication
sent in the protocol is significantly reduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1106.0832</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1106.0832</id><created>2011-06-04</created><updated>2014-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kupervasser</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames></author></authors><title>Laplacian Growth II: Saffman - Taylor Problem Without Surface Tension in
  Filtration Combustion: Formation of One Finger with Half of the Channel Width</title><categories>nlin.CD nlin.PS</categories><comments>19 pages, 3 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:nlin/0306038</comments><msc-class>37C99</msc-class><journal-ref>Complexity, Vol. 21, Is. 5, pp. 31-42, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/cplx.21627</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Filtration combustion is described by Laplacian growth without surface
tension. These equations have elegant analytical solutions that replace the
complex integro-differential motion equations by simple differential equations
of pole motion in a complex plane. The main problem with such a solution is the
existence of finite time singularities. To prevent such singularities, nonzero
surface tension is usually used.However, nonzero surface tension does not exist
in filtration combustion, and this destroys the analytical solutions. However,
a more elegant approach exists for solving the problem. First, we can introduce
a small amount of pole noise to the system. Second, for regularisation of the
problem, we throw out all new poles that can produce a finite time singularity.
It can be strictly proved that the asymptotic solution for such a system is a
single finger. Moreover, the qualitative consideration demonstrates that a
finger with 1/2 of the channel width is statistically stable. Therefore, all
properties of such a solution are exactly the same as those of the solution
with nonzero surface tension under numerical noise. The solution of the ST
problem without surface tension is similar to the solution for the equation of
cellular flames in the case of the combustion of gas mixtures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.0104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.0104</id><created>2011-10-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Ben-Bassat</keyname><forenames>Oren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasparim</keyname><forenames>Elizabeth</forenames></author></authors><title>Moduli Stacks of Bundles on Local Surfaces</title><categories>math.AG hep-th</categories><comments>submitted upon invitation to the 2011 Mirror Symmetry and Tropical
  Geometry Conference (Cetraro, Italy) volume of the Springer Lecture Notes in
  Mathematics</comments><msc-class>14D20, 14H60, 14J60, 14D23</msc-class><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-06514-4_1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give an explicit groupoid presentation of certain stacks of vector bundles
on formal neighborhoods of rational curves inside algebraic surfaces. The
presentation involves a M\&quot;obius type action of an automorphism group on a
space of extensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1203.4247</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1203.4247</id><created>2012-03-19</created><updated>2012-03-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe1;lsson</keyname><forenames>Gunnar K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xe4;lde</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amft</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yuanyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahlberg</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pundt</keyname><forenames>Astrid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hj&#xf6;rvarsson</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rgvin</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrogen site occupancy and strength of forces in nano-sized metal
  hydrides</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.85.195407</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dipole force components in nano-sized metal hydrides are quantitatively
determined with curvature and x-ray diffraction measurements. Ab-initio density
functional theory is used to calculate the dipole components and the symmetry
of the strain field. The hydrogen occupancy in a 100 nm thick V film is shown
to be tetrahedral with a slight asymmetry at low concentration and a transition
to octahedral occupancy is shown to take place at around 0.07 [H/V] at 360 K.
When the thickness of the V layer is reduced to 3 nm and biaxially strained, in
a Fe_0.5V_0.5/V superlattice, the hydrogen unequivocally occupies octahedral
z-like sites, even at and below concentrations of 0.02 [H/V].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1209.1504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1209.1504</id><created>2012-09-07</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Emary</keyname><forenames>Clive</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gernert</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klapp</keyname><forenames>Sabine H. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A minimal model for short-time diffusion in periodic potentials</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 86, 061135 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.86.061135</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the dynamics of a single, overdamped colloidal particle, which
is driven by a constant force through a one-dimensional periodic potential. We
focus on systems with large barrier heights where the lowest-order cumulants of
the density field, that is, average position and the mean-squared displacement,
show nontrivial (non-diffusive) short-time behavior characterized by the
appearance of plateaus. We demonstrate that this &quot;cage-like&quot; dynamics can be
well described by a discretized master equation model involving two states
(related to two positions) within each potential valley. Non-trivial
predictions of our approach include analytic expressions for the plateau
heights and an estimate of the &quot;de-caging time&quot; obtained from the study of
deviations from Gaussian behaviour. The simplicity of our approach means that
it offers a minimal model to describe the short-time behavior of systems with
hindered dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.3784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.3784</id><created>2012-10-14</created><updated>2012-10-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Surnis</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLaughlin</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gajjar</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of an Intermittent Pulsar: PSR J1839+15</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures. To appear in the proceedings of IAU Symposium
  291: Neutron Stars and Pulsars: Challenges and Opportunities after 80 years</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the International Astronomical Union / Volume 8 /
  Symposium S291 / August 2012, pp 508-510</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S1743921312024684</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the discovery of a new pulsar PSR J1839+15, having a period of 549
ms and a DM of 68 pc-cm^-3. We also present its timing solution and report the
intermittent behaviour of its radio emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.8638</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.8638</id><created>2013-10-31</created><updated>2013-12-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bray</keyname><forenames>Hubert L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jauregui</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time flat surfaces and the monotonicity of the spacetime Hawking mass</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages; sign error fixed from previous version, statement of
  Theorem 1.1 changed accordingly</comments><msc-class>53C20 (Primary), 83C99 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys., Vol. 335, No. 1 (2015), pp. 285-307</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-014-2162-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We identify a condition on spacelike 2-surfaces in a spacetime that is
relevant to understanding the concept of mass in general relativity. We prove a
formula for the variation of the spacetime Hawking mass under a uniformly area
expanding flow and show that it is nonnegative for these so-called &quot;time flat
surfaces.&quot; Such flows generalize inverse mean curvature flow, which was used by
Huisken and Ilmanen to prove the Riemannian Penrose inequality for one black
hole. A flow of time flat surfaces may have connections to the problem in
general relativity of bounding the mass of a spacetime from below by the
quasi-local mass of a spacelike 2-surface contained therein.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.6604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.6604</id><created>2014-02-26</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Santoyo</keyname><forenames>Miguel A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Garz&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Patricia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Jerez</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luz&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface Dynamic Deformation Estimates from Local Seismicity: the Itoiz
  Reservoir, Spain</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the ground motion time histories due to the local seismicity near
the Itoiz reservoir to estimate the near-source, surface 3D
displacement-gradients and dynamic deformations. The seismic data were obtained
by a semi-permanent broadband and accelerometric network located on surface and
at underground sites. The dynamic deformation field was calculated by two
different methodologies. First, by the Seismo-Geodetic method using the data
from a three-station micro-array located close to the dam; second, by
Single-Station estimates of the displacement gradients. The dynamic
deformations obtained from both methods were compared and analyzed in the
context of the local free-field effects. The shallow 1D velocity structure was
estimated from the seismic data by modeling the body wave travel times. Time
histories obtained from both methods results quite similar in the time-window
of body-wave arrivals. The strain misfits between methods vary from 1.4% to
35.0% and rotational misfits vary from 2.5% to 36.0%. Amplitudes of
displacement gradients vary in the range of 10-8 to 10-7 strains. From these
results, a new scaling analysis by numerical modeling is proposed in order to
estimate the peak dynamic deformations for different magnitudes, up to the
expected maximum MW in the region (M5.5). Peak dynamic deformations due to
local MW5.5 earthquakes would reach amplitudes of 10-5 strain and 10-3 radians
at the Itoiz dam. The Single-Station method shows to be an adequate option for
the analysis of local seismicity, where few three-component stations are
available. The results obtained here could help to extend the applicability of
these methodologies to other sites of engineering interest.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1495</id><created>2014-03-06</created><updated>2014-07-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sobk&#xf3;w</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Theoretical Physics, University of Wroclaw, Poland</affiliation></author></authors><title>Right-handed chirality of muon neutrinos in polarized muon decay at rest</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, 1 table. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1102.1331 (unpublished)</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 74, 2997 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-014-2997-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we analyze the polarized muon decay at rest (PMDaR) admitting
the non-standard V+A interaction in addition to the standard V-A interaction.
We show that the angle-energy distribution of Dirac muon neutrinos is sensitive
to the interference terms between the standard V-A coupling of left-chirality
muon neutrino and exotic V+A coupling of right-chirality one, which are
proportional to the transverse components of muon neutrino spin polarization.
The interferences do not vanish in a massless limit and include the relative
phases to test the CP violation (CPV). It allows to calculate a neutrino flux
for an assumed configuration of detector in the case of SM prediction, and the
upper limits on the neutrino flux for the left-right muon neutrino mixture. We
also demonstrate that the effects of neutrino mass and mixing are tiny
corrections and can be omitted. The most important conclusion is that even in
the massless limit, there are physical effects connected with the mixture of
left- and right-handed helicity components in a spin 1/2 quantum state, when
exotic interaction V+A is admitted contrary to the electron observables, where
all the possible interferences vanish.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.6441</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.6441</id><created>2014-06-24</created><updated>2014-11-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smerlak</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of inequalities: from precariousness to economic
  stratification</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech q-fin.EC</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 441, 40-50 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2015.09.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Growing economic inequalities are observed in several countries throughout
the world. Following Pareto, the power-law structure of these inequalities has
been the subject of much theoretical and empirical work. But their
nonequilibrium dynamics, e.g. after a policy change, remains incompletely
understood. Here we introduce a thermodynamical theory of inequalities based on
the analogy between economic stratification and statistical entropy. Within
this framework we identify the combination of upward mobility with
precariousness as a fundamental driver of inequality. We formalize this
statement by a &quot;second-law&quot; inequality displaying upward mobility and
precariousness as thermodynamic conjugate variables. We estimate the time scale
for the &quot;relaxation&quot; of the wealth distribution after a sudden change of the
after-tax return on capital. Our method can be generalized to gain insight into
the dynamics of inequalities in any Markovian model of socioeconomic
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1407.5936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1407.5936</id><created>2014-07-22</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zlotnikov</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Sub-sub-leading soft-graviton theorem in arbitrary dimension</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>References added, 19 pages, published version</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2014)148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CHY formula which describes an $n$-point tree level scattering amplitude
for scalars, gluons or gravitons in arbitrary dimension [22], is used to prove
the sub-sub-leading soft- graviton theorem recently proposed by Cachazo and
Strominger [13].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.6682</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.6682</id><created>2014-10-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>SQUID-based Resonant Detection of Axion Dark Matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Experimental and Theoretical Physics 122 (2), pp.
  236-242 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063776116020114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new method for searching for Dark Matter axions is proposed. It is shown
that a two-contact SQUID can detect oscillating magnetic perturbations induced
by the axions in a strong inhomogeneous magnetic field. A resonant signal is a
steplike response in the SQUID current-voltage characteristic at a voltage
corresponding to the axion mass with a height depending on the axion energy
density near the Earth. The proposed experimental technique appears to be
sensitive to the axions with masses $m_a\lesssim 10^{-4}$ eV, which is
well-motivated by current researches both in cosmology and in particle physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02006</id><created>2015-03-04</created><updated>2015-03-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Shuang-ren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Kang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xingang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xintie</forenames></author></authors><title>The modified Poynting theorem and the concept of mutual energy</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Derivation of the mutual energy theorem from Fourier domain is added.
  Time-reversed transform, time-reversed mutual energy theorem, time reversed
  reciprocity theorem, mixed mutual energy theorem are added, Complementary
  theorems are added</comments><msc-class>83C50</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The goal of this article is to derive the reciprocity theorem, mutual energy
theorem from Poynting theorem instead of from Maxwell equation. The Poynting
theorem is generalized to the modified Poynting theorem. In the modified
Poynting theorem the electromagnetic field is superimposition of different
electromagnetic fields including the retarded potential and advanced potential,
time-offset field. The media epsilon (permittivity) and mu (permeability) can
also be different in the different fields. The concept of mutual energy is
introduced which is the difference between the total energy and self-energy.
Mixed mutual energy theorem is derived. We derive the mutual energy from
Fourier domain. We obtain the time-reversed mutual energy theorem and the
mutual energy theorem. Then we derive the mutual energy theorem in time-domain.
The instantaneous modified mutual energy theorem is derived. Applying
time-offset transform and time integral to the instantaneous modified mutual
energy theorem, the time-correlation modified mutual energy theorem is
obtained. Assume there are two electromagnetic fields one is retarded potential
and one is advanced potential, the convolution reciprocity theorem can be
derived. Corresponding to the modified time-correlation mutual energy theorem
and the time-convolution reciprocity theorem in Fourier domain, there is the
modified mutual energy theorem and the Lorentz reciprocity theorem. Hence all
mutual energy theorem and the reciprocity theorems are put in one frame of the
concept of the mutual energy. 3 new Complementary theorems are derived. The
inner product is introduced for two different electromagnetic fields in both
time domain and Fourier domain for the application of the wave expansion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.00256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.00256</id><created>2015-04-01</created><updated>2015-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Characterization of Extended Quantum Ising Models</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 177204 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.177204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a class of exactly solvable quantum Ising models, including the
transverse-field Ising model and anisotropic XY model, can be characterized as
the loops in a two-dimensional auxiliary space. The transverse-field Ising
model corresponds to a circle and the XY model corresponds to an ellipse, while
other models yield cardioid, limacon, hypocycloid, and Lissajous curves etc. It
is shown that the variation of the ground state energy density, which is a
function of the loop, experiences a nonanalytical point when the winding number
of the corresponding loop changes. The winding number can serve as a
topological quantum number of the quantum phases in the extended quantum Ising
model, which sheds some light upon the relation between quantum phase
transition and the geometrical order parameter characterizing the phase
diagram.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.01694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.01694</id><created>2015-04-07</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gro&#xdf;mann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peruani</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;r</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>A geometric approach to self-propelled motion in isotropic and
  anisotropic environments</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, published in EPJ-ST</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J.: Spec. Top. 224 (2015) 1377-1394</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjst/e2015-02465-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a geometric perspective to describe the motion of self-propelled
particles moving at constant speed in d dimensions. We exploit the fact that
the vector that conveys the direction of motion of the particle performs a
random walk on a $(d-1)$-dimensional manifold. We show that the particle
performs isotropic diffusion in d-dimensions if the manifold corresponds to a
hypersphere. In contrast, we find that the self-propelled particle exhibits
anisotropic diffusion if this manifold corresponds to a deformed hypersphere
(e.g. an ellipsoid). This simple approach provides an unified framework to deal
with isotropic as well as anisotropic diffusion of particles moving at constant
speed in any dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03167</id><created>2015-04-13</created><authors><author><keyname>S&#xe1;ndor</keyname><forenames>Bulcs&#xfa;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gros</keyname><forenames>Claudius</forenames></author></authors><title>A versatile class of prototype dynamical systems for complex bifurcation
  cascades of limit cycles</title><categories>physics.comp-ph nlin.CD</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 5, 12316 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep12316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a versatile class of prototype dynamical systems for the study
of complex bifurcation cascades of limit cycles, including bifurcations
breaking spontaneously a symmetry of the system, period doubling bifurcations
and transitions to chaos induced by sequences of limit cycle bifurcations. The
prototype system consist of a $2d$-dimensional dynamical system with friction
forces $f(V(\mathbf{x}))$ functionally dependent exclusively on the mechanical
potential $V(\mathbf{x})$, which is typically characterized, here, by a finite
number of local minima. We present examples for $d=1,2$ and simple polynomial
friction forces $f(V)$, where the zeros of $f(V)$ regulate the relative
importance of energy uptake and dissipation respectively, serving as
bifurcation parameters. Starting from simple Hopf- and homoclinic bifurcations,
complex sequences of limit cycle bifurcation are observed when energy uptake
gains progressively in importance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00035</id><created>2015-04-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Hockett</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wollenhaupt</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumert</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherent Control of Photoelectron Wavepacket Angular Interferograms</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 48, 214004 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/48/21/214004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coherent control over photoelectron wavepackets, via the use of
polarization-shaped laser pulses, can be understood as a time and
polarization-multiplexed process. In this work, we investigate this
multiplexing via computation of the observable photoelectron angular
interferograms resulting from multi-photon atomic ionization with
polarization-shaped laser pulses. We consider the polarization sensitivity of
both the instantaneous and cumulative continuum wavefunction; the nature of the
coherent control over the resultant photoelectron interferogram is thus
explored in detail. Based on this understanding, the use of coherent control
with polarization-shaped pulses as a methodology for a highly multiplexed
coherent quantum metrology is also investigated, and defined in terms of the
information content of the observable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03393</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03393</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Yijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sykes</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burdick</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bohn</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lev</keyname><forenames>Benjamin L.</forenames></author></authors><title>s-wave scattering lengths of the strongly dipolar bosons $^{162}$Dy and
  $^{164}$Dy</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>corrected a typo in the value of the 162Dy scattering length</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 022703 (2015); erratum: Phys. Rev. A 93,
  059905(E) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.022703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the measurement of the triplet s-partial-wave scattering length $a$
of two bosonic isotopes of the highly magnetic element, dysprosium:
$a=122(10)a_0$ for $^{162}$Dy and $a=92(8)a_0$ for $^{164}$Dy, where $a_0$ is
the Bohr radius. The scattering lengths are determined by the cross-dimensional
relaxation of ultracold gases of these Dy isotopes at temperatures above
quantum degeneracy. In this temperature regime, the measured rethermalization
dynamics can be compared to simulations of the Boltzmann equation using a
direct-simulation Monte Carlo (DSMC) method employing the anisotropic
differential scattering cross section of dipolar particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.02540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.02540</id><created>2015-07-09</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asadian</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdi</keyname><forenames>Mehdi</forenames></author></authors><title>Heralded entangled coherent states between spatially separated massive
  resonators</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 052315 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.052315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We put forward an experimentally feasible scheme for heralded entanglement
generation between two distant macroscopic mechanical resonators. The protocol
exploits a hybrid quantum device, a qubit interacting with a mechanical
resonator as well as a cavity mode, for each party. The cavity modes interfere
on a beam-splitter followed by suitable heralding detections which post-select
a hybrid entangled state with success probability 1/2. Subsequently, by local
measurements on the qubits a mechanical entangled coherent state can be
achieved. The mechanical entanglement can be further verified via monitoring
the entanglement of the qubit pair. The setup is envisioned as a test bench for
sensing gravitational effects on the quantum dynamics of gravitationally
coupled massive objects. As a concrete example, we illustrate the
implementation of our protocol using the current circuit QED architectures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06212</id><created>2015-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wubs</keyname><forenames>Martijn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vos</keyname><forenames>Willem L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Foerster resonance energy transfer rate and local density of optical
  states are uncorrelated in any dielectric nanophotonic medium</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 053037 ( 2016 )</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/5/053037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the ongoing debate about nanophotonic control of Foerster
resonance energy transfer (FRET), notably by the local density of optical
states (LDOS), we study an analytic model system wherein a pair of ideal dipole
emitters - donor and acceptor - exhibit energy transfer in the vicinity of an
ideal mirror. The FRET rate is controlled by the mirror up to distances
comparable to the donor-acceptor distance, that is, the few-nanometer range.
For vanishing distance, we find a complete inhibition or a four-fold
enhancement, depending on dipole orientation. For mirror distances on the
wavelength scale, where the well-known `Drexhage' modification of the
spontaneous-emission rate occurs, the FRET rate is constant. Hence there is no
correlation between the Foerster (or total) energy transfer rate and the LDOS.
At any distance to the mirror, the total energy transfer between a
closely-spaced donor and acceptor is dominated by Foerster transfer, i.e., by
the static dipole-dipole interaction that yields the characteristic
inverse-sixth-power donor-acceptor distance dependence in homogeneous media.
Generalizing to arbitrary inhomogeneous media with weak dispersion and weak
absorption in the frequency overlap range of donor and acceptor, we derive two
main theoretical results. Firstly, the spatially dependent Foerster energy
transfer rate does not depend on frequency, hence not on the LDOS. Secondly the
FRET rate is expressed as a frequency integral of the imaginary part of the
Green function. This leads to an approximate FRET rate in terms of the LDOS
integrated over a huge bandwidth from zero frequency to about 10 times the
donor emission frequency, corresponding to the vacuum-ultraviolet. Even then,
the broadband LDOS hardly contributes to the energy transfer rates. We discuss
practical consequences including quantum information processing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00554</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>Jose Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Congkao</forenames></author></authors><title>Instanton corrections to the effective action of N=4 SYM</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 2 figures; v2: 26 pages, 2 figures, typos corrected, match
  the published version; v3: eq.(5.14) corrected</comments><report-no>ROM2F/2015/11</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1511 (2015) 006</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the one-instanton effective action of N=4 super Yang-Mills theory
with gauge group Sp(2N). The result can be written in a very compact and
manifestly supersymmetric form involving an integral over the superspace of an
irrational function of the N=4 on-shell superfields. In the Coulomb branch, the
instanton corrects both the MHV and next-to-next-MHV higher derivative terms
D^4F^{2n+2} and F^{2n+4}. We confirm at the non-perturbative level the
non-renormalization theorems for MHV F^{2n+2} terms that are expected to
receive perturbative corrections only at n-loops. We compute also the one and
two-loop corrections to the D^4F^4 term and show that its completion under
SL(2,Z) duality is consistent with the one-instanton results of U(2) gauge
group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05771</id><created>2015-09-18</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Choudhury</keyname><forenames>Arghya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalska</keyname><forenames>Kamila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roszkowski</keyname><forenames>Leszek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sessolo</keyname><forenames>Enrico Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Less-simplified models of dark matter for direct detection and the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>29 pages, 9 figures. Text matches published version. References added</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1604 (2016) 182</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)182</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct models of dark matter with suppressed spin-independent
scattering cross section utilizing the existing simplified model framework.
Even simple combinations of simplified models can exhibit interference effects
that cause the tree level contribution to the scattering cross section to
vanish, thus demonstrating that direct detection limits on simplified models
are not robust when embedded in a more complicated and realistic framework. In
general for fermionic WIMP masses &gt;10 GeV direct detection limits on the
spin-independent scattering cross section are much stronger than those coming
from the LHC. However these model combinations, which we call less-simplified
models, represent situations where LHC searches become more competitive than
direct detection experiments even for moderate dark matter mass. We show that a
complementary use of several searches at the LHC can strongly constrain the
direct detection blind spots by setting limits on the coupling constants and
mediators' mass. We derive the strongest limits for combinations of vector +
scalar, vector + &quot;squark&quot;, and &quot;squark&quot; + scalar mediator, and present the
corresponding projections for the LHC 14 TeV for a number of searches:
mono-jet, jets + missing energy, and searches for heavy vector resonances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08475</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2015-10-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Shamik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Arpan</forenames></author></authors><title>RG Flow and Thermodynamics of Causal Horizons in Higher-Derivative AdS
  Gravity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>30 pages, Latex, Three figures, Includes a short review of
  arXiv:1508.01343 [hep-th], references added, more discussion on c-theorem in
  the presence of non-minimal matter coupling</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1605 (2016) 126</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2016)126</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In arXiv:1508.01343 [hep-th], one of the authors proposed that in AdS/CFT the
gravity dual of the boundary $c$-theorem is the second law of thermodynamics
satisfied by causal horizons in AdS and this was verified for Einstein gravity
in the bulk. In this paper we verify this for higher derivative theories. We
pick up theories for which an entropy expression satisfying the second law
exists and show that the entropy density evaluated on the causal horizon in a
RG flow geometry is a holographic c-function. We also prove that given a theory
of gravity described by a local covariant action in the bulk a sufficient
condition to ensure holographic c-theorem is that the second law of causal
horizon thermodynamics be satisfied by the theory. This allows us to explicitly
construct holographic c-function in a theory where there is curvature coupling
between gravity and matter and standard null energy condition cannot be defined
although second law is known to hold. Based on the duality between c-theorem
and the second law of causal horizon thermodynamics proposed in
arXiv:1508.01343 [hep-th] and the supporting calculations of this paper we
conjecture that every Unitary higher derivative theory of gravity in AdS
satisfies the second law of causal horizon thermodynamics. If this is not true
then c-theorem will be violated in a unitary Lorentz invariant field theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03894</id><created>2015-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sobk&#xf3;w</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Theoretical Physics, University of Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland</affiliation></author><author><keyname>B&#x142;aut</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Institute of Theoretical Physics, University of Wroc&#x142;aw, Poland</affiliation></author></authors><title>Azimuthal asymmetry of recoil electrons in neutrino-electron elastic
  scattering as signature of neutrino nature</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76, 257 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4077-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we show how a presence of the exotic scalar, tensor weak
interactions in addition to the standard vector-axial (V-A) one may help to
distinguish the Dirac from Majorana neutrinos in the elastic scattering of
(anti)neutrino beam off the unpolarized electrons in the limit of vanishing
(anti)neutrino mass. We assume that the incoming (anti)neutrino beam comes from
the polarized muon decay at rest and is the left-right chiral mixture with
assigned direction of the transversal spin polarization with respect to the
production plane. We display that the azimuthal asymmetry in the angular
distribution of recoil electrons is generated by the interference terms between
the standard and exotic couplings, which are proportional to the transversal
(anti)neutrino spin polarization and independent of the neutrino mass. This
asymmetry for the Majorana neutrinos is distinct from the one for the Dirac
neutrinos through the absence of interference between the standard and tensor
couplings. Additionally, the interference term between the standard and scalar
coupling of the only left chiral neutrinos, absent in the Dirac case, appears.
We also indicate the possibility of utilizing the azimuthal asymmetry
measurements to search for the new CP-violating phases. Our analysis is
model-independent and consistent with the current upper limits on the
non-standard couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05468</id><created>2015-10-19</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Coecke</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kissinger</keyname><forenames>Aleks</forenames></author></authors><title>Categorical Quantum Mechanics I: Causal Quantum Processes</title><categories>quant-ph math.CT</categories><comments>42 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the category-theoretic backbone of quantum theory from a process
ontology. More specifically, we treat quantum theory as a theory of systems,
processes and their interactions.
  In this first part of a three-part overview, we first present a general
theory of diagrams, and in particular, of string diagrams. We discuss why
diagrams are a very natural starting point for developing scientific theories.
Then we define process theories, and define a very general notion of quantum
type. We show how our process ontology enables us to assert causality, that is,
compatibility of quantum theory and relativity theory, and we prove the
no-signalling theorem.
  Other notable contributions include new, elegant derivations of the
no-broadcasting theorem, unitarity of evolution, and Stinespring dilation, all
for any 'quantum' type in a general class of process theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08961</id><created>2015-10-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jingzhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yiou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tse</keyname><forenames>Kinfai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Bei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Junyi</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface energy calculations from Zinc blende (111)/(-1-1-1) to Wurtzite
  (0001)/(000-1):a study of ZnO and GaN</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>14 pages,5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 119, 205302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4952395</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The accurate absolute surface energies of (0001)/(000-1) surfaces of wurtzite
structures are crucial in determining the thin film growth mode of important
energy materials. However, the surface energies still remain to be solved due
to the intrinsic difficulty of calculating dangling bond energy of
asymmetrically bonded surface atoms. In this study, we used a pseudo-hydrogen
passivation method to estimate the dangling bond energy and calculate the polar
surfaces of ZnO and GaN. The calculations were based on the pseudo chemical
potentials obtained from a set of tetrahedral clusters or simple
pseudo-molecules, using density functional theory approaches. And the surface
energies of (0001)/(000-1) surfaces of wurtzite ZnO and GaN we obtained showed
relatively high self-consistencies. A wedge structure calculation with a new
bottom surface passivation scheme of group I and group VII elements was also
proposed and performed to show converged absolute surface energy of wurtzite
ZnO polar surfaces, and the result were also compared with the above method.
These calculations and comparisons may provide important insights to crystal
growths of the above materials, thereby leading to significant performance
enhancements of semiconductor devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00484</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00484</id><created>2015-11-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Chabab</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batoul</keyname><forenames>A. El</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oulne</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Closed analytical solutions of the d-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger equation
  with deformed Woods-Saxon potential plus double ring-shaped potential</title><categories>nucl-th math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, Latex, accepted in Zeitschrift f\&quot;ur Naturforschung A
  (ZNA), 2015</comments><journal-ref>Zeitschrift fur Naturforschung A, Volume 71, Issue 1 (2016) 59</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/zna-2015-0136</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By employing the Pekeris approximation, the D-dimensional Schr\&quot;odinger
equation is solved for the nuclear deformed Woods-Saxon potential plus double
ring-shaped potential within the framework of the Asymptotic Iteration Method
(AIM). The energy eingenvalues are given in a closed form and the corresponding
normalized eigenfunctions are obtained in terms of hypergeometric functions.
Our general results reproduce many predictions obtained in the literature,
using the Nikiforov-Uvarov method (NU) and the Improved Quantization Rule
approach, particulary those derived by considering Woods-Saxon potential
without deformation and/or without ring shape interaction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03516</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dzhafarov</keyname><forenames>Ehtibar N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kujala</keyname><forenames>Janne V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Context-Content Systems of Random Variables: The
  Contextuality-by-Default Theory</title><categories>math.PR quant-ph</categories><comments>to be published in Journal of Mathematical Psychology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper provides a systematic yet accessible presentation of the
Contextuality-by-Default theory. The consideration is confined to finite
systems of categorical random variables, which allows us to focus on the basics
of the theory without using full-scale measure-theoretic language.
Contextuality-by-Default is a theory of random variables identified by their
contents and their contexts, so that two variables have a joint distribution if
and only if they share a context. Intuitively, the content of a random variable
is the entity the random variable measures or responds to, while the context is
formed by the conditions under which these measurements or responses are
obtained. A system of random variables consists of stochastically unrelated
&quot;bunches,&quot; each of which is a set of jointly distributed random variables
sharing a context. The variables that have the same content in different
contexts form &quot;connections&quot; between the bunches. A probabilistic coupling of
this system is a set of random variables obtained by imposing a joint
distribution on the stochastically unrelated bunches. A system is considered
noncontextual or contextual according to whether it can or cannot be coupled so
that the joint distributions imposed on its connections possess a certain
property (in the present version of the theory, &quot;maximality&quot;). We present a
criterion of contextuality for a special class of systems of random variables,
called cyclic systems. We also introduce a general measure of contextuality
that makes use of (quasi-)couplings whose distributions may involve negative
numbers or numbers greater than 1 in place of probabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04365</id><created>2015-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Braghin</keyname><forenames>Fabio L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher order effective interactions and effective bosonized model for
  2-N particle states</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>Contribution to the Proceedings of the 21st International Conference
  on the Few Body Problem in Physics, Chicago, May 2015</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 113, 05018 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201611305018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, an effective fermion model with particular higher order
interactions given by: $I_{II} = \sum_n^N g_{2^n} (\bar{\psi}_a \psi_a)^{2^n}$,
for finite $N$, is investigated by means of the auxiliary field method by
taking into account 2$n$-particle states as proposed in Ref. [1]. The bosonized
model was found to exhibit an approximate symmetry when expanded for weak field
fluctuations around the mean field solutions. In the present work, the role of
the mean field solutions for the corresponding auxiliary fields is
investigated. With the integration of fermions, the resulting determinant is
expanded in a polynomial boson model in the weak field approximation and the
approximate symmetry found for this series does not appear if the boson mean
fields are set to zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04542</id><created>2015-11-14</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gro&#xdf;mann</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peruani</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#xe4;r</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion properties of active particles with directional reversal</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures; published in New Journal of Physics</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 043009</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/4/043009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The diffusion properties of self-propelled particles which move at constant
speed and, in addition, reverse their direction of motion repeatedly are
investigated. The internal dynamics of particles triggering these reversal
processes is modeled by a stochastic clock. The velocity correlation function
as well as the mean squared displacement is investigated and, furthermore, a
general expression for the diffusion coefficient for self-propelled particles
with directional reversal is derived. Our analysis reveals the existence of an
optimal, finite rotational noise amplitude which maximizes the diffusion
coefficient. We comment on the relevance of these results with regard to
microbiological systems and suggest further experiments in this context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07677</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07677</id><created>2015-11-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Wohlbrandt</keyname><forenames>Attila</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weckm&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;rin</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>A robust extension to the triple plane pressure mode matching method by
  filtering convective perturbations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cs.CE</categories><comments>Accepted 15-05-11 by International Journal of Aeroacoustics to be
  published in the special issue focusing on turbomachinery aeroacoustics</comments><doi>10.1177/1475472X16630842</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Time-periodic CFD simulations are widely used to investigate turbomachinery
components. The triple-plane pressure mode matching method (TPP) developed by
Ovenden and Rienstra extracts the acoustic part in such simulations. Experience
shows that this method is subject to significant errors when the amplitude of
pseudo-sound is high compared to sound. Pseudo-sound are unsteady pressure
fluctuations with a convective character. The presented extension to the TPP
improves the splitting between acoustics and the rest of the unsteady flow
field. The method is simple: i) the acoustic eigenmodes are analytically
determined for a uniform mean flow as in the original TPP; ii) the suggested
model for convective pressure perturbations uses the convective wavenumber as
axial wavenumber and the same orthogonal radial shape functions as for the
acoustic modes. The reliability is demonstrated on the simulation data of a
low-pressure fan. As acoustic and convective perturbations are separated, the
accuracy of the results increases close to sources, allowing a reduction of the
computational costs by shortening the simulation domain. The extended method is
as robust as the original one--giving the same results for the acoustic modes
in absence of convective perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08192</id><created>2015-11-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;n-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>Javier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trotta</keyname><forenames>Rinaldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piredda</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schimpf</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trevisi</keyname><forenames>Giovanna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seravalli</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frigeri</keyname><forenames>Paola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stroj</keyname><forenames>Sandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lettner</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reindl</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wildmann</keyname><forenames>Johannes S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Edlinger</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rastelli</keyname><forenames>Armando</forenames></author></authors><title>Full Dynamic Control of In-plane Elastic Stress Tensor in Nanomembranes</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Advanced Optical Materials 4(5), 682-687 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adom.201500779</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strain engineering allows the physical properties of materials and devices to
be widely tailored, as paradigmatically demonstrated by strained transistors
and semiconductor lasers employed in consumer electronics. For this reason, its
potential impact on our society has been compared to that of chemical alloying.
Although significant progress has been made in the last years on strained
nanomaterials, strain fields (which are of tensorial nature, with six
independent components) are still mostly used in a &quot;scalar&quot; and/or static
fashion. Here we present a new class of strain actuators which allow the three
components of the in-plane stress tensor in a nanomembrane to be independently
and reversibly controlled. The actuators are based on monolithic piezoelectric
substrates, which are micro-machined via femtosecond-laser processing. Their
functionality is demonstrated by &quot;programming&quot; arbitrary stress states in a
semiconductor layer, whose light emission is used as a local and sensitive
strain gauge. The results shown in this work open a new route to investigate
and make use of strain effects in materials and devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08375</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08375</id><created>2015-11-26</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lauricella</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pontrelli</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisignano</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Succi</keyname><forenames>Sauro</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic mesh refinement for discrete models of jet electro-hydrodynamics</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures in Journal of Computational Science, 2016</comments><msc-class>37N10, 76A05, 76A10, 76D25</msc-class><doi>10.1016/j.jocs.2016.05.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nowadays, several models of unidimensional fluid jets exploit discrete
element methods. In some cases, as for models aiming at describing the
electrospinning nanofabrication process of polymer fibers, discrete element
methods suffer a non constant resolution of the jet representation. We develop
a dynamic mesh-refinement method for the numerical study of the
electro-hydrodynamic behavior of charged jets using discrete element methods.
To this purpose, we import ideas and techniques from the string method
originally developed in the framework of free-energy landscape simulations. The
mesh-refined discrete element method is demonstrated for the case of
electrospinning applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03699</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03699</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>The GlueX Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Ghoul</keyname><forenames>H. Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anassontzis</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbosa</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beattie</keyname><forenames>T. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berdnikov</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Black</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boeglin</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>W. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cannon</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyshov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chudakov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crede</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalton</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deur</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dobbs</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolgolenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dugger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Egiyan</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eugenio</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foda</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frye</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furletov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasparian</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerasimov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gevorgyan</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goryachev</keyname><forenames>V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guegan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakobyan</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hakobyan2</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hardin</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ireland</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ito</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarvis</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>R. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kakoyan</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kourkoumeli</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuleshov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawrence</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leckey</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>W. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Livingston</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lolos</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mack</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mattione</keyname><forenames>P. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matveev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCaughan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGinley</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McIntyre</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mendez</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miskimen</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mokaya</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriya</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nigmatkulov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochoa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostrovidov</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Papandreou</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedroni</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pennington</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pentchev</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponosov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pooser</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pratt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinhold</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritchie</keyname><forenames>B. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robison</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romanov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salgado</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumacher</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenov</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenova</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senderovich</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seth</keyname><forenames>K. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shepherd</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sober</keyname><forenames>D. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Somov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Somov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soto</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sparks</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staib</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stevens</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subedi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarasov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tolstukhin</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaradze</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toro</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsaris</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasileiadis</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vega</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voulgaris</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walford</keyname><forenames>N. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitlatch</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Williams</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zarling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zihlmann</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>First Results from The GlueX Experiment</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, Invited contribution to the Hadron 2015
  Conference, Newport News VA, September 2015</comments><report-no>JLAB-PHY-16-2195</report-no><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1735, 020001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4949369</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The GlueX experiment at Jefferson Lab ran with its first commissioning beam
in late 2014 and the spring of 2015. Data were collected on both plastic and
liquid hydrogen targets, and much of the detector has been commissioned. All of
the detector systems are now performing at or near design specifications and
events are being fully reconstructed, including exclusive production of
$\pi^{0}$, $\eta$ and $\omega$ mesons. Linearly-polarized photons were
successfully produced through coherent bremsstrahlung and polarization transfer
to the $\rho$ has been observed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04800</id><created>2015-11-29</created><updated>2016-04-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oliveira</keyname><forenames>Firmin J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Time Transformations in Cosmological Relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>36 pages, 1 table, 13 figures</comments><doi>10.4236/jhepgc.2016.22022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relativity of cosmic time is developed within the framework of
Cosmological Relativity in five dimensions of space, time and velocity. A
general linearized metric element is defined to have the form $ds^2 = (1+\phi)
c^2 dt^2 - dr^2 + (1+\psi) \tau^2 dv^2$, where the coordinates are time $t$,
radial distance $r=\sqrt{x^2 + y^2 + z^2}$ for spatials $x$, $y$ and $z$, and
velocity $v$, with $c$ the speed of light in vacuum and $\tau$ the
Hubble-Carmeli time constant. The metric is accurate to first order in $t/\tau$
and $v/c$. The fields $\phi$ and $\psi$ are general functions of the
coordinates. By showing that $\phi = \psi$, a metric of the form $ds^2 = c^2
dt^2 - dr^2 + \tau^2 dv^2$ is obtained from the general metric, implying that
the universe is flat. For cosmological redshift $z$, the luminosity distance
relation $D_L (z,t) = r (1 + z) / \sqrt{1 - t^2 / \tau^2}$ is used to fit
combined distance moduli from Type Ia Supernovae up to $z &lt; 1.5$ and Gamma-Ray
Bursts up to $z &lt; 7$, from which a value of $\Omega_M = 0.800 \pm 0.080$ is
obtained for the matter density parameter at the present epoch. Assuming a
baryon density of $\Omega_B = 0.038 \pm 0.004$, a rest mass energy of $( 9.79
\pm 0.47 ) \, {\rm GeV}$ is predicted for the anti-baryonic $\bar{Y}$ and the
$\Phi^{*}$ particles which decay from a hypothetical $\bar{X}_1$ particle. The
cosmic aging function $g_1(z,t)= ( 1 + z) ( 1 - t^2 / \tau^2 )$ makes good fits
to light curve data from two reports of Type 1a supernovae and in fitting to
simulated quasar like light curve power spectra separated by redshift
$\Delta{z} \approx 1$. We determine the multipole of the first acoustic peak of
the Cosmic Microwave Background radiation anisotropy to be $l \approx 224 \pm
5$ and a sound horizon of $\theta_{sh0} \approx (0.805 \pm 0.020 ) {}^{\circ}$
on today's sky.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06016</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lund</keyname><forenames>Ross G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robbins</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slastikov</keyname><forenames>Valeriy</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence of travelling-wave solutions representing domain wall motion
  in a thin ferromagnetic nanowire</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of a domain wall under the influence of applied
magnetic fields in a one-dimensional ferromagnetic nanowire, governed by the
Landau--Lifshitz--Gilbert equation. Existence of travelling-wave solutions
close to two known static solutions is proven using
implicit-function-theorem-type arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06761</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>York</keyname><forenames>James W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Causal Propagation of Constraints in General Relativity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn because the results were found to be
  incorrect</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, I demonstrate that the constraint functions are propagated by
a first order symmetric (or symmetrizable) hyperbolic system whose
characteristic cone is the light cone. This result follows from the
twice-contracted Bianchi identities. Analyticity is not required.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08510</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08510</id><created>2015-12-28</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pershin</keyname><forenames>Yuriy V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Memristive Sisyphus circuit for clock signal generation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 26155 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep26155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Frequency generators are widely used in electronics. Here, we report the
design and experimental realization of a memristive frequency generator
employing a unique combination of only digital logic gates, a single-supply
voltage and a realistic threshold-type memristive device. In our circuit, the
oscillator frequency and duty cycle are defined by the switching
characteristics of the memristive device and external resistors. We demonstrate
the circuit operation both experimentally, using a memristor emulator, and
theoretically, using a model memristive device with threshold. Importantly,
nanoscale realizations of memristive devices offer small-size alternatives to
conventional quartz-based oscillators. In addition, the suggested approach can
be used for mimicking some cyclic (Sisyphus) processes in nature, such as
&quot;dripping ants&quot; or drops from leaky faucets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09342</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>Heather A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kataria</keyname><forenames>Tiffany</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>Nikole K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burrows</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortney</keyname><forenames>Jonathan J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwartz</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shporer</keyname><forenames>Avi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agol</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cowan</keyname><forenames>Nicholas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deming</keyname><forenames>Drake</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desert</keyname><forenames>Jean-Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fulton</keyname><forenames>Benjamin J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howard</keyname><forenames>Andrew W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langton</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laughlin</keyname><forenames>Gregory</forenames></author><author><keyname>Showman</keyname><forenames>Adam P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Todorov</keyname><forenames>Kamen</forenames></author></authors><title>3.6 and 4.5 $\mu$m ${\it Spitzer}$ Phase Curves of the Highly-Irradiated
  Hot Jupiters WASP-19b and HAT-P-7b</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>22 pages, 29 figures, accepted by ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ 823 122 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/823/2/122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze full-orbit phase curve observations of the transiting hot Jupiters
WASP-19b and HAT-P-7b at 3.6 and 4.5 $\mu$m obtained using the Spitzer Space
Telescope. For WASP-19b, we measure secondary eclipse depths of $0.485\%\pm
0.024\%$ and $0.584\%\pm 0.029\%$ at 3.6 and 4.5 $\mu$m, which are consistent
with a single blackbody with effective temperature $2372 \pm 60$ K. The
measured 3.6 and 4.5 $\mu$m secondary eclipse depths for HAT-P-7b are
$0.156\%\pm 0.009\%$ and $0.190\%\pm 0.006\%$, which are well-described by a
single blackbody with effective temperature $2667\pm 57$ K. Comparing the phase
curves to the predictions of one-dimensional and three-dimensional atmospheric
models, we find that WASP-19b's dayside emission is consistent with a model
atmosphere with no dayside thermal inversion and moderately efficient day-night
circulation. We also detect an eastward-shifted hotspot, suggesting the
presence of a superrotating equatorial jet. In contrast, HAT-P-7b's dayside
emission suggests a dayside thermal inversion and relatively inefficient
day-night circulation; no hotspot shift is detected. For both planets, these
same models do not agree with the measured nightside emission. The
discrepancies in the model-data comparisons for WASP-19b might be explained by
high-altitude silicate clouds on the nightside and/or high atmospheric
metallicity, while the very low 3.6 $\mu$m nightside planetary brightness for
HAT-P-7b may be indicative of an enhanced global C/O ratio. We compute Bond
albedos of 0 ($&lt;0.08$ at $1\sigma$) and $0.38\pm 0.06$ for WASP-19b and
HAT-P-7b, respectively. In the context of other planets with thermal phase
curve measurements, we show that WASP-19b and HAT-P-7b fit the general trend of
decreasing day-night heat recirculation with increasing irradiation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01042</id><created>2016-01-05</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Daqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shuyue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shengli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ning</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective fermion excitation in a warm massless Dirac system</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Basing on a self-consistent method, we predict theoretically that there
occurs not only a normal (quasi) fermion mode, but also a collective fermion
mode, plasmino, in a warm 2D massless Dirac system, especially in a warm
intrinsic graphene system. Results of Landau damping show that both fermion and
plasmino are well defined modes. We find that there are sharp differences
between the discussed system and the QCD/QED system. Firstly, the thermal mass
is proportional to $\alpha_g^{3/4}T$ but not $\alpha_g T$. Secondly, at
$0&lt;q&lt;q_c$, the fermion channel and plasmino channel are nearly degenerate and
furthermore, the energy difference between fermion and plasmino becomes more
and more larger with increasing $q$ at the region $q&gt;q_c$. Thirdly, the fermion
behaves as a &quot;relativity particles&quot; with none zero mass and the plasmino
exhibits an anormal dispersion at moderate momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02466</id><created>2016-01-11</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Verbiest</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stampfer</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reuter</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interplay between nanometer-scale strain variations and externally
  applied strain in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 195438 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.195438</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a molecular modeling study analyzing nanometer-scale strain
variations in graphene as a function of externally applied tensile strain. We
consider two different mechanisms that could underlie nanometer-scale strain
variations: static perturbations from lattice imperfections of an underlying
substrate and thermal fluctuations. For both cases we observe a decrease in the
out-of-plane atomic displacements with increasing strain, which is accompanied
by an increase in the in-plane displacements. Reflecting the non-linear elastic
properties of graphene, both trends together yield a non-monotonic variation of
the total displacements with increasing tensile strain. This variation allows
to test the role of nanometer-scale strain variations in limiting the carrier
mobility of high-quality graphene samples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03243</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>De Martino</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capuani</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Martino</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Growth against entropy in bacterial metabolism: the phenotypic trade-off
  behind empirical growth rate distributions in E. coli</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.dis-nn physics.bio-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Biol. 13 (2016) 036005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1478-3975/13/3/036005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The solution space of genome-scale models of cellular metabolism provides a
map between physically viable flux configurations and cellular metabolic
phenotypes described, at the most basic level, by the corresponding growth
rates. By sampling the solution space of E. coli's metabolic network, we show
that empirical growth rate distributions recently obtained in experiments at
single-cell resolution can be explained in terms of a trade-off between the
higher fitness of fast-growing phenotypes and the higher entropy of
slow-growing ones. Based on this, we propose a minimal model for the evolution
of a large bacterial population that captures this trade-off. The scaling
relationships observed in experiments encode, in such frameworks, for the same
distance from the maximum achievable growth rate, the same degree of growth
rate maximization, and/or the same rate of phenotypic change. Being grounded on
genome-scale metabolic network reconstructions, these results allow for
multiple implications and extensions in spite of the underlying conceptual
simplicity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03946</id><created>2016-01-14</created><updated>2016-03-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dehghani</keyname><forenames>Mohsen</forenames></author></authors><title>Group theoretical interpretation of the modified gravity in de Sitter
  space</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. High Energy Phys. 03(2016)203</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A frame work has been presented for theoretical interpretation of various
modified gravitational models which is based on the group theoretical approach
and unitary irreducible representations (UIR's) of de Sitter (dS) group. In
order to illustrate the application of the proposed method, a model of modified
gravity has been investigated. The background field method has been utilized
and the linearized modified gravitational field equation has been obtained in
the 4-dimensional dS space-time as the background. The field equation has been
written as the eigne-value equation of the Casimir operators of dS space using
the flat 5-dimensional ambient space notations. The Minkowskian correspondence
of the theory has been obtained by taking the zero curvature limit. It has been
shown that under some simple conditions, the linearized modified field equation
transforms according to two of the UIR's of dS group labeled by $\Pi^\pm_{2,1}$
and $\Pi^\pm_{2,2}$ in the discrete series. It means that the proposed modified
gravitational theory can be a suitable one to describe the quantum
gravitational effects in its linear approximation on dS space. The field
equation has been solved and the solution has been written as the
multiplication of a symmetric rank-2 polarization tensor and a massless scalar
field using the ambient space notations. Also the two-point function has been
calculated in the ambient space formalism. It is dS invariant and free of any
theoretical problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04342</id><created>2016-01-17</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guella</keyname><forenames>Chahrazed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherigui</keyname><forenames>Dounia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahriche</keyname><forenames>Amine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasri</keyname><forenames>Salah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soualah</keyname><forenames>Rachik</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing Radiative Neutrino Mass Models with Dilepton Events at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures &amp; 2 tables. Published version matched</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 095022 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.095022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we investigate the possibility of probing a class of neutrino
mass models at the LHC proton-proton collisions with 8 and 14 TeV energies. The
existence of lepton flavor violating interactions for a singlet charged scalar,
$S^{\pm}$, that couples to the leptons could induce many processes such as
$pp\rightarrow\ell_{\alpha}^{\pm}\ell_{\beta}^{\mp}+\slashed E $. Using the
processes with $\ell_{\alpha}\ell_{\beta}=ee,e\mu,\mu\mu$, we found that an
inclusive cut on the $M_{T2}$ event variable is vital in our analysis and leads
to an effective suppression of the large Standard Model background. Our results
show possible detectability of the charged scalars effect, especially at the
$\sqrt{s}= 14~\text{TeV}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04916</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04916</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2016-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Braghin</keyname><forenames>Fabio L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quark and pion effective couplings from polarization effects</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>20 pages, revised version to be published in Eur. Phys. Journ. A</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A 52, 134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16134-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A flavor SU(2) effective model for pions and quarks is derived by considering
polarization effects departing from the usual quark-quark effective interaction
induced by dressed gluon exchange, i.e. a global color model for QCD. For that,
the quark field is decomposed into a component that yields light mesons and the
quark-antiquark condensate, being integrated out by means of the auxiliary
field method, and another component which yields constituent quarks, which is
basically a background quark field. Within a longwavelength and weak quark
field expansion (or large quark effective mass expansion) of a quark
determinant, the leading terms are found up to the second order in a zero order
derivative expansion, by neglecting vector mesons that are considerably heavier
than the pion. Pions are considered in the structureless limit and, besides the
chiral invariant terms that reproduce previously derived expressions, symmetry
breaking terms are also presented. The leading chiral quark-quark effective
couplings are also found corresponding to a NJL and a vector-NJL couplings. All
the resulting effective coupling constants and parameters are expressed in
terms of the current and constituent quark masses and of the coupling $g$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06167</id><created>2016-01-22</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakagawa</keyname><forenames>Yuya O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Misguich</keyname><forenames>Gr&#xe9;goire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oshikawa</keyname><forenames>Masaki</forenames></author></authors><title>Flux quench in a system of interacting spinless fermions in one
  dimension</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures; v2: Added references. Figures are refined and
  animations are added. Corrected typos. Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 174310 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.174310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a quantum quench in a one-dimensional spinless fermion model
(equivalent to the XXZ spin chain), where a magnetic flux is suddenly switched
off. This quench is equivalent to imposing a pulse of electric field and
therefore generates an initial particle current. This current is not a
conserved quantity in presence of a lattice and interactions and we investigate
numerically its time-evolution after the quench, using the infinite
time-evolving block decimation method. For repulsive interactions or large
initial flux, we find oscillations that are governed by excitations deep inside
the Fermi sea. At long times we observe that the current remains non-vanishing
in the gapless cases, whereas it decays to zero in the gapped cases. Although
the linear response theory (valid for a weak flux) predicts the same long-time
limit of the current for repulsive and attractive interactions (relation with
the zero-temperature Drude weight), larger nonlinearities are observed in the
case of repulsive interactions compared with that of the attractive case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06720</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Marston</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chini</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobias</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Generalized Quasilinear Approximation: Application to Zonal Jets</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn astro-ph.EP astro-ph.SR physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>5 pages and 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 214501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.214501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quasilinear theory is often utilized to approximate the dynamics of fluids
exhibiting significant interactions between mean flows and eddies. In this
paper we present a generalization of quasilinear theory to include dynamic mode
interactions on the large scales. This generalized quasilinear (GQL)
approximation is achieved by separating the state variables into large and
small zonal scales via a spectral filter rather than by a decomposition into a
formal mean and fluctuations. Nonlinear interactions involving only small zonal
scales are then removed. The approximation is conservative and allows for
scattering of energy between small-scale modes via the large scale (through
non-local spectral interactions). We evaluate GQL for the paradigmatic problems
of the driving of large-scale jets on a spherical surface and on the beta-plane
and show that it is accurate even for a small number of large-scale modes. As
this approximation is formally linear in the small zonal scales it allows for
the closure of the system and can be utilized in direct statistical simulation
schemes that have proved an attractive alternative to direct numerical
simulation for many geophysical and astrophysical problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07868</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Production of K$^{*}$(892)$^{0}$ and $\phi$(1020) in p-Pb collisions at
  $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}$ = 5.02 TeV</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>31 pages, 9 captioned figures, 4 tables, authors from page 25,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/2271</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-326</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 245</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4088-7</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The production of K$^{*}$(892)$^{0}$ and $\phi$(1020) mesons has been
measured in p-Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}$ = 5.02 TeV. K$^{*0}$
and $\phi$ are reconstructed via their decay into charged hadrons with the
ALICE detector in the rapidity range $-0.5 &lt; y &lt;0$. The transverse momentum
spectra, measured as a function of the multiplicity, have p$_{\mathrm{T}}$
range from 0 to 15 GeV/$c$ for K$^{*0}$ and from 0.3 to 21 GeV/$c$ for $\phi$.
Integrated yields, mean transverse momenta and particle ratios are reported and
compared with results in pp collisions at $\sqrt{s}$ = 7 TeV and Pb-Pb
collisions at $\sqrt{s_{\mathrm{NN}}}$ = 2.76 TeV. In Pb-Pb and p-Pb
collisions, K$^{*0}$ and $\phi$ probe the hadronic phase of the system and
contribute to the study of particle formation mechanisms by comparison with
other identified hadrons. For this purpose, the mean transverse momenta and the
differential proton-to-$\phi$ ratio are discussed as a function of the
multiplicity of the event. The short-lived K$^{*0}$ is measured to investigate
re-scattering effects, believed to be related to the size of the system and to
the lifetime of the hadronic phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01392</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Particle identification in ALICE: a Bayesian approach</title><categories>physics.data-an hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>32 pages, 15 captioned figures, 1 table, authors from page 26,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/2285</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-023</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus 131 (2016) 168</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16168-5</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Bayesian approach to particle identification (PID) within the
ALICE experiment. The aim is to more effectively combine the particle
identification capabilities of its various detectors. After a brief explanation
of the adopted methodology and formalism, the performance of the Bayesian PID
approach for charged pions, kaons and protons in the central barrel of ALICE is
studied. PID is performed via measurements of specific energy loss
($\mathrm{d}E/\mathrm{d}x$) and time-of-flight. PID efficiencies and
misidentification probabilities are extracted and compared with Monte Carlo
simulations using high-purity samples of identified particles in the decay
channels ${\rm K}^0_S \rightarrow \pi^-\pi^+$, $\phi \rightarrow {\rm K}^-{\rm
K}^+$, and $\Lambda \rightarrow {\rm p}\pi^-$ in p-Pb collisions at
$\sqrt{s_{\rm NN}}=5.02$ TeV. In order to thoroughly assess the validity of the
Bayesian approach, this methodology was used to obtain corrected $p_{\rm T}$
spectra of pions, kaons, protons, and D$^0$ mesons in pp collisions at
$\sqrt{s}=7$ TeV. In all cases, the results using Bayesian PID were found to be
consistent with previous measurements performed by ALICE using a standard PID
approach. For the measurement of D$^0 \rightarrow {\rm K}^-\pi^+$, it was found
that a Bayesian PID approach gave a higher signal-to-background ratio and a
similar or larger statistical significance when compared with standard PID
selections, despite a reduced identification efficiency. Finally, we present an
exploratory study of the measurement of $\Lambda_{\rm c}^{+}\rightarrow {\rm p}
{\rm K}^-\pi^+$ in pp collisions at $\sqrt{s}=7$ TeV, using the Bayesian
approach for the identification of its decay products.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03748</id><created>2016-02-11</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pudleiner</keyname><forenames>Petra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rost</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mer</keyname><forenames>Nils</forenames></author></authors><title>Momentum structure of the self-energy and its parametrization for the
  two-dimensional Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 195134 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.195134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the self-energy for the half-filled Hubbard model on a square
lattice using lattice quantum Monte Carlo simulations and the dynamical vertex
approximation. The self-energy is strongly momentum dependent, but it can be
parametrized via the non-interacting energy-momentum dispersion
$\varepsilon_{\mathbf{k}}$, except for pseudogap features right at the Fermi
edge. That is, it can be written as $\Sigma(\varepsilon_{\mathbf{k}},\omega)$,
with two energy-like parameters ($\varepsilon$, $\omega$) instead of three
($k_x$, $k_y$ and $\omega$). The self-energy has two rather broad and weakly
dispersing high energy features and a sharp $\omega= \varepsilon_{\mathbf{k}}$
feature at high temperatures, which turns to $\omega=
-\varepsilon_{\mathbf{k}}$ at low temperatures. Altogether this yields a Z- and
reversed-Z-like structure, respectively, for the imaginary part of
$\Sigma(\varepsilon_{\mathbf{k}},\omega)$. We attribute the change of the low
energy structure to antiferromagnetic spin fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04380</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04380</id><created>2016-02-13</created><updated>2016-05-06</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andraschko</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sirker</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entanglement entropy of disordered quantum chains following a global
  quench</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>Slightly expanded and updated version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 205146 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.205146</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We numerically investigate the growth of the entanglement entropy S_{ent}(t)
in time t---after a global quench from a product state---in quantum chains with
various kinds of disorder. The main focus is, in particular, on fermionic
chains with bond disorder. In the noninteracting case at criticality we
numerically test recent predictions by the real space renormalization group for
the entanglement growth in time, the maximal entanglement as a function of
block size, and the decay of a density wave order parameter. We show that
multiprecision calculations are required to reach the scaling regime and
perform such calculations for specific cases. For interacting models with
binary bond disorder we present data based on infinite size density matrix
renormalization group calculations and exact diagonalizations. We obtain first
numerical evidence for a many-body localized phase in bond disordered systems
where S_{ent}(t)~ln t$ seems to hold. Our results for bond disorder are
contrasted with the well studied case of potential disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04724</id><created>2016-02-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Fucci</keyname><forenames>Guglielmo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirsten</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional determinants and Casimir energy in higher dimensional
  spherically symmetric background potentials</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>17 pages, LaTeX</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 ( 2016 ) 275203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/27/275203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we analyze the spectral zeta function associated with a Laplace
operator acting on scalar functions on an N-dimensional Euclidean space in the
presence of a spherically symmetric background potential. The obtained analytic
continuation of the spectral zeta function is then used to derive very simple
results for the functional determinant of the operator and the Casimir energy
of the scalar field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00144</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00144</id><created>2016-03-01</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>Yuhei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Komura</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishima</keyname><forenames>Shota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Touta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niikura</keyname><forenames>Naeko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kosaka</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames></author></authors><title>Geometric spin echo under zero field</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 11668 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms11668</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin echo is a fundamental tool for quantum registers and biomedical imaging.
It is believed that a strong magnetic field is needed for the spin echo to
provide long memory and high resolution since a degenerate spin cannot be
controlled or addressed under a zero magnetic field. While a degenerate spin is
never subject to dynamic control, it is still subject to geometric control.
Here we show the spin echo of a degenerate spin subsystem, which is
geometrically controlled via a mediating state split by the crystal field, in a
nitrogen vacancy center in diamond. The demonstration reveals that the
degenerate spin is protected by inherent symmetry breaking called zero-field
splitting. The geometric spin echo under zero field provides an ideal way to
maintain the coherence without any dynamics, thus opening the way to
pseudo-static quantum random access memory and non-invasive biosensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00752</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00752</id><created>2016-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Latham</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>The Laura++ Dalitz plot fitter</title><categories>physics.data-an hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, submitted to the proceedings of Hadron 2015</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1735, 070001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4949449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Laura++ software package is designed for performing fits of amplitude
models to data from decays of spin-0 particles into final states containing
three spin-0 particles - so-called Dalitz-plot analysis. An overview of the
amplitude formalism and its software implementation is given as well as
summaries of recently added features and planned future developments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01504</id><created>2016-03-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Tran</keyname><forenames>Fabien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stelzl</keyname><forenames>Julia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blaha</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Rungs 1 to 4 of DFT Jacob's ladder: extensive test on the lattice
  constant, bulk modulus, and cohesive energy of solids</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 144, 204120 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4948636</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A large panel of old and recently proposed exchange-correlation functionals
belonging to rungs 1 to 4 of Jacob's ladder of density functional theory are
tested (with and without a dispersion correction term) for the calculation of
the lattice constant, bulk modulus, and cohesive energy of solids. Particular
attention will be paid to the functionals MGGA_MS2 [J. Sun et al., J. Chem.
Phys. 138, 044113 (2013)], mBEEF [J. Wellendorff et al., J. Chem. Phys. 140,
144107 (2014)], and SCAN [J. Sun et al., Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 036402 (2015)]
that are approximations of the meta-generalized gradient type and were
developed with the goal to be universally good. Another goal is also to
determine for which semilocal functionals and groups of solids it is beneficial
(or not necessary) to use the Hartree-Fock exchange or a dispersion correction
term.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02162</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>Ranga</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noked</keyname><forenames>Ori</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silvera</keyname><forenames>Isaac F.</forenames></author></authors><title>New low temperature phase in dense hydrogen: The phase diagram to 421
  GPa</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>Title modified; some rewriting to clarify table; references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the quest to make metallic hydrogen at low temperatures a rich number of
new phases have been found and the highest pressure ones have somewhat flat
phase lines, around room temperature. We have studied hydrogen to static
pressures of GPa in a diamond anvil cell and down to liquid helium
temperatures, using infrared spectroscopy. We report a new phase at a pressure
of GPa and T=5 K. Although we observe strong darkening of the sample in the
visible, we have no evidence that this phase is metallic hydrogen.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03821</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arcod&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Marcos R. A.</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET &amp; UNMdP</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>Mauricio</forenames><affiliation>IFIMAR - CONICET &amp; UNMdP</affiliation></author></authors><title>Geometric back-reaction in pre-inflation from relativistic quantum
  geometry</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>improved version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The pre-inflationary evolution of the universe describes the beginning of the
expansion from a static initial state, such that the Hubble parameter is
initially zero, but increases to an asymptotic constant value, in which it
could achieve a de Sitter (inflationary) expansion. The expansion is driven by
a background phantom field. The back-reaction effects at this moment should
describe vacuum geometrical excitations, which are studied with detail in this
work using Relativistic Quantum Geometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04495</id><created>2016-03-14</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Boos</keyname><forenames>Edward E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunichev</keyname><forenames>Viacheslav E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volobuev</keyname><forenames>Igor P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Can the 750 GeV diphoton LHC excess be due to a radion-dominated state?</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures; added some references and comments, fixed typos.
  arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1505.05892</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the possibility of interpreting the 125 GeV scalar boson and the
750 GeV diphoton excess recently reported by the ATLAS and CMS experiments as a
Higgs-dominated and a radion-dominated states respectively in a stabilized
brane-world model. It is shown that in the simplest variant of the model, where
only the gravitational degrees of freedom propagate in the bulk, the production
cross section of the radion-dominated state with mass 750 GeV turns out to be
too small in the allowed region of the model parameter space for explaining the
nature of the excess in this approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04634</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Theophilou</keyname><forenames>Iris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lathiotakis</keyname><forenames>Nektarios N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helbig</keyname><forenames>Nicole</forenames></author></authors><title>Conditions for describing triplet states in reduced density matrix
  functional theory</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.jctc.6b00257</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider necessary conditions for the one-body-reduced density matrix
(1RDM) to correspond to a triplet wave-function of a two electron system. The
conditions concern the occupation numbers and are different for the high spin
projections, $S_z=\pm 1$, and the $S_z=0$ projection. Hence, they can be used
to test if an approximate 1RDM functional yields the same energies for both
projections. We employ these conditions in reduced density matrix functional
theory calculations for the triplet excitations of two-electron systems. In
addition, we propose that these conditions can be used in the calculation of
triplet states of systems with more than two electrons by restricting the
active space. We assess this procedure in calculations for a few atomic and
molecular systems. We show that the quality of the optimal 1RDMs improves by
applying the conditions in all the cases we studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04723</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sierra</keyname><forenames>D. Aristizabal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simoes</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wegman</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Closing in on minimal dark matter and radiative neutrino masses</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables. Two diagrams updated, few
  clarifications and references added. Matches version accepted for publication
  in JHEP</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study one-loop radiative neutrino mass models in which one of the
beyond-the-standard model fields is either a hypercharge-zero fermion quintet
(minimal dark matter) or a hypercharge-zero scalar septet. By systematically
classifying all possible one-loop such models we identify various processes
that render the neutral component of these representations (dark matter)
cosmologically unstable. Thus, our findings show that these scenarios are in
general not reconcilable with dark matter stability unless tiny couplings or
additional ad hoc symmetries are assumed, in contrast to minimal dark matter
models where stability is entirely due to the standard model gauge symmetry.
For some variants based on higher-order loops we find that $\alpha_2$ reaches a
Landau pole at rather low scales, a couple orders of magnitude from the
characteristic scale of the model itself. Thus, we argue that some of these
variations although consistent with dark matter stability and phenomenological
constraints are hard to reconcile with perturbativity criteria.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06532</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Breivik</keyname><forenames>&#xd8;yvind</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear and depth-averaged Stokes drift under a Phillips-type spectrum</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>Five pages, one figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transport and shear under a Phillips-type spectrum are presented. A
combined profile for monochromatic swell and a Phillips-type wind sea spectrum
which can be used to investigate the shear under crossing seas is then
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07354</id><created>2016-03-23</created><updated>2016-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rezaeian</keyname><forenames>Amir H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon-jet ridge at RHIC and the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures; v2: results unchanged, presentation improved,
  typos corrected. The version to appear in PRD. arXiv admin note: text overlap
  with arXiv:1209.0478</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 094030 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.094030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate long range rapidity correlations of pairs of prompt photon and
jet in the Color Glass Condensate (CGC) framework in proton-proton and
proton-nucleus collisions at RHIC and the LHC. We show that photon-jet
correlations exhibit long-range azimuthal collimation at near-side for low
transverse momenta of the produced photon and jet in high-multiplicity events.
These ridge-like features are strikingly similar to the observed ridge effect
for di-hadron correlations at RHIC and the LHC. We show that correlations in
the relative rapidity and the relative azimuthal angle between pairs of prompt
photon and jet strongly depend on the gluon saturation dynamics at small-x
kinematics and such measurements can help to understand the true origin of the
observed di-hadron ridge in p+A collisions, and address whether the ridge is a
universal phenomenon for all two particle correlations at high energy and high
multiplicity events. We also investigate if there is a ridge-like structure for
photon-hadron pair correlations at RHIC and the LHC. We found that the
hadronization of jet has non-trivial effects on the photon-jet correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.08178</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.08178</id><created>2016-03-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Mohsen</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author></authors><title>Fermions on the Worldsheet of Effective Strings via Coset Construction</title><categories>hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 106007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.106007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper the detailed CCWZ procedure for introducing fermions on the
world sheet of a string propagating in flat space-time is presented. The theory
of nonlinear realizations is used to derive the transformation as well as the
interactions of fermionic matter fields under arbitrary spinorial
representations of the unbroken subgroup. This demonstrates that even for
non-supersymmetric spinors, the interactions are still severely restricted by
the nonlinearly realized symmetry. We also explain how supersymmetric models
provide an example for this construction with Goldstinos as matter fields, and
how one can use the $\kappa$-symmetry of the Green Schwarz action in
particular, to verify this nonlinear transformation for a specific matter field
representation. We finally restrict the target space dimension without
reference to supersymmetry, but rather by imposing one-loop integrability on a
fermionic string that nonlinearly realizes Poincare symmetry. This singles out
the critical dimension $D=10$ for heterotic, GS and RNS supersymmetric strings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02658</id><created>2016-04-10</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Spinrath</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Sum Rules for Leptons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, contribution to the International Conference on New Physics
  at the Large Hadron Collider, Singapore, 29 February - 4 March 2016</comments><report-no>TTP16-012</report-no><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A, Vol. 31 (2016) 1630021</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16300210</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is a wide class of models which give a dynamical description of the
origin of flavour in terms of spontaneous symmetry breaking of an underlying
symmetry. Many of these models exhibit sum rules which relate on the one hand
mixing angles and the Dirac CP phase with each other and/or on the other hand
neutrino masses and Majorana phases with each other. We will briefly sketch how
this happens and discuss briefly the impact of renormalisation group
corrections to the mass sum rules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02828</id><created>2016-04-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Haoyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author></authors><title>Background-free coherent anti-stokes Raman spectroscopy and microscopy
  by dual-soliton pulse generation</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>78A10</msc-class><doi>10.1364/OL.41.002628</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose an all-fiber-generated dual-soliton pulses based scheme for the
background-free detection of coherent anti-Stokes Raman spectroscopy under the
spectral focusing mechanism. Due to the strong birefringence and high
nonlinearity of a polarization-maintaining photonic crystal fiber (PM-PCF), two
redshifted soliton pulses can be simultaneously generated relying on high-order
dispersion and nonlinear effects along two eigenpolarization axes in the
anomalous dispersion regime, while allowing feasible tunability of the
frequency distance and temporal interval between them. This proposed scheme,
termed as DS-CARS, exploits a unique combination of slight frequency-shift and
advisable temporal walk-off of this two soliton pulses to achieve robust and
efficient suppression of nonresonant background with compact all-fiber coherent
excitation source. Capability of the DS-CARS is experimentally demonstrated by
the background-free CARS spectroscopy and unambiguous CARS microscopy of
polymer beads in the fingerprint region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03604</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2016-05-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuyubamba</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konoplya</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhidenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasinormal modes and a new instability of Einstein-Gauss-Bonnet black
  holes in the de Sitter world</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 104053 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.104053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Analysis of time-domain profiles for gravitational perturbations shows that
Gauss-Bonnet black holes in a de Sitter world possess a new kind of dynamical
instability which does not take place for asymptotically flat
Einstein-Gauss-Bonnet black holes. The new instability is in the gravitational
perturbations of the scalar type and is due to the nonvanishing cosmological
constant. Analysis of the quasinormal spectrum in the stability sector shows
that although the scalar type of gravitational perturbations alone does not
obey Hod's conjectural bound, connecting the damping rate and the Hawking
temperature, the vector and tensor types (and thereby the gravitational
spectrum as a whole) do obey it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05385</id><created>2016-04-18</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Waegell</keyname><forenames>Mordecai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aharonov</keyname><forenames>Yakir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patti</keyname><forenames>Taylor Lee</forenames></author></authors><title>Interference Energy Spectrum of the Infinite Square Well</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>26 Pages, 5 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Entropy, 18(4), p.149 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/e18040149</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Certain superposition states of the 1-D infinite square well have transient
zeros at locations other than the nodes of the eigenstates that comprise them.
It is shown that if an infinite potential barrier is suddenly raised at some or
all of these zeros, the well can be split into multiple adjacent infinite
square wells without affecting the wavefunction. This effects a change of the
energy eigenbasis of the state to a basis that does not commute with the
original, and a subsequent measurement of the energy now reveals a completely
different spectrum, which we call the {interference energy spectrum} of the
state. This name is appropriate because the same splitting procedure applied at
the stationary nodes of any eigenstate does not change the measurable energy of
the state. Of particular interest, this procedure can result in measurable
energies that are greater than the energy of the highest mode in the original
superposition, raising questions about the conservation of energy akin to those
that have been raised in the study of superoscillations. An analytic derivation
is given for the interference spectrum of a given wavefunction $\Psi(x,t)$ with
$N$ known zeros located at points $s_i = (x_i, t_i)$. Numerical simulations
were used to verify that a barrier can be rapidly raised at a zero of the
wavefunction without significantly affecting it. The interpretation of this
result with respect to the conservation of energy and the energy-time
uncertainty relation is discussed, and the idea of alternate energy eigenbases
is fleshed out. The question of whether or not a preferred discrete energy
spectrum is an inherent feature of a particle's quantum state is examined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05667</id><created>2016-04-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>S. Krishna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jess</keyname><forenames>D. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keys</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Time-dependent suppression of oscillatory power in evolving solar
  magnetic fields</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>accepted for publication in ApJ (in press)</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/823/1/45</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oscillation amplitudes are generally smaller within magnetically active
regions like sunspots and plage, when compared to their surroundings. Such
magnetic features, when viewed in spatially-resolved powermaps, appear as
regions of suppressed power due to reductions in the oscillation amplitudes.
Employing high spatial- and temporal-resolution observations from the Dunn
Solar Telescope (DST) in New Mexico, we study the power suppression in a region
of evolving magnetic fields adjacent to a pore. By utilising wavelet analysis,
we study for the first time, how the oscillatory properties in this region
change as the magnetic field evolves with time. Image sequences taken in the
blue continuum, G-band, Ca~\textsc{ii}~K and H$\alpha$ filters were used in
this study. It is observed that the suppression found in the chromosphere
occupies a relatively larger area confirming previous findings. Also, the
suppression is extended to structures directly connected to the magnetic region
and is found to get enhanced as the magnetic field strength increased with
time. The dependence of the suppression on the magnetic field strength is
greater at longer periods and higher formation heights. Furthermore, the
dominant periodicity in the chromosphere was found to be anti-correlated with
increases in the magnetic field strength.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06534</id><created>2016-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Itoi</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>General properties of overlap operators in disordered quantum spin
  systems</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.dis-nn math.MP</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Phys. (2016) 163: 1339-1349</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1527-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study short-range quantum spin systems with Gaussian disorder. We obtain
quantum mechanical extensions of the Ghirlanda-Guerra identities. We discuss
properties of overlap spin operators with these identities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04627</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04627</id><created>2016-05-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Kento</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monnai</keyname><forenames>Yasuaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saijo</keyname><forenames>Soya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Ryushiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watanabe</keyname><forenames>Hideyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishi-Hayase</keyname><forenames>Junko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itoh</keyname><forenames>Kohei M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>Eisuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Broadband, large-area microwave antenna for optically-detected magnetic
  resonance of nitrogen-vacancy centers in diamond</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures, to appear in Review of Scientific Instruments</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Sci. Instrum. 87, 053904 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4952418</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on a microwave planar ring antenna specifically designed for
optically-detected magnetic resonance (ODMR) of nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers
in diamond. It has the resonance frequency at around 2.87 GHz with the
bandwidth of 400 MHz, ensuring that ODMR can be observed under external
magnetic fields up to 100 G without the need of adjustment of the resonance
frequency. It is also spatially uniform within the 1-mm-diameter center hole,
enabling the magnetic-field imaging in the wide spatial range. These features
facilitate the experiments on quantum sensing and imaging using NV centers at
room temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07475</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Xing-Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Shu-Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai-Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Tai-Fu</forenames></author></authors><title>The Feynman rules for neutrinos and new neutralinos in BLMSSM</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Accepted by Chinese Physics C</comments><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/9/093103</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a supersymmetric extension of the standard model where baryon and lepton
numbers are local gauge symmetries(BLMSSM), we deduce the Feynman rules for
neutrinos and new neutralinos. We briey introduce the mass matrices for the
particles and the related couplings in this work, which are very useful to
research the neutrinos and new neutralinos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08234</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rustad</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasiharmonic Lattice Dynamics Calculations of Energy Balances in the
  Thermal Expansion of ULE Glass</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quasiharmonic lattice dynamics calculations are carried out on SiO2-TiO2
glass mixtures (TiO2 less than or equal to 20 weight percent) showing that the
addition of TiO2 systematically lowers the thermal expansion of high purity
fused silica. Adding ten weight percent titania lowers the thermal expansion
coefficient by approximately 0.5 ppm/K in agreement with observations. The
driving force for lowering the thermal expansion coefficient in the model
system is broken down into mode-by-mode contributions. The driving force is
distributed broadly across the frequency spectrum and is not localized into
particular frequency ranges that can be associated with the coordination
structure of Ti4+ in the simulated glass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08443</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Khoury</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark Matter Superfluidity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 2 figures. Invited plenary talk at the Dark Side of the
  Universe conference, Kyoto, Japan, December 2015. To appear in the
  proceedings. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1507.03013</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this talk I summarize a novel framework that unifies the stunning success
of MOND on galactic scales with the triumph of the $\Lambda$CDM model on
cosmological scales. This is achieved through the rich and well-studied physics
of superfluidity. The dark matter and MOND components have a common origin,
representing different phases of a single underlying substance. In galaxies,
dark matter thermalizes and condenses to form a superfluid phase. The
superfluid phonons couple to baryonic matter particles and mediate a MOND-like
force. This framework naturally distinguishes between galaxies (where MOND is
successful) and galaxy clusters (where MOND is not): dark matter has a higher
temperature in clusters, and hence is in a mixture of superfluid and normal
phase. The rich and well-studied physics of superfluidity leads to a number of
striking observational signatures, which we briefly discuss. Remarkably the
critical temperature and equation of state of the dark matter superfluid are
similar to those of known cold atom systems. Identifying a precise cold atom
analogue would give important insights on the microphysical interactions
underlying DM superfluidity. Tantalizingly, it might open the possibility of
simulating the properties and dynamics of galaxies in laboratory experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08452</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08452</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Filho</keyname><forenames>Gilberto N. Santos</forenames></author></authors><title>The exact solution of a generalized Bose-Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figure. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1309.2956</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I present the exact solution of a family of fragmented Bose-Hubbard models
and represent the models as graphs in one-dimension, two-dimensions and
three-dimensions with the condensates in the vertices. The models are solved by
the algebraic Bethe ansatz method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08455</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Tandon</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Auton Lab, Carnegie Mellon University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Huggins</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>Auton Lab, Carnegie Mellon University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Dubrawski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Auton Lab, Carnegie Mellon University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Labov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory</affiliation></author></authors><title>Suppressing Background Radiation Using Poisson Principal Component
  Analysis</title><categories>cs.LG physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Performance of nuclear threat detection systems based on gamma-ray
spectrometry often strongly depends on the ability to identify the part of
measured signal that can be attributed to background radiation. We have
successfully applied a method based on Principal Component Analysis (PCA) to
obtain a compact null-space model of background spectra using PCA projection
residuals to derive a source detection score. We have shown the method's
utility in a threat detection system using mobile spectrometers in urban scenes
(Tandon et al 2012). While it is commonly assumed that measured photon counts
follow a Poisson process, standard PCA makes a Gaussian assumption about the
data distribution, which may be a poor approximation when photon counts are
low. This paper studies whether and in what conditions PCA with a Poisson-based
loss function (Poisson PCA) can outperform standard Gaussian PCA in modeling
background radiation to enable more sensitive and specific nuclear threat
detection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08457</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuzhel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sudilovskaya</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards theory of C-symmetries</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of C-symmetry originally appeared in PT-symmetric quantum
mechanics is studied within the Krein spaces framework.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08458</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08458</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Potts</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swailes</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reeks</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>An LES study of turbulent flow over in-line tube-banks and comparison
  with experimental measurements</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>38 pages, 15 Figs</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Turbulent flow across an in-line array of tube-banks with transverse and
longitudinal pitch PT /D = 2.67, and PL /D = 2.31, has been simulated
successfully by Large Eddy Simulation (LES) based on the dynamic Smagorinsky
subgrid scale model (SGS), in which a wall-layer model is used to reduce the
computational cost. The flow structures across the tube-banks were examined
through the normalized Q criterion. The surface pressure characteristics from
the middle cylinder within each column of cylinders are found to agree well
with the existing experimental data, as did also the values of drag and lift
coefficients. These results indicate that cylinders from the second column
experience the minimum drag force and maximum lift force fluctuation. Spectral
analyses were performed for velocity signals sampled behind each middle
cylinder axis, which show that the dominant vortex shedding frequency does not
vary across the tube-banks. On this basis, we also examined the shear layer
instability. Finally, we report auto-correlation functions for streamwise and
cross velocity fluctuations as a function of the spanwise length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08489</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Jinhai</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chunguang</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author></authors><title>The Primary Design of the Ridgetron</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ridgetron is used to accelerate the intense beam for the electron
irradiation. According to the electromagnetic field simulation, the extend
electrode should be cancelled to increase the shunt impedence. The method of
parameter sweeping with constraint variables (PSCV) is used to scan the
mechanical parameters of the cavity to optimize the shunt impedence. The
thermal analysis also has been done for water cooling. The beam dynamic
simulation has been done at last.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08495</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiao-yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhu-an</forenames></author></authors><title>Matched witness for multipartite entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, no figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We transform the way of finding entanglement criterion into two steps: to
obtain necessary criterion of separability by maximizing an algebra function
for a set of characteristic variables of the witness operator and the given
number of partitions, then to obtain the sufficient criterion by minimizing an
algebra function with respect to the characteristic variables for a given
quantum state. Our method avoids the semi-definite program calculation in the
witness operator entanglement detection. The necessary and sufficient criterion
of separability for the three qubit X shaped state is given to illustrate the
procedure of finding the criterion. We give the necessary and sufficient
criteria of the three partite and full separabilities for the four qubit noisy
GHZ state and the four qubit noisy cluster state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08504</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kimm</keyname><forenames>Kyoungtae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiply Phased Traveling BPS Vortex</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the multiply phased current carrying vortex solutions in the U(1)
gauge theory coupled to an $(N+1)$-component SU(N+1) scalar multiplet in the
Bogomolny limit. Our vortex solutions correspond to the static vortex dressed
with traveling waves along the axis of symmetry. What is notable in our vortex
solutions is that the frequencies of traveling waves in each component of the
scalar field can have different values. The energy of the static vortex is
proportional to the topological charge of $CP^N$ model in the BPS limit, and
the multiple phase of the vortex supplies additional energy contribution which
is proportional to the Noether charge associated to the remaining symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08541</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>Mir Vahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Inhomogeneous superconductivity in the presence of time-reversal
  symmetry</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL (Europhysics Letters), Volume 110, Number 4 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/110/47010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new type of non-uniform condensate state in the presence of
time-reversal symmetry. The underlying platform of this state is a corrugated
honeycomb lattice which exhibits an inhomogeneous pseudo magnetic field. Using
the self-consistent tight-binding Bogoliubov-de Gennes formalism, we show that
an s-wave pairing of chiral carriers in the presence of an inhomogeneous pseudo
magnetic field results in a spatially modulated order parameter with the half
wavelength of the corrugation. The manner of modulation depends on the
fundamental directions of the honeycomb lattice, the zigzag and armchair
directions. The stability of this inhomogeneous superconductivity is also
analyzed and possible experimental realization is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08546</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Cai-Dian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Si-Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-body Charmed $B$ Meson Decays In Factorization Assisted Topological
  Amplitude Approach</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure. Talk given at Moriond QCD conference. LA THUILE,
  MARCH 19-26, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the two-body charmed $B$ meson decays $B_{u,d,s} \to D^{(*)}P(V)$
in the factorization assisted topological amplitude approach, where $P(V)$
denoting a light pseudoscalar (vector) meson. Different from the conventional
topological diagram approach, flavor $SU(3)$ symmetry breaking effects are
taken into account. Therefore only four universal nonperturbative parameters
are introduced to describe the contribution from non-factorization diagrams for
all the decay channels. The number of free parameters and the $\chi^2$ per
degree of freedom are both significantly reduced comparing with the
conventional topological diagram approach. With the 4 fitted parameters, we
predict the branching fractions of 120 decay modes induced by both $b\to c$ and
$b\to u$ transitions, which are well consistent with the measured data or to be
tested on the future experiments. We also investigated the relative size of
different topological diagrams, isospin violation, flavor $SU(3)$ symmetry
breaking effects, compared with previous approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08559</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Valkovic</keyname><forenames>Vlado</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical Elements Abundance in the Universe and the Origin of Life</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>21 pages, 1 figure. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1304.3381, arXiv:0901.1149, arXiv:1010.2746, arXiv:astro-ph/0403047 by
  other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Element synthesis which started with p-p chain has resulted in several
specific characteristics including lack of any stable isotope having atomic
masses 5 or 8. The carbon to oxygen ratio is fixed early by the chain of
coincidences. These, remarkably fine-tuned, conditions are responsible for our
own existence and indeed the existence of any carbon based life in the
Universe. Chemical evolution of galaxies reflects in the changes of chemical
composition of stars, interstellar gas and dust. The evolution of chemical
element abundances in a galaxy provides a clock for galactic aging. On the
other hand, the living matter on the planet Earth needs only some elements for
its existence. Compared with element requirements of living matter a hypothesis
is put forward, by accepting the Anthropic Principle, which says: life as we
know, (H-C-N-O) based, relying on the number of bulk and trace elements
originated when two element abundance curves, living matter and galactic,
coincided. This coincidence occurring at particular redshift could indicates
the phase of the Universe when the life originated. It is proposed to look into
redshift region z = 0.5 to 2.5 (approximately t = -5.2x10E9 to -11.3x10E9
years) where many galaxies have been observed and to use these data to study
the evolution of metallicity with respect to the other properties of galaxies
in order to determine the time when universal element abundance curve coincided
with the element abundance curve of LUCA. The characteristic properties of the
latter have been transmitted by the genetic code while the universe element
abundance curve changed as the galaxies aged.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08561</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Trzop</keyname><forenames>Elzbieta</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Daopeng</forenames><affiliation>ICMol</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pi&#xf1;eiro-Lopez</keyname><forenames>Lucia</forenames><affiliation>ICMol</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Valverde-Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>Francisco J.</forenames><affiliation>ICMol</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mu&#xf1;oz</keyname><forenames>M Carmen</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Palatinus</keyname><forenames>Lukas</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;rin</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Cailleau</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Real</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; Antonio</forenames><affiliation>ICMol</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Collet</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames><affiliation>IPR</affiliation></author></authors><title>First step towards a Devil's Staircase in Spin Crossover materials First
  step towards Devil's Staircase in Spin Crossover materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>in Angewandte Chemie International Edition, Wiley-VCH Verlag, 2016</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><doi>10.1002/anie.201602441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The devil is in the detail: Periodic and aperiodic spin-state concentration
waves form during &quot;Devil's staircase&quot;-type spincrossover in a new bimetallic 2D
coordination polymer {Fe[(Hg(SCN)3)2](4,4'-bipy)2}n.The unprecedented
bimetallic 2D coordination polymer {Fe[(Hg(SCN)3)2](4,4'-bipy)2}n exhibits a
thermal high-spin (HS)$low-spin (LS) staircase-like conversion characterized by
a multi-step dependence of the HS molar fraction gHS. Between the fully HS
(gHS=1) and LS (gHS=0) phases, two steps associated with different ordering
appear in terms of spin-state concentration waves (SSCW). On the gHS=0.5 step,
a periodic SSCW forms with a HS-LS-HS-LS sequence. On the gHS=0.34 step, the 4D
superspace crystallography structural refinement reveals an aperiodic SSCW,
with a HS-LS sequence incommensurate with the molecular lattice. The formation
of these different long-range spatially ordered structures of LS and HS states
during the multi-step spin-crossover is discussed within the framework of
&quot;Devil's staircase&quot;-type transitions. Spatially modulated phases are known in
various types of materials but are uniquely related to molecular HS/LS
bistability in this case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08577</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Cooper-Sarkar</keyname><forenames>A. M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abt</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foster</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wing</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myronenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wichmann</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of HERA data at Low Q^2 and Low x</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures, proceedings of XXIV International Workshop on
  Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the HERAPDF2.0 PDF analysis it was noted that the fit $\chi^2$ worsens
significantly at low $Q^2$ for both NLO and NNLO fits. The turn over of the
reduced cross section at low-$x$ and low $Q^2$ due to the contribution of the
longitudinal cross section $F_L$ is also not very well described. In this paper
the prediction for $F_L$ is highlighted and the corresponding extraction of
$F_2$ from the data is further investigated, showing discrepancies with
description of HERAPDF2.0 at low $x$ and $Q^2$. The effect of adding a simple
higher twist term of the form ~$F_L*A/Q^2$ to the description of $F_L$ is
investigated. This results in a significantly better description of the reduced
cross-sections, $F_2$ and $F_L$ at low $x$, $Q^2$ and a significantly lower
$\chi^2$ for the NNLO fit as compared to the NLO fit. This is not the case if
the higher twist term is added to $F_2$
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08578</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruevich</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruevich</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimanovskaya</keyname><forenames>E. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic cycles of Sun-like stars with different levels of coronal and
  chromospheric activity -- comparison with the Sun</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>17 pages, 8 figures in Research in Astronomy and Astrophysics, 2016.
  arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1508.00258</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The atmospheric activity of the Sun and Sun-like stars is analyzed involving
observations from HK-project at the Mount Wilson Observatory, the California
and Carnegie Planet Search Program at the Keck and Lick Observatories and the
Magellan Planet Search Program at the Las Campanas Observatory. We show that
for stars of F, G and K spectral classes, the cyclic activity, similar to the
11-yr solar cycles, is different: it becomes more prominent in K-stars.
Comparative study of Sun-like stars with different levels of the chromospheric
and coronal activity confirms that the Sun belongs to stars with the low level
of the chromospheric activity and stands apart among these stars by the minimum
level of its coronal radiation and the minimum level of its variations of the
photospheric flux.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08584</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Milovanovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Milo&#x161;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medi&#x107;-Simi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Gordana</forenames></author></authors><title>Aesthetical criterion in art and science</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>21 page, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the paper, the authors elaborate some recently published research
concerning the originality of artworks in terms of self-organization in the
complex systems physics. It has been demonstrated that the originality issue
such conceived leads to the criterion of a substantial aesthetics whose
applicability is not restricted to the fine arts domain only covering also
physics, biology, cosmology and other fields construed in the complex systems
terms. Moreover, it is about a truth criterion related to the traditional
personality conception revealing the ontological context transcendent to the
gnoseological dualism of subjective and objective reality that is
characteristic of modern science and humanities. Thus, it is considered to be
an aesthetical criterion substantiating art and science as well as the other
developments of the postmodern era. Its impact to psychology, education,
ecology, culture and other humanities is briefly indicated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08598</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Rustad</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effect of Tetrahedral versus Octahedral Network-Blocking Atom
  Substitutions on Lithium Ion Conduction in LLZO Garnet</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular dynamics calculations are carried out on pure, Al-substituted, and
In-substituted LLZO. The calculations show that the tendency of Al to occupy
the 24d sites in LLZO lithium ion conductors is hypothesized here to negatively
impact ionic conductivity. The room-temperature ionic conductivity of In-LLZO,
in which the In resides at the 48g sites, is predicted to be an order of
magnitude higher than Al-LLZO. Consideration of the simple tetrahedral topology
of the lithium ion conduction network suggests that the increased conductivity
arises because the 48g site sits at a bridge in the lithium ion conduction
network. An immobile ion residing in this location blocks fewer lithium
conduction pathways than an ion, such as Al, that preferentially occupies the
24d site located at a node within the network. In addition, the electronic
structure calculations presented here indicate no large difference in the
stabilities of tetragonal and cubic phases for the aluminum-substituted and
indium-substituted compounds. In both cases, the cubic phase is more stable
than the tetragonal phase. This indicates that it should be possible to make a
cubic In-LLZO phase with significant conductivity enhancement over the cubic
Al-LLZO phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08602</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Herz</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knabner</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling and simulation of coagulation according to DLVO-theory in a
  continuum model for electrolyte solutions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft math.AP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a model of coagulation in electrolyte solutions. In this
paper, the coagulation process is modeled according to DLVO-theory, which is an
atomistic theory. On the other hand, we describe the dynamics in the
electrolyte solutions by the Poisson-Nernst-Planck system, which is a continuum
model. The contribution of this paper is to include the atomistic description
of coagulation based on DLVO-theory in the continuum Poisson-Nernst-Planck
system. Thereby, we involve information from different spatial scales. For this
reason, the presented model accounts for the short-range interactions and the
long-range interactions, which drive the coagulation process. Furthermore,
many-body effects are naturally included as the resulting model is a continuum
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08604</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Nakhaee</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketabi</keyname><forenames>S Ahmad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amiri</keyname><forenames>Saeed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keshtan</keyname><forenames>M Ali M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moallem</keyname><forenames>Mahmoud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahmati</keyname><forenames>Elham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakbaz</keyname><forenames>M Taher</forenames></author></authors><title>Condensed Matter Laboratory: new application for quantum simulation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><msc-class>81-08, 82-08</msc-class><acm-class>J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this paper is to introduce Condensed-Matter-Laboratory (CML)
application for simulating solids and nanostructures and calculating different
properties of them by density functional theory and using Green's function
theory in tight-binding approximation to calculate phononic and spin dependent
or independent electronic properties of different systems. Also, it can be used
for calculating thermodynamic properties of solids and nanostructures using
statistical mechanics. The CML is a cross-platform application with a graphical
user interface design that is user-friendly and easy to work with. This
application is written in c++ and fortran and has parallel processing ability.
To show flexibility of this application some reasons are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08617</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Coecke</keyname><forenames>Bob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kissinger</keyname><forenames>Aleks</forenames></author></authors><title>Categorical Quantum Mechanics II: Classical-Quantum Interaction</title><categories>quant-ph math.CT</categories><comments>54 pp., many figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is the second part of a three-part overview, in which we derive the
category-theoretic backbone of quantum theory from a process ontology, treating
quantum theory as a theory of systems, processes and their interactions. In
this part we focus on classical-quantum interaction.
  Classical and quantum systems are treated as distinct types, of which the
respective behavioural properties are specified in terms of processes and their
compositions. In particular, classicality is witnessed by 'spiders' which fuse
together whenever they connect. We define mixedness and show that pure
processes are extremal in the space of all processes, and we define
entanglement and show that quantum theory indeed exhibits entanglement. We
discuss the classification of tripartite qubit entanglement and show that both
the GHZ-state and the W-state come from spider-like families of processes,
which differ only in how they behave when they are connected by two or more
wires. We define measurements and provide fully-comprehensive descriptions of
several quantum protocols involving classical data flow. Finally, we give a
notion of 'genuine quantumness', from which special processes called 'phase
spiders' arise, and get a first glimpse of quantum non-locality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08622</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08622</id><created>2016-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Bo-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Bright-dark vector soliton solutions for the coupled complex short pulse
  equations in nonlinear optics</title><categories>nlin.PS physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under investigation in this paper are the coupled complex short pulse
equations, which describe the propagation of ultra-short optical pulses in
cubic nonlinear media.Through the Hirota method, bright-dark one- and
two-soliton solutions are obtained. Interactions between two bright or two dark
solitons are verified to be elastic through the asymptotic analysis. With
different parameter conditions of the vector bright-dark two solitons, the
oblique interactions, bound states of solitons and parallel solitons are
analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08623</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08623</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>Ivan I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the maximum Lyapunov exponent of the motion in a chaotic layer</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>JETP Letters, vol. 79, issue 11, pp. 523-528 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/1.1787098</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The maximum Lyapunov exponent (referred to the mean half-period of phase
libration) of the motion in the chaotic layer of a nonlinear resonance subject
to symmetric periodic perturbation, in the limit of infinitely high frequency
of the perturbation, has been numerically estimated by two independent methods.
The newly derived value of this constant is 0.80, with precision presumably
better than 0.01.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08625</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08625</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Nagy</keyname><forenames>Attila L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transition in a double branching annihilating random walk</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><msc-class>60K35, 82C22</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper investigates the long-time behavior of double branching
annihilating random walkers with nearest-neighbor dependent rates. The system
consists of even number of particles which can execute nearest-neighbor random
walk and they can as well give birth in a parity conserving manner to two other
particles with rates $1$ and $b$, respectively, until they meet. Upon meeting,
each of the adjacent particles can branch with rate $p\cdot b$ while it can
annihilate, i.e. hop on, the other particle with rate $p$ for some $0&lt; p\leq
1$. This process first appeared in the article by D. ben Avraham, F. Leyvraz
and S. Redner (Propagation and extinction in branching annihilating random
walks, Phys. Rev. E 50(3), 1994) and can be considered as the extension of
Sudbury's model (The branching annihilating process: an interacting particle
system, Ann. Probab., 18(2), 1990). We prove that in some region of the
parameters $(p,b)$, the process survives with positive probability. Combining
with Sudbury's extinction result it shows a phase transition phenomenon for
this model. In some sense our result also shows the sharpness of the
assumptions of the article by M. Bal\'azs and A. L. Nagy (Dependent double
branching annihilating random walk, Electron. J. Probab., 20(84), 2015). We use
similar arguments that was developed by M. Bramson and L. Gray in their article
titled &quot;The survival of branching annihilating random walk&quot; (Z. Wahrsch. Verw.
Gebiete, 68(4), 1985).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08626</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Szczurek</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klusek-Gawenda</keyname><forenames>Mariola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lebiedowicz</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-by-light scattering in ultraperipheral heavy-ion collisions at the
  LHC</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 7 figures, invited talk at the &quot;Excited QCD 2016, Costa da
  Caparica, Portugal, 7-11 March, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present cross sections for diphoton production in (semi)exclusive $PbPb$
collisions, relevant for the LHC. The calculation is based on equivalent photon
approximation in the impact parameter space. The cross sections for elementary
elastic scattering $\gamma \gamma \to \gamma \gamma$ subprocess are calculated
including two mechanisms: box diagrams with leptons and quarks in the loops and
a mechanism based on vector-meson dominance (VDM-Regge) model with virtual
intermediate vector-like excitations of the photons. We get measureable cross
sections in $PbPb$ collisions. We present many interesting differential
distributions which could be measured by the ALICE, CMS or ATLAS Collaborations
at the LHC. We study whether a separation of box and VDM-Regge contributions is
possible. We find that the cross section for elastic $\gamma \gamma$ scattering
could be measured in the heavy-ion collisions for subprocess energies smaller
than $W_{\gamma\gamma} \approx 15-20$~GeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08637</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Dromard</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bietenholz</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cichy</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wagner</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author></authors><title>Computing the topological susceptibility from fixed topology QCD
  simulations</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>Presented at Excited QCD 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topological susceptibility is an important quantity in QCD, which can be
computed using lattice methods. However, at a fine lattice spacing, or when
using high quality chirally symmetric quarks, algorithms which proceed in small
update steps --- in particular the HMC algorithm --- tend to get stuck in a
single topological sector. In such cases, the computation of the topological
susceptibility is not straightforward. Here, we explore two methods to extract
the topological susceptibility from lattice QCD simulations restricted to a
single topological sector. The first method is based on the correlation
function of the topological charge density, while the second method relies on
measuring the topological charge within spacetime subvolumes. Numerical results
for two-flavor QCD obtained by using both methods are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08679</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Vidal</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Astrakharchik</keyname><forenames>G. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marki&#x107;</keyname><forenames>L. L. Vranje&#x161;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boronat</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>One Dimensional 1H, 2H and 3H</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>19 pages, 7 figures, contribution to special issue in NJP in memory
  of Marvin Girardeau</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 055013 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/5/055013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ground-state properties of one-dimensional electron-spin-polarized
hydrogen $^1$H, deuterium $^2$H, and tritium $^3$H are obtained by means of
quantum Monte Carlo methods. The equations of state of the three isotopes are
calculated for a wide range of linear densities. The pair correlation function
and the static structure factor are obtained and interpreted within the
framework of the Luttinger liquid theory. We report the density dependence of
the Luttinger parameter and use it to identify different physical regimes:
Bogoliubov Bose gas, super-Tonks-Girardeau gas, and quasi-crystal regimes for
bosons; repulsive, attractive Fermi gas, and quasi-crystal regimes for
fermions. We find that the tritium isotope is the one with the richest
behaviour. Our results show unambiguously the relevant role of the isotope mass
in the properties of this quantum system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08689</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Dingxun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>N</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghalamestani</keyname><forenames>Sepideh Gorji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dick</keyname><forenames>Kimberly A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>H Q</forenames></author></authors><title>Schottky barrier and contact resistance of InSb nanowire field effect
  transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 275204 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/27/275204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding of the electrical contact properties of semiconductor nanowire
(NW) field effect transistors (FETs) plays a crucial role in employing
semiconducting NWs as building blocks for future nanoelectronic devices and in
the study of fundamental physics problems. Here, we report on a study of the
contact properties of Ti/Au, a widely used contact metal combination, to
individual InSb NWs via both two-probe and four-probe transport measurements.
We show that a Schottky barrier of height $\Phi_{\rm{SB}}\sim20\ \rm{meV}$ is
present at the metal-InSb NW interfaces and its effective height is gate
tunable. The contact resistance ($R_{\rm{c}}$) in the InSb NWFETs is also
analyzed by magnetotransport measurements at low temperatures. It is found that
$R_{\rm{c}}$ at on-state exhibits a pronounced magnetic field dependent
feature, namely it is increased strongly with increasing magnetic field after
an onset field $B_{\rm{c}}$. A qualitative picture that takes into account
magnetic depopulation of subbands in the NWs is provided to explain the
observation. Our results provide a solid experimental evidence for the presence
of a Schottky barrier at Ti/Au-InSb NW interfaces and can be used as a basis
for design and fabrication of novel InSb NW based nanoelectronic devices and
quantum devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08692</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Hosseini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad-Parsa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soltanian-Zadeh</keyname><forenames>Hamid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akhlaghpoor</keyname><forenames>Shahram</forenames></author></authors><title>Computerized Processing and Analysis of CT Images for Developing a New
  Criterion in COPD Diagnosis</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><comments>http://jims.mui.ac.ir/index.php/jims/article/view/1276</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Isfahan Medical School (I.U.M.S),2012; 29(174)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Background: Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is one of the most
prevalent and dangerous pulmonary diseases in the world. It is forecasted that
COPD will be the third deadly disease in the future. Therefore, developing
non-invasive methods for diagnosis of the disease would be helpful for
physicians and patients.
  Methods: Based on clinical investigations and spirometry tests, ten adult
patients with COPD (6 male and 4 female) with mean age of 49.8 years were
enrolled as the case group. In addition, ten age and sex-matched healthy,
non-COPD individuals (6 male and 4 female) with mean age of 45.4 years were
recruited as the controls. Lung CT-scan images of the subjects were processed
and analyzed by a computer to find a relationship.
  Findings: The elasticity of lung parenchyma variation was obtained with
digital image processing. The normalized average of this pattern was found to
be 21.6% in patients and 40.7% in controls. In addition, normalized mean value
of Hounsfield unit variations in square 10 pixel * 10 pixel windows in the
expiratory images were calculated as a parameter of air-trapping in COPD.
Differences between the groups were shown by student t-test (P &lt; 0.05).
  Conclusion: This study showed that the variation of lung parenchyma
elasticity and Hounsfield units are found by processing and analysis of the
full inspiration and expiration images. These factors can be used as criteria
in diagnosis of COPD. Moreover, the severity of the disease can be presented by
the proposed method.
  Keywords: Air-trapping, Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, Image
processing and analysis, CT-scan lung images
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08703</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08703</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kuic</keyname><forenames>Domagoj</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximum information entropy principle and the interpretation of
  probabilities in statistical mechanics - a short review</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, revtex4; The final publication is available at Springer via
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1140/epjb/e2016-70175-6</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2016) 89: 124</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70175-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper an alternative approach to statistical mechanics based on the
maximum information entropy principle (MaxEnt) is examined, specifically its
close relation with the Gibbs method of ensembles. It is shown that the MaxEnt
formalism is the logical extension of the Gibbs formalism of equilibrium
statistical mechanics that is entirely independent of the frequentist
interpretation of probabilities only as factual (i.e. experimentally
verifiable) properties of the real world. Furthermore, we show that,
consistently with the law of large numbers, the relative frequencies of the
ensemble of systems prepared under identical conditions (i.e. identical
constraints) actually correspond to the MaxEnt probabilites in the limit of a
large number of systems in the ensemble. This result implies that the
probabilities in statistical mechanics can be interpreted, independently of the
frequency interpretation, on the basis of the maximum information entropy
principle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08705</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08705</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Transtrum</keyname><forenames>Mark K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Manifold boundaries give &quot;gray-box&quot; approximations of complex models</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss a method of parameter reduction in complex models known as the
Manifold Boundary Approximation Method (MBAM). This approach, based on a
geometric interpretation of statistics, maps the model reduction problem to a
geometric approximation problem. It operates iteratively, removing one
parameter at a time, by approximating a high-dimension, but thin manifold by
its boundary. Although the method makes no explicit assumption about the
functional form of the model, it does require that the model manifold exhibit a
hierarchy of boundaries, i.e., faces, edges, corners, hyper-corners, etc. We
empirically show that a variety of model classes have this curious feature,
making them amenable to MBAM. These model classes include models composed of
elementary functions (e.g., rational functions, exponentials, and partition
functions), a variety of dynamical system (e.g., chemical and biochemical
kinetics, Linear Time Invariant (LTI) systems, and compartment models), network
models (e.g., Bayesian networks, Markov chains, artificial neural networks, and
Markov random fields), log-linear probability distributions, and models with
symmetries. We discuss how MBAM recovers many common approximation methods for
each model class and discuss potential pitfalls and limitations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08724</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Zubkov</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Absence of equilibrium chiral magnetic effect</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Latex, 18 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1603.03665</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D93 (2016) no.10, 105036</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.105036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the $3+1$ D equilibrium chiral magnetic effect (CME). We apply
derivative expansion to the Wigner transform of the two - point Green function.
This technique allows us to express the response of electric current to
external electromagnetic field strength through the momentum space topological
invariant. We consider the wide class of the lattice regularizations of quantum
field theory (that includes, in particular, the regularization with Wilson
fermions) and also certain lattice models of solid state physics (including
those of Dirac semimetals). It appears, that in these models the mentioned
topological invariant vanishes identically at nonzero chiral chemical
potential. That means, that the bulk equilibrium CME is absent in those
systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08747</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Iurov</keyname><forenames>Andrii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gumbs</keyname><forenames>Godfrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Danhong</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature-dependent collective effects for silicene, germanene and
  monolayer black phosphorus</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have calculated numerically electron exchange, correlation energies and
dynamical polarization function for newly discovered silicene, germanene and
black phosphorus (BP), consisting of puckered layers of elemental phosphorus
atoms, broadening the range of two-dimensional (2D) materials at various
temperatures. As a matter of fact, monolayer BP, produced by mechanical and
liquid exfoliation techniques, has been predicted to be an insulator with a
large energy splitting 1.6 eV for the quasiparticle band structure. We compare
the dependence of these energies on the chemical potential, field-induced gap
and the temperature and concluded that in many cases they behave qualitatively
similarly, i.e., increasing with the doping, decreasing significantly at
elevated temperatures, and displaying different dependence on the asymmetry gap
at various temperatures. Furthermore, we used the dynamical polarizability to
investigate the new &quot;split&quot; plasmon branches in the puckered lattices and
predict a unique splitting, different from that in gapped graphene, for various
energy gaps. Our results are crucial for stimulating electronic, transport and
collective studies of these novel materials, as well as for enhancing
silicene-based fabrication and technologies for photovoltaics and transistor
devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08755</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panwar</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khanna</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganguly</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author></authors><title>Space Charge Limited Current with Self-heating in
  Pr$_{0.7}$Ca$_{0.3}$MnO$_3$ based RRAM</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 5 figures, Submitted to Applied Physics Letters</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Space Charge Limited Current (SCLC) based conduction has been identified for
PCMO-based RRAM devices based on the observation that $I \propto V^{\alpha}$
where $\alpha \approx 2$. A critical feature of the IV characteristics is a
sharp rise in current ($\alpha \gg 2$) which has been widely attributed to
trap-filled limit (TFL) followed by an apparent trap-free SCLC conduction. In
this paper, we show by TCAD analysis that trap-filled limit (TFL) is
insufficient to explain the sharp current rise ($\alpha \gg 2$). As an
alternative, we propose a shallow trap SCLC model with selfheating effect based
thermal runaway to explain the sharp current rise followed by a series
resistance dominated regime. Experimental results over a range of
25{\deg}C-125{\deg}C demonstrate all 4 regimes (i) Ohmic ($\alpha = 1$), (ii)
shallow trap SCLC ($\alpha \approx 2$), (iii) current shoot up ($\alpha \gg 2$)
and (iv) series resistance ($\alpha = 1$). Further, TCAD simulations with
thermal modeling are able to match the experimental IV characteristics in all
the regimes. Thus, a current conduction mechanism in PCMO-based RRAM supported
by detailed TCAD model is presented. Such a model is essential for further
quantitative understanding and design for PCMO-based RRAM.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08756</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Salehi</keyname><forenames>Saboura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saffarzadeh</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic defect states in monolayers of MoS$_2$ and WS$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Surface Science 651, 215 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.susc.2016.05.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The influence of atomic vacancy defects at different concentrations on
electronic properties of MoS$_2$ and WS$_2$ monolayers is studied by means of
Slater-Koster tight-binding model with non-orthogonal $sp^3d^5$ orbitals and
including the spin-orbit coupling. The presence of vacancy defects induces
localized states in the bandgap of pristine MoS$_2$ and WS$_2$, which have
potential to modify the electronic structure of the systems, depending on the
type and concentration of the defects. It is shown that although the
contribution of metal (Mo or W) $d$ orbitals is dominant in the formation of
midgap states, the sulphur $p$ and $d$ orbitals have also considerable
contribution in the localized states, when metal defects are introduced. Our
results suggest that Mo and W defects can turn the monolayers into p-type
semiconductors, while the sulphur defects make the system a n-type
semiconductor, in agreement with ab initio results and experimental
observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08765</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08765</id><created>2016-05-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>Ivan I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the recurrence and Lyapunov time scales of the motion near the chaos
  border</title><categories>nlin.CD astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Letters A, v. 241, pp. 53-60 (1998)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0375-9601(98)00093-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conditions for the emergence of a statistical relationship between $T_r$, the
chaotic transport (recurrence) time, and $T_L$, the local Lyapunov time (the
inverse of the numerically measured largest Lyapunov characteristic exponent),
are considered for the motion inside the chaotic layer around the separatrix of
a nonlinear resonance. When numerical values of the Lyapunov exponents are
measured on a time interval not greater than $T_r$, the relationship is shown
to resemble the quadratic one. This tentatively explains numerical results
presented in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0309212</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-30</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0309212</id><created>2003-09-29</created><updated>2016-05-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carteret</keyname><forenames>Hilary A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact interferometers for the concurrence and residual 3-tangle</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages PDFLaTeX (format changed; older versions were in revtex4) 6
  figures (now in pdf format, older versions were in encapsulated postscript).
  v7: small error in circuits corrected, and presentation improved. Old
  affiliation used in paper as that's where I was at the time. (The date is
  from the last change to the physics content. The files got lost in the
  shuffle when moving to a new laptop.)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we describe a set of circuits that can measure the concurrence
of a two qubit density matrix without requiring the deliberate addition of
noise. We then extend these methods to obtain a circuit to measure one type of
three qubit entanglement for pure states, namely the 3-tangle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
