<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:15:43Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-05-28" from="2016-05-27" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.2307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.2307</id><created>2011-09-11</created><updated>2012-02-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qijin</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of the particle-hole channel on BCS--Bose-Einstein condensation
  crossover in atomic Fermi gases</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Substantial rewriting of the theory section and the discussion of
  Tc/E_F at unitarity</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 25772 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep25772</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  BCS--Bose-Einstein condensation (BEC) crossover is effected by increasing
pairing strength between fermions from weak to strong in the particle-particle
channel. Here we study the effect of the particle-hole channel on the zero $T$
gap $\Delta(0)$, superfluid transition temperature $T_{\text{c}}$ and the
pseudogap at $T_{\text{c}}$, as well as the mean-field ratio
$2\Delta(0)/T_{\text{c}}^{\text{MF}}$, from BCS through BEC regimes, in the
framework of a pairing fluctuation theory which includes self-consistently the
contributions of finite-momentum pairs. These pairs necessarily lead to a
pseudogap in single particle excitation spectrum above and below
$T_{\text{c}}$. We sum over the infinite particle-hole ladder diagrams so that
the particle-particle and particle-hole $T$-matrices are entangled with each
other. We find that the particle-hole susceptibility has a complex dynamical
structure, with strong momentum and frequency dependencies, and is sensitive to
temperature, gap size and interaction strength. We conclude that neglecting the
self-energy feedback causes a serious over-estimate of the particle-hole
susceptibility. In the BCS limit, the particle-hole channel effect may be
approximated by the same reduction in the overall pairing strength so that the
ratio $2\Delta(0)/T_{\text{c}}$ is unaffected, in agreement with Gor'kov
\textit{et al.} to the leading order. However, the effect becomes more complex
and pronounced in the crossover regime, where the particle-hole susceptibility
is reduced by both a smaller Fermi surface and a big (pseudo)gap. Deep in the
BEC regime, the particle-hole channel contributions drop to zero. We propose
that precision measurements of the magnetic field for Feshbach resonance at low
temperatures as a function of density can be used to quantify the particle-hole
susceptibility and test different theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.2900</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.2900</id><created>2011-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kramer</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectra of Harmonium in a magnetic field using an initial value
  representation of the semiclassical propagator</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Math. Theor 44, 445309 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/44/44/445309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For two Coulombically interacting electrons in a quantum dot with harmonic
confinement and a constant magnetic field, we show that time-dependent
semiclassical calculations using the Herman-Kluk initial value representation
of the propagator lead to eigenvalues of the same accuracy as WKB calculations
with Langer correction. The latter are restricted to integrable systems,
however, whereas the time-dependent initial value approach allows for
applications to high-dimensional, possibly chaotic dynamics and is extendable
to arbitrary shapes of the potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.6409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.6409</id><created>2012-08-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Diener</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weissbarth</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>R&#xfc;diger</forenames></author></authors><title>Obtaining Maxwell's equations heuristically</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><journal-ref>American Journal of Physics 81, 120 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1119/1.4768196</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from the experimental fact that a moving charge experiences the
Lorentz force and applying the fundamental principles of simplicity (first
order derivatives only) and linearity (superposition principle), we show that
the structure of the microscopic Maxwell equations for the electromagnetic
fields can be deduced heuristically by using the transformation properties of
the fields under space inversion and time reversal. Using the experimental
facts of charge conservation and that electromagnetic waves propagate with the
speed of light together with Galileo invariance of the Lorentz force allows us
to introduce arbitrary electrodynamic units naturally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.2899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.2899</id><created>2013-04-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chan</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microwave induced elastic deformation of a metallic thin film</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages,3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. D Appl. Phys. 46, 395104 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0022-3727/46/39/395104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The microwave induced elastic deformation of a metallic thin film is computed
numerically and we found that the deformation can be significantly enhanced at
resonance. We show that an analytical transmission line model can reproduce the
numerical results almost quantitatively and at the same time reveal the
underlying physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1307.7669</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1307.7669</id><created>2013-07-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Vaikuntanathan</keyname><forenames>Suriyanarayanan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geissler</keyname><forenames>Phillip L</forenames></author></authors><title>Putting water on a lattice: The importance of long wavelength density
  fluctuations in theories of hydrophobic and interfacial phenomena</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figure (main text)</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.112.020603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physics of air-water interfaces plays a central role in modern theories
of the hydrophobic effect. Implementing these theories, however, has been
hampered by the difficulty of addressing fluctuations in the shape of such soft
interfaces. We show that this challenge is a fundamental consequence of mapping
long wavelength density variations onto discrete degrees of freedom. Drawing
from studies of surface roughness in lattice models, we account for the
resulting nonlinearities simply but accurately. Simulations show that this
approach captures complex solvation behaviors quantitatively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.6707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.6707</id><created>2014-05-26</created><updated>2014-06-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lawyer</keyname><forenames>Glenn</forenames></author></authors><title>Understanding the spreading power of all nodes in a network: a
  continuous-time perspective</title><categories>cs.SI cs.CY physics.soc-ph</categories><doi>10.1038/srep08665</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Centrality measures such as the degree, k-shell, or eigenvalue centrality can
identify a network's most influential nodes, but are rarely usefully accurate
in quantifying the spreading power of the vast majority of nodes which are not
highly influential. The spreading power of all network nodes is better
explained by considering, from a continuous-time epidemiological perspective,
the distribution of the force of infection each node generates. The resulting
metric, the \textit{expected force}, accurately quantifies node spreading power
under all primary epidemiological models across a wide range of archetypical
human contact networks. When node power is low, influence is a function of
neighbor degree. As power increases, a node's own degree becomes more
important. The strength of this relationship is modulated by network structure,
being more pronounced in narrow, dense networks typical of social networking
and weakening in broader, looser association networks such as the Internet. The
expected force can be computed independently for individual nodes, making it
applicable for networks whose adjacency matrix is dynamic, not well specified,
or overwhelmingly large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.2290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.2290</id><created>2014-06-09</created><updated>2014-06-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berkovits</keyname><forenames>Nathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jusinskas</keyname><forenames>Renann Lipinski</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-Cone Analysis of the Pure Spinor Formalism for the Superstring</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages. Added reference to the paper of Mukhopadhyay</comments><journal-ref>JHEP08(2014)102</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP08(2014)102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Physical states of the superstring can be described in light-cone gauge by
acting with transverse bosonic $\alpha_{-n}^{j}$ and fermionic
$\bar{q}_{-n}^{\dot{a}}$ operators on an $SO\left(8\right)$-covariant
superfield where $j,\dot{a}=1$ to $8$. In the pure spinor formalism, these
states are described in an $SO\left(9,1\right)$-covariant manner by the
cohomology of the BRST charge $Q=\frac{1}{2\pi
i}\oint\lambda^{\alpha}d_{\alpha}$. In this paper, a similarity transformation
is found which simplifies the form of $Q$ and maps the light-cone description
of the superstring vertices into DDF-like operators in the cohomology of $Q$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.0717</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.0717</id><created>2014-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Lulu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woolf</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>Alejandro W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capasso</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author></authors><title>Absolute Position Total Internal Reflection Microscopy with an Optical
  Tweezer</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages. Submitted for peer review 8/20/2014</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 111.52 (2014):
  E5609-E5615</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1422178112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A non-invasive, in-situ calibration method for Total Internal Reflection
Microscopy (TIRM) based on optical tweezing is presented which greatly expands
the capabilities of this technique. We show that by making only simple
modifications to the basic TIRM sensing setup and procedure, a probe particle's
absolute position relative to a dielectric interface may be known with better
than 10 nm precision out to a distance greater than 1 $\mu$m from the surface.
This represents an approximate 10x improvement in error and 3x improvement in
measurement range over conventional TIRM methods. The technique's advantage is
in the direct measurement of the probe particle's scattering intensity vs.
height profile in-situ, rather than relying on calculations or inexact system
analogs for calibration. To demonstrate the improved versatility of the TIRM
method in terms of tunability, precision, and range, we show our results for
the hindered near-wall diffusion coefficient for a spherical dielectric
particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.5324</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.5324</id><created>2014-10-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sin</keyname><forenames>Celine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiarugi</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valleriani</keyname><forenames>Angelo</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-molecule modeling of mRNA degradation by miRNA: Lessons from data</title><categories>q-bio.SC physics.bio-ph q-bio.BM q-bio.MN</categories><comments>It contains also the Supplementary Materials as appendix A</comments><doi>10.1186/1752-0509-9-S3-S2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experimental results on the effect of miRNA on the decay of its target
mRNA have been analyzed against a previously hypothesized single molecule
degradation pathway. According to that hypothesis, the silencing complex
(miRISC) first interacts with its target mRNA and then recruits the protein
complexes associated with NOT1 and PAN3 to trigger deadenylation (and
subsequent degradation) of the target mRNA. Our analysis of the experimental
decay patterns allowed us to refine the structure of the degradation pathways
at the single molecule level. Surprisingly, we found that if the previously
hypothesized network was correct, only about 7% of the target mRNA would be
regulated by the miRNA mechanism, which is inconsistent with the available
knowledge. Based on systematic data analysis, we propose the alternative
hypothesis that NOT1 interacts with miRISC before binding to the target mRNA.
Moreover, we show that when miRISC binds alone to the target mRNA, the mRNA is
degraded more slowly, probably through a deadenylation-independent pathway. The
new biochemical pathway we propose both fits the data and paves the way for new
experimental work to identify new interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.03296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.03296</id><created>2015-02-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Altmann</keyname><forenames>Eduardo G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerlach</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical laws in linguistics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.LG physics.data-an</categories><comments>Proceedings of the Flow Machines Workshop: Creativity and
  Universality in Language, Paris, June 18 to 20, 2014</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-24403-7_2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Zipf's law is just one out of many universal laws proposed to describe
statistical regularities in language. Here we review and critically discuss how
these laws can be statistically interpreted, fitted, and tested (falsified).
The modern availability of large databases of written text allows for tests
with an unprecedent statistical accuracy and also a characterization of the
fluctuations around the typical behavior. We find that fluctuations are usually
much larger than expected based on simplifying statistical assumptions (e.g.,
independence and lack of correlations between observations).These
simplifications appear also in usual statistical tests so that the large
fluctuations can be erroneously interpreted as a falsification of the law.
Instead, here we argue that linguistic laws are only meaningful (falsifiable)
if accompanied by a model for which the fluctuations can be computed (e.g., a
generative model of the text). The large fluctuations we report show that the
constraints imposed by linguistic laws on the creativity process of text
generation are not as tight as one could expect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00526</id><created>2015-03-02</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>Indranil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rom&#xe3;o</keyname><forenames>Nuno M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A no-go theorem for nonabelionic statistics in gauged linear
  sigma-models</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Final version; to appear in Adv. Theo. Math. Phys</comments><msc-class>14D21, 14H81, 58Z05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gauged linear sigma-models at critical coupling on Riemann surfaces yield
self-dual field theories, their classical vacua being described by the vortex
equations. For local models with structure group ${\rm U}(r)$, we give a
description of the vortex moduli spaces in terms of a fibration over symmetric
products of the base surface $\Sigma$, which we assume to be compact. Then we
show that all these fibrations induce isomorphisms of fundamental groups. A
consequence is that all the moduli spaces of multivortices in this class of
models have abelian fundamental groups. We give an interpretation of this fact
as a no-go theorem for the realization of nonabelions through the ground states
of a supersymmetric version (topological via an A-twist) of these gauged
sigma-models. This analysis is based on a semi-classical approximation of the
QFTs via supersymmetric quantum mechanics on their classical moduli spaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06200</id><created>2015-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kutepov</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Full self-consistency versus quasiparticle self-consistency in
  diagrammatic approaches: Exactly solvable two-site Hubbard Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 27 (2015) 315603</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/27/31/315603</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-consistent solutions of Hedin's diagrammatic theory equations (HE) for
the two-site Hubbard Model (HM) have been studied. They have been found for
three-point vertices of increasing complexity ($\Gamma=1$ (GW approximation),
$\Gamma_{1}$ from the first order perturbation theory, and exact vertex
$\Gamma_{E}$). The comparison is being made when an additional quasiparticle
(QP) approximation for the Green function is applied during the self-consistent
iterative solving of HE and when QP approximation is not applied. The results
obtained with the exact vertex are directly related to the presently open
question - which approximation is more advantageous for future implementations
- GW+DMFT or QPGW+DMFT. It is shown that in the regime of strong correlations
only originally proposed GW+DMFT scheme is able to provide reliable results.
Vertex corrections based on Perturbation Theory (PT) systematically improve the
GW results when full self-consistency is applied. The application of the QP
self-consistency combined with PT vertex corrections shows similar problems to
the case when the exact vertex is applied combined with QP sc. The analysis of
Ward Identity violation is performed for all studied in this work
approximations and its relation to the general accuracy of the schemes used is
provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03685</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03685</id><created>2015-04-14</created><updated>2015-06-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>van de Voort</keyname><forenames>Freeke</forenames><affiliation>UC Berkeley</affiliation><affiliation>ASIAA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>Timothy A.</forenames><affiliation>Hertfordshire</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Keres</keyname><forenames>Dusan</forenames><affiliation>UCSD</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Quataert</keyname><forenames>Eliot</forenames><affiliation>UC Berkeley</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Faucher-Giguere</keyname><forenames>Claude-Andre</forenames><affiliation>Northwestern</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Philip F.</forenames><affiliation>Caltech</affiliation></author></authors><title>The creation and persistence of a misaligned gas disc in a simulated
  early-type galaxy</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS. Revised
  version: minor changes. A movie of the evolution of the gas disc can be
  viewed at http://astro.berkeley.edu/~freeke/misalign.html</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 2015, Volume 451, Issue 3, pp.3269-3277</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive early-type galaxies commonly have gas discs which are kinematically
misaligned with the stellar component. These discs feel a torque from the stars
and the angular momentum vectors are expected to align quickly. We present
results on the evolution of a misaligned gas disc in a cosmological simulation
of a massive early-type galaxy from the Feedback In Realistic Environments
project. This galaxy experiences a merger which, together with a strong
galactic wind, removes most of the original gas disc. The galaxy subsequently
reforms a gas disc through accretion of cold gas, but it is initially 120
degrees misaligned with the stellar rotation axis. This misalignment persists
for about 2 Gyr before the gas-star misalignment angle drops below 20 degrees.
The time it takes for the gaseous and stellar components to align is much
longer than previously thought, because the gas disc is accreting a significant
amount of mass for about 1.5 Gyr after the merger, during which the angular
momentum change induced by accreted gas dominates over that induced by stellar
torques. Once the gas accretion rate has decreased sufficiently, the gas disc
decouples from the surrounding halo gas and realigns with the stellar component
in about 6 dynamical times. During the late evolution of the misaligned gas
disc, the centre aligns faster than the outskirts, resulting in a warped disc.
We discuss the observational consequences of the long survival of our
misaligned gas disc and how our results can be used to calibrate merger rate
estimates from observed gas misalignments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05743</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05743</id><created>2015-04-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Lawyer</keyname><forenames>Glenn</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochasticity in pandemic spread over the World Airline Network
  explained by local flight connections</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>article text: 6 pages, 5 figures, 28 references</comments><doi>10.1186/s12879-016-1350-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive growth in human mobility has dramatically increased the risk and rate
of pandemic spread. Macro-level descriptors of the topology of the World
Airline Network (WAN) explains middle and late stage dynamics of pandemic
spread mediated by this network, but necessarily regard early stage variation
as stochastic. We propose that much of early stage variation can be explained
by appropriately characterizing the local topology surrounding the debut
location of an outbreak. We measure for each airport the expected force of
infection (AEF) which a pandemic originating at that airport would generate. We
observe, for a subset of world airports, the minimum transmission rate at which
a disease becomes pandemically competent at each airport. We also observe, for
a larger subset, the time until a pandemically competent outbreak achieves
pandemic status given its debut location. Observations are generated using a
highly sophisticated metapopulation reaction-diffusion simulator under a
disease model known to well replicate the 2009 influenza pandemic. The
robustness of the AEF measure to model misspecification is examined by
degrading the network model. AEF powerfully explains pandemic risk, showing
correlation of 0.90 to the transmission level needed to give a disease pandemic
competence, and correlation of 0.85 to the delay until an outbreak becomes a
pandemic. The AEF is robust to model misspecification. For 97% of airports,
removing 15% of airports from the model changes their AEF metric by less than
1%. Appropriately summarizing the size, shape, and diversity of an airport's
local neighborhood in the WAN accurately explains much of the macro-level
stochasticity in pandemic outcomes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06599</id><created>2015-04-24</created><updated>2016-02-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Epping</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kampermann</keyname><forenames>Hermann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bru&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>Dagmar</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-scale quantum networks based on graphs</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables, revised text and new results regarding
  the optimisation of quantum networks</comments><journal-ref>NewJ.Phys.18 (2016) 053036</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/5/053036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Society relies and depends increasingly on information exchange and
communication. In the quantum world, security and privacy is a built-in feature
for information processing. The essential ingredient for exploiting these
quantum advantages is the resource of entanglement, which can be shared between
two or more parties. The distribution of entanglement over large distances
constitutes a key challenge for current research and development. Due to losses
of the transmitted quantum particles, which typically scale exponentially with
the distance, intermediate quantum repeater stations are needed. Here we show
how to generalise the quantum repeater concept to the multipartite case, by
fully describing large-scale quantum networks, i.e. network nodes and their
long-distance links, in the language of graphs and graph states. This unifying
approach comprises both the distribution of multipartite entanglement across
the network, and the protection against errors via encoding. The correspondence
to graph states also provides a tool for optimising the architecture of quantum
networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.02323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.02323</id><created>2015-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Murugan</keyname><forenames>Arvind</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaikuntanathan</keyname><forenames>Suriyanarayanan</forenames></author></authors><title>Biological implications of dynamical phases in non-equilibrium networks</title><categories>q-bio.MN cond-mat.stat-mech physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>10 figures. Submitted to the Journal of Statistical Physics (special
  issue on &quot;Information Processing in Living Systems&quot;)</comments><doi>10.1007/s10955-015-1445-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biology achieves novel functions like error correction, ultra-sensitivity and
accurate concentration measurement at the expense of free energy through
Maxwell Demon-like mechanisms. The design principles and free energy trade-offs
have been studied for a variety of such mechanisms. In this review, we
emphasize a perspective based on dynamical phases that can explain
commonalities shared by these mechanisms. Dynamical phases are defined by
typical trajectories executed by non-equilibrium systems in the space of
internal states. We find that coexistence of dynamical phases can have dramatic
consequences for function vs free energy cost trade-offs. Dynamical phases can
also provide an intuitive picture of the design principles behind such
biological Maxwell Demons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05333</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05333</id><created>2015-06-17</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Budi&#x161;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Marko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siegmund</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Son</keyname><forenames>Doan Thai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author></authors><title>Mesochronic classification of trajectories in incompressible 3D vector
  fields over finite times</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>37 pages, 14 figures, 4 tables</comments><msc-class>37N10, 37B55, 37Exx</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mesochronic velocity is the average of the velocity field along
trajectories generated by the same velocity field over a time interval of
finite duration. In this paper we classify initial conditions of trajectories
evolving in incompressible vector fields according to the character of motion
of material around the trajectory. In particular, we provide calculations that
can be used to determine the number of expanding directions and the presence of
rotation from the characteristic polynomial of the Jacobian matrix of
mesochronic velocity. In doing so, we show that (a) the mesochronic velocity
can be used to characterize dynamical deformation of three-dimensional volumes,
(b) the resulting mesochronic analysis is a finite-time extension of the
Okubo--Weiss--Chong analysis of incompressible velocity fields, (c) the
two-dimensional mesochronic analysis from Mezic et al. \emph{A New Mixing
Diagnostic and Gulf Oil Spill Movement}, Science 330, (2010), 486-489, extends
to three-dimensional state spaces. Theoretical considerations are further
supported by numerical computations performed for a dynamical system arising in
fluid mechanics, the unsteady Arnold--Beltrami--Childress (ABC) flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05727</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05727</id><created>2015-06-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Beiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Dohun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuhrer</keyname><forenames>Michael S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Ichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greene</keyname><forenames>Richard L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of electronic states in n-type copper oxide superconductor via
  electric double layer gating</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 figures, SI not included. Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 26642 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the discovery of n-type copper oxide superconductors, the evolution of
electron- and hole-bands and its relation to the superconductivity have been
seen as a key factor in unveiling the mechanism of high-Tc superconductors. So
far, the occurrence of electrons and holes in n-type copper oxides has been
achieved by chemical doping, pressure, and/or deoxygenation. However, the
observed electronic properties are blurred by the concomitant effects such as
change of lattice structure, disorder, etc. Here, we report on successful
tuning the electronic band structure of n-type Pr2-xCexCuO4 (x = 0.15)
ultrathin films, via the electric double layer transistor technique. Abnormal
transport properties, such as multiple sign reversals of Hall resistivity in
normal and mixed states, have been revealed within an electrostatic field in
range of -2 V to +2 V, as well as varying the temperature and magnetic field.
In the mixed state, the intrinsic anomalous Hall conductivity invokes the
contribution of both electron and hole-bands as well as the energy dependent
density of states near the Fermi level. The two-band model can also describe
the normal state transport properties well, whereas the carrier concentrations
of electrons and holes are always enhanced or depressed simultaneously in
electric fields. This is in contrast to the scenario of Fermi surface
reconstruction by antiferromagnetism, where an anti-correlation between
electrons and holes is commonly expected. Our findings paint the picture where
Coulomb repulsion plays an important role in the evolution of the electronic
states in n-type cuprate superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01870</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Droz-Vincent</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic two-boson system in presence of electromagnetic plane waves</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, no figure. Revised version; two errors corrected; Section
  2.2 clarified. To be published in Int.J.of Theor.Phys</comments><doi>10.1007/s10773-016-3040-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relativistic two-body problem is considered for spinless particles
subject to an external macroscopic electromagnetic field. When this field is
made of the monochromatic superposition of two counter-propagating plane waves
(and provided the mutual interaction between particles is known), it is
possible to write down explicitly a pair of coupled wave equations
(corresponding to a pair of mass-shell constraints) which takes into account
also the field contribution. These equations are manifestly covariant;
constants of the motion are exhibited, so one ends up with a reduced problem
involving five degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03756</id><created>2015-08-15</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gibbon</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krstulovic</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandit</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Politano</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ponty</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pouquet</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stawarz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Depletion of Nonlinearity in Magnetohydrodynamic Turbulence: Insights
  from Analysis and Simulations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn nlin.CD</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 043104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.043104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We build on recent developments in the study of fluid turbulence [Gibbon
\textit{et al.} Nonlinearity 27, 2605 (2014)] to define suitably scaled,
order-$m$ moments, $D_m^{\pm}$, of $\omega^\pm= \omega \pm j$, where $\omega$
and $j$ are, respectively, the vorticity and current density in
three-dimensional magnetohydrodynamics (MHD). We show by mathematical analysis,
for unit magnetic Prandtl number $P_M$, how these moments can be used to
identify three possible regimes for solutions of the MHD equations; these
regimes are specified by inequalities for $D_m^{\pm}$ and $D_1^{\pm}$. We then
compare our mathematical results with those from our direct numerical
simulations (DNSs) and thus demonstrate that 3D MHD turbulence is like its
fluid-turbulence counterpart insofar as all solutions, which we have
investigated, remain in \textit{only one of these regimes}; this regime has
depleted nonlinearity. We examine the implications of our results for the
exponents $q^{\pm}$ that characterize the power-law dependences of the energy
spectra $\mathcal{E}^{\pm}(k)$ on the wave number $k$, in the inertial range of
scales. We also comment on (a) the generalization of our results to the case
$P_M \neq 1$ and (b) the relation between $D_m^{\pm}$ and the order-$m$ moments
of gradients of hydrodynamic fields, which are used in characterizing
intermittency in turbulent flows.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.04763</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.04763</id><created>2015-08-19</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Piattella</keyname><forenames>Oliver F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lensing in the McVittie metric</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Mistakes corrected. Conclusions completely
  changed</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D93 (2016) no.2, 024020</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of the cosmological expansion on the bending of
light due to an isolated point-like mass. We adopt McVittie metric as the model
for the geometry of the lens. Assuming a constant Hubble factor we find an
analytic expression involving the bending angle, which turns out to be
unaffected by the cosmological expansion at the leading order.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.05917</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.05917</id><created>2015-08-24</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Loft</keyname><forenames>N. J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kristensen</keyname><forenames>L. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomsen</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinner</keyname><forenames>N. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comparing models for the ground state energy of a trapped
  one-dimensional Fermi gas with a single impurity</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables, final version</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. B: At. Mol. Opt. Phys. 49 125305 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-4075/49/12/125305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the local density approximation approach to calculating the ground
state energy of a one-dimensional Fermi gas containing a single impurity, and
compare the results with exact numerical values that we have for up to 11
particles for general interaction strengths and up to 30 particles in the
strongly interacting case. We also calculate the contact coefficient in the
strongly interacting regime. The different theoretical predictions are compared
to recent experimental results with few-atom systems. Firstly, we find that the
local density approximation suffers from great ambiguity in the few-atom
regime, yet it works surprisingly well for some models. Secondly, we find that
the strong interaction theories quickly break down when the number of particles
increase or the interaction strength decreases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06678</id><created>2015-08-26</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Study of B meson production in pPb collisions at sqrt(s_NN) = 5.02 TeV
  using exclusive hadronic decays</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. All figures can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/HIN-14-004/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-HIN-14-004, CERN-PH-EP-2015-209</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116 (2016) 032301</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.032301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production cross sections of the B+, B0, and B0s mesons, and of their
charge conjugates, are measured via exclusive hadronic decays in pPb collisions
at the center-of-mass energy sqrt(s_NN) = 5.02 TeV with the CMS detector at the
CERN LHC. The data set used for this analysis corresponds to an integrated
luminosity of 34.6 inverse nanobarns. The production cross sections are
measured in the transverse momentum range between 10 and 60 GeV/c. No
significant modification is observed compared to proton-proton perturbative QCD
calculations scaled by the number of incoherent nucleon-nucleon collisions.
These results provide a baseline for the study of in-medium b quark energy loss
in PbPb collisions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00848</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00848</id><created>2015-09-02</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Petreska</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohanesjan</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pejov</keyname><forenames>Ljupco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocarev</keyname><forenames>Ljupco</forenames></author></authors><title>Tunneling of electrons via rotor-stator molecular interfaces: combined
  ab initio and model study</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Chem. Phys., 473 (2016), p. 32</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.04.013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tunneling of electrons through rotor-stator anthracene aldehyde molecular
interfaces is studied with a combined ab initio and model approach. Molecular
electronic structure calculated from first principles is utilized to model
different shapes of tunneling barriers. Together with a rectangular barrier, we
also consider a sinusoidal shape that captures the effects of the molecular
internal structure more realistically. Quasiclassical approach with the
Simmons' formula for current density is implemented. Special attention is paid
on conformational dependence of the tunneling current. Our results confirm that
the presence of the side aldehyde group enhances the interesting electronic
properties of the pure anthracene molecule, making it a bistable system with
geometry dependent transport properties. We also investigate the transition
voltage and we show that confirmation dependent field emission could be
observed in these molecular interfaces at realistically low voltages. The
present study accompanies our previous work where we investigated the coherent
transport via strongly coupled delocalized orbital by application of
Non-equilibrium Green's Function Formalism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07870</id><created>2015-09-25</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lan</keyname><forenames>Ting-Wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe9;nard</keyname><forenames>Brice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>Houjun</forenames></author></authors><title>The galaxy luminosity function in groups and clusters: the faint-end
  upturn and the connection to the field luminosity function</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>24 pages, 17 figures. Figure 7 shows the main result. Matched the
  published version. The data can be found at
  http://www.pha.jhu.edu/~tlan/research/CLFs/</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016 459 (4):
  3998-4019</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw898</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize the luminosity functions of galaxies residing in $z\sim0$
groups and clusters over the broadest ranges of luminosity and mass reachable
by the Sloan Digital Sky Survey. Our measurements cover four orders of
magnitude in luminosity, down to about $M_r=-12$ mag or $L=10^7\,L_\odot$, and
three orders of magnitude in halo mass, from $10^{12}$ to $10^{15} \, {\rm
M}_\odot$. We find a characteristic scale, $M_r\sim-18$ mag or $L\sim10^9\,
L_\odot$, below which the slope of the luminosity function becomes
systematically steeper. This trend is present for all halo masses and
originates mostly from red satellites. This ubiquitous faint-end upturn
suggests that it is formation, rather than halo-specific environmental effect,
that plays a major role in regulating the stellar masses of faint satellites.
We show that the satellite luminosity functions can be described in a simple
manner by a double Schechter function with amplitudes scaling with halo mass
over the entire range of observables. Combining these conditional luminosity
functions with the dark matter halo mass function, we accurately recover the
entire field luminosity function over 10 visual magnitudes and reveal that
satellite galaxies dominate the field luminosity function at magnitudes fainter
than $-17$. We find that the luminosity functions of blue and red satellite
galaxies show distinct shapes and we present estimates of the stellar mass
fraction as a function of halo mass and galaxy type. Finally, using a simple
model, we demonstrate that the abundances and the faint-end slopes of blue and
red satellite galaxies can be interpreted in terms of their formation history,
with two distinct modes separated by some characteristic time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08258</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08258</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>ALICE Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Inclusive quarkonium production at forward rapidity in pp collisions at
  $\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV</title><categories>hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 4 captioned figures, 2 tables, authors from page 12,
  published version, figures at
  http://aliceinfo.cern.ch/ArtSubmission/node/1911</comments><proxy>Alice Collaboration</proxy><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-267</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 184</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-3987-y</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the inclusive production cross sections of J/$\psi$, $\psi$(2S),
$\Upsilon$(1S), $\Upsilon$(2S) and $\Upsilon$(3S), measured at forward rapidity
with the ALICE detector in pp collisions at a center-of-mass energy
$\sqrt{s}=8$ TeV. The analysis is based on data collected at the LHC and
corresponds to an integrated luminosity of 1.28 pb$^{-1}$. Quarkonia are
reconstructed in the dimuon-decay channel. The differential production cross
sections are measured as a function of the transverse momentum $p_{\rm T}$ and
rapidity $y$, over the $p_{\rm T}$ ranges $0&lt;p_{\rm T}&lt;20$ GeV/$c$ for
J/$\psi$, $0&lt;p_{\rm T}&lt;12$ GeV/$c$ for all other resonances, and for $2.5&lt;y&lt;4$.
The cross sections, integrated over $p_{\rm T}$ and $y$, and assuming
unpolarized quarkonia, are $\sigma_{{\rm J}/\psi} = 8.98\pm0.04\pm0.82$ $\mu$b,
$\sigma_{\psi{\rm (2S)}} = 1.23\pm0.08\pm0.22$ $\mu$b,
$\sigma_{\Upsilon{\rm(1S)}} = 71\pm6\pm7$ nb, $\sigma_{\Upsilon{\rm(2S)}} =
26\pm5\pm4$ nb and $\sigma_{\Upsilon{\rm(3S)}} = 9\pm4\pm1$ nb, where the first
uncertainty is statistical and the second one is systematic. These values
agree, within at most $1.4\sigma$, with measurements performed by the LHCb
collaboration in the same rapidity range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08875</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08875</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2016-05-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Joe P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teplyaev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Singularly continuous spectrum of a self-similar Laplacian on the
  half-line</title><categories>math-ph math.DS math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>v3: 12 pages, 2 figures; to appear in the Journal of Mathematical
  Physics in May or June 2016/ JMP 2016</comments><msc-class>47A10, 37F50, 81Q12, 81Q35, 60J35, 28A80</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 052104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4949471</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spectrum of the self-similar Laplacian, which generates
the so-called &quot;$pq$ random walk&quot; on the integer half-line $\mathbb{Z}_+$. Using
the method of spectral decimation, we prove that the spectral type of the
Laplacian is singularly continuous whenever $p\neq \frac{1}{2}$. This serves as
a toy model for generating singularly continuous spectrum, which can be
generalized to more complicated settings. We hope it will provide more insight
into Fibonacci and other weakly self-similar models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.09183</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.09183</id><created>2015-09-30</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ortiz</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina</keyname><forenames>Rafael A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platero</keyname><forenames>Gloria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunde</keyname><forenames>Anders Mathias</forenames></author></authors><title>Generic helical edge states due to Rashba spin-orbit coupling in a
  topological insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>21 pages (main text 11 pages), 11 figures</comments><report-no>NBI QDEV CMT 2016</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 205431 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.205431</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the helical edge states of a two-dimensional topological insulator
without axial spin symmetry due to the Rashba spin-orbit interaction. Lack of
axial spin symmetry can lead to so-called generic helical edge states, which
have energy-dependent spin orientation. This opens the possibility of inelastic
backscattering and thereby nonquantized transport. Here we find analytically
the new dispersion relations and the energy dependent spin orientation of the
generic helical edge states in the presence of Rashba spin-orbit coupling
within the Bernevig-Hughes-Zhang model, for both a single isolated edge and for
a finite width ribbon. In the single-edge case, we analytically quantify the
energy dependence of the spin orientation, which turns out to be weak for a
realistic HgTe quantum well. Nevertheless, finite size effects combined with
Rashba spin-orbit coupling result in two avoided crossings in the energy
dispersions, where the spin orientation variation of the edge states is very
significantly increased for realistic parameters. Finally, our analytical
results are found to compare well to a numerical tight-binding regularization
of the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00754</id><created>2015-10-02</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>XMASS Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraide</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichimura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishimoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakagawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takachio</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>N. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasaka</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martens</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miuchi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itow</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kegasa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masuda</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishijima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murayama</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for two-neutrino double electron capture on $^{124}$Xe with the
  XMASS-I detector</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, accepted for publication in Physics Letters B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 759 (2016) 64-68</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.05.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Double electron capture is a rare nuclear decay process in which two orbital
electrons are captured simultaneously in the same nucleus. Measurement of its
two-neutrino mode would provide a new reference for the calculation of nuclear
matrix elements whereas observation of its neutrinoless mode would demonstrate
lepton number violation. A search for two-neutrino double electron capture on
$^{124}$Xe is performed using 165.9 days of data collected with the XMASS-I
liquid xenon detector. No significant excess above background was observed and
we set a lower limit on the half-life as $4.7 \times 10^{21}$ years at 90%
confidence level. The obtained limit has ruled out parts of some theoretical
expectations. We obtain a lower limit on the $^{126}$Xe two-neutrino double
electron capture half-life of $4.3 \times 10^{21}$ years at 90% confidence
level as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02954</id><created>2015-10-10</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caglioti</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Infusino</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuna</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author></authors><title>Translation invariant realizability problem on the $d-$dimensional
  lattice: an explicit construction</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>44A60, 60G55, 82B20</msc-class><journal-ref>Electronic Communications in Probability, 21 (2016), no.1, 1-9</journal-ref><doi>10.1214/16-ECP4620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a particular instance of the truncated realizability problem on
the $d-$dimensional lattice. Namely, given two functions $\rho_1({\bf i})$ and
$\rho_2({\bf i},{\bf j})$ non-negative and symmetric on $\mathbb{Z}^d$, we ask
whether they are the first two correlation functions of a translation invariant
point process. We provide an explicit construction of such a realizing process
for any $d\geq 2$ when the radial distribution has a specific form. We also
derive from this construction a lower bound for the maximal realizable density
and compare it with the already known lower bounds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03335</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rantaharju</keyname><forenames>Jarno</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rantalaiho</keyname><forenames>Teemu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rummukainen</keyname><forenames>Kari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuominen</keyname><forenames>Kimmo</forenames></author></authors><title>Running coupling in SU(2) gauge theory with two adjoint fermions</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures. Revisions in the abstract and introduction, as
  well as the handling of the continuum limit</comments><report-no>CP3-Origins-2015-040 DNRF90, DIAS-2015-40, HIP-2015-33/TH</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 094509 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.094509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study SU(2) gauge theory with two Dirac fermions in the adjoint
representation of the gauge group on the lattice. Using clover improved Wilson
fermion action with hypercubic truncated stout smearing we perform simulations
at larger coupling than earlier. We measure the evolution of the coupling
constant using the step scaling method with Schr\&quot;odinger functional and study
the remaining discretization effects. At weak coupling we observe significant
discretization effects, which make it difficult to obtain a fully controlled
continuum limit. Nevertheless, the data remains consistent with the existence
of a fixed point in the interval $2.2\lesssim g^{\ast 2}\lesssim 3$. We also
measure the anomalous dimension and find its value at the fixed point is
$\gamma^\ast\simeq 0.2\pm 0.03$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06991</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06991</id><created>2015-10-23</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Oriti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pranzetti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sindoni</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author></authors><title>Horizon entropy from quantum gravity condensates</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 211301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.211301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct condensate states encoding the continuum spherically symmetric
quantum geometry of an horizon in full quantum gravity, i.e. without any
classical symmetry reduction, in the group field theory formalism. Tracing over
the bulk degrees of freedom, we show how the resulting reduced density matrix
manifestly exhibits an holographic behavior. We derive a complete orthonormal
basis of eigenstates for the reduced density matrix of the horizon and use it
to compute the horizon entanglement entropy. By imposing consistency with the
horizon boundary conditions and semiclassical thermodynamical properties, we
recover the Bekenstein--Hawking entropy formula for any value of the Immirzi
parameter. Our analysis supports the equivalence between the von Neumann
(entanglement) entropy interpretation and the Boltzmann (statistical) one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04807</id><created>2015-11-15</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>XMASS Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraide</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichimura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kishimoto</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takachio</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashita</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>N. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasaka</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fushimi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martens</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>B. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miuchi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oka</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>K. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Itow</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kegasa</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masada</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishijima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct dark matter search by annual modulation in XMASS-I</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ex nucl-ex physics.ins-det</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search for dark matter was conducted by looking for an annual modulation
signal due to the Earth's rotation around the Sun using XMASS, a single phase
liquid xenon detector. The data used for this analysis was 359.2 live days
times 832 kg of exposure accumulated between November 2013 and March 2015. When
we assume Weakly Interacting Massive Particle (WIMP) dark matter elastically
scattering on the target nuclei, the exclusion upper limit of the WIMP-nucleon
cross section 4.3$\times$10$^{-41}$cm$^2$ at 8 GeV/c$^2$ was obtained and we
exclude almost all the DAMA/LIBRA allowed region in the 6 to 16 GeV/c$^2$ range
at $\sim$10$^{-40}$cm$^2$. The result of a simple modulation analysis, without
assuming any specific dark matter model but including electron/$\gamma$ events,
showed a slight negative amplitude. The $p$-values obtained with two
independent analyses are 0.014 and 0.068 for null hypothesis, respectively. we
obtained 90\% C.L. upper bounds that can be used to test various models. This
is the first extensive annual modulation search probing this region with an
exposure comparable to DAMA/LIBRA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05594</id><created>2015-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Moler&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serra-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Marc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daraio</keyname><forenames>Chiara</forenames></author></authors><title>Visco-thermal effects in acoustic metamaterials: from total transmission
  to total reflection and high absorption</title><categories>physics.class-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 033003 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/3/033003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically and experimentally investigate visco-thermal effects on the
acoustic propagation through metamaterials consisting of rigid slabs with
subwavelength slits embedded in air. We demonstrate that this unavoidable loss
mechanism is not merely a refinement, but it plays a dominant role in the
actual acoustic response of the structure. Specifically, in the case of very
narrow slits, the visco-thermal losses avoid completely the excitation of
Fabry-Perot resonances, leading to 100% reflection. This is exactly opposite to
the perfect transmission predicted in the idealised lossless case. Moreover,
for a wide range of geometrical parameters, there exists an optimum slit width
at which the energy dissipated in the structure can be as high as 50%. This
work provides a clear evidence that visco-thermal effects are necessary to
describe realistically the acoustic response of locally resonant metamaterials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06371</id><created>2015-11-19</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brdar</keyname><forenames>Vedran</forenames><affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</affiliation></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nig</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames><affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kopp</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames><affiliation>Johannes Gutenberg University Mainz</affiliation></author></authors><title>Neutrino Anarchy and Renormalization Group Evolution</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 12 figures. v2: References added, matches version to be
  published in PRD</comments><report-no>MITP/15-104</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 093010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.093010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The observed pattern of neutrino mixing angles is in good agreement with the
hypothesis of neutrino anarchy, which posits that Nature has chosen the entries
of the leptonic mixing matrix at random. In this paper we investigate how
stable this conclusion is under renormalization group effects. Working in the
simplest type-I seesaw model and two variants of the inverse seesaw model we
study how the statistical distributions of the neutrino mixing parameters
evolve between the Grand Unification scale and the electroweak scale.
Especially in the inverse seesaw case we find significant distortions: mixing
angles tend to be smaller after RG running, and the Dirac CP phase tends to be
closer to zero. The p-value describing the compatibility between the observed
mixing angles and the anarchy hypothesis increases by 10-20%. This illustrates
that RG effects are highly relevant for quantitative studies of the anarchy
scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00185</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>A semiclassical hybrid approach to linear response functions for
  infrared spectroscopy</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physica Scripta 91, 044004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0031-8949/91/4/044004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the integral representation of the semiclassical propagator of
Herman and Kluk (HK), and in the limit of high temperatures, we formulate a
hybrid expression for the correlation function of infrared spectroscopy. This
is achieved by performing a partial linearization inside the integral over the
difference of phase space variables that occurs after a twofold application of
the HK propagator. A numerical case study for a coupled anharmonic oscillator
shows that already for a total number of only two degrees of freedom, one of
which is treated in the simplified manner, a substantial reduction of the
numerical effort is achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00341</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Rainone</keyname><forenames>Corrado</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbani</keyname><forenames>Pierfrancesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Following the evolution of glassy states under external perturbations:
  the full replica symmetry breaking solution</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>35 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 053302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/05/053302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The state-following technique allows the study of metastable glassy states
under external perturbations. Here we show how this construction can be used to
study the behavior of glassy states of Hard Spheres in infinite dimensions
under compression or shear strain. In a preceding work it has been shown that
in both cases, when the external perturbation is sufficiently strong, glassy
states undergo a second-order transition, called the Gardner transition,
whereupon a hierarchical structure of marginal micro-states manifests within
the original glass state. The purpose of this work is to study the solution of
the state-following construction in this marginal phase. We show that upon
compression, close to the jamming transition, the metastable states are
described by a scaling solution characterized by a set of non-trivial critical
exponents that agree with the results obtained in a preceding work, and we
compute the value of the final jamming density for various glassy states.
Moreover we show that under the action of the shear strain, beyond the Gardner
point, the metastable states can be followed in the marginal phase and we
detect an overshoot in the stress-strain curve in agreement with numerical and
experimental observations. Finally we further characterize the Gardner
transition point by computing both the critical 4-point susceptibility and the
exponents that characterize the critical slowing down of the dynamics within a
glassy state close to the transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01345</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01345</id><created>2015-12-04</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Paranjape</keyname><forenames>Aseem</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Choudhury</keyname><forenames>T. Roy</forenames><affiliation>NCRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>Hamsa</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Photon Number Conserving Models of H II Bubbles during Reionization</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures; v2: revised to match version accepted in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Traditional excursion set based models of H II bubble growth during the epoch
of reionization are known to violate photon number conservation, in the sense
that the mass fraction in ionized bubbles in these models does not equal the
ratio of the number of ionizing photons produced by sources and the number of
hydrogen atoms in the intergalactic medium. E.g., for a Planck13 cosmology with
electron scattering optical depth $\tau\simeq0.066$, the discrepancy is
$\sim15$ per cent for $x_{\rm HII}=0.1$ and $\sim5$ per cent for $x_{\rm
HII}=0.5$. We demonstrate that this problem arises from a fundamental
conceptual shortcoming of the excursion set approach (already recognised in the
literature on this formalism) which only tracks average mass fractions instead
of the exact, stochastic source counts. With this insight, we build an
approximately photon number conserving Monte Carlo model of bubble growth based
on partitioning regions of dark matter into halos. Our model, which is formally
valid for white noise initial conditions (ICs), shows dramatic improvements in
photon number conservation, as well as substantial differences in the bubble
size distribution, as compared to traditional models. We explore the trends
obtained on applying our algorithm to more realistic ICs, finding that these
improvements are robust to changes in the ICs. Since currently popular
semi-numerical schemes of bubble growth also violate photon number
conservation, we argue that it will be worthwhile to pursue new, explicitly
photon number conserving approaches. Along the way, we clarify some
misconceptions regarding this problem that have appeared in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02885</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02885</id><created>2015-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Buchholz</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceotto</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixed Semiclassical Initial Value Representation Time-Averaging
  Propagator for Spectroscopic Calculations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics, 144, 094102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4942536</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A mixed semiclassical initial value representation expression for
spectroscopic calculations is derived. The formulation takes advantage of the
time-averaging filtering and the hierarchical properties of different
trajectory based propagation methods. A separable approximation is then
introduced that greatly reduces (about an order of magnitude) the computational
cost compared with a full Herman-Kluk time-averaging semiclassical calculation
for the same systems. The expression is exact for the harmonic case and it is
tested numerically for a Morse potential coupled to one or two additional
harmonic degrees of freedom. Results are compared to full Herman-Kluk
time-averaging calculations and exact quantum wavepacket propagations. We found
the peak positions of the mixed semiclassical approximations to be always in
very good agreement with full quantum calculations, while overtone peak
intensities are lower with respect to the exact ones. Given the reduced
computational effort required by this new mixed semiclassical approximation, we
believe the present method to make spectroscopic calculations available for
higher dimensional systems than accessible before.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05540</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-01-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Naze</keyname><forenames>Yael</forenames></author></authors><title>Tribute to an astronomer: the work of Max Ernst on Wilhelm Tempel</title><categories>physics.hist-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>18 pages, accepted by JHA - this is the submitted version (accepted
  version on http://hdl.handle.net/2268/189328)</comments><journal-ref>JHA, 47(2), 115-135 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1177/0021828615625476</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In 1964-1974, the German artist Max Ernst created, with the help of two
friends, a series of works (books, movie, paintings) related to the astronomer
Wilhelm Tempel. Mixing actual texts by Tempel and artistic features, this
series pays homage to the astronomer by recalling his life and discoveries.
Moreover, the core of the project, the book Maximiliana or the Illegal Practice
of Astronomy, actually depicts the way science works, making this artwork a
most original tribute to a scientist.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06461</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06461</id><created>2015-12-20</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Study of Z boson production in pPb collisions at sqrt(s[NN]) = 5.02 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All the figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/HIN-15-002/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-HIN-15-002, CERN-PH-EP-2015-302</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 759 (2016) 36</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.05.044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of Z bosons in pPb collisions at sqrt(s[NN]) = 5.02 TeV is
studied by the CMS experiment via the electron and muon decay channels. The
inclusive cross section is compared to pp collision predictions, and found to
scale with the number of elementary nucleon-nucleon collisions. The
differential cross sections as a function of the Z boson rapidity and
transverse momentum are measured. Though they are found to be consistent within
uncertainty with theoretical predictions both with and without nuclear effects,
the forward-backward asymmetry suggests the presence of nuclear effects at
large rapidities. These results provide new data for constraining nuclear
parton distribution functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08002</id><created>2015-12-25</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for supersymmetry in events with soft leptons, low jet
  multiplicity, and missing transverse momentum in proton-proton collisions at
  sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added the journal reference and DOI.
  All figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/SUS-14-021/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-SUS-14-021, CERN-PH-EP-2015-307</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 759 (2016) 9</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.05.033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Results are presented from a search for supersymmetric particles in scenarios
with a compressed mass spectrum. The data sample corresponds to 19.7 inverse
femtobarns of proton-proton collisions recorded by the CMS experiment at
sqrt(s) = 8 TeV. The search targets top squark pair production in scenarios
with mass differences Delta m = m(top squark) - m(neutralino) below the W-boson
mass and with top-squark decays in the four-body mode (top squark to b l nu
neutralino), where the neutralino is assumed to be the lightest supersymmetric
particle (LSP). The signature includes a high transverse momentum (pt) jet
associated with initial-state radiation, one or two low-pt leptons, and
significant missing transverse energy. The event yields observed in data are
consistent with the expected background contributions from standard model
processes. Limits are set on the cross section for top squark pair production
as a function of the top squark and LSP masses. Assuming a 100% branching
fraction for the four-body decay mode, top-squark masses below 316 GeV are
excluded for Delta m = 25 GeV at 95% CL. The dilepton data are also interpreted
under the assumption of chargino-neutralino production, with subsequent decays
to sleptons or sneutrinos. Assuming a difference between the common lightest
chargino/next lightest neutralino mass and the LSP mass of 20 GeV and a
tau-enriched decay scenario, masses in the range m(chargino) &lt; 307 GeV are
excluded at 95% CL.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00621</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rozo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hollowood</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bermeo-Hernandez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jeltema</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romer</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rooney</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saro</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervantes</keyname><forenames>C. Vergara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wechsler</keyname><forenames>R. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilcox</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbott</keyname><forenames>T. M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allam</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Annis</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benoit-L&#xe9;vy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernstein</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capozzi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosell</keyname><forenames>A. Carnero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kind</keyname><forenames>M. Carrasco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castander</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Childress</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collins</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Costa</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>H. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evrard</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finley</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaugher</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fosalba</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frieman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glazebrook</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldstein</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruendl</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hilton</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honscheid</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoyle</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kay</keyname><forenames>S. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuropatkin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahav</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewis</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lidman</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maia</keyname><forenames>M. A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchior</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miquel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nichol</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogando</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plazas</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reil</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahl&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santiago</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarpine</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schubnell</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla-Noarbe</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares-Santos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreira</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stott</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suchyta</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swanson</keyname><forenames>M. E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarle</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uddin</keyname><forenames>s.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viana</keyname><forenames>P. T. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vikram</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>The redMaPPer Galaxy Cluster Catalog From DES Science Verification Data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>21 pages, accepted to ApJS (The Astrophysical Journal Supplement
  Series, Volume 224, Issue 1, article id. 1, pp. (2016))</comments><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/224/1/1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe updates to the \redmapper{} algorithm, a photometric red-sequence
cluster finder specifically designed for large photometric surveys. The updated
algorithm is applied to $150\,\mathrm{deg}^2$ of Science Verification (SV) data
from the Dark Energy Survey (DES), and to the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS)
DR8 photometric data set. The DES SV catalog is locally volume limited, and
contains 786 clusters with richness $\lambda&gt;20$ (roughly equivalent to
$M_{\rm{500c}}\gtrsim10^{14}\,h_{70}^{-1}\,M_{\odot}$) and $0.2&lt;z&lt;0.9$. The DR8
catalog consists of 26311 clusters with $0.08&lt;z&lt;0.6$, with a sharply increasing
richness threshold as a function of redshift for $z\gtrsim 0.35$. The
photometric redshift performance of both catalogs is shown to be excellent,
with photometric redshift uncertainties controlled at the $\sigma_z/(1+z)\sim
0.01$ level for $z\lesssim0.7$, rising to $\sim0.02$ at $z\sim0.9$ in DES SV.
We make use of \emph{Chandra} and \emph{XMM} X-ray and South Pole Telescope
Sunyaev-Zeldovich data to show that the centering performance and
mass--richness scatter are consistent with expectations based on prior runs of
\redmapper{} on SDSS data. We also show how the \redmapper{} \photoz{} and
richness estimates are relatively insensitive to imperfect star/galaxy
separation and small-scale star masks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01664</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01664</id><created>2016-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Cairns</keyname><forenames>Andrew B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cliffe</keyname><forenames>Matthew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paddison</keyname><forenames>Joseph A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Daisenberger</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tucker</keyname><forenames>Matthew G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coudert</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois-Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goodwin</keyname><forenames>Andrew L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Encoding Complexity within Supramolecular Analogues of Frustrated
  Magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 3 figures. Submitted to Nature Chemistry</comments><journal-ref>Nature Chemistry, 2016, 8, 442-447</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nchem.2462</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At the heart of systems chemistry lies the idea that supramolecular
interactions can give rise to complex and unexpected collective states that
emerge on a fundamentally different lengthscale to that of the interactions
themselves. While in certain cases - e.g. the self-assembly of virus-like
polyhedral cages from coordination building blocks - it is possible to control
emergence in a systematic manner, the development of general approaches remains
a fundamental challenge in the field. In the conceptually-related domain of
frustrated magnetism - where collective states give rise to exotic physics of
relevance to data storage and spintronics - the task of predicting emergent
behaviour is simplified through control over the geometry and form of the
magnetic interactions from which complexity arises. Seeking to combine
approaches from these two fields, we study here the solid phases of inorganic
polymer chains assembled from non-magnetic gold(I)/silver(I) cations and
cyanide anions. We show the periodic inter-chain potential encodes a
supramolecular interaction that can be tuned to mimic different magnetic
interactions between XY spins (&quot;spin rotors&quot;). Because the chains pack on a
triangular lattice, the crystal structures of gold(I)/silver(I) cyanides can be
interpreted in terms of the phase behaviour of triangular XY magnets. Complex
magnetic states predicted for this family - including hidden quadrupolar order
and emergent spin-vortex quasiparticles - are realised for the first time in
the structural chemistry of these cyanide polymers. In this way we demonstrate
both how simple inorganic materials might behave as structural analogues of
otherwise-unrealisable &quot;toy&quot; spin models, and also how a theoretical
understanding of those models might be used to predict and control emergent
phenomena in chemical systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02171</id><created>2016-01-09</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Kent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yunes</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>I-Love-Q Relations: From Compact Stars to Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>36 pages, 10 figures; minor modifications, typos corrected; published
  in CQG</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quant. Grav. 33, 095005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/9/095005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relations between most observables associated with a compact star, such
as the mass and radius of a neutron star or a quark star, typically depend
strongly on their unknown internal structure. The I-Love-Q relations (between
the moment of inertia, the tidal deformability and the quadrupole moment) are
however approximately insensitive to this structure. These relations become
exact for stationary black holes in General Relativity as shown by the no-hair
theorems. In this paper, we take the first steps toward studying how the
approximate I-Love-Q relations become exact in the limit as compact stars
become black holes. To do so, we consider a toy model, i.e. incompressible
stars with anisotropic pressure, which allows us to model an equilibrium
sequence of stars with their compactness approaching the black hole limit
arbitrarily closely. We extract the I-Love-Q trio by numerically constructing
such a sequence in the slow-rotation and small-tide approximations. We find
that the I-Love-Q relations approach the black hole limit in a nontrivial way,
with the quadrupole moment and the tidal deformability changing sign as the
compactness and the amount of anisotropy are increased. Generalizing Maclaurin
spheroids to anisotropic stars, we show that the multipole moments also change
sign in the Newtonian limit as the amount of anisotropy is increased. We also
prove analytically that the stellar moment of inertia reaches the black hole
limit as the compactness reaches the black hole value in the strongly
anisotropic limit. Modeling the black hole limit through a sequence of
anisotropic stars, however, fails when considering other theories of gravity.
We calculate the scalar dipole charge and the moment of inertia in a
parity-violating modified theory and find that these quantities do not tend to
their black hole counterparts as the anisotropic stellar sequence approaches
the black hole limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02174</id><created>2016-01-09</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sago</keyname><forenames>Norichika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujita</keyname><forenames>Ryuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Hiroyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Accuracy of the Post-Newtonian Approximation for Extreme-Mass Ratio
  Inspirals from Black-hole Perturbation Approach</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures, minor modifications to match the published
  version in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 104023 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.104023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the accuracy of the post-Newtonian (PN) approximation and its
region of validity for quasi-circular orbits of a point particle in the Kerr
spacetime, by using an analytically known highest post-Newtonian order
gravitational energy flux and accurate numerical results in the black hole
perturbation approach. It is found that regions of validity become larger for
higher PN order results although there are several local maximums in regions of
validity for relatively low-PN order results. This might imply that higher PN
order calculations are also encouraged for comparable-mass binaries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.04809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.04809</id><created>2016-01-19</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kanda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsui</keyname><forenames>Taku</forenames></author></authors><title>KMS States of Weakly Coupled Anharmonic Crystals and the Resolvent CCR
  Algebra</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Lemma 5.2 and 5.3 of the 1st version were wrong and are placed by
  correct statements</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider equilibrium states of weakly coupled anharmonic quantum
oscillators on Z. We consider the Resolvent CCR Algebra introduced by
D.Buchholtz and H.Grundling, and we show that the infinite volume limit of
equilibrium states satisfies the KMS (Kubo-Martin-Schwinger) condition with
good regularity(= locally Fock representation).
  Uniqueness of the KMS states is proven as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06794</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Pinaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Datta</keyname><forenames>Shouvik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinha</keyname><forenames>Ritam</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher-point conformal blocks and entanglement entropy in heavy states</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>41 pages, 10 figures. (Published version; typos corrected and
  references added.)</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1605 (2016) 127</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2016)127</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider conformal blocks of two heavy operators and an arbitrary number
of light operators in a (1+1)-d CFT with large central charge. Using the
monodromy method, these higher-point conformal blocks are shown to factorize
into products of 4-point conformal blocks in the heavy-light limit for a class
of OPE channels. This result is reproduced by considering suitable worldline
configurations in the bulk conical defect geometry. We apply the CFT results to
calculate the entanglement entropy of an arbitrary number of disjoint intervals
for heavy states. The corresponding holographic entanglement entropy calculated
via the minimal area prescription precisely matches these results from CFT.
Along the way, we briefly illustrate the relation of these conformal blocks to
Riemann surfaces and their associated moduli space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07321</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07321</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-05-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cuevas-Maraver</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malomed</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>A PT-symmetric dual-core system with the sine-Gordon nonlinearity and
  derivative coupling</title><categories>nlin.PS</categories><comments>Symmetry, in press (special issue on Parity-Time Symmetry in Optics
  and Photonics)</comments><journal-ref>Symmetry 8 (2016) 39</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/sym8060039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a system of sine-Gordon equations, with the $\mathcal{PT}$
symmetry represented by balanced gain and loss in them. The equations are
coupled by sine-field terms and first-order derivatives. The sinusoidal
coupling stems from local interaction between adjacent particles in the coupled
Frenkel-Kontorova (FK) chains and related sine-lattices, while the
cross-derivative coupling, which was not considered before, is induced by
\emph{three-particle} interactions, provided that the particles in the parallel
FK\ chains move in different directions. Nonlinear wave structures are then
studied in this model. In particular, kink-kink (KK) and kink-antikink (KA)
complexes are explored by means of analytical and numerical methods. It is
predicted analytically and confirmed numerically that the complexes are
unstable for one sign of the sinusoidal coupling, and stable for another.
Stability regions are delineated in the underlying parameter space. Unstable
complexes split into free kinks/antikinks that may propagate or become
stationary, depending on whether they are subject to gain or loss,
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07641</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07641</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kawano</keyname><forenames>Akio</forenames></author></authors><title>A simple volume-of-fluid reconstruction method for three-dimensional
  two-phase flows</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.compfluid.2016.05.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new PLIC (piecewise linear interface calculation)-type VOF (volume of
fluid) method, called APPLIC (approximated PLIC) method, is presented. Although
the PLIC method is one of the most accurate VOF methods, the three-dimensional
algorithm is complex. Accordingly, it is hard to develop and maintain the
computational code. The APPLIC method reduces the complexity using simple
approximation formulae. Three numerical tests were performed to compare the
accuracy of the SVOF (simplified volume of fluid), VOF/WLIC (weighed line
interface calculation), THINC/SW (tangent of hyperbola for interface
capturing/slope weighting), THINC/WLIC, PLIC, and APPLIC methods. The results
of the tests show that the APPLIC results are as accurate as the PLIC results
and are more accurate than the SVOF, VOF/WLIC, THINC/SW, and THINC/WLIC
results. It was demonstrated that the APPLIC method is more computationally
efficient than the PLIC method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00338</id><created>2016-01-31</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saberi-Pouya</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazifehshenas</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farmanbar</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salavati-fard</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coulomb drag in anisotropic systems: a theoretical study on a
  double-layer phosphorene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 285301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/28/285301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically study the Coulomb drag resistivity in a double-layer
electron system with highly anisotropic parabolic band structure using
Boltzmann transport theory. As an example, we consider a double-layer
phosphorene on which we apply our formalism. This approach, in principle, can
be tuned for other double-layered systems with paraboloidal band structures.
Our calculations show the rotation of one layer with respect to another layer
can be considered a way of controlling the drag resistivity in such systems. As
a result of rotation, the off-diagonal elements of drag resistivity tensor have
non-zero values at any temperature. In addition, we show that the anisotropic
drag resistivity is very sensitive to the direction of momentum transfer
between two layers due to highly anisotropic inter-layer electron-electron
interaction and also the plasmon modes. In particular, the drag anisotropy
ratio, \r{ho}yy/\r{ho}xx, can reach up to ~ 3 by changing the temperature.
Furthermore,our calculations suggest that including the local field correction
in dielectric function changes the results significantly. Finally, We examine
the dependence of drag resistivity and its anisotropy ratio on various
parameters like inter-layer separation, electron density, short-range
interaction and insulating substrate/spacer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01138</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01138</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lang</keyname><forenames>Rafael F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Ethan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervantes</keyname><forenames>Mayra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macmullin</keyname><forenames>Sean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masson</keyname><forenames>Darryl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schreiner</keyname><forenames>Jochen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Simgen</keyname><forenames>Hardy</forenames></author></authors><title>A Rn-220 source for the calibration of low-background experiments</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation, Volume 11, P04004 (April 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/04/P04004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We characterize two 40 kBq sources of electrodeposited Th-228 for use in
low-background experiments. The sources efficiently emanate Rn-220, a noble gas
that can diffuse in a detector volume. Rn-220 and its daughter isotopes produce
alpha, beta, and gamma-radiation, which may used to calibrate a variety of
detector responses and features, before decaying completely in only a few days.
We perform various tests to place limits on the release of other long-lived
isotopes. In particular, we find an emanation of &lt;0.008 atoms/min/kBq (90% CL)
for Th-228 and 1.53 atoms/min/kBq for Ra-224. The sources lend themselves in
particular to the calibration of detectors employing liquid noble elements such
as argon and xenon. With the source mounted in a noble gas system, we
demonstrate that filters are highly efficient in reducing the activity of these
longer-lived isotopes further. We thus confirm the suitability of these sources
even for use in next-generation experiments, such as XENON1T/XENONnT, LZ, and
nEXO.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06527</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06527</id><created>2016-02-21</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Yun-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Zhao-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Yi-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lei</keyname><forenames>Shi-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>En-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author></authors><title>Search for a gamma-ray line feature from a group of nearby Galaxy
  clusters with Fermi LAT Pass 8 data</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>The version published in Phys. Rev. D, minor revision (10 pages
  including 4 eps figures)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 103525 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.103525</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Galaxy clusters are the largest gravitationally bound objects in the universe
and may be suitable targets for indirect dark matter searches. With 85 months
of Fermi-LAT Pass 8 publicly available data, we analyze the gamma-ray emission
in the directions of 16 nearby Galaxy Clusters with an unbinned likelihood
analysis. No globally statistically-significant $\gamma-$ray line feature is
identified and a tentative line signal may be present at $\sim 43$ GeV. The
95\% confidence level upper limits on the velocity-averaged cross section of
dark matter particles annihilating into double $\gamma-$rays (i.e., $\langle
\sigma v \rangle_{\chi\chi\rightarrow \gamma\gamma}$) are derived. Unless very
optimistic boost factors of dark matter annihilation in these Galaxy Clusters
have been assumed, such constraints are much weaker than the bounds set by the
Galactic $\gamma-$ray data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07694</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07694</id><created>2016-02-24</created><updated>2016-05-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Johannsen</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames><affiliation>Perimeter, Waterloo</affiliation></author></authors><title>Testing the No-Hair Theorem with Observations of Black Holes in the
  Electromagnetic Spectrum</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.GA gr-qc</categories><comments>33 pages, 10 figures, invited review for the CQG special issue &quot;Hairy
  Black Holes: Beyond the Kerr Paradigm,&quot; eds. C.A.R. Herdeiro, E. Radu.</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33, 124001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/12/124001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to the general-relativistic no-hair theorem, astrophysical black
holes depend only on their masses and spins and are uniquely described by the
Kerr metric. Mass and spin are the first two multipole moments of the Kerr
spacetime and completely determine all other moments. The no-hair theorem can
be tested by measuring potential deviations from the Kerr metric which alter
such higher-order moments. In this review, I discuss tests of the no-hair
theorem with current and future observations of such black holes across the
electromagnetic spectrum, focusing on near-infrared observations of the
supermassive black hole at the Galactic center, pulsar-timing and very-long
baseline interferometric observations, as well as X-ray observations of
fluorescent iron lines, thermal continuum spectra, variability, and
polarization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08797</id><created>2016-02-28</created><updated>2016-04-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Heshan</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Ge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Beiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Kui</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport anomalies and quantum criticality in electron-doped cuprate
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>35 figures; a brief summary of transport properties; the common
  features seen in the last figure</comments><journal-ref>Physica C, 525 18(2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physc.2016.03.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superconductivity research is like running a marathon. Three decades after
the discovery of high-Tc cuprates, there have been mass data generated from
transport measurements, which bring fruitful information. In this review, we
give a brief summary of the intriguing phenomena reported in electron-doped
cuprates from the aspect of electrical transport as well as the complementary
thermal transport. We attempt to sort out common features of the electron-doped
family, e.g. the strange metal, negative magnetoresistance, multiple sign
reversals of Hall in mixed state, abnormal Nernst signal, complex quantum
criticality. Most of them have been challenging the existing theories,
nevertheless, a unified diagram certainly helps to approach the nature of
electron-doped cuprates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02709</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stephan</keyname><forenames>Alexander P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naoz</keyname><forenames>Smadar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghez</keyname><forenames>Andrea M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witzel</keyname><forenames>Gunther</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sitarski</keyname><forenames>Breann N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>Tuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocsis</keyname><forenames>Bence</forenames></author></authors><title>Merging Binaries in the Galactic Center: The eccentric Kozai-Lidov
  mechanism with stellar evolution</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures, accepted by MNRAS and available through 'Advance
  Access'</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1220</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most, if not all, stars in the field are born in binary configurations or
higher multiplicity systems. In dense stellar environment such as the Galactic
Center (GC), many stars are expected to be in binary configurations as well.
These binaries form hierarchical triple body systems, with the massive black
hole (MBH) as the third, distant object. The stellar binaries are expected to
undergo large amplitude eccentricity and inclination oscillations via the
so-called &quot;eccentric Kozai-Lidov&quot; (EKL) mechanism. These eccentricity
excitations, combined with post main sequence stellar evolution, can drive the
inner stellar binaries to merge. We study the mergers of stellar binaries in
the inner 0.1 pc of the GC caused by gravitational perturbations due to the
MBH. We run a large set of Monte Carlo simulations that include the secular
evolution of the orbits, general relativistic precession, tides, and
post-main-sequence stellar evolution. We find that about 13 % of the initial
binary population will have merged after a few million years and about 29 %
after a few billion years. These expected merged systems represent a new class
of objects at the GC and we speculate that they are connected to G2-like
objects and the young stellar population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02883</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-05-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gaurav</keyname><forenames>Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Sudhir K</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying the applicability of different thermoelectric materials for
  efficiency calculation in hybrid thermoelectric generator for waste heat
  recovery from automobile and steel industry</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the suitability of different thermoelectric materials
like $Bi_2Te_3$, $Sb_{2}Te_{3}$, $PbTe$, $TAGS$, $CeFe_{4}Sb_{12}$, $SiGe$ and
$TiO_{1.1}$ in estimation of thermoelectric generator's (TEG) efficiency. The
efficiency of TEG made up of ${Be_{2}Te_{3}}$ or $Sb_{2}Te_{3}$ gives $\sim$7\%
in temperature range of 310 K - 500 K. $PbTe$ or $TAGS$ or $CeFe_{4}Sb_{12}$
gives $\sim$6\% in temperature range of 500 K - 900 K and $SiGe$ or $TiO_{1.1}$
also have remarkable efficiency in higher temperature range i.e $\sim$1200 K.
Here, we report the enhancement of efficiency by using hybridization technique
for different combination of above-mentioned materials. Hybridization of two
different materials of TEG module is done by considering compatibility factor
aspect. To this end, the proposed values of overall efficiency of TEG by
hybridizing ${Be_{2}Te_{3}}$ and $PbTe$; ${Be_{2}Te_{3}}$ and $TAGS$;
$Bi_{2}Te_{3}$ and $CeFe_{4}Sb_{12}$ are 12\%, 14\% and 11.88\%, respectively,
for temperature range of 310 K to 900 K, which can be installed in an
automobile. For steel industry and spacecraft application (till 1200 K)
hybridization of $Bi_{2}Te_{3}$, $PbTe$ and $SiGe$; ${Be_{2}Te_{3}}$ and
$TiO_{1.1}$ yields efficiency of $\sim$15.2\% and $\sim$17.2\%, respectively.
The proposed results can be treated as a viable option for engineers, who are
looking for fabricating TEG in real life applications such as automobile,
spacecraft and steel industry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06264</id><created>2016-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gavrilov</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gitman</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shishmarev</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unitarity and vacuum deformation in QED with critical potential steps</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 105040 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.105040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present article can be considered as a complement to the work P.R.D 93,
045002 (2016) where an nonperturbative approach to QED with x-electric critical
potential steps was developed. In the beginning we study conditions when in-
and out-spaces of the QED under consideration are unitarily equivalent. Then we
construct a general density operator with the vacuum initial condition. Such an
operator describes a deformation of the initial vacuum state by x-electric
critical potential steps. We construct reductions of the deformed state to
electron and positron subsystems, calculating the loss of the information in
these reductions. We illustrate the general consideration studying the
deformation of the quantum vacuum between two capacitor plates. Finally we
calculate the entanglement measures of these reduced matrices as von Neumann
entropies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07412</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07412</id><created>2016-03-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsutsui</keyname><forenames>Satoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sugimoto</keyname><forenames>Kunihisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsunoda</keyname><forenames>Ryoma</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirose</keyname><forenames>Yusuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mito</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Settai</keyname><forenames>Rikio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizumaki</keyname><forenames>Masaichiro</forenames></author></authors><title>First-Order Structural Change Accompanied by Yb Valence Transition in
  YbInCu4</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures, strongly correlated 4f-electron systems</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 063602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.063602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A diffraction experiment using a high energy x-ray was carried out on
YbInCu4. Below the Yb valence transition temperature, the splitting of Bragg
peaks was detected in higher-order reflections. No superlattice reflections
accompanying the valence ordering were found below the transition temperature.
These experimental findings indicate that a structural change from a cubic
structure to a tetragonal structure without valence ordering occurs at the
transition temperature. Such a structural change free from any valence ordering
is difficult to understand only in terms of Yb valence degrees of freedom. This
means that the structural change may be related to electronic symmetries such
as quadrupolar degrees of freedom as well as the change in Yb valence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07873</id><created>2016-03-25</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Juanjuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jinchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Jieming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Aifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xianhui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danilkin</keyname><forenames>Sergey A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bao</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>The influence of the structural transition on magnetic fluctuations in
  NaFeAs</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 27LT01 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/27/27LT01</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  NaFeAs belongs to a class of Fe-based superconductors which parent compounds
show separated structural and magnetic transitions. Effects of the structural
transition on spin dynamics therefore can be investigated separately from the
magnetic transition. A plateau in dynamic spin response is observed in a
critical region around the structural transition temperature T_S. It is
interpreted as due to the stiffening of spin fluctuations along the in-plane
magnetic hard axis due to the dxz and dyz orbital ordering. The appearance of
anisotropic spin dynamics in the critical region above the T_S at T* offers a
dynamic magnetic scattering mechanism for anisotropic electronic properties in
the commonly referred &quot;nematic phase&quot;.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00716</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00716</id><created>2016-04-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jihn E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Axionic domain wall number related to U(1)$_{\rm anom}$ global symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B759 (2016) 58-63</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.05.041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The QCD axion with $f_a$ at an intermediate scale, 10**9-10**12 GeV, seems in
conflict with the gravity spoil of global symmetries and may face the axionic
domain wall problem. We point out that the string compactifications with an
anomalous U(1) gauge symmetry, allowing desirable chiral matter spectra,
circumvent these two problems simultaneously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02915</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02915</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jusinskas</keyname><forenames>Renann Lipinski</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on the ambitwistor pure spinor string</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, reference and clarifications added, typos fixed. Published
  version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP05(2016)116</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2016)116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, some aspects of the ambitwistor pure spinor string are
investigated. The $b$ ghost is presented and its main properties are derived in
a simple way, very similar to the usual pure spinor $b$ ghost construction. The
heterotic case is also addressed with a new proposal for the BRST charge. The
BRST cohomology is shown to correctly describe the heterotic supergravity
spectrum and a semi-composite $b$ ghost is constructed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08018</id><created>2016-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Domon</keyname><forenames>Kaoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Takemi</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x14c;no</keyname><forenames>Yoshiaki</forenames></author></authors><title>First- and second-order phase transitions between the uniform and FFLO
  excitonic states in the three-chain Hubbard model for Ta2NiSe5</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>3 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn 85 065005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.065005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the free energy and the thermodynamic properties in the
three-chain Hubbard model for Ta2NiSe5 to clarify the phase transitions between
the uniform and the FFLO excitonic states which are expected to be observed in
Ta2NiSe5 under high pressure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01444</id><created>2016-05-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bailey</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woodraska</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Woods</keyname><forenames>T. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eparvier</keyname><forenames>F. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieman</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Didkovsky</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Soft X-ray irradiance measured by the Solar Aspect Monitor on the Solar
  Dynamic Observatory Extreme ultraviolet Variability Experiment</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.IM physics.space-ph</categories><comments>28 text pages + references, 13 figures, 2 tables; accepted for
  publication in Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Geophysical Research: Space Physics, Vol. 121, Issue 4,
  pp. 3648-3664; 2016 April 22</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/2015JA021726</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Solar Aspect Monitor (SAM) is a pinhole camera on the Extreme-ultraviolet
Variability Experiment (EVE) aboard the Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO). SAM
projects the solar disk onto the CCD through a metallic filter designed to
allow only solar photons shortward of 7 nm to pass. Contamination from
energetic particles and out-of-band irradiance is, however, significant in the
SAM observations. We present a technique for isolating the 0.01--7 nm
integrated irradiance from the SAM signal to produce the first results of
broadband irradiance for the time period from May 2010 to May 2014. The results
of this analysis agree with a similar data product from EVE's EUV
SpectroPhotometer (ESP) to within 25%. We compare our results with measurements
from the Student Nitric Oxide Explorer (SNOE) Solar X-ray Photometer (SXP) and
the Thermosphere Ionosphere Mesosphere Energetics and Dynamics (TIMED) Solar
EUV Experiment (SEE) at similar levels of solar activity. We show that the
full-disk SAM broadband results compare well to the other measurements of the
0.01--7 nm irradiance. We also explore SAM's capability toward resolving
spatial contribution from regions of solar disk in irradiance and demonstrate
this feature with a case study of several strong flares that erupted from
active regions on March 11, 2011.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02698</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02698</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Het&#xe9;nyi</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanatar</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martelo</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational Monte Carlo method for the Baeriswyl wavefunction:
  application to the one-dimensional bosonic Hubbard model</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>minor changes compared to previous version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev B vol. 93 art.174518 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.174518</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A variational Monte Carlo method for bosonic lattice models is introduced.
The method is based on the Baeriswyl projected wavefunction. The Baeriswyl
wavefunction consists of a kinetic energy based projection applied to the
wavefunction at infinite interaction, and is related to the shadow wavefunction
already used in the study of continuous models of bosons. The wavefunction at
infinite interaction, and the projector, are represented in coordinate space,
leading to an expression for expectation values which can be evaluated via
Monte Carlo sampling. We calculate the phase diagram and other properties of
the bosonic Hubbard model. The calculated phase diagram is in excellent
agreement with known quantum Monte Carlo results. We also analyze correlation
functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03974</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bizet</keyname><forenames>Nana Cabo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loaiza-Brito</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zavala</keyname><forenames>Ivonne</forenames></author></authors><title>Mirror quintic vacua: hierarchies and inflation</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>50 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the moduli space of type IIB string theory flux compactifications on
the mirror of the CY quintic 3-fold in P4. We focus on the dynamics of the four
dimensional moduli space, defined by the axio-dilaton {\tau} and the complex
structure modulus z. The z-plane has critical points, the conifold, the
orbifold and the large complex structure with non trivial monodromies. We find
the solutions to the Picard-Fuchs equations obeyed by the periods of the CY in
the full z-plane as a series expansion in z around the critical points to
arbitrary order. This allows us to discard fake vacua, which appear as a result
of keeping only the leading order term in the series expansions. Due to
monodromies vacua are located at a given sheet in the z-plane. A dS vacuum
appears for a set of fluxes. We revisit vacua with hierarchies among the 4D and
6D physical scales close to the conifold point and compare them with those
found at leading order in [1, 2]. We explore slow-roll inflationary directions
of the scalar potential by looking at regions where the multi-field slow-roll
parameters {\epsilon} and {\eta} are smaller than one. The value of {\epsilon}
depends strongly on the approximation of the periods and to achieve a stable
value, several orders in the expansion are needed. We do not find realisations
of single field axion monodromy inflation. Instead, we find that inflationary
regions appear along linear combinations of the four real field directions and
for certain configurations of fluxes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04676</id><created>2016-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Jibitesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Saugata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chetry</keyname><forenames>Binod</forenames></author></authors><title>Modified Bekenstein-Hawking system in $f(R)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, six figs. Accepted for publication in IJTP. Welcome
  comments</comments><doi>10.1007/s10773-016-3052-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work deals with four alternative formulation of Bekenstein system
on event horizon in $f(R)$ gravity. While thermodynamical laws holds in
universe bounded by apparent horizon, these laws break down on event horizon.
With alternative formulation of thermodynamical parameters (temperature and
entropy), thermodynamical laws hold on event horizon in Einstein Gravity. With
this motivation, we extend the idea of generalised Hawking temperature and
modified Bekenstein entropy in homogeneous and isotropic model of universe on
event horizon and examine whether thermodynamical laws hold in f(R) gravity.
Specifically, we examine and compare validity of generalised second law of
thermodynamics (GSLT) and thermodynamical equilibrium (TE) in four alternative
modified Bekenstein scenarios. As Dark energy is a possible dominant candidate
for matter in the univerese and Holographic Dark Energy (HDE) can give
effective description of f(R) gravity, so matter in the universe is taken as in
the form interacting HDE. In order to understand the complicated expressions,
finally the above laws are examined from graphical representation using three
Planck data sets and it is found that generalised/modified Hawking temperature
has a crucial role in making perfect thermodynamical system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04833</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04833</id><created>2016-05-13</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jun</keyname><forenames>Kyungtaek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Seokhwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kwon</keyname><forenames>Kyu</forenames></author></authors><title>Alignment Solution for CT Image Reconstruction by Fixed Point and
  Virtual Rotation Axis</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>28 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since X-ray tomography is now widely adopted in many different areas, it
becomes more crucial to find a robust routine of handling tomographic data to
get quality reconstructed images. Though there are several existing techniques,
it seems helpful to have a more automated method to remove the possible errors
that hinder clearer image reconstruction. Here, we proposed an alternative
method and new algorithm using the sinogram and the fixed point. A new physical
concept of Center of Attenuation (CA) was also introduced to figure out how
this fixed point is applied to the image reconstruction with errors we further
categorized. Our technique showed a promising performance in restoring images
with translation and vertical tilt errors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06151</id><created>2016-05-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Miri</keyname><forenames>Mohammad-Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eftekhar</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Amin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Facao</keyname><forenames>Margarida</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abouraddy</keyname><forenames>Ayman F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bakry</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Razvi</keyname><forenames>Mir A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alshahrie</keyname><forenames>Ahmed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Al&#xf9;</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christodoulides</keyname><forenames>Demetrios N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering properties of PT-symmetric objects</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. 18, 075104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/2040-8978/18/7/075104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the scattering response of parity-time (PT) symmetric
structures. We show that, due to the local flow of energy between gain and loss
regions, such systems can deflect light in unusual ways, as a function of the
gain/loss contrast. Such structures are highly anisotropic and their scattering
patterns can drastically change as a function of the angle of incidence. In
addition, we derive a modified optical theorem for PT-symmetric scattering
systems, and discuss its ramifications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07287</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07287</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-05-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asano</keyname><forenames>Motoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Yuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;zdemir</keyname><forenames>&#x15e;ahin Kaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikuta</keyname><forenames>Rikizo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Stimulated Brillouin scattering and Brillouin-coupled four-wave-mixing
  in a silica microbottle resonator</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 12082-12092 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.012082</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the first observation of stimulated Brillouin scattering (SBS) with
Brillouin lasing, and Brillouin-coupled four-wave-mixing (FWM) in an
ultra-high-Q silica microbottle resonator. The Brillouin lasing was observed at
the frequency of $\Omega_B=2\pi\times10.4$ GHz with a threshold power of $0.45$
mW. Coupling between Brillouin and FWM was observed in both backward and
forward scattering directions with separations of $2\Omega_B$. At a pump power
of $10$ mW, FWM spacing reached to 7th and 9th order anti-Stokes and Stokes,
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07825</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07825</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-05-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Catherine</forenames><affiliation>Leiden Observatory, The Netherlands</affiliation></author></authors><title>Chemical complexity in protoplanetary disks in the era of ALMA and
  Rosetta</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Conference proceedings from The 6th Zermatt ISM Symposium: Conditions
  and Impact of Star Formation</comments><journal-ref>EAS publications series, 75-76 (2015), 315-320</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/eas/1575063</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Comets provide a unique insight into the molecular composition and complexity
of the material in the primordial solar nebula. Recent results from the Rosetta
mission, currently monitoring comet 67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko in situ, and ALMA
(the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array), have demonstrated a
tantalising link between the chemical complexity now confirmed in disks (via
the detection of gas-phase CH3CN; Oberg et al. 2015) and that confirmed on the
surface of 67P (Goesmann et al. 2015), raising questions concerning the
chemical origin of such species (cloud or inheritance versus disk synthesis).
Results from an astrochemical model of a protoplanetary disk are presented in
which complex chemistry is included and in which it is assumed that simple ices
only are inherited from the parent molecular cloud. The model results show good
agreement with the abundances of several COMs observed on the surface of 67P
with Philae/COSAC. Cosmic-ray and X-ray-induced photoprocessing of
predominantly simple ices inherited by the protoplanetary disk is sufficient to
generate a chemical complexity similar to that observed in comets. This
indicates that the icy COMs detected on the surface of 67P may have a disk
origin. The results also show that gas-phase CH3CN is abundant in the inner
warm disk atmosphere where hot gas-phase chemistry dominates and potentially
erases the ice chemical signature. Hence, CH3CN may not be an unambiguous
tracer of the complex organic ice reservoir. However, a better understanding of
the hot gas-phase chemistry of CH3CN is needed to confirm this preliminary
conclusion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08032</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08032</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Dzyurkevich</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Commer&#xe7;on</keyname><forenames>Beno&#xee;t</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesaffre</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Semenov</keyname><forenames>Dimitry</forenames></author></authors><title>3D radiative hydrodynamic simulations of protostellar collapse with
  H-C-O dynamical chemistry</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 12 figures. Submitted to A&amp;A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Combining the co-evolving chemistry, hydrodynamics and radiative transfer is
an important step for star formation studies. It allows both a better link to
observations and a self-consistent monitoring of the magnetic dissipation in
the collapsing core. Our aim is to follow a chemo-dynamical evolution of
collapsing dense cores with a reduced gas-grain chemical network. We present
the results of radiative hydrodynamic (RHD) simulations of 1 M$_\odot$ isolated
dense core collapse. The physical setup includes RHD and dynamical evolution of
a chemical network. To perform those simulations, we merged the
multi-dimensional adaptive-mesh-refinement code RAMSES and the thermo-chemistry
Paris-Durham shock code. We simulate the formation of the first hydro-static
core (FHSC) and the co-evolution of 56 species describing mainly H-C-O
chemistry. Accurate benchmarking is performed, testing the reduced chemical
network against a well-establiched complex network. We show that by using a
compact set of reactions, one can match closely the CO abundances with results
of a much more complex network. Our main results are: (a) We find that
gas-grain chemistry post-processing can lead to one order of magnitude lower CO
gas-phase abundances compared to the dynamical chemistry, with strongest effect
during the isothermal phase of collapse. (b) The free-fall time has little
effect on the chemical abundances for our choice of the parameters. (c)
Dynamical chemical evolution is required to describe the CO gas phase abundance
as well as the CO ice formation for the mean grain size larger then 1$\mu{}$m.
(d) Furthermore, dust mean size and size distribution have a strong effect on
chemical abundances and hence on the ionization degree and magnetic
dissipation. We conclude that dust grain growth in the collapse simulations can
be as important as coupling the collapse with chemistry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08033</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08033</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Piron</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delacroix</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huby</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mawet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruane</keyname><forenames>M. Karlsson ad G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Habraken</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Absil</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Surdej</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Mach-Zehnder interferometer based on orbital angular momentum for
  improved vortex coronagraph efficiency</title><categories>physics.optics astro-ph.IM</categories><journal-ref>Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 9605, id. 96051J 13 pp. (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1117/12.2189329</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Annular Groove Phase Mask (AGPM) is a vectorial vortex phase mask. It
acts as a half-wave plate with a radial fast axis orientation operating in the
mid infrared domain. When placed at the focus of a telescope element provides a
continuous helical phase ramp for an on axis sources, which creates the orbital
angular momentum. Thanks to that phase, the intensity of the central source is
canceled by a down-stream pupil stop, while the off axis sources are not
affected. However due to experimental conditions the nulling is hardly perfect.
To improve the null, a Mach-Zehnder interferometer containing Dove prisms
differently oriented can be proposed to sort out light based on its orbital
angular momentum (OAM). Thanks to the differential rotation of the beam, a
{\pi} phase shift is achieved for the on axis light affected by a non zero OAM.
Therefore the contrast between the star and its faint companion is enhanced.
Nevertheless, due the Dove prisms birefringence, the performance of the
interferometer is relatively poor. To solve this problem, we propose to add a
birefringent wave-plate in each arm to compensate this birefringence. In this
paper, we will develop the mathematical model of the wave front using the Jones
formalism. The performance of the interferometer is at first computed for the
simple version without the birefringent plate. Then the effect of the
birefringent plate is be mathematically described and the performance is
re-computed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08058</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08058</id><created>2016-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Duluard</keyname><forenames>Corinne Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hubert</keyname><forenames>Julie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical diagnostics and mass spectrometry on the afterglow of an
  atmospheric pressure Ar/O$_2$ radiofrequency plasma used for polymer surface
  treatment</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>http://mpserver.pst.qub.ac.uk/sites/icpig2011/301_C10_Duluard.pdf,
  30th-ICPIG, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 28th August-2nd September 2011, C10</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of polymer surface treatment, the afterglow of an atmospheric
pressure Ar/O$_2$ radiofrequency plasma is characterized by optical emission
spectroscopy, laser induced fluorescence and mass spectrometry. The influence
of the O$_2$ gas flow rate and the source power on the plasma properties (gas
temperature, Ar excitation temperature, relative concentrations of O atoms and
OH radicals) are evaluated. We show that for plasma torch-to-substrate
distances lower than 6 mm, the afterglow creates a protective atmosphere, thus
the plasma gas composition interacting with the substrate is well controlled.
For higher distances, the influence of ambient air can no longer be neglected
and gradients in Ar, O$_2$ and N$_2$ concentrations are measured as a function
of axial and vertical position.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08069</id><created>2016-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Buelow</keyname><forenames>Henning</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aref</keyname><forenames>Vahid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Idler</keyname><forenames>Wilfried</forenames></author></authors><title>Transmission of Waveforms Determined by 7 Eigenvalues with PSK-Modulated
  Spectral Amplitudes</title><categories>physics.optics cs.IT math.IT</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  2-ns waveforms with 7 eigenvalues and their QPSK-modulated spectral
amplitudes were optimized by taking constraints of link, transmitter, and
receiver into account. In experiment these signals were transmitted with a BER
of 3.2E-3 over 1440-km of NZ-DSF fiber spans.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08075</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Schnitzer</keyname><forenames>Howard J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological R\'enyi and Entanglement Entropy for a 2d q-deformed $U(N)$
  Yang-Mills theory and its Chern-Simons dual</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><report-no>BRX-TH-6303</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  R\'enyi and entanglement entropies are constructed for 2d q-deformed
topological Yang-Mills theories with gauge group $U(N)$, as well as the dual 3d
Chern-Simons (CS) theory on Seifert manifolds. When $q=\exp[2\pi i/(N+K)]$, and
$K$ is odd, the topological R\'enyi entropy and Wilson line observables of the
CS theory can be expressed in terms of the modular transformation matrices of
the WZW theory, $\rm{\hat{U}(N)}_{K,N(K+N)}$. If both $K$ and $N$ are odd,
there is a level-rank duality of the 2d qYM theory and of the associated CS
theory, as well as that of the R\'enyi and entanglement entropies, and Wilson
line observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08076</id><created>2016-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Yuwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Hongfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Liangsheng</forenames></author></authors><title>The optimization for the conceptual design of a 300 MeV proton
  synchrotron</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A research complex for aerospace radiation effects research has been proposed
in Harbin Institute of Technology. Its core part is a proton accelerator
complex, which consists of a 10 MeV injector, a 300 MeV synchrotron and beam
transport lines. The proton beam extracted from the synchrotron is utilized for
the radiation effects research. Based on the conceptual design [1], the design
study for optimizing the synchrotron has been done. A new lattice design was
worked out, and the multi-turn injection and slow extraction system were
optimized with the new lattice design. In order to improve the time structure
of the extracted beam, a RF knock-out method is employed. To meet the
requirement of accurate control of dose, the frequency of the RF kicker is well
investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08079</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08079</id><created>2016-05-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Leghrib</keyname><forenames>Radouane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dufour</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Demoisson</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Claessens</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reniers</keyname><forenames>Fran&#xe7;ois</forenames></author><author><keyname>Llobet</keyname><forenames>Eduard</forenames></author></authors><title>Gas sensing properties of multiwall carbon nanotubes decorated with Rh
  nanoparticles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.plasm-ph</categories><journal-ref>Sensors and actuators B: Chemical, 2011, Vol. 160, Issue 1,
  974-980</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.snb.2011.09.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present work, multiwalled carbon nanotubes were decorated with rhodium
nanoparticles using a colloidal solution in the post-discharge of an RF
atmospheric plasma of argon (Ar) or argon/oxygen (Ar:O$_2$). The properties of
these hybrid materials towards the room temperature detection of NO$_2$,
C$_2$H$_4$, CO, C$_6$H$_6$ and moisture were investigated and discussed in view
of compositional and morphological studies. It was found that the presence of
oxygen in the plasma treatment is essential to significantly enhance the gas
response of Rh-decorated multiwalled carbon nanotubes and to avoid response
saturation even at low gas/vapor concentrations. These desirable effects are
attributed to the presence of oxygen during the CNT plasma treatment since
oxygenated vacancies act both as active adsorption sites for gases and as
anchoring sites for Rh nanoparticles (the presence of Rh nanoclusters is nearly
doubled in Ar-O$_2$ treated samples as compared to Ar treated samples). The
oxygen treatment also makes easier the charge transfer between Rh nanoparticles
and carbon nanotubes upon gas adsorption. The method for treating and
decorating multiwalled carbon nanotubes used here is simple, fast and scalable
for producing gas sensitive nanohybrid materials with uniform and
well-controlled properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08080</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Solovyeva</keyname><forenames>Alisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Lilienfeld</keyname><forenames>O. Anatole</forenames></author></authors><title>Rapid yet accurate first principle based predictions of alkali halide
  crystal phases using alchemical perturbation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We assess the predictive power of alchemical perturbations for estimating
fundamental properties in ionic crystals. Using density functional theory we
have calculated formation energies, lattice constants, and bulk moduli for all
sixteen iso-valence-electronic combinations of pure pristine alkali halides
involving elements $A \in \{$Na, K, Rb, Cs$\}$ and $X \in \{$F, Cl, Br, I$\}$.
For rock salt, zincblende and cesium chloride symmetry, alchemical
Hellmann-Feynman derivatives, evaluated along lattice scans of sixteen
reference crystals, have been obtained for all respective 16$\times$15
combinations of reference and predicted target crystals. Mean absolute errors
(MAE) are on par with density functional theory level of accuracy for energies
and bulk modulus. Predicted lattice constants are less accurate. NaCl is the
best reference salt for alchemical estimates of relative energies (MAE $&lt;$ 40
meV/atom) while alkali fluorides are the worst. By contrast, lattice constants
are predicted best using NaF as a reference salt (MAE $&lt;$ 0.5{\AA}), yielding
only semi-quantitative accuracy. The best reference salt for the prediction of
bulk moduli is CsCl (MAE $&lt;$ 0.4$\times$10$^{11}$ dynes/cm$^2$). Alchemical
derivatives can also be used to predict competing rock salt and cesium chloride
phases in binary and ternary solid mixtures with CsCl. Alchemical predictions
based on dispersion corrected density functional theory with pure RbI as a
reference salt reproduce reasonably well the reversal of the rock salt/cesium
chloride stability trend for binary $(AX)_{1-x}$CsCl$_x$ as well as for ternary
$(AX)_{0.5-0.5x}(BY)_{0.5-0.5x}$CsCl$_x$ mixtures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08085</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Vavrycuk</keyname><forenames>Vaclav</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of galactic and intergalactic dust on the stellar EBL</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysics and Space Science (2016), vol. 361, art. no. 198</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2785-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current theories assume that the low intensity of the stellar extragalactic
background light (stellar EBL) is caused primarily by finite age of the
Universe because the finite age limits the number of photons pumped into the
space by galaxies and thus the sky is dark in the night. We oppose this opinion
and show that two main factors are responsible for the extremely low intensity
of the observed stellar EBL: (1) a low mean surface brightness of galaxies,
which causes a low luminosity density in the local Universe, and (2) light
extinction due to absorption by galactic and intergalactic dust. Dust produces
a partial opacity of galaxies and of the Universe. The galactic opacity reduces
the intensity of light from more distant background galaxies obscured by
foreground galaxies. The effective extinction AV for light passing through a
galaxy is 0.2 mag. This causes that distant background galaxies do not
contribute to the EBL significantly. In addition, light of distant galaxies is
dimmed due to absorption by intergalactic dust. Even a minute intergalactic
opacity of 1x10^(-2) mag per Gpc is high enough to produce significant effects
on the EBL. The absorbed starlight heats up the galactic and intergalactic dust
and is further re-radiated at the IR, FIR and micro-wave spectrum. Assuming
static infinite universe with no galactic and intergalactic dust, the stellar
EBL should be as high as the surface brightness of stars. However, if dust is
considered, the predicted stellar EBL is about 290 nWm^(-2)sr^(-1), which is
only 5 times higher than the observed value. Hence, the presence of dust has
higher impact on the EBL than currently assumed. In the expanding universe, the
calculated value of the EBL is further decreased, because the obscuration
effect and intergalactic absorption become more pronounced at high redshifts
when the matter was concentrated at smaller volume than at present.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08087</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>El-Showk</keyname><forenames>Sheer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paulos</keyname><forenames>Miguel F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extremal bootstrapping: go with the flow</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>35+5 pages and lots of nice figures</comments><report-no>CERN-TH-2016-125</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extremal functional method determines approximate solutions to the
constraints of crossing symmetry, which saturate bounds on the space of unitary
CFTs. We show that such solutions are characterized by extremality conditions,
which may be used to flow continuously along the boundaries of parameter space.
Along the flow there is generically no further need for optimization, which
dramatically reduces computational requirements, bringing calculations from the
realm of computing clusters to laptops. Conceptually, extremality sheds light
on possible ways to bootstrap without positivity, extending the method to
non-unitary theories, and implies that theories saturating bounds, and
especially those sitting at kinks, have unusually sparse spectra. We discuss
several applications, including the first high-precision bootstrap of a
non-unitary CFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08091</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08091</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fodor</keyname><forenames>Zoltan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holland</keyname><forenames>Kieran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuti</keyname><forenames>Julius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondal</keyname><forenames>Santanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogradi</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Chik Him</forenames></author></authors><title>New approach to the Dirac spectral density in lattice gauge theory
  applications</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, Proceedings of the 33rd International Symposium on Lattice
  Field Theory (LATTICE2015), Kobe, Japan, 14-18 July 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report tests and results from a new approach to the spectral density and
the mode number distribution of the Dirac operator in lattice gauge theories.
The algorithm generates the spectral density of the lattice Dirac operator as a
continuous function over all scales of the complete eigenvalue spectrum. This
is distinct from an earlier method where the integrated spectral density (mode
number) was calculated efficiently for some preselected fixed range of the
integration. The new algorithm allows global studies like the chiral condensate
from the Dirac spectrum at any scale including the cutoff-dependent IR and UV
range of the spectrum. Physics applications include the scale-dependent mass
anomalous dimension, spectral representation of composite fermion operators,
and the crossover transition from the $\epsilon$-regime of Random Matrix Theory
to the p-regime in chiral perturbation theory. We present thorough tests of the
algorithm in the 2-flavor sextet SU(3) gauge theory that we continue to pursue
for its potential as a minimal realization of the composite Higgs scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08105</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Sayre</keyname><forenames>Eleanor C</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fracchiolla</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dusen</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>iPad Screencasts as Evidence of Accountable Disciplinary Knowledge</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures, submitted to Physical Review -- Physics Education
  Research</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We define knowledge as facts, information, and skills acquired by a person
through experience or education. In turn, Disciplinary Knowledge is the
knowledge related to a specific field or discipline, such as physics.
Accountable Disciplinary Knowledge (ADK) is &quot;what counts&quot; as important to a
community or discipline: the kinds of activities that participants engage in,
the problems they value and solve, and methods for solving those problems.
Because ADK is determined on a community basis, the details of &quot;what counts&quot;
will vary with the norms and expectations of the community. In this paper, we
use the ADK framework to investigate &quot;what counts&quot; as solving problems well in
a high school physics classroom from the perspective of the students.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08116</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Tanabe</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Elastic instability of black rings at large D</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages, 1 figure, Ancillary Mathematica notebook contains effective
  equations at NNLO</comments><report-no>RUP-16-15</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the inverse dimensional expansion method we study the elastic
instability of black rings found recently in numerical analysis of fully
nonlinear dynamical evolutions. In our analysis we should perform 1/D^1/2
expansions, not usual 1/D expansions, of the Einstein equations to capture this
elastic instability of D dimensional black rings. By solving the Einstein
equations at large D we obtain the effective equations for black rings, and the
perturbation analysis of the large D effective equations with 1/D^1/2
expansions yields the formula for quasinormal mode frequencies. From this
formula, we find that black rings actually suffer from both elastic and
Gregory-Laflamme like instabilities. These instabilities are coupled and appear
at the same time as observed in numerical analysis. The elastic instability
does disappear at the infinite limit of a ring radius, which implies that the
(boosted) black string is stable to elastic perturbations. Furthermore we
observe that the Gregory-Laflamme like instability becomes more efficient than
the elastic instability even for certain thin black rings in enough higher
dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08126</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Amore</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Francisco M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobo</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhevandrov</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author></authors><title>Bound states in weakly deformed waveguides: numerical vs analytical
  results</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the emergence of bound states in weakly deformed and/or
heterogeneous waveguides, comparing the analytical predictions obtained using a
recently developed perturbative method, with precise numerical results, for
different configurations (a homogeneous asymmetric waveguide, a heterogenous
asymmetric waveguide and a homogeneous broken-strip). In all the examples
considered in this paper we have found excellent agreement between analytical
and numerical results, thus providing a numerical verification of the
analytical approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08139</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Banura</keyname><forenames>Natsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mimura</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimoto</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murase</keyname><forenames>Kenya</forenames></author></authors><title>Heat Transfer Simulation for Optimization and Treatment Planning of
  Magnetic Hyperthermia Using Magnetic Particle Imaging</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This study was undertaken to develop a system for heat transfer simulation
for optimization and treatment planning of magnetic hyperthermia treatment
(MHT) using magnetic particle imaging (MPI). First, we performed phantom
experiments to obtain the regression equation between the MPI pixel value and
the specific absorption rate (SAR) of magnetic nanoparticles (MNPs), from which
the MPI pixel value was converted to the SAR value in the simulation. Second,
we generated the geometries for use in the simulation by processing X-ray
computed tomography (CT) and MPI images of tumor-bearing mice injected
intratumorally with MNPs (Resovist). The geometries and MPI images were then
imported into software based on a finite element method (COMSOL Multiphysics)
to compute the time-dependent temperature distribution for 20 min after the
start of MHT. There was an excellent correlation between the MPI pixel value
and the SAR value (r = 0.956). There was good agreement between the time course
of the temperature rise in the tumors obtained by simulation and that obtained
experimentally. The time-dependent temperature distributions under various
blood perfusion rates in the tumors and at various locations could be
simulated, which cannot be easily obtained experimentally. These results
suggest that our system for heat transfer simulation using MPI will be useful
for the optimization and treatment planning of MHT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08145</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Munusamy</keyname><forenames>Selva Balaji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dhar</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author></authors><title>Can We Remove Secular Terms for Analytical Solution of Groundwater
  Response under Tidal Influence?</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a secular term removal methodology based on the homotopy
perturbation method for analytical solutions of nonlinear problems with
periodic boundary condition. The analytical solution for groundwater response
to tidal fluctuation in a coastal unconfined aquifer system with the vertical
beach is provided as an example. The non-linear one-dimensional Boussinesq's
equation is considered as the governing equation for the groundwater flow. An
analytical solution is provided for non-dimensional Boussinesq's equation with
cosine harmonic boundary condition representing tidal boundary condition. The
analytical solution is obtained by using homotopy perturbation method with a
virtual embedding parameter. The present approach does not require
pre-specified perturbation parameter and also facilitates secular terms
elimination in the perturbation solution. The solutions starting from
zeroth-order up to third-order are obtained. The non-dimensional expression,
$A/D_{\infty}$ emerges as an implicit parameter from the homotopy perturbation
solution. The non-dimensional solution is valid for all ranges of $A/D$ values.
Higher order solution reveals the characteristics of the tidal groundwater
table fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08155</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Subir K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pattern, Growth and Aging in a Colony of Clustering Active Swimmers</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Via molecular dynamics simulations, we study the kinetics in a phase
separating active matter model. Quantitative results for the isotropic
bicontinuous pattern formation, its growth and aging, studied, respectively,
via the two-point equal-time density-density correlation function, the average
domain length and the two-time density autocorrelation function, are presented.
Both the correlation functions exhibit basic scaling properties, implying
self-similarity in the pattern dynamics, for which the average domain size
exhibits a power-law growth in time. The equal-time correlation has a short
distance behavior that provides reasonable agreement of the corresponding
structure factor tail with the Porod law. The autocorrelation decay is a
power-law in the average domain size. Apart from these basic similarities, the
quantitative behavior of the above mentioned observables are found to be vastly
different from those of the corresponding passive limit of the model which also
undergoes phase separation. The functional forms of these have been quantified.
An exceptionally rapid growth in the active system occurs due to fast coherent
motion of the particles, mean-squared-displacements of which exhibit multiple
scaling regimes, including a long time ballistic one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08158</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Jifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermoelectric properties of $n$-type SrTiO3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>APL Materials 4, 104803 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4952610</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an investigation of the thermoelectric properties of cubic
perovskite SrTiO3. The results are derived from a combination of calculated
transport functions obtained from Boltzmann transport theory in the constant
scattering time approximation based on the electronic structure and existing
experimental data for La-doped SrTiO3. The figure of merit ZT is modeled with
respect to carrier concentration and temperature. The model predicts a
relatively high $ZT$ at optimized doping, and suggests that the $ZT$ value can
reach 0.7 at T = 1400 K. Thus $ZT$ can be improved from the current
experimental values by carrier concentration optimization.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08171</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zaijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Renli</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of level inversion on the Coulomb displacement energies of the
  Ar-K isobaric analog state pairs</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Coulomb displacement energies of the neutron-rich Ar-K isobaric analog
state pairs with mass number $A=35-47$ are calculated within the relativistic
mean field model and the effects of level inversion on the Coulomb displacement
energies of the Ar-K isobaric analog state pairs are studied. The calculations
are carried out in two cases, with and without consideration of the possible
$2s_{1/2}$ and $1d_{3/2}$ proton level inversion of the neutron-rich Ar
isotopes. Results show that the $2s_{1/2}$ and $1d_{3/2}$ level inversion of
the neutron-rich Ar isotopes may reduce the Coulomb displacement energy by
0.06$\sim$0.17 MeV for the Ar-K isobaric analog state pairs. The results may
provide a reference for experimental investigations of nuclear level inversion
and a new test of the relativistic mean field model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08173</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Narendranath</keyname><forenames>Aneet Dharmavaram</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of thin liquid films on a porous substrate in zero gravity</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The long-wave dynamics of liquid films on isothermal substrates show a
dynamic competition between various physical mechanisms. If the destabilizing
effect of thermocapillarity overcomes the stabilizing effect of surface tension
and gravity, the liquid film ruptures in finite time, through the formation of
primary and secondary thermocapillary finger structures.
  The long-wave evolution dynamics are compared for two different substrate
types: isothermal non-porous and isothermal porous for small Biot number in a
zero gravity environment. The multi-time-scale dynamics is revealed through
time scales obtained from a method of similarity solutions. It is observed that
with an isothermal porous substrate, in zero gravity, secondary thermocapillary
structures are damped through imbibition and that primary thermocapillary
structures persist for long times without rupture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08176</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08176</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhan</keyname><forenames>Haifei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhan</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Vincent BC</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>John M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Yuantong</forenames></author></authors><title>Diamond nanothread as a new reinforcement for nanocomposites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>in press, early view online in Advanced Functional Materials, 2016</comments><doi>10.1002/adfm.201600119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work explores the application of a new one-dimensional carbon
nanomaterial, the diamond nanothread (DNT), as a reinforcement for
nanocomposites. Owing to the existence of Stone-Wales transformation defects,
the DNT intrinsically possesses irregular surfaces, which is expected to
enhance the non-covalent interfacial load transfer. Through a series of in
silico pull-out studies of the DNT in polyethylene (PE) matrix, we found that
the load transfer between DNT and PE matrix is dominated by the non-covalent
interactions, in particular the van der Waals interactions. Although the
hydrogenated surface of the DNT reduces the strength of the van der Waals
interactions at the interface, the irregular surface of the DNT can compensate
for the weak bonds. These factors lead to an interfacial shear strength of the
DNT/PE interface comparable with that of the carbon nanotube (CNT)/PE
interface. Our results show that the DNT/PE interfacial shear strength remains
high even as the number of Stone-Wales transformation defects decreases. It can
be enhanced further by increasing the PE density or introduction of functional
groups to the DNT, both of which greatly increase the non-covalent
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08181</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirza</keyname><forenames>Imran M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Begzjav</keyname><forenames>Tuguldur</forenames></author></authors><title>Fano-Agarwal couplings and non-rotating wave approximation in
  single-photon timed-Dicke subradiance</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 114 (2016) 24004</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/24004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently a new class of single-photon timed-Dicke (TD) subradiant states has
been introduced with possible applications in single-photon based quantum
information storage and on demand ultrafast retrieval [Scully M. O., Phys. Rev.
Lett., 115 (2015) 243602]. However, the influence of any kind of virtual
processes on the decay of these new kind of subradiant states has been left as
an open question. In the present paper, we focus on this problem in detail. In
particular, we investigate how pure Fano-Agarwal couplings and other virtual
processes arising from non-rotating wave approximation impact the decay of
otherwise sub and superradiant states. In addition to the overall virtual
couplings among all TD states, we also focus on the dominant role played by the
couplings between specific TD states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08182</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mirza</keyname><forenames>Imran M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong coupling optical spectra in dipole-dipole interacting
  optomechanical Tavis-Cummings models</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures, Application of non-local Lindblad model</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters, Vol. 41, No. 11 / June 1 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.002422</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We theoretically investigate the emission spectrum of an optomechanical
Tavis-Cummings model: two dipole-dipole interacting atoms coupled to an
optomechanical cavity (OMC). In particular, we study the influence of
dipole-dipole interaction (DDI) on the single-photon spectrum emitted by this
hybrid system in the presence of a strong atom-cavity as well as strong
optomechanical interaction (hereinafter called the strong-strong coupling). We
also show that our analysis is amenable to inclusion of mechanical losses
(under the weak mechanical damping limit) and single-photon loss through
spontaneous emission from the two-level emitters under a non-local Lindblad
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08184</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Ankan</forenames></author></authors><title>Acceleration of the universe: a reconstruction of the effective equation
  of state</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 460, 273 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw964</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work is based upon a parametric reconstruction of the effective
or total equation of state in a model for the universe with accelerated
expansion. The constraints on the model parameters are obtained by maximum
likelihood analysis using the supernova distance modulus data, observational
Hubble data, baryon acoustic oscillation data and cosmic microwave background
shift parameter data. For statistical comparison, the same analysis has also
been carried out for the wCDM dark energy model. Different model selection
criteria (Akaike information criterion (AIC)) and (Bayesian Information
Criterion (BIC)) give the clear indication that the reconstructed model is well
consistent with the wCDM model. Then both the models (w_{eff}(z) model and wCDM
model) have also been presented through (q_0 ,j_0 ) parameter space. Tighter
constraint on the present values of dark energy equation of state parameter
(w_{DE}(z = 0)) and cosmological jerk (j_0) have been achieved for the
reconstructed model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08190</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Weak boson production from D0 and LHCb in the NNPDF global analysis</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the XXIV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects,
  11-15 April, 2016, DESY Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  High-precision electroweak production measurements from the Tevatron and the
LHC provide important constraints on the quark flavor separation in global PDF
fits. In this contribution, we study the impact of the recent D0 W asymmetry
measurements and of the LHCb W and Z Run I combination in the global NNPDF
analysis. We find that these measurements can be described by NLO QCD theory
and that they lead to a significant reduction of PDF uncertainties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08192</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08192</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghose</keyname><forenames>Partha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical Electrodynamics in a Unified Theory</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Some consequences of a fully classical unified theory of gravity and
electromagnetism are worked out for the electromagnetic sector such as the
occurrence of classical light beams with spin and orbital angular momenta that
are topologically quantized in units of $q_e q_m=\sigma$, independent of the
beam size. Empirical fits require $\sigma = \hbar$. The theory also predicts a
generalized coherency matrix whose consequences are testable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08205</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Fabr&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Ferran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montany&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Joan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marisaldi</keyname><forenames>Martino</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Velde</keyname><forenames>Oscar A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuschino</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Analysis of global Terrestrial Gamma Ray Flashes distribution and
  special focus on AGILE detections over South America</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.jastp.2015.01.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Global distribution of the Terrestrial Gamma-ray Flashes (TGFs) detected by
AGILE and RHESSI for the period from March 2009 to July 2012 has been analysed.
A fourth TGF production region has been distinguished over the Pacific. It is
confirmed that TGF occurrence follows the Intertropical Convergence Zone(ITCZ)
seasonal migration and prefers afternoons. TGF/lightning ratio appears to be
lower over America than other regions suggesting that meteorological regional
differences are important for the TGF production. Diurnal cycle of TGFs peaks
in the afternoon suggesting that Convective Available Potential Energy (CAPE)
and convection are important for TGF production. Moreover all AGILE passages
over South America in the same period have been analysed to find meteorological
preferences for TGF occurrence. In each passage the analysis of Cloud Top
Altitude (CTA), CAPE, number of strokes, number of storms and coverage area of
clouds with temperatures below $-70\,^{\circ}{\rm C}$ (Cloud Top Coverage area,
CTC) are computed. On average, AGILE has been exposed to 19,100 strokes between
each TGF representing $\sim$68 hours of exposure over active storms. High CAPE
values, high cloud tops and high stroke occurrence suggests that meteorological
conditions conducive to vigorous and electrically active storms are important
for TGF production. It is shown that a high number of thunderstorms is
preferable for TGF production which may be explained by a greater chance of the
presence of a thunderstorm in the best development stage for TGF production.
High tropopause altitude seems to be important but not primordial for TGF
production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08210</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bera</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yusuf</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Amit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Majumder</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghoshray</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-range and short-range magnetic correlations, and microscopic origin
  of net magnetization in the spin-1 trimer chain compound CaNi3P4O14</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 184409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.184409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin-spin correlations and microscopic origin of net magnetization in the
spin-1 trimer chain compound CaNi3P4O14 have been investigated by powder
neutron diffraction. The present study reveals a 3D long-range magnetic
ordering below 16 K where the magnetic structure consists of ferromagnetic
trimers that are coupled ferromagnetically along the spin-chain. The moment
components along the a and c axes arrange antiferromagnetically. Our study
establishes that the uncompensated moment components along the b axis result in
a net magnetization per unit cell. The magnetic structure, determined in the
present study, is in agreement with the results of recent first principles
calculation; however, it is in contrast to a fascinating experimental
prediction of ferrimagnetic ordering based on the periodicity of the exchange
interactions in CaNi3P4O14. Our study also confirms the presence of broad
diffuse magnetic scattering, due to 1D short-range spin-spin correlations, over
a wide temperature range below ~50 K down to a temperature well below the Tc.
Total neutron scattering analysis by the RMC method reveals that the dominating
spin-spin correlation above Tc is ferromagnetic and along the b axis. The
nearest neighbour spin-spin correlations along the a and c axes are found to be
weakly antiferromagnetic. The nature of the trimer spin structure of the
short-range state is similar to that of the 3D long-range ordered state. The
present investigation of microscopic nature of the magnetic ground state also
explains the condition required for the 1/3 magnetization plateau to be
observed in the trimer spin-chains. In spite of the S=1 trimer chain system,
the present compound CaNi3P4O14 is found to be a good realization of 3D magnet
below the Tc=16 K with full ordered moment values of ~2 mu_B/Ni2+ (1.98 and
1.96 mu_B/Ni2+ for two Ni sites, respectively) at 1.5 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08218</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08218</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoshiike</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishiyama</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tatsumi</keyname><forenames>Toshitaka</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic properties in the inhomogeneous chiral phase</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, talk given in Excited QCD 2016, Mar. 6-12, 2016,
  Costa da Caparica, Portugal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the magnetic properties of quark matter in the inhomogeneous
chiral phase, where both scalar and pseudoscalar condensates spatially
modulate. The energy spectrum of the lowest Landau level becomes asymmetric
about zero in the external magnetic field, and gives rise to the remarkably
magnetic properties: quark matter has a spontaneous magnetization, while the
magnetic susceptibility does not diverge on the critical point.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08239</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Fear</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milan</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carter</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggiolo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The interaction between transpolar arcs and cusp spots</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><doi>10.1002/2015GL066194</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transpolar arcs and cusp spots are both auroral phenomena which occur when
the interplanetary magnetic field is northward. Transpolar arcs are associated
with magnetic reconnection in the magnetotail, which closes magnetic flux and
results in a &quot;wedge&quot; of closed flux which remains trapped, embedded in the
magnetotail lobe. The cusp spot is an indicator of lobe reconnection at the
high-latitude magnetopause; in its simplest case, lobe reconnection
redistributes open flux without resulting in any net change in the open flux
content of the magnetosphere. We present observations of the two phenomena
interacting--i.e., a transpolar arc intersecting a cusp spot during part of its
lifetime. The significance of this observation is that lobe reconnection can
have the effect of opening closed magnetotail flux. We argue that such events
should not be rare.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08252</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yuwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Mao-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Qiaoling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Lijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhengd</keyname><forenames>Weitao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Yanming</forenames></author></authors><title>Design of ternary alkaline-earth metal Sn(II) oxides with potential good
  p-type conductivity</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>new Sn(II) oxides with potential good p-type conductivity</comments><journal-ref>J. Mater. Chem. C, 2016,4, 4592-4599</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6TC00996D</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Oxides with good p-type conductivity have been long sought after to achieve
high performance all-oxide optoelectronic devices. Divalent Sn(II) based oxides
are promising candidates because of their rather dispersive upper valence bands
caused by the Sn-5s/O-2p anti-bonding hybridization. There are so far few known
Sn(II) oxides being p-type conductive suitable for device applications. Here,
we present via first-principles global optimization structure searches a
material design study for a hitherto unexplored Sn(II)-based system, ternary
alkaline-earth metal Sn(II) oxides in the stoichiometry of MSn2O3 (M = Mg, Ca,
Sr, Ba). We identify two stable compounds of SrSn2O3 and BaSn2O3, which can be
stabilized by Sn-rich conditions in phase stability diagrams. Their structures
follow the Zintl behaviour and consist of basic structural motifs of SnO3
tetrahedra. Unexpectedly they show distinct electronic properties with band
gaps ranging from 1.90 (BaSn2O3) to 3.15 (SrSn2O3) eV, and hole effective
masses ranging from 0.87 (BaSn2O3) to above 6.0 (SrSn2O3) m0. Further
exploration of metastable phases indicates a wide tunability of electronic
properties controlled by the details of the bonding between the basic
structural motifs. This suggests further exploration of alkaline-earth metal
Sn(II) oxides for potential applications requiring good p-type conductivity
such as transparent conductors and photovoltaic absorbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08255</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Kapral</keyname><forenames>Raymond</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface hopping from the perspective of quantum-classical Liouville
  dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><doi>10.1016/j.chemphys.2016.05.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fewest-switches surface hopping is studied in the context of
quantum-classical Liouville dynamics. Both approaches are mixed
quantum-classical theories that provide a way to describe and simulate the
nonadiabatic quantum dynamics of many-body systems. Starting from a
surface-hopping solution of the quantum-classical Liouville equation, it is
shown how fewest-switches dynamics can be obtained by dropping terms that are
responsible for decoherence and restricting the nuclear momentum changes that
accompany electronic transitions to those events that occur between population
states. The analysis provides information on some of the elements that are
essential for the construction of accurate and computationally tractable
algorithms for nonadiabatic processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08268</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08268</id><created>2016-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Bu</keyname><forenames>Shou-Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative Energy: From Lamb Shift to Entanglement</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><msc-class>81T08</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  &quot;Negative energy&quot; has been one of the most enduring puzzles in quantum
theory, whereas the present work reveals that it actually plays a central role
in clarifying various controversies of quantum theory. The basic idea is
contained in a hypothesis on negative energy, and it is shown that the idea:
(1)is compatible with both relativistic quantum mechanics and known
experimental results; (2)helps to clarify the essence of matter waves, and
therefore better understand the reality of the wave function, the so-called
'wave-packet reduction' occurring in quantum measurement, and the ghost like
correlations between entangled systems; (3)is helpful for distinguishing the
vacuum from the ground state of the quantized field, and may supply a possible
way for removing the deep-rooted infinities in quantum field theory. The vacuum
energy density of the electromagnetic field is calculated here as an example.
By employing the same idea, the Lamb-Shift is recalculated in a different way
from conventional renormalization method, yet the same result as Bethe's can be
definitely obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08271</id><created>2016-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Shnirelman</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>On the butterfly effect</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>35Q31, 76E20, 76F65</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The term &quot;butterfly effect&quot; means an extreme sensitivity of a dynamical
system to small perturbations: &quot;The beating of a butterfly wing in South
America can result in the considerable change of positions and force of a
tropical cyclon in Atlantic 2 weeks later&quot;. Numerical simulations of R.Robert
show the absence of the butterfly effect in some simple flows of 2-d ideal
incompressible fluid which is a model of the atmosphere. In this work a more
complicated flow is considered. Numerical simulation demonstrates the butterfly
effect in the strongest form. The effect is robust, and the experiment is 100%
reproducible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08272</id><created>2016-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>De Boni</keyname><forenames>Cristiano</forenames></author></authors><title>The mass accretion rate of galaxy clusters: a measurable quantity</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Based on arXiv:1501.01977 and on a poster presented at Rencontres de
  Moriond 2016: to appear in the proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are interested in investigating the growth of structures at the nonlinear
scales of galaxy clusters from an observational perspective: we explore the
possibility of measuring the mass accretion rate of galaxy clusters from their
mass profile beyond the virial radius. We derive the accretion rate from the
mass of a spherical shell whose infall velocity is extracted from $N$-body
simulations. In the redshift range $z=[0,2]$, our prescription returns an
average mass accretion rate within $20-40 \%$ of the average rate derived from
the merger trees of dark matter haloes extracted from $N$-body simulations. Our
result suggests that measuring the mean mass accretion rate of a sample of
galaxy clusters is actually feasible, thus providing a new potential
observational test of the cosmological and structure formation models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08274</id><created>2016-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Majumdar</keyname><forenames>Mrittunjoy Guha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnes</keyname><forenames>Crispin HW</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation of Quantum Cluster States using Surface Acoustic Waves</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One-way quantum computation, also known as Cluster State Quantum Computation,
provides a robust and efficient tool to perform universal quantum computation
using only single-qubit projective measurements, given a highly entangled
cluster state. The cluster-state approach to quantum computation also leads to
certain practical advantages such as robustness against errors. In this paper,
we propose a SAW-driven One-Way Quantum Computation approach that is realizable
using a mentioned architecture and elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08295</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhan</keyname><forenames>Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhiqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>All-fiber generation of 29-fs pulses at 1.3-{\mu}m via Cherenkov
  radiation</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>5 papes, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have experimentally demonstrated the all-fiber generation of 1.3-{\mu}m
femtosecond pulses via Cherenkov radiation (CR) from an ultrafast Er-doped
fiber laser. The experiment shows that the pulses maintain below 40 fs in the
range from 1270 to 1315 nm with multi-milliwatt average output power. The
shortest generated pulses can be as short as 29 fs. This ultrashort pulse
source in 1.3-{\mu}m window can bring the benefits to many fields such as the
bio-imaging and the ultrafast spectroscopy, and so on.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08302</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rojo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author></authors><title>Parton Distributions at a 100 TeV Hadron Collider</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the XXIV
  International Workshop on Deep-Inelastic Scattering and Related Subjects,
  11-15 April, 2016, DESY Hamburg, Germany</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The determination of the parton distribution functions (PDFs) of the proton
will be an essential input for the physics program of a future 100 TeV hadron
collider. The unprecedented center-of-mass energy will require knowledge of
PDFs in currently unexplored kinematical regions such as the ultra low-x region
or the region of multi-TeV momentum transfers. In this contribution we briefly
summarise the studies presented in the PDF section of the upcoming report on
&quot;Physics at a 100 TeV pp collider: Standard Model processes&quot;. First we map the
PDF kinematical coverage in the $(x,Q^2)$ plane, quantify PDF uncertainties,
and compute ratios of PDF luminosities between 100 TeV and 14 TeV. Then we show
how the extreme kinematics of such collider lead to a number of remarkable
PDF-related phenomena such as the top quark as a massless parton, an increased
role of photon-initiated processes and the possible need of PDFs with
high-energy resummation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08306</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08306</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnhart</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced flexural wave sensing by adaptive gradient-index metamaterials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Increasing sensitivity and signal to noise ratios of conventional wave
sensors is an interesting topic in structural health monitoring, medical
imaging, aerospace and nuclear instrumentation. Here, we report the concept of
a gradient piezoelectric self-sensing system by integrating shunting circuitry
into conventional sensors. By tuning circuit elements properly, both the
quality and quantity of the flexural wave measurement data can be significantly
increased for new adaptive sensing applications. Through analytical, numerical
and experimental studies, we demonstrate that the metamaterial-based sensing
system (MBSS) with gradient bending stiffness can be designed by connecting
gradient negative capacitance circuits to an array of piezoelectric patches
(sensors). We further demonstrate that the proposed system can achieve more
than two orders of magnitude amplification of flexural wave signals to overcome
the detection limit. This research encompasses fundamental advancements in the
MBSS with improved performance and functionalities, and will yield significant
advances for a range of applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08316</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Quach</keyname><forenames>James Q.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin gravitational resonance and graviton detection</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 104048 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.104048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a gravitational analogue of spin magnetic resonance, called spin
gravitational resonance, whereby a gravitational wave interacts with a magnetic
field to produce a spin transition. In particular, an external magnetic field
separates the energy spin states of a spin-1/2 particle, and the presence of
the gravitational wave produces a perturbation in the components of the
magnetic field orthogonal to the gravitational wave propagation. In this
framework we test Dyson's conjecture that individual gravitons cannot be
detected. Although we find no fundamental laws preventing single gravitons
being detected with spin gravitational resonance, we show that it cannot be
used in practice, in support of Dyson's conjecture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08318</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Vastel</keyname><forenames>Charlotte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ceccarelli</keyname><forenames>Cecilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lefloch</keyname><forenames>Bertrand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bachiller</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author></authors><title>Abundance of HOCO+ and CO2 in the outer layers of the L1544 prestellar
  core</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>To appear in A&amp;A Letters</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628427</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The L1544 prestellar core has been observed as part of the ASAI IRAM Large
Program at 3 mm. These observations led to the detection of many complex
molecules. In this Letter, we report the detection of two lines, at 85.5 GHz
(4,0,4-3,0,3) and 106.9 GHz (5,0,5-4,0,4), respectively, of the protonated
carbon dioxide ion, HOCO+. We also report the tentative detection of the line
at 100.4 GHz (5,0,5-4,0,4) of DOCO+. The non-LTE analysis of the detected lines
shows that the HOCO+ emission originates in the external layer where
non-thermal desorption of other species has previously been observed. Its
abundance is (5 +/- 2) e-11. Modelling of the chemistry involved in the
formation and destruction of HOCO+ provides a gaseous CO2 abundance of 2e-7
(with respect to H2) with an upper limit of 2e-6.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08331</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08331</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>IDILICO Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Solanes</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perea</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darriba</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-G&#xf3;mez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bosma</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Athanassoula</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Forming first-ranked early-type galaxies through hierarchical
  dissipationless merging</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>25 pages, 14 figures, 3 tables. Accepted to MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have developed a computationally competitive N-body model of a
previrialized aggregation of galaxies in a flat LambdaCDM universe to assess
the role of the multiple mergers that take place during the formation stage of
such systems in the configuration of the remnants assembled at their centres.
An analysis of a suite of 48 simulations of low-mass forming groups (of about
1E13 solar masses) demonstrates that the gravitational dynamics involved in
their hierarchical collapse is capable of creating realistic first-ranked
galaxies without the aid of dissipative processes. Our simulations indicate
that the brightest group galaxies (BGGs) constitute a distinct population from
other group members, sketching a scenario in which the assembly path of these
objects is dictated largely by the formation of their host system. We detect
significant differences in the distribution of Sersic indices and total
magnitudes, as well as a luminosity gap between BGGs and the next brightest
galaxy that is positively correlated with the total luminosity of the parent
group. Such gaps arise from both the grow of BGGs at the expense of lesser
companions and the decrease in the relevance of second-ranked objects in equal
measure. This results in a dearth of intermediate-mass galaxies which explains
the characteristic central dip detected in their luminosity functions in
dynamically young galaxy aggregations. The fact that the basic global
properties of our BGGs define a thin mass fundamental plane strikingly similar
to that followed giant early-type galaxies in the local universe reinforces
confidence in the results obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08335</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08335</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez-Jimenez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergara</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gauge Invariance and the Quantum Metric Tensor</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The quantum metric tensor was introduced for defining the distance in the
parameter space of a system. However, it is also useful for other purposes,
like predicting quantum phase transitions. Due to the physical information this
tensor provides, its gauge independence sounds reasonable. More over, its
original construction was made by looking for this gauge independence. The aim
of this paper, however, is to prove that the quantum metric tensor does depend
on the gauge. In addition, a real gauge invariant quantum metric tensor is
introduced. In this paper, the gauge dependence is explicitly shown by
computing the quantum metric tensor of the Landau problem in different gauges.
Then, a real gauge independent metric tensor is proposed and computed for the
same Landau problem. Since the gauge dependence has not been observed before,
the results of this paper might lead to a new study of topics that were
believed to be completely understood.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08348</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bach</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballesteros</keyname><forenames>Miguel</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;nenberg</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menrath</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence of Ground State Eigenvalues for the Spin-Boson Model with
  Critical Infrared Divergence and Multiscale Analysis</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>29 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A two-level atom coupled to the radiation field is studied. First principles
in physics suggest that the coupling function, representing the interaction
between the atom and the radiation field, behaves like $\vert k \vert^{- 1/2}$,
as the photon momentum k tends to zero. Previous results on non-existence of
ground state eigenvalues suggest that in the most general case binding does not
occur in the spin-boson model, i.e., the minimal energy of the atom-photon
system is not an eigenvalue of the energy operator. Hasler and Herbst have
shown [12], however, that under the additional hypothesis that the coupling
function be off-diagonal -which is customary to assume-binding does indeed
occur. In this paper an alternative proof of binding in case of off-diagonal
coupling is given, i.e., it is proven that, if the coupling function is
off-diagonal, the ground state energy of the spin-boson model is an eigenvalue
of the Hamiltonian. We develop a multiscale method that can be applied in the
situation we study, identifying a new key symmetry operator which we use to
demonstrate that the most singular terms appearing in the multiscale analysis
vanish.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08349</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08349</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Varinderjit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vadas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinbach</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiggins</keyname><forenames>B. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>R. T. deSouza Zidu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horowitz</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baby</keyname><forenames>L. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuvin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tripathi</keyname><forenames>Vandana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedenhover</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancement of fusion at near and sub-barrier energies for neutron-rich
  light nuclei</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1603.09314</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurement of the fusion cross-section for neutron-rich light nuclei is
crucial in ascertaining if fusion of these nuclei occurs in the outer crust of
a neutron star. We have therefore measured the fusion excitation function at
near-barrier energies for the 19O + 12C system and compared the experimental
results with the fusion excitation function of 18O + 12C and 16O + 12C. In the
experiment a beam of 19O, produced via the 18O(d,p) reaction, was incident on a
12C target at energies near the Coulomb barrier. Evaporation residues produced
in fusion of 18,19O ions with 12C target nuclei were detected with good
geometric efficiency and identified by measuring their energy and
time-of-flight. A significant enhancement in the fusion probability of 19O ions
with a 12C target as compared to 18O ions is observed. The significantly larger
cross-sections observed at near barrier energies are not predicted by a static
model of fusion for 19O + 12C indicating that dynamics play an important role
in the fusion of neutron-rich light nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08351</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>D.</keyname><forenames>Radhika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nandi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agrawal</keyname><forenames>V. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seetha</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>'Spectro-temporal' variabilities and possible physical mechanism for Jet
  ejections</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1239</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we attempt to find out the `spectro-temporal' characteristics
during the jet ejection, of several outbursting Galactic black hole sources
based on RXTE-PCA/HEXTE data in the energy band of 2 - 100 keV. We present
results of detailed analysis of these sources during the rising phase of their
outburst, whenever simultaneous or near-simultaneous X-ray and Radio
observations are `available'. We find that before the peak radio flare
(transient jet) a few of the sources (in addition to those reported earlier)
exhibit `local' softening within the soft intermediate state itself. Except the
duration, all the properties of the `local' softening (QPO not observed,
reduction in total rms, soft spectra) are observed to be similar to the
canonical soft state. We find similar `local' softening for the recent outburst
of V404 Cyg also based on SWIFT observations. Fast changes in the
`spectro-temporal' properties during the `local' softening implies that it may
not be occurring due to change in Keplerian accretion rate. We discuss these
results in the framework of the magnetized two component advective flow model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08365</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Garrigues</keyname><forenames>Alvar R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lejia</forenames></author><author><keyname>del Barco</keyname><forenames>Enrique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nijhuis</keyname><forenames>Christian A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electrostatic Control over Temperature-Dependent Tunneling across a
  Single Molecule Junction</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>37 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, Article number: 11595 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms11595</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding how the mechanism of charge transport through molecular tunnel
junctions depends on temperature is crucial to control electronic function in
molecular electronic devices. With just a few systems investigated as a
function of bias and temperature so far, thermal effects in molecular tunnel
junctions remain poorly understood. Here we report a detailed charge transport
study of an individual redox-active ferrocene-based molecule over a wide range
of temperatures and applied potentials. The results show the temperature
dependence of the current to vary strongly as a function of the gate voltage.
Specifically, the current across the molecule exponentially increases in the
Coulomb blockade regime and decreases at the charge degeneracy points, while
remaining temperature-independent at resonance. Our observations can be well
accounted for by a formal single-level tunneling model where the temperature
dependence relies on the thermal broadening of the Fermi distributions of the
electrons in the leads.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08371</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08371</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Farrell</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dotti</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asai</keyname><forenames>Makoto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calafiura</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monnard</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-threaded Geant4 on the Xeon-Phi with Complex High-Energy Physics
  Geometry</title><categories>physics.comp-ph hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  To study the performance of multi-threaded Geant4 for high-energy physics
experiments, an application has been developed which generalizes and extends
previous work. A highly-complex detector geometry is used for benchmarking on
an Intel Xeon Phi coprocessor. In addition, an implementation of parallel I/O
based on Intel SCIF and ROOT technologies is incorporated and studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08379</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Webber</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determination of the Total Solar Modulation Factors in the Heliosphere
  For Cosmic Ray Protons and Electrons by Comparing Interstellar Spectra
  Deduced from Voyager Measurements and PAMELA Spectra of These Particles at
  the Earth</title><categories>physics.space-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have determined the interstellar spectra of cosmic ray protons and
electrons from a few MeV to ~10 GeV. These interstellar spectra are based on
Voyager data and a normalization of specific galactic propagation model
calculations of both protons and electrons to PAMELA data at the Earth at 10
GeV, where the solar modulation is small. These resulting interstellar spectra
are then compared with spectra of protons and electrons measured at lower
energies at the Earth by PAMELA in 2009. The total amount of modulation at
lower rigidities (energies) is found to be nearly the same at the same rigidity
for both protons and electrons and ranges in magnitude from a factor ~400 at
0.1 GV for electrons, to a factor ~15 at 0.44 GV (100 MeV for protons), to a
factor ~3.3 at 1 GV for both components. The magnitude of this total modulation
of both components are the same to within + 10% from ~0.3 to ~3 GV in rigidity.
The observed total modulation for protons can be matched quite closely using a
simple spherically symmetric modulation picture involving a force field model
for the modulation and a constant energy loss at all energies. The electrons
require a set of parameters to calculate more detailed features of the
modulation using the diffusion coefficient and its variation with rigidity and
radius at rigidities less than few GV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08388</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08388</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Choudhary</keyname><forenames>Kamal</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational Design Of Surfaces, Nanostructures and Optoelectronic
  Materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>PhD dissertation, university of florida, 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Properties of engineering materials are generally influenced by defects such
as point defects (vacancies, interstitials, substitutional defects), line
defects (dislocations), planar defects (grain boundaries, free
surfaces/nanostructures, interfaces, stacking faults) and volume defects
(voids). Classical physics based molecular dynamics and quantum physics based
density functional theory can be useful in designing materials with controlled
defect properties. In this thesis, empirical potential based molecular dynamics
was used to study the surface modification of polymers due to energetic
polyatomic ion, thermodynamics and mechanics of metal-ceramic interfaces and
nanostructures, while density functional theory was used to screen substituents
in optoelectronic materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08393</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08393</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ahmadi</keyname><forenames>Aidin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiraz</keyname><forenames>Hamid Ghorbani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasiri</keyname><forenames>Mahdi Faghih</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabeti</keyname><forenames>Moones</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanical properties of metal decorated graphyne, graphyne-BN-yne, and
  BN-yne sheets</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, the mechanical properties of two-dimensional structures of
metal decoration systems of simple graphyne (CC), analogous system of BN sheet
(BN-yne), also the graphyne-BN sheet (CC-BN-yne) was investigated. The
properties such as Young and Bulk moduli were studied using Energy-Strain
correlation. We introduced calculations based on density functional theory
(DFT); the generalized gradient approximation (GGA) framework was used in this
regard. The results demonstrated very competitive values for Young and Bulk
moduli of the Pt decorated CC and BN-yne. However, the CC-BN-yne structure
defined around 80% of Young and 77% of Bulk values of that of pure structures.
Also Na decorated ones were examined and the results showed the same trend for
all three structures. The CC-BN-yne defined the lowest values for either Young
or Bulk moduli.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08408</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ruijl</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames><affiliation>Nikhef, Amsterdam</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Nikhef, Amsterdam</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vermaseren</keyname><forenames>J. A. M.</forenames><affiliation>Nikhef, Amsterdam</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>Liverpool U., Dept. Math.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Vogt</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Liverpool U., Dept. Math.</affiliation></author></authors><title>First Forcer results on deep-inelastic scattering and related quantities</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, LaTeX (PoS style), 4 eps-figures. To appear in the
  proceedings of `Loops &amp; Legs 2016', Leipzig (Germany), April 2016</comments><report-no>LTH 1084, Nikhef 2016-023</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results on the fourth-order splitting functions and coefficient
functions obtained using Forcer, a four-loop generalization of the Mincer
program for the parametric reduction of self-energy integrals. We have computed
the respective lowest three even-N and odd-N moments for the non-singlet
splitting functions and the non-singlet coefficient functions in
electromagnetic and nu+nu(bar) charged-current deep-inelastic scattering, and
the N=2 and N=4 results for the corresponding flavour-singlet quantities.
Enough moments have been obtained for an LLL-based determination of the
analytic N-dependence of the nf^3 and nf^2 parts, respectively, of the singlet
and non-singlet splitting functions. The large-N limit of the latter provides
the complete nf^2 contributions to the four-loop cusp anomalous dimension. Our
results also provide additional evidence of a non-vanishing contribution of
quartic group invariants to the cusp anomalous dimension.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08409</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Lande</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hraivoronska</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berezin</keyname><forenames>B. O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Agent-based model of information spread in social networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose evolution rules of the multiagent network and determine
statistical patterns in life cycle of agents - information messages. The main
discussed statistical pattern is connected with the number of likes and reposts
for a message. This distribution corresponds to Weibull distribution according
to modeling results. We examine proposed model using the data from Twitter, an
online social networking service.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08410</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08410</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chawla</keyname><forenames>Nitesh V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lichtenwalter</keyname><forenames>Ryan N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yuxiao</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence Activation Model: A New Perspective in Social Influence
  Analysis and Social Network Evolution</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  What drives the propensity for the social network dynamics? Social influence
is believed to drive both off-line and on-line human behavior, however it has
not been considered as a driver of social network evolution. Our analysis
suggest that, while the network structure affects the spread of influence in
social networks, the network is in turn shaped by social influence activity
(i.e., the process of social influence wherein one person's attitudes and
behaviors affect another's). To that end, we develop a novel model of network
evolution where the dynamics of network follow the mechanism of influence
propagation, which are not captured by the existing network evolution models.
Our experiments confirm the predictions of our model and demonstrate the
important role that social influence can play in the process of network
evolution. As well exploring the reason of social network evolution, different
genres of social influence have been spotted having different effects on the
network dynamics. These findings and methods are essential to both our
understanding of the mechanisms that drive network evolution and our knowledge
of the role of social influence in shaping the network structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08425</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Yachao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nian</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Form Invariance, Topological Fluctuations and Mass Gap of Yang-Mills
  Theory</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP nucl-th</categories><comments>54 + 48 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to have a new perspective on the long-standing problem of the mass
gap in Yang-Mills theory, we study the quantum Yang-Mills theory in the
presence of topologically nontrivial backgrounds in this paper. The
topologically stable gauge fields are constrained by the form invariance
condition and the topological properties. Obeying these constraints, the known
classical solutions to the Yang-Mills equation in the 3- and 4-dimensional
Euclidean spaces are recovered, and the other allowed configurations form the
nontrivial topological fluctuations at quantum level. Together, they constitute
the background configurations, upon which the quantum Yang-Mills theory can be
constructed. We demonstrate that the theory mimics the Higgs mechanism in a
certain limit and develops a mass gap at semi-classical level on a flat space
with finite size or on a sphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08429</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Guinea</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walet</keyname><forenames>Niels R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interaction between point charges, dipoles and graphene layers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the interaction between charges and graphene layers. The electric
polarisability of graphene induces a force, that can be described by an image
charge. The analysis shows that graphene can be described as an imperfect
conductor with a finite dielectric constant, $\epsilon_r$, for weak coupling,
and it behaves as a metal for strong fields. As a consequence, the interaction
between polar molecules and graphene layer(s) tends to align the molecular
dipole along the direction normal to the graphene, and quantitative estimates
of the energy gain are given The strength of this interaction can be sufficient
to overcome thermal effects when the molecule is close to the layer, even at
room temperature. Hence, boundary effects play a significant role in
determining the structure of systems such as water confined in atomically
narrow van der Waals heterostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08432</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-27</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08432</id><created>2016-05-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>Irene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fusco</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leoni</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morini</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author></authors><title>A model for dislocations in epitaxially strained elastic films</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A variational model for epitaxially strained films accounting for the
presence of dislocations is considered. Existence, regularity and some
qualitative properties of solutions are addressed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
