<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:12:46Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-05-16" from="2016-05-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0804.2268</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0804.2268</id><created>2008-04-14</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Wei-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental quantum coding against photon loss error</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>&quot;Quantum Computing even when Photons Go AWOL&quot;. published version</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 105, 11050-11054 (2008)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.0800740105</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A significant obstacle for practical quantum computation is the loss of
physical qubits in quantum computers, a decoherence mechanism most notably in
optical systems. Here we experimentally demonstrate, both in the quantum
circuit model and in the one-way quantum computer model, the smallest
non-trivial quantum codes to tackle this problem. In the experiment, we encode
single-qubit input states into highly-entangled multiparticle codewords, and we
test their ability to protect encoded quantum information from detected
one-qubit loss error. Our results prove the in-principle feasibility of
overcoming the qubit loss error by quantum codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1303.3831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1303.3831</id><created>2013-03-15</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Morf</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmerling</keyname><forenames>Tino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haas</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batlogg</keyname><forenames>Bertram</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiation induced electronic trap states and local structural disorder
  in van~der~Waals bonded semiconductor crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures; revised text implementing a referees feedback
  regarding the interpretation/conclusion</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In controlled X-ray irradiation experiments, the formation of trap states in
the prototypical van der Waals bonded semiconductor Rubrene is studied
quantitatively for doses up to 82 Gy (Gy = J/kg). About 100 electronic trap
states, located around 0.3 eV above the valence band, are created by each
absorbed 8 keV photon which is 2-3 orders of magnitude more than 1 MeV protons
produce. Thermal annealing is shown to reduce these traps. Local structural
disorder, which has also been induced by other means in different studies, is
thus identified as a common origin of trap states in van der Waals bonded
molecular organic semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.1302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.1302</id><created>2014-11-05</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khavkine</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Valter</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic Dependence is an Unnecessary Requirement in Renormalization of
  Locally Covariant QFT</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v3: 44 pages; expanded Discussion; close to published version</comments><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. 344 (2016), 581-620</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2618-7</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Finite renormalization freedom in locally covariant quantum field theories on
curved spacetime is known to be tightly constrained, under certain standard
hypotheses, to the same terms as in flat spacetime up to finitely many
curvature dependent terms. These hypotheses include, in particular, locality,
covariance, scaling, microlocal regularity and continuous and analytic
dependence on the metric and coupling parameters. The analytic dependence
hypothesis is somewhat unnatural, because it requires that locally covariant
observables (which are simultaneously defined on all spacetimes) depend
continuously on an arbitrary metric, with the dependence strengthened to
analytic on analytic metrics. Moreover the fact that analytic metrics are
globally rigid makes the implementation of this requirement at the level of
local $*$-algebras of observables rather technically cumbersome. We show that
the conditions of locality, covariance, scaling and a naturally strengthened
microlocal spectral condition, are actually sufficient to constrain the allowed
finite renormalizations equally strongly, thus eliminating both the continuity
and the somewhat unnatural analyticity hypotheses. The key step in the proof
uses the Peetre-Slov\'ak theorem on the characterization of (in general
non-linear) differential operators by their locality and regularity properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.06635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.06635</id><created>2015-01-26</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei-Kuo</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational representations for the Parisi functional and the
  two-dimensional Guerra-Talagrand bound</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>31 pages. Major revisions on Sections 1, 2 and 5</comments><msc-class>60K35, 82B44</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The validity of the Parisi formula in the Sherrington-Kirkpatrick model (SK)
was initially proved by Talagrand [18]. The central argument therein relied on
a very dedicated study of the coupled free energy via the two-dimensional
Guerra-Talagrand (GT) replica symmetry breaking bound. It is believed that this
bound and its higher dimensional generalization are highly related to the
conjectures of temperature chaos and ultrametricity in the SK model, but a
complete investigation remains elusive. Motivated by Bovier-Klimovsky [2] and
Auffinger-Chen [3], the aim of this paper is to present a novel approach to
analyzing the Parisi functional and the two-dimensional GT bound in the mixed
$p$-spin models in terms of optimal stochastic control problems. We compute the
directional derivative of the Parisi functional and derive equivalent criteria
for the Parisi measure. We demonstrate how our approach provides a simple and
efficient control for the GT bound that yields several new results on
Talagrand's positivity of the overlap [20,Section 14.12] and disorder chaos in
Chatterjee [5] and Chen [6]. In particular, we provide some examples of the
models containing odd $p$-spin interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.05002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.05002</id><created>2015-05-19</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Letizia</keyname><forenames>Viviana</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Olla</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames><affiliation>CEREMADE</affiliation></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium isothermal transformations in a temperature gradient
  from a microscopic dynamics</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>New version, for the publications in Annals of Probability</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a chain of anharmonic oscillators immersed in a heat bath with a
temperature gradient and a time varying tension applied to one end of the chain
while the other side is fixed to a point. We prove that under diffusive
space-time rescaling the volume strain distribution of the chain evolves
following a non-linear diffusive equation. The stationary states of the
dynamics are of non-equilibrium and have a positive entropy production, so the
classical relative entropy methods cannot be used. We develop new estimates
based on entropic hypocoercivity, that allows to control the distribution of
the positions configurations of the chain. The macroscopic limit can be used to
model isothermal thermodynamic transformations between non-equilibrium
stationary states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01443</id><created>2015-06-03</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>CMS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for a massive resonance decaying into a Higgs boson and a W or Z
  boson in hadronic final states in proton-proton collisions at sqrt(s) = 8 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Replaced with published version. Added journal reference and DOI. All
  figures and tables can be found at
  http://cms-results.web.cern.ch/cms-results/public-results/publications/EXO-14-009/index.html</comments><report-no>CMS-EXO-14-009, CERN-PH-EP-2015-096</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 02 (2016) 145</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP02(2016)145</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search for a massive resonance decaying into a standard-model-like Higgs
boson (H) and a W or Z boson is reported. The analysis is performed on a data
sample corresponding to an integrated luminosity of 19.7 inverse femtobarns,
collected in proton-proton collisions at a centre-of-mass energy of 8 TeV with
the CMS detector at the LHC. Signal events, in which the decay products of
Higgs, W, or Z bosons at high Lorentz boost are contained within single
reconstructed jets, are identified using jet substructure techniques, including
the tagging of b hadrons. This is the first search for heavy resonances
decaying into HW or HZ resulting in an all-jet final state, as well as the
first application of jet substructure techniques to identify H to WW* to 4q
decays at high Lorentz boost. No significant signal is observed and limits are
set at 95% confidence level on the production cross section of W' and Z' in a
model with mass-degenerate charged and neutral spin-1 resonances. Resonance
masses are excluded for W' in the interval [1.0, 1.6] TeV, for Z' in the
intervals [1.0, 1.1] and [1.3, 1.5] TeV, and for mass-degenerate W' and Z' in
the interval [1.0, 1.7] TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05290</id><created>2015-06-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Ritzmann</keyname><forenames>Ulrike</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinzke</keyname><forenames>Denise</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kehlberger</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Er-Jia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xe4;ui</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field control of the spin Seebeck effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.174411</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the suppression of the longitudinal spin Seebeck effect by
applied magnetic fields is studied. We perform numerical simulations of the
stochastic Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation of motion for an atomistic spin
model and calculate the magnon accumulation in linear temperature gradients for
different strengths of applied magnetic fields and different length scales of
the temperature gradient. We observe a decrease of the magnon accumulation with
increasing magnetic field and we reveal that the origin of this effect is a
field dependent change of the frequency distribution of the propagating
magnons. With increasing field the magnonic spin currents are reduced due to a
suppression of parts of the frequency spectrum. By comparison with measurements
of the magnetic field dependent longitudinal spin Seebeck effect in YIG thin
films with various thicknesses, we find that our model describes the
experimental data very well, demonstrating the importance of this effect for
experimental systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.03210</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.03210</id><created>2015-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bruno</keyname><forenames>Natalia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pini</keyname><forenames>Vittorio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korzh</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bussi&#xe8;res</keyname><forenames>F&#xe9;lix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Varun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Sae Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirin</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lita</keyname><forenames>Adriana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsili</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangouard</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zbinden</keyname><forenames>Hugo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gisin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thew</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Heralded amplification of photonic qubits</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Optics Express Vol. 24, Issue 1, pp. 125-133 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.000125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate heralded qubit amplification for Time-Bin and Fock-state
qubits in an all-fibre, telecom-wavelength, scheme that highlights the
simplicity, the stability and potential for fully integrated photonic
solutions. Exploiting high-efficiency superconducting detectors, the gain, the
fidelity and the performance of the amplifier are studied as a function of
loss. We also demonstrate the first heralded Fock-state qubit amplifier without
post-selection. This provides a significant advance towards demonstrating
Device-Independent Quantum Key Distribution as well as fundamental tests of
quantum mechanics over extended distances.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04259</id><created>2015-07-15</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bernoff</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Topaz</keyname><forenames>Chad M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Biological aggregation driven by social and environmental factors: A
  nonlocal model and its degenerate Cahn-Hilliard approximation</title><categories>nlin.PS nlin.AO q-bio.PE</categories><comments>33 pages, 10 figures; to appear in SIAM J. Appl. Dyn. Sys</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Biological aggregations such as insect swarms and bird flocks may arise from
a combination of social interactions and environmental cues. We focus on
nonlocal continuum equations, which are often used to model aggregations, and
yet which pose significant analytical and computational challenges. Beginning
with a particular nonlocal aggregation model [Topaz et al., Bull. Math. Bio.,
2006], we derive the minimal well-posed long-wave approximation, which is a
degenerate Cahn-Hilliard equation. Energy minimizers of this reduced, local
model retain many salient features of those of the nonlocal model, especially
for large populations and away from an aggregation's boundaries. Using the
Cahn-Hilliard model as a testbed, we investigate the degree to which an
external potential modeling food sources can be used to suppress peak
population density, which is essential for controlling locust outbreaks. A
random distribution of food sources tends to increase peak density above its
intrinsic value, while a periodic pattern of food sources can decrease it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00011</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barenboim</keyname><forenames>Gabriela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>Wan-Il</forenames></author></authors><title>Peccei-Quinn field for inflation, baryogenesis, dark matter, and much
  more</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>7 pages, journal version</comments><report-no>FTUV-15-07-31, IFIC-15-49</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.03.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a scenario of brane cosmology in which the Peccei-Quinn field
plays the role of the inflaton and solves simultaneously many cosmological and
phenomenological issues such as the generation of a heavy Majorana mass for the
right-handed neutrinos needed for seesaw mechanism, MSSM $\mu$-parameter, the
right amount of baryon number asymmetry and dark matter relic density at the
present universe, together with an axion solution to the strong CP problem
without the domain wall obstacle. Interestingly, the scales of the soft
SUSY-breaking mass parameter and that of the breaking of $U(1)_{\rm PQ}$
symmetry are lower bounded at $\mathcal{O}(10) {\mathrm TeV}$ and
$\mathcal{O}(10^{11}) {\mathrm GeV}$, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00466</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zippilli</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitali</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author></authors><title>Discriminating the effects of collapse models from environmental
  diffusion with levitated nanospheres</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>close to the published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 050102(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.050102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Collapse models postulate the existence of intrinsic noise which modifies
quantum mechanics and is responsible for the emergence of macroscopic
classicality. Assessing the validity of these models is extremely challenging
because it is nontrivial to discriminate unambiguously their presence in
experiments where other hardly controllable sources of noise compete to the
overall decoherence. Here we provide a simple procedure able to probe the
hypothetical presence of the collapse noise with a levitated nanosphere in a
Fabry-Perot cavity. We show that the stationary state of the system is
particularly sensitive, under specific experimental conditions, to the
interplay between the trapping frequency, the cavity size, and the momentum
diffusion induced by the collapse models, allowing to detect them even in the
presence of standard environmental noises.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.03941</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.03941</id><created>2015-08-17</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xi-Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cho</keyname><forenames>Sam Young</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batchelor</keyname><forenames>Murray T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Huan-Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>The antiferromagnetic cross-coupled spin ladder: quantum fidelity and
  tensor networks approach</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Korean Phys.Soc. 68,1114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3938/jkps.68.1114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the phase diagram of the cross-coupled Heisenberg spin ladder
with antiferromagnetic couplings. For this model there have been conflicting
results for the existence of the columnar dimer phase, which was predicted on
the basis of weak coupling field theory renormalisation group arguments. The
numerical work on this model has been based on various approaches, including
exact diagonalization, series expansions and density-matrix renormalization
group calculations. Using the recently developed tensor network states and
ground-state fidelity approach for quantum spin ladders we find no evidence for
the existence of the columnar dimer phase. We also provide an argument based on
the symmetry of the Hamiltonian which suggests that the phase diagram for
antiferromagnetic couplings consists of a single line separating the
rung-singlet and Haldane phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02737</id><created>2015-09-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Auliel</keyname><forenames>Maria Ines</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miquel</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mordant</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Wave turbulence buildup in a vibrating plate</title><categories>nlin.CD physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>accepted for publication in European Physical Journal B</comments><journal-ref>European Physical Journal B (2015) vol. 88 p 276</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60256-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report experimental and numerical results on the buildup of the energy
spectrum in wave turbulence of a vibrating thin elastic plate. Three steps are
observed: first a short linear stage, then the turbulent spectrum is
constructed by the propagation of a front in wave number space and finally a
long time saturation due to the action of dissipation. The propagation of a
front at the second step is compatible with scaling predictions from the Weak
Turbulence Theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01978</id><created>2015-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>N&#xe1;dvorn&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#x11b;mec</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janda</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olejn&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nov&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skoromets</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>N&#x11b;mec</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ku&#x17e;el</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troj&#xe1;nek</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jungwirth</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wunderlich</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanosecond spin-transfer over tens of microns in a bare GaAs/AlGaAs
  layer</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 22901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep22901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spin-conserving length-scale is a key parameter determining
functionalities of a broad range of spintronic devices including magnetic
multilayer spin-valves in the commercialized magnetic memories or lateral spin
transistors in experimental spin-logic elements. Spatially resolved optical
pump-and-probe experiments in the lateral devices allow for the direct
measurement of the lengthscale and the time-scale at which spin-information is
transferred from the injector to the detector. Using this technique, we
demonstrate that in an undoped GaAs/AlGaAs layer spins are detected at
distances reaching more than ten microns from the injection point at times as
short as nanoseconds after the pump-pulse. The observed unique combination of
the long-range and highrate electronic spin-transport requires simultaneous
suppression of mechanisms limiting the spin life-time and mobility of carriers.
Unlike earlier attempts focusing on elaborate doping, gating, or
heterostructures we demonstrate that the bare GaAs/AlGaAs layer intrinsically
provides superior spin-transport characteristics whether deposited directly on
the substrate or embedded in complex heterostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02665</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-02-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tiranov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavoie</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strassmann</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangouard</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Afzelius</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bussi&#xe8;res</keyname><forenames>F&#xe9;lix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gisin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Light-matter micro-macro entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 190502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.190502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum mechanics predicts microscopic phenomena with undeniable success.
Nevertheless, current theoretical and experimental efforts still do not yield
conclusive evidence that there is, or not, a fundamental limitation on the
possibility to observe quantum phenomena at the macroscopic scale. This
question prompted several experimental efforts producing quantum superpositions
of large quantum states in light or matter. Here we report on the observation
of entanglement between a single photon and an atomic ensemble. The certified
entanglement stems from a light-matter micro-macro entangled state that
involves the superposition of two macroscopically distinguishable solid-state
components composed of several tens of atomic excitations. Our approach
leverages from quantum memory techniques and could be used in other systems to
expand the size of quantum superpositions in matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05068</id><created>2015-10-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Chunjing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wohlfeld</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moritz</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devereaux</keyname><forenames>Thomas P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using RIXS to uncover elementary charge and spin excitations in
  correlated materials</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. X 6, 021020 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevX.6.021020</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Despite significant progress in resonant inelastic x-ray scattering (RIXS)
experiments on cuprates at the Cu L-edge, a theoretical understanding of the
cross-section remains incomplete in terms of elementary excitations and the
connection to both charge and spin structure factors. Here we use
state-of-the-art, unbiased numerical calculations to study the low energy
excitations probed by RIXS in undoped and doped Hubbard model relevant to the
cuprates. The results highlight the importance of scattering geometry, in
particular both the incident and scattered x-ray photon polarization, and
demonstrate that on a qualitative level the RIXS spectral shape in the
cross-polarized channel approximates that of the spin dynamical structure
factor. However, in the parallel-polarized channel the complexity of the RIXS
process beyond a simple two-particle response complicates the analysis, and
demonstrates that approximations and expansions which attempt to relate RIXS to
less complex correlation functions can not reproduce the full diversity of RIXS
spectral features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05807</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05807</id><created>2015-10-20</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leseur</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierrat</keyname><forenames>Romain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carminati</keyname><forenames>R&#xe9;mi</forenames></author></authors><title>High-density hyperuniform materials can be transparent</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that materials made of scatterers distributed on a stealth
hyperuniform point pattern can be transparent at densities for which an
uncorrelated disordered material would be opaque due to multiple scattering.
The conditions for transparency are analyzed using numerical simulations, and
an explicit criterion is found based on a perturbative theory. The broad
applicability of the concept offers perspectives for various applications in
photonics, and more generally in wave physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05843</id><created>2015-10-20</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gutman</keyname><forenames>Yonatan</forenames></author></authors><title>Takens' embedding theorem with a continuous observable</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>To appear in Assani, Idris (Ed.). 2016. Ergodic Theory. Advances in
  Dynamical Systems. Berlin, Boston: De Gruyter</comments><msc-class>37C45, 54H20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $(X,T)$ be a dynamical system where $X$ is a compact metric space and
$T:X\rightarrow X$ is continuous and invertible. Assume the Lebesgue covering
dimension of $X$ is $d$. We show that for a generic continuous map
$h:X\rightarrow[0,1]$, the $(2d+1)$-delay observation map
$x\mapsto\big(h(x),h(Tx),\ldots,h(T^{2d}x)\big)$ is an embedding of $X$ inside
$[0,1]^{2d+1}$. This is a generalization of the discrete version of the
celebrated Takens embedding theorem, as proven by Sauer, Yorke and Casdagli to
the setting of a continuous observable. In particular there is no assumption on
the (lower) box-counting dimension of $X$ which may be infinite.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06344</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06344</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-01-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jianji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hugonin</keyname><forenames>Jean-Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lalanne</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author></authors><title>Near-to-far field transformations for radiative and guided waves</title><categories>physics.optics physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>an associated open-source code will be available on line after the
  publication in an archive journal</comments><journal-ref>ACS Photonics,3, 395 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsphotonics.5b00559</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Light emitters or scatterers embedded in stratified media may couple energy
to both free space modes and guided modes of the stratified structure. For a
comprehensive analysis, it is important to evaluate the angular intensity
distribution of both the free-space modes and guided modes excited in such
systems. In the present work, we propose an original method based on
Lorentz-reciprocity theorem to efficiently calculate the free-space and guided
radiation diagrams with a high accuracy from the sole knowledge of the
near-field around the emitters or scatterers. Compared to conventional
near-to-far field transformation techniques, the proposal allows one to easily
evaluate the guided-mode radiation diagrams, even if material dissipation is
present in the stack, and thus to simultaneously track the coupling of light to
all channels (i.e., free-space and guided-ones). We also provide an open-source
code that may be used with essentially any Maxwell's equation solver. The
numerical tool may help to engineer various devices, such as light-emitting
diodes or nanoantennas to achieve directional and efficient radiative
spontaneous decays in free space and guided optics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00031</id><created>2015-10-30</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cortes</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicola</keyname><forenames>Angel Gomez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-$N$ pion scattering at finite temperature: the $f_0(500)$ and
  chiral restoration</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>24 pages, 12 figures. Funding agency added in the Acknowledgments</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 036001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.036001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the $O(N+1)/O(N)$ Non-Linear Sigma Model for large $N$ as an
effective theory for low-energy QCD at finite temperature $T$, in the chiral
limit. At $T=0$ this formulation provides a good description of scattering data
in the scalar channel and generates dynamically the $f_0(500)$ pole, the pole
position lying within experimental determinations. Previous $T=0$ results with
this model are updated using newer analysis of pion scattering data. We
calculate the pion scattering amplitude at finite $T$ and show that it
satisfies exactly thermal unitarity, which had been assumed but not formally
proven in previous works. We discuss the main differences with the $T=0$ result
and we show that one can define a proper renormalization scheme with $T=0$
counterterms such that the renormalized amplitude can be chosen to depend only
on a few parameters. Next, we analyze the behaviour of the $f_0(500)$ pole at
finite $T$, which is consistent with chiral symmetry restoration when the
scalar susceptibility is saturated by the $f_0(500)$ state, in a second-order
transition scenario and in accordance with lattice and theoretical analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01318</id><created>2015-11-04</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhengxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Shuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biesiada</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Xiaogang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zong-Hong</forenames></author></authors><title>The Distance Duality Relation from Strong Gravitational Lensing</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>2016, ApJ, 822, 74</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/822/2/74</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under very general assumptions of metric theory of spacetime, photons
traveling along null geodesics and photon number conservation, two observable
concepts of cosmic distance, i.e. the angular diameter and the luminosity
distances are related to each other by the so-called distance duality relation
(DDR) $D^L=D^A(1+z)^2$. Observational validation of this relation is quite
important because any evidence of its violation could be a signal of new
physics. In this paper we introduce a new method to test DDR based on strong
gravitational lensing systems and type Ia supernovae under a flat universe. The
method itself is worth attention, because unlike previously proposed
techniques, it does not depend on all other prior assumptions concerning the
details of cosmological model. We tested it using a new compilation of strong
lensing systems and JLA compilation of type Ia supernovae and found no evidence
of DDR violation. For completeness, we also combined it with previous cluster
data and showed its power on constraining DDR. It could become a promising new
probe in the future in light of forthcoming massive strong lensing surveys and
because of expected advances in galaxy cluster modlelling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01660</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01660</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>Sanefumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suyama</keyname><forenames>Takao</forenames></author></authors><title>Instanton Effects in Orientifold ABJM Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 1 figure, v2: a reference added, minor changes, v3: typos
  corrected, published version</comments><report-no>OCU-PHYS 432</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate another supersymmetric Chern-Simons theory called the
orientifold ABJM theory, which replaces the unitary supergroup structure of the
ABJM theory with an orthosymplectic one. Its non-perturbative structure is
completely clarified by considering the duplication of the quiver.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04225</id><created>2015-11-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Toga</keyname><forenames>Yuta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>Hisatoshi</forenames></author></authors><title>Loop Current and Antiferromagnetic States in Fermionic Hubbard Model
  with Staggered Flux at Half Filling</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, submitted to Physics Procedia as proceedings of
  ISS2015</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Proc. 81, 13 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.phpro.2016.04.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Anticipating realization of interacting fermions in an optical lattice with a
large gauge field, we consider phase transitions and loop currents in a
two-dimensional S=1/2 fermionic-Hubbard model with $\pi$/2-staggered flux at
half filling. We use a variational Monte Carlo method, which is reliable even
for strong correlations. As a trial wave function, a coexistent state of
antifferomagnetic and staggered-flux orders is studied. In a strongly
correlated regime, the ground state becomes an insulating coexistent state with
loop currents. By comparing fermions with bosons, we discuss an important role
of Pauli principle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05382</id><created>2015-11-17</created><updated>2016-03-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Albarrac&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>F. A. G&#xf3;mez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosales</keyname><forenames>H. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Field induced multiple order-by-disorder state selection in
  antiferromagnetic honeycomb bilayer lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>revised version - accepted for publication in Physical Review B - 12
  pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 144413 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.144413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a detailed study of the antiferromagnetic classical
Heisenberg model on a bilayer honeycomb lattice in a highly frustrated regime
in presence of a magnetic field. This study shows strong evidence of entropic
order-by-disorder selection in different sectors of the magnetization curve.
For antiferromagnetic couplings $J_1=J_x=J_p/3$, we find that at low
temperatures there are two different regions in the magnetization curve
selected by this mechanism with different number of soft and zero modes. These
regions present broken $Z_2$ symmetry and are separated by a not fully
collinear classical plateau at $M=1/2$. At higher temperatures, there is a
crossover from the conventional paramagnet to a cooperative magnet. Finally, we
also discuss the low temperature behavior of the system for a less frustrated
region, $J_1=J_x&lt;J_p/3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09326</id><created>2015-10-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colonna</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baran</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burrello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effects of symmetry energy and momentum dependent interaction on
  low-energy reaction mechanisms</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, contribution to NN2015</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 117, 07206 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201611707026</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dipole response associated with the Pygmy Dipole Resonance (PDR)
and the Isovector Giant Dipole Resonance (IVGDR), in connection with specific
properties of the nuclear effective interaction (symmetry energy and momentum
dependence), in the neutron-rich systems $^{68}$Ni, $^{132}$Sn and $^{208}$Pb.
We perform our investigation within a microscopic transport model based on the
Landau-Vlasov kinetic equation. We observe that the peak energies of PDR and
IVGDR are shifted to higher values when employing momentum dependent
interactions, with respect to the results obtained neglecting momentum
dependence. The calculated energies are close to the experimental values and
similar to the results obtained in Hartree-Fock (HF) with Random Phase
Approximation (RPA) calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01238</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fischler</keyname><forenames>Willy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>Sandipan</forenames></author></authors><title>Membrane Paradigm, Gravitational $\Theta$-Term and Gauge/Gravity Duality</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.HE gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>28+9 pages; minor changes, conclusions unchanged</comments><report-no>UTTG-21-15, TCC-010-15</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1604 (2016) 112</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following the membrane paradigm, we explore the effect of the gravitational
$\Theta$-term on the behavior of the stretched horizon of a black hole in
(3+1)-dimensions. We reformulate the membrane paradigm from a quantum
path-integral point of view where we interpret the macroscopic properties of
the horizon as effects of integrating out the region inside the horizon. The
gravitational $\Theta$-term is a total derivative, however, using our framework
we show that this term affects the transport properties of the horizon. In
particular, the horizon acquires a third order parity violating, dimensionless
transport coefficient which affects the way localized perturbations scramble on
the horizon. Then we consider a large-N gauge theory in (2+1)-dimensions which
is dual to an asymptotically AdS background in (3+1)-dimensional spacetime to
show that the $\Theta$-term induces a non-trivial contact term in the
energy-momentum tensor of the dual theory. As a consequence, the dual gauge
theory in the presence of the $\Theta$-term acquires the same third order
parity violating transport coefficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03753</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Jose</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molina</keyname><forenames>Rafael A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Macroscopic degeneracy of zero-mode rotating surface states in 3D Dirac
  and Weyl semimetals under radiation</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages + supplemental material</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 156803 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.156803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the development of novel surface states when 3D Dirac or Weyl
semimetals are placed under circularly polarized electromagnetic radiation. We
find that the hybridization between inverted Floquet bands opens in general a
gap, which closes at so-called exceptional points found for complex values of
the momentum. This corresponds to the appearance of midgap surface states in
the form of evanescent waves decaying from the surface exposed to the
radiation. We observe a phenomenon reminiscent of Landau quantization by which
the midgap surface states get a large degeneracy proportional to the radiation
flux traversing the surface of the semimetal. We show that all these surface
states carry angular current, leading to an angular modulation of their charge
that rotates with the same frequency of the radiation, which should manifest in
the observation of a macroscopic chiral current in the irradiated surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06270</id><created>2015-12-19</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Frandsen</keyname><forenames>Benjamin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunelli</keyname><forenames>Michela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Page</keyname><forenames>Katharine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uemura</keyname><forenames>Yasutomo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staunton</keyname><forenames>Julie B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Billinge</keyname><forenames>Simon J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Verification of Anderson superexchange in MnO via magnetic pair
  distribution function analysis and \textit{ab initio} theory</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 197204 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.197204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present temperature-dependent atomic and magnetic pair distribution
function (PDF) analysis of neutron total scattering measurements of
antiferromagnetic MnO, an archetypal strongly correlated transition-metal
oxide. The known antiferromagnetic ground-state structure fits the
low-temperature data closely with refined parameters that agree with
conventional techniques, confirming the reliability of the newly developed
magnetic PDF method. The measurements performed in the paramagnetic phase
reveal significant short-range magnetic correlations on a $\sim$1~nm length
scale that differ substantially from the low-temperature long-range spin
arrangement. \textit{Ab initio} calculations using a self-interaction-corrected
local spin density approximation of density functional theory predict magnetic
interactions dominated by Anderson superexchange and reproduce the measured
short-range magnetic correlations to a high degree of accuracy. Further
calculations simulating an additional contribution from a direct exchange
interaction show much worse agreement with the data. The Anderson superexchange
model for MnO is thus verified by experiment and confirmed by \textit{ab
initio} theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06696</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06696</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Tai-Fu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xue-Qian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hai-Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Shu-Min</forenames></author></authors><title>The LHC 750 GeV diphoton excess in supersymmetry with gauged baryon and
  lepton numbers</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>34 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The significance of discovering the boson of 750 GeV is beyond finding a
single heavy boson, because it may hint the location of the scale for new
physics beyond the standard model which is the target of long-time exploration.
There have been many models to explain the diphoton excess observed by the
ATLAS and CMS collaborations and the BLMSSM is one of them. The BLMSSM is an
extension of the minimal supersymmetric model where baryon and lepton numbers
are local gauge symmetries. We analyze the decay channels $\Phi\rightarrow gg$,
$\Phi\rightarrow\gamma\gamma$, $\Phi\rightarrow Z\gamma$, and $\Phi\rightarrow
\bar{t}t,\;VV\;(V=Z,\;W)$ with the mass of the CP-odd scalar $\Phi=A_{_B}^0$
being around $750\;{\rm GeV}$ in this model. Within a certain parameter space,
the scenario can account for the experimental data on the diphoton excess.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06774</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-04-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schewtschenko</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baugh</keyname><forenames>C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkinson</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boehm</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascoli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawala</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dark matter-radiation interactions: the structure of Milky Way satellite
  galaxies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 1 table. Augmented content available for figures
  (cf. 'Augmented Content' section). V3: Matches version in MNRAS</comments><report-no>DURAST/2016/0001, IPPP/16/03</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the thermal dark matter (DM) paradigm, primordial interactions between DM
and Standard Model particles are responsible for the observed DM relic density.
In Boehm et al. (2014), we showed that weak-strength interactions between DM
and radiation (photons or neutrinos) can erase small-scale density
fluctuations, leading to a suppression of the matter power spectrum compared to
the collisionless cold DM (CDM) model. This results in fewer DM subhaloes
within Milky Way-like DM haloes, implying a reduction in the abundance of
satellite galaxies. Here we use very high resolution N-body simulations to
measure the dynamics of these subhaloes. We find that when interactions are
included, the largest subhaloes are less concentrated than their counterparts
in the collisionless CDM model and have rotation curves that match
observational data, providing a new solution to the &quot;too big to fail&quot; problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08300</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08300</id><created>2015-12-27</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Xiangke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Xingbiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szmigielski</keyname><forenames>Jacek</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipeakons of a two-component modified Camassa-Holm equation and the
  relation with the finite Kac-van Moerbeke lattice</title><categories>nlin.SI math-ph math.AP math.CA math.MP</categories><comments>28 pages,5 figures, to appear in Adv. Math</comments><msc-class>37K15, 37K40, 35Q51, 34A55</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A spectral and the inverse spectral problem are studied for the two-component
modified Camassa-Holm type for measures associated to interlacing peaks. It is
shown that the spectral problem is equivalent to an inhomogenous string problem
with Dirichlet/Neumann boundary conditions. The inverse problem is solved by
Stieltjes' continued fraction expansion, leading to an explicit construction of
peakon solutions. Sufficient conditions for the global existence in $t$ are
given. The large time asymptotics reveals that, asymptotically, peakons pair up
to form bound states moving with constant speeds. The peakon flow is shown to
project to one of the isospectral flows of the finite Kac--van Moerbeke
lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00273</id><created>2016-01-03</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Park</keyname><forenames>DaeKil</forenames></author></authors><title>Tripartite Entanglement Dynamics in the presence of Non-Markovian
  Environment</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19pages, 7 pdf figures V2: 24 pages, 11 figures, will appear in QIP</comments><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1331-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study on the tripartite entanglement dynamics when each party is initially
entangled with other parties, but they locally interact with their own
non-Markovian environment. First, we consider three GHZ-type initial states,
all of which have GHZ symmetry provided that the parameters are chosen
appropriately. However, this symmetry is broken due to the effect of
environment. The corresponding $\pi$-tangles, one of the tripartite
entanglement measure, are analytically computed at arbitrary time. The revival
phenomenon of entanglement occurs after complete disappearance of entanglement.
We also consider two W-type initial states. The revival phenomenon also occurs
in this case. On the analytical ground the robustness issue against the effect
of environment is examined for both GHZ-type and W-type initial states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00284</id><created>2016-01-03</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>Z. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregersen</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unsleber</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamp</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Chao-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Jian-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>On-Demand Single Photons with High Extraction Efficiency and Near-Unity
  Indistinguishability from a Resonantly Driven Quantum Dot in a Micropillar</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>submitted to PRL on 29/09/2015, accepted on 01/12/2015, published on
  14/01/2016, the first work reporting an &quot;all-around&quot; single-photon source
  that combines purity, indistinguishability, and efficiency. see
  https://aps.altmetric.com/details/4994109</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 020401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.020401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Scalable photonic quantum technologies require on-demand single-photon
sources with simultaneously high levels of purity, indistinguishability, and
efficiency. These key features, however, have only been demonstrated separately
in previous experiments. Here, by s-shell pulsed resonant excitation of a
Purcell-enhanced quantum dot-micropillar system, we deterministically generate
resonance fluorescence single photons which, at pi pulse excitation, have an
extraction efficiency of 66%, single-photon purity of 99.1%, and photon
indistinguishability of 98.5%. Such a single-photon source for the first time
combines the features of high efficiency and near-perfect levels of purity and
indistinguishabilty, and thus open the way to multi-photon experiments with
semiconductor quantum dots.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00588</id><created>2016-01-04</created><updated>2016-03-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ruggiero</keyname><forenames>Matteo Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Light bending in $f(T)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 figure; revised to match the version accepted for
  publication in IJMPD</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D, 25, 1650073 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271816500735</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of $f(T)$ gravity, we focus on a weak-field and spherically
symmetric solution for the Lagrangian $f(T)=T+\alpha T^{2}$, where $\alpha$ is
a small constant which parameterizes the departure from General Relativity. In
particular, we study the propagation of light and obtain the correction to the
general relativistic bending angle. Moreover, we discuss the impact of this
correction on some gravitational lensing observables, and evaluate the
possibility of constraining the theory parameter $\alpha$ by means of
observations. In particular, on taking into account the astrometric accuracy in
the Solar System, we obtain that $|\alpha| \leq 1.85 \times 10^{5}\,
\mathrm{m^{2}}$; this bound is looser than those deriving from the analysis of
Solar System dynamics, e.g. $|\alpha| \leq 5 \times 10^{-1}\, \mathrm{m^{2}}$,
$|\alpha| \leq 1.8 \times 10^{4}\, \mathrm{m^{2}}$ or $|\alpha| \leq 1.2 \times
10^{2}\, \mathrm{m^{2}}$ . However we suggest that, since the effect only
depends on the impact parameter, better constraints could be obtained by
studying light bending from planetary objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02041</id><created>2016-01-08</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diniz</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Microscopic origin of subthermal magnons and the spin Seebeck effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>I Diniz and A T Costa 2016 New J. Phys. 18 052002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/5/052002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent experimental evidence points to low-energy magnons as the primary
contributors to the spin Seebeck effect. This spectral dependence is puzzling
since it is not observed on other thermocurrents in the same material. Here, we
argue that the physical origin of this behavior is the magnon-magnon scattering
mediated by phonons, in a process which conserves the number of magnons. To
assess the importance and features of this kind of scattering, we derive the
effective magnon-phonon interaction from a microscopic model, including band
energy, a screened electron-electron interaction and the electron-phonon
interaction. Unlike higher order magnon-only scattering, we find that the
coupling with phonons induce a scattering which is very small for low-energy
(or subthermal) magnons but increases sharply above a certain energy --
rendering magnons above this energy poor spin-current transporters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02064</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02064</id><created>2016-01-08</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hayami</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Shi-Zeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batista</keyname><forenames>Cristian D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bubble and Skyrmion Crystals in Frustrated Magnets with Easy-Axis
  Anisotropy</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 184413 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.184413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We clarify the conditions for the emergence of multiple-${\bf Q}$ structures
out of lattice and easy-axis spin anisotropy in frustrated magnets. By
considering magnets whose exchange interaction has multiple global minima in
momentum space, we find that both types of anisotropy stabilize triple-${\bf
Q}$ orderings. Moderate anisotropy leads to a magnetic field-induced skyrmion
crystal, which evolves into a bubble crystal for increasing spatial or spin
anisotropy. The bubble crystal exhibits a quasi-continuous (devil's staircase)
temperature dependent ordering wave-vector, characteristic of the competition
between frustrated exchange and strong easy-axis anisotropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03357</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03357</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ballesteros</keyname><forenames>Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blasco</keyname><forenames>Alfonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musso</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable deformations of R\&quot;ossler and Lorenz systems from Poisson-Lie
  groups</title><categories>nlin.SI math.DS</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures. Revised version, minor changes included</comments><msc-class>37J35, 34A26, 34C14, 17B62, 17B63</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Differential Equations, vol. 260 (2016) 8207</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jde.2016.02.014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A method to construct integrable deformations of Hamiltonian systems of ODEs
endowed with Lie-Poisson symmetries is proposed by considering Poisson-Lie
groups as deformations of Lie-Poisson (co)algebras. Moreover, the underlying
Lie-Poisson symmetry of the initial system of ODEs is used to construct
integrable coupled systems, whose integrable deformations can be obtained
through the construction of the appropriate Poisson-Lie groups that deform the
initial symmetry. The approach is applied in order to construct integrable
deformations of both uncoupled and coupled versions of certain integrable types
of R\&quot;ossler and Lorenz systems. It is worth stressing that such deformations
are of non-polynomial type since they are obtained through an exponentiation
process that gives rise to the Poisson-Lie group from its infinitesimal Lie
bialgebra structure. The full deformation procedure is essentially algorithmic
and can be computerized to a large extent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.05319</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.05319</id><created>2016-01-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>N. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrova</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnack</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Alternating-spin S=3/2 and sigma=1/2 Heisenberg chain with three-body
  exchange interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B 89 (2016) 121</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70057-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The promotion of collinear classical spin configurations as well as the
enhanced tendency towards nearest-neighbor clustering of the quantum spins are
typical features of the frustrating isotropic three-body exchange interactions
in Heisenberg spin systems. Based on numerical density-matrix renormalization
group calculations, we demonstrate that these extra interactions in the
Heisenberg chain constructed from alternating S=3/2 and sigma=1/2 site spins
can generate numerous specific quantum spin states, including some
partially-polarized ferrimagnetic states as well as a doubly-degenerate
non-magnetic gapped phase. In the non-magnetic region of the phase diagram, the
model describes a crossover between the spin-1 and spin-2 Haldane-type states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06840</id><created>2016-01-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Stephanie A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raithel</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Radio-frequency-modulated Rydberg states in a vapor cell</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 053017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/5/053017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measure strong radio-frequency (RF) electric fields using rubidium Rydberg
atoms prepared in a room-temperature vapor cell as field sensors.
Electromagnetically induced transparency is employed as an optical readout. We
RF-modulate the 60$S_{1/2}$ and 58$D_{5/2}$ Rydberg states with 50~MHz and
100~MHz fields, respectively. For weak to moderate RF fields, the Rydberg
levels become Stark-shifted, and sidebands appear at even multiples of the
driving frequency. In high fields, the adjacent hydrogenic manifold begins to
intersect the shifted levels, providing rich spectroscopic structure suitable
for precision field measurements. A quantitative description of strong-field
level modulation and mixing of $S$ and $D$ states with hydrogenic states is
provided by Floquet theory. Additionally, we estimate the shielding of DC
electric fields in the interior of the glass vapor cell.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07182</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-04-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Desai</keyname><forenames>Shantanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kummel</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wetzstein</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection and Removal of Artifacts in Astronomical Images</title><categories>astro-ph.IM physics.data-an</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures. Accepted for publication in Astronomy and
  Computing</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy and Computing 16, 67 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2016.04.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Astronomical images from optical photometric surveys are typically
contaminated with transient artifacts such as cosmic rays, satellite trails and
scattered light. We have developed and tested an algorithm that removes these
artifacts using a deep, artifact free, static sky coadd image built up through
the median combination of point spread function (PSF) homogenized, overlapping
single epoch images. Transient artifacts are detected and masked in each single
epoch image through comparison with an artifact free, PSF-matched simulated
image that is constructed using the PSF-corrected, model fitting catalog from
the artifact free coadd image together with the position variable PSF model of
the single epoch image. This approach works well not only for cleaning single
epoch images with worse seeing than the PSF homogenized coadd, but also the
traditionally much more challenging problem of cleaning single epoch images
with better seeing. In addition to masking transient artifacts, we have
developed an interpolation approach that uses the local PSF and performs well
in removing artifacts whose widths are smaller than the PSF full width at half
maximum, including cosmic rays, the peaks of saturated stars and bleed trails.
We have tested this algorithm on Dark Energy Survey Science Verification data
and present performance metrics. More generally, our algorithm can be applied
to any survey which images the same part of the sky multiple times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07195</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-05-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smelyanskiy</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawaya</keyname><forenames>Nicolas P. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aspuru-Guzik</keyname><forenames>Al&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>qHiPSTER: The Quantum High Performance Software Testing Environment</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DC</categories><comments>9 pages, 10 figures, 3 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present qHiPSTER, the Quantum High Performance Software Testing
Environment. qHiPSTER is a distributed high-performance implementation of a
quantum simulator on a classical computer, that can simulate general
single-qubit gates and two-qubit controlled gates. We perform a number of
single- and multi-node optimizations, including vectorization, multi-threading,
cache blocking, as well as overlapping computation with communication. Using
the TACC Stampede supercomputer, we simulate quantum circuits (&quot;quantum
software&quot;) of up to 40 qubits. We carry out a detailed performance analysis to
show that our simulator achieves both high performance and high hardware
efficiency, limited only by the sustainable memory and network bandwidth of the
machine.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07611</id><created>2016-01-27</created><updated>2016-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barbarona</keyname><forenames>Rona F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paraan</keyname><forenames>Francis N. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Integer effects in the entanglement and spin fluctuations of a quantum
  Hall system with Rashba interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages PDFLATEX, 5 figures, added references</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 053104</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/05/053104</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report distinct nonanalytic signatures in the spin-orbit entanglement of a
2D electron gas with Rashba interactions at integer values of the filling
factor and at certain level crossings. The accompanying sharp changes in the
bulk spin-orbit entanglement entropy can be probed by measuring the fluctuation
in the transverse spin polarization of the electron gas.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00803</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00803</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nogawa</keyname><forenames>Tomoaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>Takehisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemoto</keyname><forenames>Koji</forenames></author></authors><title>Local cluster-size statistics in the critical phase of bond percolation
  on the Cayley tree</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Mechanics (2016) 053202</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/05/053202</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study bond percolation of the Cayley tree (CT) by focusing on the
probability distribution function (PDF) of a local variable, namely, the size
of the cluster including a selected vertex. Because the CT does not have a
dominant bulk region, which is free from the boundary effect, even in the
large-size limit, the phase of the system on it is not well defined. We herein
show that local observation is useful to define the phase of such a system in
association with the well-defined phase of the system on the Bethe lattice,
that is, an infinite regular tree without boundary. Above the percolation
threshold, the PDFs of the vertex at the center of the CT (the origin) and of
the vertices near the boundary of the CT (the leaves) have different forms,
which are also dissimilar to the PDF observed in the ordinary percolating phase
of a Euclidean lattice. The PDF for the origin of the CT is bimodal: a decaying
exponential function and a system-size-dependent asymmetric peak, which obeys a
finite-size-scaling law with a fractal exponent. These modes are respectively
related to the PDFs of the finite and infinite clusters in the nonuniqueness
phase of the Bethe lattice. On the other hand, the PDF for the leaf of the CT
is a decaying power function. This is similar to the PDF observed at a critical
point of a Euclidean lattice but is attributed to the nesting structure of the
CT around the boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01907</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Vivoli</keyname><forenames>Valentina Caprara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekatski</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sangouard</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>What does it take to see entanglement?</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optica, 3 473 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tremendous progress has been realized in quantum optics for engineering and
detecting the quantum properties of light. Today, photon pairs are routinely
created in entangled states. Entanglement is revealed using single-photon
detectors in which a single photon triggers an avalanche current. The resulting
signal is then processed and stored in a computer. Here, we propose an approach
to get rid of all the electronic devices between the photons and the
experimentalist i.e. to use the experimentalist's eye to detect entanglement.
We show in particular, that the micro entanglement that is produced by sending
a single photon into a beam-splitter can be detected with the eye using the
magnifying glass of a displacement in phase space. The feasibility study
convincingly demonstrates the possibility to realize the first experiment where
entanglement is observed with the eye.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02438</id><created>2016-02-07</created><updated>2016-02-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Tian-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bosonic integer quantum Hall states in topological bands with Chern
  number two</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures, References added and minor correction</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 195121 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.195121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the interacting bosons in topological Hofstadter bands with Chern
number two. Using exact diagonalization, we demonstrate that bosonic integer
quantum Hall (BIQH) state emerges at integer boson filling factor $\nu=1$ of
the lowest Chern band with evidences including a robust spectrum gap and
quantized topological Hall conductance two. Moreover, the robustness of BIQH
state against different interactions and next-nearest neighbor hopping is
investigated. The strong nearest neighbor interaction would favor a charge
density wave. When the onsite interaction decreases, BIQH state undergoes a
continuous transition into a superfluid state. Without next-nearest neighbor
hopping, the ground state is possibly in a metallic Fermi-liquid-like phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04204</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Chengcheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagida</keyname><forenames>Tsutomu T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokozaki</keyname><forenames>Norimi</forenames></author></authors><title>Implications of the 750 GeV Diphoton Excess in Gaugino Mediation</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures, typos and small numerical errors corrected</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 055025 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.055025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The 750 GeV diphoton excess reported by ATLAS and CMS indicates the presence
of several pairs of the vector-like matter multiplets around TeV scale. If that
is the case, radiative corrections from the $SU(3)$ gauge interaction
significantly change from those of MSSM, and the infrared-free nature of the
gauge interaction leads to characteristic SUSY mass spectra: a ratio of a
squark mass to the gluino mass, and scalar trilinear couplings are enhanced at
the low-energy scale. Consequently, even in gaugino mediation models, the Higgs
boson mass of 125 GeV is explained with the fairly light gluino of 2-3 TeV,
which can be accessible at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05855</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vroylandt</keyname><forenames>Hadrien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonfils</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verley</keyname><forenames>Gatien</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficiency fluctuations of small machines with unknown losses</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures, v2: version accepted in PRE</comments><report-no>LPT-Orsay-16-13</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 052123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.052123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The efficiency statistics of a small thermodynamic machine has been recently
investigated assuming that the total dissipation was a linear combination of
two currents: the input and output currents. Here, we relax this standard
assumption and reconsider the question of the efficiency fluctuations for a
machine involving three different processes, first in full generality and
second for two different examples. Since the third process may not be
measurable and/or may decrease the machine efficiency, our motivation is to
study the effect of unknown losses in small machines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07003</id><created>2016-02-22</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ki&#xdf;ler</keyname><forenames>Henry</forenames></author></authors><title>Hopf-algebraic Renormalization of QED in the linear covariant Gauge</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.05.008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of massless quantum electrodynamics (QED) with a linear
covariant gauge fixing, the connection between the counterterm and the
Hopf-algebraic approach to renormalization is examined. The coproduct formula
of Green's functions contains two invariant charges, which give rise to
different renormalization group functions. All formulas are tested by explicit
computations to third loop order. The possibility of a finite electron
self-energy by fixing a generalized linear covariant gauge is discussed. An
analysis of subdivergences leads to the conclusion that such a gauge only
exists in quenched QED.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07269</id><created>2016-02-23</created><updated>2016-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez</keyname><forenames>Israel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mixed OPEs in ${\mathcal N}=2$ Superconformal Theories</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Fixed typos in Eq (3.11), (3.13), (3.14), (3.20) and (3.30)</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2016)043</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using superspace techniques, we compute the mixed OPE between an ${\mathcal
N}=2$ stress-tensor multiplet, a chiral multiplet and a flavor current
multiplet. We perform a detailed analysis of the three-point function between
two of the mentioned multiplets and a third arbitrary operator. We then solve
all the constraints coming from the ${\mathcal N}=2$ superconformal symmetry
and from the equations of motion and/or conservation equations, and obtain all
the possible operators that can appear in the expansion. This calculation is
the first step towards a more general superconformal block analysis of mixed
correlators in ${\mathcal N}=2$ theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04568</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chiu</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuo</keyname><forenames>T. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization of the quark mass matrix</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 093006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.093006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using a set of rephasing-invariant variables, it is shown that the
renormalization group equations for quark mixing parameters can be written in a
form that is compact, in addition to having simple properties under flavor
permutation. We also found approximate solutions to these equations if the
quark masses are hierarchical or nearly degenerate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09628</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>ZEUS Collaboration</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abramowicz</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abt</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adamczyk</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adamus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonelli</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aushev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behnke</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behrens</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertolin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhadra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloch</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boos</keyname><forenames>E. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brock</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brook</keyname><forenames>N. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brugnera</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bussey</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldwell</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capua</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catterall</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chwastowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciborowski</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciesielski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cooper-Sarkar</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corradi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dementiev</keyname><forenames>R. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Devenish</keyname><forenames>R. C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dusini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foster</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gach</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garfagnini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geiser</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gizhko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gladilin</keyname><forenames>L. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golubkov</keyname><forenames>Yu. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grzelak</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guzik</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gwenlan</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hain</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hlushchenko</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hochman</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hori</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ibrahim</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iga</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishitsuka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Januschek</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jomhari</keyname><forenames>N. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadenko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kananov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karshon</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaur</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisielewska</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klanner</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korzhavina</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kotanski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koetz</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalchuk</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalski</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krupa</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuprash</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuze</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levchenko</keyname><forenames>B. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Limentani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lisovyi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lobodzinska</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loehr</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lohrmann</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longhin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lontkovskyi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukina</keyname><forenames>O. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makarenko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malka</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastroberardino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Idris</keyname><forenames>F. Mohamad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nasir</keyname><forenames>N. Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myronenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagano</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nobe</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onishchuk</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perlanski</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pokrovskiy</keyname><forenames>N. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Polini</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przybycien</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roloff</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruspa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saxon</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schioppa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneekloth</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoerner-Sadenius</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shcheglova</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shevchenko</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shkola</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shyrma</keyname><forenames>Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skillicorn</keyname><forenames>I. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slominski</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanco</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefaniuk</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stopa</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sztuk-Dambietz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tassi</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokushuku</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomaszewska</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsurugai</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turcato</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turkot</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tymieniecka</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verbytskyi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>W. A. T. Wan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wichmann</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wing</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamazaki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakharchuk</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zarnecki</keyname><forenames>A. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zawiejski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenaiev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhautykov</keyname><forenames>B. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zotkin</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Combined QCD and electroweak analysis of HERA data</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 10 figures, accepted by Phys. Rev. D. Small corrections
  from proofing process and small change to Fig. 12 and Table 4</comments><report-no>DESY-16-039</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simultaneous fit of parton distribution functions (PDFs) and electroweak
parameters to HERA data on deep inelastic scattering is presented. The input
data are the neutral current and charged current inclusive cross sections which
were previously used in the QCD analysis leading to the HERAPDF2.0 PDFs. In
addition, the polarisation of the electron beam was taken into account for the
ZEUS data recorded between 2004 and 2007. Results on the vector and
axial-vector couplings of the Z boson to u- and d-type quarks, on the value of
the electroweak mixing angle and the mass of the W boson are presented. The
values obtained for the electroweak parameters are in agreement with Standard
Model predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00839</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00839</id><created>2016-04-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Misumi</keyname><forenames>Tatsuhiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nitta</keyname><forenames>Muneto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakai</keyname><forenames>Norisuke</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-BPS exact solutions and their relation to bions in ${\mathbb
  C}P^{N-1}$ models</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>48 pages, 34 figures</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 05 (2016) 057</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP05(2016)057</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate non-BPS exact solutions in ${\mathbb C}P^{N-1}$ sigma models
on ${\mathbb R}^1 \times S^{1}$ with twisted boundary conditions, by using the
Din-Zakrzewski projection method. We focus on the relation of the non-BPS
solutions to the ansatz of multi-instanton (bion) configurations and discuss
their significance in the context of the resurgence theory. We find that the
transition between seemingly distinct configurations of multi-instantons occur
as moduli changes in the non-BPS solutions, and the simplest non-BPS exact
solution corresponds to multi-bion configurations with fully-compressed double
fractional instantons in the middle. It indicates that the non-BPS solutions
make small but nonzero contribution to the resurgent trans-series as special
cases of the multi-bion configurations. We observe a generic pattern of
transitions between distinct multi-bion configurations (flipping partners),
leading to the three essential properties of the non-BPS exact solution: (i)
opposite sign for terms corresponding to the left and right infinities, (ii)
symmetric location of fractional instantons, and (iii) the transition between
distinct bion configurations. By studying the balance of forces, we show that
the relative phases between the instanton constituents play decisive roles in
stability and instability of the muli-instanton configurations. We discuss
local and global instabilities of the solutions such as negative modes and the
flow to the other saddle points, by considering the deformations of the non-BPS
exact solutions within our multi-instanton ansatz. We also briefly discuss some
classes of the non-BPS exact solutions in Grassmann sigma models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04821</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04821</id><created>2016-04-16</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramya</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reddy</keyname><forenames>Bacham E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>David L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Musthafa</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical compositions and kinematics of the Hercules stream</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw852</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An abundance analysis is reported of 58 K giants identified by Famaey et al.
(2005) as highly probable members of the Hercules stream selected from stars
north of the celestial equator in the Hipparcos catalogue. The giants have
compositions spanning the interval [Fe/H] from $-$0.17 to $+$0.42 with a mean
value of $+$0.15 and relative elemental abundances [El/Fe] representative of
the Galactic thin disc. Selection effects may have biassed the selection from
the Hipparcos catalogue against the selection of metal-poor stars. Our
reconsideration of the recent extensive survey of FG dwarfs which included
metal-poor stars (Bensby et al. 2014) provides a [Fe/H] distribution for the
Hercules stream which is similar to that from the 58 giants. It appears that
the stream is dominated by metal-rich stars from the thin disc. Suggestions in
the literature that the stream includes metal-poor stars from the thick disc
are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05881</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05881</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>C. de la Fuente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcos</keyname><forenames>R. de la Fuente</forenames></author></authors><title>Commensurabilities between ETNOs: a Monte Carlo survey</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables. Revised to match version published in
  MNRAS: Letters</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016, 460 (1):
  L64-L68 (July 21, 2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw077</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many asteroids in the main and trans-Neptunian belts are trapped in mean
motion resonances with Jupiter and Neptune, respectively. As a side effect,
they experience accidental commensurabilities among themselves. These
commensurabilities define characteristic patterns that can be used to trace the
source of the observed resonant behaviour. Here, we explore systematically the
existence of commensurabilities between the known ETNOs using their
heliocentric and barycentric semimajor axes, their uncertainties, and Monte
Carlo techniques. We find that the commensurability patterns present in the
known ETNO population resemble those found in the main and trans-Neptunian
belts. Although based on small number statistics, such patterns can only be
properly explained if most, if not all, of the known ETNOs are subjected to the
resonant gravitational perturbations of yet undetected trans-Plutonian planets.
We show explicitly that some of the statistically significant
commensurabilities are compatible with the Planet Nine hypothesis; in
particular, a number of objects may be trapped in the 5:3 and 3:1 mean motion
resonances with a putative Planet Nine with semimajor axis of about 700 au.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00798</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborti</keyname><forenames>Subhadip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>Shradha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pradhan</keyname><forenames>Punyabrata</forenames></author></authors><title>Additivity, density fluctuations, and nonequilibrium thermodynamics for
  active Brownian particles</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 052606 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.052606</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using an additivity property, we study particle-number fluctuations in a
system of interacting self-propelled particles, called active Brownian
particles (ABPs), which consists of repulsive disks with random self-propulsion
velocities. From a fluctuation-response relation - a direct consequence of
additivity, we formulate a thermodynamic theory which captures the previously
observed features of nonequilibrium phase transition in the ABPs from a
homogeneous fluid phase to an inhomogeneous phase of coexisting gas and liquid.
We substantiate the predictions of additivity by analytically calculating the
subsystem particle-number distributions in the homogeneous fluid phase away
from criticality where analytically obtained distributions are compatible with
simulations in the ABPs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01840</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01840</id><created>2016-05-06</created><updated>2016-05-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Yi-Fu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xinmin</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing the origin of our universe through primordial gravitational
  waves by Ali CMB project</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>Research highlight invited by SCIENCE CHINA Physics, Mechanics &amp;
  Astronomy; 3 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Sci. China-Phys. Mech. Astron. 59, 670431 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11433-016-0178-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a research highlight invited by SCIENCE CHINA Physics, Mechanics &amp;
Astronomy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01937</id><created>2016-05-06</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anchordoqui</keyname><forenames>Luis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldberg</keyname><forenames>Haim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraints on 750 GeV colorless Q-onia from running couplings</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>This version includes effects of longitudinal modes decays in HZ</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present yet another composite model explaining the relatively broad peak
in the diphoton invariant mass distribution around 750 GeV recently observed at
the LHC experiments. We consider the excess originates in bound states of
vector-like fermions Q transforming under the electroweak group (but not QCD)
of the standard model and which are also charged under a new SU(N_{TC})
QCD-like confining force. Since the new uncolored fields transform as SU(2)
doublets they can acquire a mass through Yukawa interactions with the
electroweak Higgs doublet, as quarks and leptons. We parametrize the Q-onium
bound state using the Coulomb approximation and give a numerical fit to the
diphoton excess consistent with no strong coupling effects up to about 30 TeV,
which is the energy scale for next generation colliders. The range of allowed
hypercharge Y_Q is given by 2.26 \leq Y_Q \leq 2.53 for N_{\rm TC} =2 and 2.17
\leq Y_Q \leq 2.31 for N_{\rm TC} = 3. The smoking gun for the model would be
the discovery of Q-onia decaying into Higgs and Z-boson.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02937</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Otulakowska-Hypka</keyname><forenames>Magdalena</forenames><affiliation>Sterrewacht Leiden</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Olech</keyname><forenames>Arkadiusz</forenames><affiliation>N. Copernicus Astronomical Center</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Patterson</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames><affiliation>Columbia University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Statistical analysis of properties of dwarf novae outbursts</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a statistical study of all measurable photometric features of a
large sample of dwarf novae during their outbursts and superoutbursts. We used
all accessible photometric data for all our objects to make the study as
complete and up-to-date as possible. Our aim was to check correlations between
these photometric features in order to constrain theoretical models which try
to explain the nature of dwarf novae outbursts. We managed to confirm a few of
the known correlations, that is the Stolz and Schoembs Relation, the Bailey
Relation for long outbursts above the period gap, the relations between the
cycle and supercycle lengths, amplitudes of normal and superoutbursts,
amplitude and duration of superoutbursts, outburst duration and orbital period,
outburst duration and mass ratio for short and normal outbursts, as well as the
relation between the rise and decline rates of superoutbursts. However, we
question the existence of the Kukarkin-Parenago Relation but we found an
analogous relation for superoutbursts. We also failed to find one presumed
relation between outburst duration and mass ratio for superoutbursts. This
study should help to direct theoretical work dedicated to dwarf novae.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03496</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Addesso</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longo</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marano</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matta</keyname><forenames>Vincenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Principe</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinto</keyname><forenames>Innocenzo M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Compressed Sensing for Time-Frequency Gravitational Wave Data Analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.IM gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages + 17 figures</comments><report-no>LIGO P120170v3</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The potential of compressed sensing for obtaining sparse time-frequency
representations for gravitational wave data analysis is illustrated by
comparison with existing methods, as regards i) shedding light on the fine
structure of noise transients (glitches) in preparation of their
classification, and ii) boosting the performance of waveform consistency tests
in the detection of unmodeled transient gravitational wave signals using a
network of detectors affected by unmodeled noise transient
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03519</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gerhardt</keyname><forenames>Claus</forenames></author></authors><title>Deriving a complete set of eigendistributions for a gravitational wave
  equation describing the quantized interaction of gravity with a Yang-Mills
  field in case the Cauchy hypersurface is non-compact</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages, v2: Some typos corrected</comments><msc-class>83, 83C, 83C45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a recent paper we quantized the interaction of gravity with a Yang-Mills
and Higgs field and obtained as a result a gravitational wave equation in a
globally hyperbolic spacetime. Assuming that the Cauchy hypersurfaces are
compact we proved a spectral resolution for the wave equation by applying the
method of separation of variables. In this paper we extend the results to the
case when the Cauchy hypersurfaces are non-compact by considering a Gelfand
triplet and applying the nuclear spectral theorem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03540</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-05-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hiroshima</keyname><forenames>Nagisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohri</keyname><forenames>Kazunori</forenames></author></authors><title>A unified model for the time variability of the Crab: the dispersion
  measure variation and the $\gamma$-ray flare of the nebula</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author due to a crucial mistake</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Crab pulsar and its nebula are very luminous and variable. Since 1982,
random fluctuations of the dispersion measure (DM) have been recorded. Also in
2011, Fermi-LAT telescope detected $\gamma$-ray flux variation of the Crab
nebula. No correlation between these phenomena have considered although their
fluctuating patterns look similar. We propose a model which connects the DM and
the Crab nebula $\gamma$-ray flux fluctuation, motivated by recently reported
correlation between the braking index and the DM variability. Considering
electrons within the inner shock region of the nebula produced in breaking
index change events, we can explain both the DM enhancement and the
$\gamma$-ray flare in a simple way.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03957</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Meisel</keyname><forenames>Zach</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Ke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jemcov</keyname><forenames>Aleksandar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Couder</keyname><forenames>Manoel</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploratory investigation of the HIPPO gas-jet target fluid dynamic
  properties</title><categories>physics.ins-det nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Nuclear Instruments and Methods in Physics Research A 828, 8
  (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.04.115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to optimize the performance of gas-jet targets for future nuclear
reaction measurements, a detailed understanding of the dependence of the
gas-jet properties on experiment design parameters is required. Common methods
of gas-jet characterization rely on measuring the effective thickness using
nuclear elastic scattering and energy loss techniques; however, these tests are
time intensive and limit the range of design modifications which can be
explored to improve the properties of the jet as a nuclear reaction target.
Thus, a more rapid jet-characterization method is desired. We performed the
first steps towards characterizing the gas-jet density distribution of the
HIPPO gas-jet target at the University of Notre Dame's Nuclear Science
Laboratory by reproducing results from
$^{20}\rm{Ne}(\alpha,\alpha)^{20}\rm{Ne}$ elastic scattering measurements with
computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations performed with the
state-of-the-art CFD software ANSYS Fluent. We find a strong sensitivity to
experimental design parameters of the gas-jet target, such as the jet nozzle
geometry and ambient pressure of the target chamber. We argue that improved
predictive power will require moving to three-dimensional simulations and
additional benchmarking with experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03958</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03958</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Young-S.</keyname><forenames>Luis E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vudragovic</keyname><forenames>Dusan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muruganandam</keyname><forenames>Paulsamy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adhikari</keyname><forenames>Sadhan K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balaz</keyname><forenames>Antun</forenames></author></authors><title>OpenMP Fortran and C programs for solving the time-dependent
  Gross-Pitaevskii equation in an anisotropic trap</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.PS physics.comp-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure; to download programs, click other formats and
  download the source</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Phys. Commun. 204 (2016) 209</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2016.03.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new version of previously published Fortran and C programs for
solving the Gross-Pitaevskii equation for a Bose-Einstein condensate with
contact interaction in one, two and three spatial dimensions in imaginary and
real time, yielding both stationary and non-stationary solutions. To reduce the
execution time on multicore processors, new versions of parallelized programs
are developed using Open Multi-Processing (OpenMP) interface. The input in the
previous versions of programs was the mathematical quantity nonlinearity for
dimensionless form of Gross-Pitaevskii equation, whereas in the present
programs the inputs are quantities of experimental interest, such as, number of
atoms, scattering length, oscillator length for the trap, etc. New output files
for some integrated one- and two-dimensional densities of experimental interest
are given. We also present speedup test results for the new programs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03969</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Wei-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Crossover From Strong to Weak Pairing States in $t-J-U$ Model Studied by
  A Slave Spin Method</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the superconductivity in the $t-J-U$ model within a slave-spin
formalism. We show that the BCS mean-field theory implemented with the slave
spin formalism naturally predicts two distinct gaps which are the pairing gap
of the spinons $\Delta_f$ and the Cooper pairing gap of the electrons
$\Delta_{SC} = Z\Delta_f$, where $Z$ is the quasiparticle weight. Furthermore,
we find that the nature of the superconducting state depends crucially on the
interaction providing the pairing mechanism. For spin interactions, the
bandwidth of the spinon hopping term is renormalized by $Z$ but the its pairing
term is not. As a result, if $U$ exceeds the critical value for the Mott
insulating state at half-filling, $Z$ develops a strong doping dependence,
leading to a doping-driven crossover from strong to weak pairing states. In the
strong pairing state, while $\Delta_f$ is enhanced as $x\to 0$,
$\Delta_{SC}\sim x$ due to the renormalization of $Z$. In the weak pairing
state, $Z$ does not change with $x$ significantly. Therefore, $\Delta_{SC}$ is
mainly controlled by $\Delta_f$, and both of them go to zero at larger doping.
The crossover from strong to weak pairing states is well captured by the slave
spin formalism within reasonable range of parameters just at the mean-field
level, indicating the slave spin formalism is a powerful tool to study
correlated materials. For charge interactions, we find that the bandwidth of
the spinon hopping term and its pairing term are renormalized by $Z$ and $Z^2$
respectively. Consequently, both $\Delta_f$ and $\Delta_{SC}$ are suppressed at
small $x$ in large U, and no crossover will occur. The implication of our
results for the superconducting states in correlated materials will be
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03970</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03970</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Price</keyname><forenames>Layne C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trac</keyname><forenames>Hy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cen</keyname><forenames>Renyue</forenames></author></authors><title>Reconstructing the redshift evolution of escaped ionizing flux from
  early galaxies with Planck and HST observations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While galaxies at $6 \lesssim z \lesssim 10$ are believed to dominate the
epoch of cosmic reionization, the escape fraction of ionizing flux
$f_\mathrm{esc}$ and the photon production rate $\dot n_\gamma$ from these
galaxies must vary with redshift to simultaneously match CMB and low-redshift
observations. We constrain $f_\mathrm{esc}(z)$ and $\dot n_\gamma(z)$ with
Planck 2015 measurements of the Thomson optical depth $\tau$, recent low
multipole E-mode polarization measurements from Planck 2016, SDSS BAO data, and
$3 \lesssim z \lesssim 10$ galaxy observations. We compare different galaxy
luminosity functions that are calibrated to HST observations, using both
parametric and non-parametric statistical methods that marginalize over the
effective clumping factor $C_\mathrm{HII}$, the LyC production efficiency
$\xi_\mathrm{ion}$, and the time-evolution of the UV limiting magnitude
$dM_\mathrm{SF}/dz$. Using a power-law model, we find $f_\mathrm{esc} \lesssim
0.5$ at $z=8$ with slope $\beta \gtrsim 2.0$ at $68\%$ confidence with little
dependence on the galaxy luminosity function or data, although there is
non-negligible probability for no redshift evolution $\beta \sim 0$ or small
escape fraction $f_\mathrm{esc} \sim 10^{-2}$. A non-parametric form for
$f_\mathrm{esc}(z)$ evolves significantly with redshift, yielding
$f_\mathrm{esc} \sim 0.2, 0.3, 0.6$ at $z=6,9,12$, respectively. However, a
model-independent reconstruction of $\dot n_\gamma(z)$ predicts a suppressed
escaped photon production rate at $z=9$ for the latest Planck data compared to
the other models, implying a quicker period of reionization. We find evidence
for redshift evolution in the limiting magnitude of the galaxy luminosity
function for empirical models of the galaxy luminosity function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03977</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Stoupin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antipov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Butler</keyname><forenames>J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolyadin</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katrusha</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-surface-area diamond (111) crystal plates for applications in
  high-heat-load wavefront-preserving x-ray crystal optics</title><categories>physics.ins-det cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report fabrication and results of high-resolution X-ray topography
characterization of diamond single crystal plates with a large surface area
(10$\times$10 mm$^2$) and (111) crystal surface orientation for applications in
high-heat-load X-ray crystal optics. The plates were fabricated by laser
cutting of the (111) facets of diamond crystals grown using high-pressure
high-temperature method. The intrinsic crystal quality of a selected
3$\times$7~mm$^2$ crystal region of one of the studied samples was found to be
suitable for applications in wavefront-preserving high-heat-load crystal
optics. The wavefront characterization was performed using sequential X-ray
diffraction topography in the pseudo plane wave configuration and data analysis
using rocking curve topography. The variation of the rocking curve width and
peak position measured with a spatial resolution of 13$\times$13 $\mu m^2$ over
the selected region were found to be less than one microradian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03996</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Capua</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rettner</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>See-Hun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parkin</keyname><forenames>Stuart S. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical limit of Rabi nutations in spins of ferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rabi oscillations describe the interaction of a two-level system with a
rotating electromagnetic field. As such, they serve as the principle method for
manipulating quantum bits. By using a combination of femtosecond laser pulses
and microwave excitations, we have observed the classical form of Rabi
nutations in a ferromagnetic system whose equations of motion mirror the case
of a precessing quantum two-level system. Key to our experiments is the
selection of a subset of spins that is in resonance with the microwave
excitation and whose coherence time is thereby extended. Taking advantage of
Gilbert damping, the relaxation times are further increased such that
mode-locking takes place. The observation of such Rabi nutations is the first
step towards potential applications based on phase-coherent spin manipulation
in ferromagnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04038</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04038</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palina</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>W. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wan</keyname><forenames>D-Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venkatesan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rusydi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ariando</keyname></author></authors><title>Controlling Kondo-like Scattering at the SrTiO3-based Interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>25 pages, 5 figure</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 25455 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep25455</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The observation of magnetic interaction at the interface between nonmagnetic
oxides has attracted much attention in recent years. In this report, we show
that the Kondo-like scattering at the SrTiO3-based conducting interface is
enhanced by increasing the lattice mismatch and growth oxygen pressure PO2. For
the 26-unit-cell LaAlO3/SrTiO3 (LAO/STO) interface with lattice mismatch being
3.0%, the Kondo-like scattering is observed when PO2 is beyond 1 mTorr. By
contrast, when the lattice mismatch is reduced to 1.0% at the
(La0.3Sr0.7)(Al0.65Ta0.35)O3/SrTiO3 (LSAT/STO) interface, the metallic state is
always preserved up to PO2 of 100 mTorr. The data from Hall measurement and
X-ray absorption near edge structure (XANES) spectroscopy reveal that the
larger amount of localized Ti3+ ions are formed at the LAO/STO interface
compared to LSAT/STO. Those localized Ti3+ ions with unpaired electrons can be
spin-polarized to scatter mobile electrons, responsible for the Kondo-like
scattering observed at the LAO/STO interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04041</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Krishnamurthy</keyname><forenames>Deepak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katsikis</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhargava</keyname><forenames>Arjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prakash</keyname><forenames>Manu</forenames></author></authors><title>Schistosoma mansoni cercariae exploit an elastohydrodynamic coupling to
  swim efficiently</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.flu-dyn q-bio.QM</categories><comments>36 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The motility of many parasites is critical for the infection process of their
host, as exemplified by the transmission cycle of the blood fluke Schistosoma
mansoni. In their human infectious stage, immature, submillimetre-scale forms
of the parasite known as cercariae swim in freshwater and infect humans by
penetrating through the skin. This infection causes Schistosomiasis, a
parasitic disease that is comparable to malaria in its global socio-economic
impact. Given that cercariae do not feed and hence have a finite lifetime of
around 12 hours, efficient motility is crucial for the parasite's survival and
transmission of Schistosomiasis. However, a first-principles understanding of
how cercariae swim is lacking. Via a combined experimental, theoretical and
robotics based approach, we demonstrate that cercariae propel themselves
against gravity by exploiting a unique elastohydrodynamic coupling. We show
that cercariae beat their tail in a periodic fashion while maintaining a fixed
flexibility near their posterior and anterior ends. The flexibility in these
regions allows an interaction between the fluid drag and bending resistance: an
elastohydrodynamic coupling, to naturally break time-reversal symmetry and
enable locomotion at small length-scales. We present a theoretical model, a
'T-swimmer', which captures the key swimming phenotype of cercariae. We further
validate our results experimentally through a macro-scale robotic realization
of the 'T-swimmer', explaining the unique forked-tail geometry of cercariae.
Finally, we find that cercariae maintain the flexibility at their posterior and
anterior ends at an optimal regime for efficient swimming, as predicted by our
theoretical model. We anticipate that our work sets the ground for linking the
swimming of S. mansoni cercariae to disease transmission and enables
explorations of novel strategies for Schistosomiasis prevention.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04051</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Devidas</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amaladass</keyname><forenames>E. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Shilpam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mani</keyname><forenames>Awadhesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajaraman</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sundar</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bharathi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Sb substitution on the Topological Surface States in
  Bi_{2}Se_{3} single crystals: a magneto-transport study</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magneto-transport measurements have been carried out on Bi2-xSbxSe3 (x = 0,
0.05, 0.1, 0.3, 0.5) single crystals at 4.2 K temperature in the magnetic field
range of -15 T to 15 T. Shubnikov-de Haas (SdH) oscillations of 2D nature were
observed in samples with Sb concentration upto x = 0.3. The analyses of SdH
oscillations observed in magneto-resistance data using Lifshitz-Kosevich
equation reveal a systematic decrease in the Fermi surface area with Sb
substitution. The Berry phase obtained from the Landau Level fan diagram
suggests the occurrence of 2D oscillations arising from a Topological Surface
State (TSS) for Sb concentrations of x = 0, 0.05 and 0.1; while 2D oscillation
seen at higher Sb concentration is attributed to surface 2D electron gas
consequent to downward band bending.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04077</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04077</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Pocheketa</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Normalized classes of generalized Burgers equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>35A30 (Primary), 35C05, 35K59, 35K05 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Proceedings of the Sixth International Workshop &quot;Group Analysis of
  Differential Equations and Integrable Systems'' (Protaras, Cyprus, June
  17--21, 2012) University of Cyprus, Nicosia, 2013, 170--178</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A hierarchy of normalized classes of generalized Burgers equations is
studied. The equivalence groupoids of these classes are computed. The
equivalence groupoids of classes of linearizable generalized Burgers equations
are related to those of the associated linear counterparts using the Hopf--Cole
transformation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04080</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04080</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Foughali</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dirac's Equation in $R$-Minkowski Spacetime</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>13 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Theo. Phys. 55 (2016) 2247</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We recently constructed the $R$-Poincar\'e algebra from an appropriate
deformed Poisson brackets which reproduce the Fock coordinate transformation.
We showed then that the spacetime of this transformation is the de Sitter one.
In this paper, we derive in the $R$-Minkowski spacetime the Dirac equation and
show that this is none other than the Dirac equation in the de Sitter spacetime
given by its conformally flat metric. Furthermore, we propose a new approach
for solving Dirac's equation in the de Sitter spacetime using the
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger picture.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04088</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Capozza</keyname><forenames>Rosario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pugno</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Surface Grooves on the Static Friction of an Elastic Slider</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Tribology Letters, 58, 35 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11249-015-0510-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerous studies have proved the usefulness of surface patterning for the
modification of tribological performances of sliding contacts. Here we
investigate the effects of patterning on the tribological properties of a
slider over a solid substrate. We show that, depending on the numerical density
of surface grooves, the tribological properties can change significantly. A low
density of surface patterning leads to a decrease of static friction force,
while a higher density weakens this effect. The decrease is related to a
non-uniform distribution of surface stress induced by patterning. We believe
these findings and approach to be relevant for technological applications and
related optimal design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04096</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04096</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Pocheketa</keyname><forenames>Oleksandr A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Equivalence groupoid of generalized potential Burgers equations</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>35A30 (Primary), 35C05, 35K59, 35K05 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 621 (2015), 012011</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/621/1/012011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find the equivalence groupoid of a~class of $(1+1)$-dimensional
second-order evolution equations, which are called generalized potential
Burgers equations. This class is related via potentialization with two classes
of variable-coefficient generalized Burgers equations. Its equivalence groupoid
is of complicated structure and is described via partitioning the entire class
into three normalized subclasses such that there are no point transformations
between equations from different subclasses. For each of these subclasses we
construct its equivalence group of an appropriate kind.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04099</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04099</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>Anjan</forenames></author></authors><title>Exact Bethe ansatz solution for a quantum field model of interacting
  scalar fields in quasi-two dimensions</title><categories>nlin.SI cond-mat.stat-mech hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>16 pages, no figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Integrable quantum field models are known to exist mostly in one
space-dimension. Exploiting the concept of multi-time in integrable systems and
a Lax matrix of higher scaling order, we construct a novel quantum field model
in quasi-two dimensions involving interacting fields. The Yang-Baxter
integrability is proved for the model by finding a new kind of commutation rule
for its basic fields, representing nonstandard scalar fields along the
transverse direction. In spite of a close link with the quantum Landau-Lifshitz
equation, the present model differs widely from it, in its content and the
result obtained. Using further the algebraic Bethe ansatz we solve exactly the
eigenvalue problem of this quantum field model for all its higher conserved
operators. The idea presented here should instigate the construction of a novel
class of integrable field and lattice models and exploration of a new type of
underlying algebras.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04104</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04104</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Haibiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Lingfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Yubin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Qingyou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Wenbin</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution and control of the phase competition morphology in a manganite
  film</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications, 6, 8980 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms9980</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The competition among different phases in perovskite manganites is pronounced
since their energies are very close under the interplay of charge, spin,
orbital and lattice degrees of freedom. To reveal the roles of underlying
interactions, many efforts have been devoted towards directly imaging phase
transitions at microscopic scales. Here we show images of the charge-ordered
insulator (COI) phase transition from a pure ferromagnetic metal with reducing
field or increasing temperature in a strained phase-separated manganite film,
using a home-built magnetic force microscope. Compared with the COI melting
transition, this reverse transition is sharp, cooperative and martensitic-like
with astonishingly unique yet diverse morphologies. The COI domains show
variable-dimensional growth at different temperatures and their distribution
can illustrate the delicate balance of the underlying interactions in
manganites. Our findings also display how phase domain engineering is possible
and how the phase competition can be tuned in a controllable manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04105</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04105</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Verzhbitskiy</keyname><forenames>Ivan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Corato</keyname><forenames>Marzio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruini</keyname><forenames>Alice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Molinari</keyname><forenames>Elisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Narita</keyname><forenames>Akimitsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Yunbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Matthias Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruna</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milana</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Xinliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;llen</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrari</keyname><forenames>Andrea C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casiraghi</keyname><forenames>Cinzia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prezzi</keyname><forenames>Deborah</forenames></author></authors><title>Raman fingerprints of atomically precise graphene nanoribbons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>This document is the unedited Author's version of a Submitted Work
  that was subsequently accepted for publication in Nano Letters, copyright
  \c{opyright} American Chemical Society after peer review. To access the final
  edited and published work see DOI: 10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b04183</comments><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.5b04183</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Bottom-up approaches allow the production of ultra-narrow and atomically
precise graphene nanoribbons (GNRs), with electronic and optical properties
controlled by the specific atomic structure. Combining Raman spectroscopy and
ab-initio simulations, we show that GNR width, edge geometry and functional
groups all influence their Raman spectra. The low-energy spectral region below
1000 cm-1 is particularly sensitive to edge morphology and functionalization,
while the D peak dispersion can be used to uniquely fingerprint the presence of
GNRs, and differentiates them from other sp2 carbon nanostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04108</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Garcilazo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valcarce</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Deeply bound $\Xi$ tribaryon</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. C93, 034001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.034001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have used realistic local interactions based on the recent update of the
strangeness $-2$ Nijmegen ESC08c potential to calculate the bound state problem
of the $\Xi NN$ system in the $(I)J^P=(\frac{1}{2})\frac{3}{2}^+$ state. We
found that this system presents a deeply bound state lying $13.5$ MeV below the
$\Xi d$ threshold. Since in lowest order, pure S$-$wave configuration, this
system can not decay into the open $\Lambda\Lambda N$ channel, its decay width
is expected to be very small. We have also recalculated the
$(I)J^P=(\frac{3}{2})\frac{1}{2}^+$ state and we have compared with results of
quark-model based potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04114</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomsen</keyname><forenames>Morten Rish&#xf8;j</forenames></author><author><keyname>Power</keyname><forenames>Stephen Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jauho</keyname><forenames>Antti-Pekka</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Thomas Garm</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic edge states and magnetotransport in graphene antidot barriers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetic fields are often used for characterizing transport in nanoscale
materials. Recent magnetotransport experiments have demonstrated that ballistic
transport is possible in graphene antidot lattices (GALs). These experiments
have inspired the present theoretical study of GALs in a perpendicular magnetic
field. We calculate magnetotransport through graphene antidot barriers (GABs),
which are finite rows of antidots arranged periodically in a pristine graphene
sheet, using a tight-binding model and the Landauer-B\&quot;uttiker formula. We show
that GABs behave as ideal Dirac mass barriers for antidots smaller than the
magnetic length, and demonstrate the presence of magnetic edge states, which
are localized states on the periphery of the antidots due to successive
reflections on the antidot edge in the presence of a magnetic field. We show
that these states are robust against variations in lattice configuration and
antidot edge chirality. Moreover, we calculate the transmittance of disordered
GABs and find that magnetic edge states survive a moderate degree of disorder.
Due to the long phase-coherence length in graphene and the robustness of these
states, we expect magnetic edge states to be observable in experiments as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04116</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>N&#xe1;dvorn&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haigh</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olejn&#xed;k</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irvine</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nov&#xe1;k</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jungwirth</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wunderlich</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient conversion of light to charge and spin in Hall-bar microdevice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 91, 125205 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.91.125205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental demonstration of a local amplification of the spin
Hall voltage using an expanding depletion zone at a pn-junction in GaAs/AlGaAs
Hall-bar microdevices. It is demonstrated that the depletion zone can be
spatially expanded by applying reverse bias by at least 10~$\mu$m at low
temperature. In the depleted regime, the spin Hall signals reached more than
one order of magnitude higher values than in the normal regime at the same
electrical current flowing through the micro-device. It is shown that the
pn-bias has two distinct effects on the detected spin Hall signal. It controls
the local drift field at the Hall cross which is highly non-linear in the
pn-bias due to the shift of the depletion front. Simultaneously, it produces a
change in the spin-transport parameters due to the non-linear change in the
carrier density at the Hall cross with the pn-bias.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04124</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Charles</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Witten asymptotic conjecture for Seifert manifolds</title><categories>math.GT math-ph math.MP math.SG</categories><msc-class>57R56, 53D50, 81Q20</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a new proof of Witten asymptotic conjecture for Seifert manifolds
with non vanishing Euler class and one exceptional fiber. Our method is based
on semiclassical analysis on a two dimensional phase space torus. We prove that
the Witten-Reshetikhin-Turaev invariant of a Seifert manifold is the scalar
product of two Lagrangian states, and we estimate this scalar product in the
large level limit. The leading order terms of the expansion are naturally given
in terms of character varieties, the Chern-Simons invariants and some
symplectic volumes. For the analytic part, we establish some singular
stationary phase lemma for discrete oscillatory sums.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04126</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04126</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ryblewski</keyname><forenames>Radoslaw</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermalization and hydrodynamization in the color-flux-tube model</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>Talk presented by Radoslaw Ryblewski at Excited QCD 2016, 6-12 March
  2016, Costa da Caparica, Portugal</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of transverse-momentum spectra of quarks and gluons produced by the
color electric flux tube decaying through the Schwinger tunneling mechanism is
reviewed. The hints for a fast hydrodynamization in the ultra-relativistic
heavy-ion collisions are found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04140</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Masharian</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zamani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete-time analysis of traveling wave solutions and steady-state of
  PASEP with open boundaries</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the dynamics of a single shock in a partially asymmetric simple
exclusion process (PASEP) on a finite lattice with open boundaries in the
sublattice-parallel updating scheme. We then construct the steady state of the
system by considering a linear superposition of these shocks. It is shown that
this steady state can also be written in terms of a product of four non-
commuting matrices. One of the main results obtained here is that these
matrices have exactly the same generic structure as the matrices first
introduced in Jafarpour and Masharian (2009 Phys. Rev. E 79 051124) indicating
that the steady state of a one-dimensional driven-diffusive system can be
written as a linear superposition of product shock measures. It is now easy to
explain the two-dimensional matrix representation of the PASEP with parallel
dynamics introduced in Essler and Rittenberg (1996 J. Phys. A: Math. Gen. 29
3375) and Honecker and Peschel (1997 J. Stat. Phys. 88 319).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04154</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>A. C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beims</keyname><forenames>M. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strunz</keyname><forenames>W. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>System-environment correlations for dephasing two-qubit states coupled
  to thermal baths</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 052316 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.052316</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Based on the exact dynamics of a two-qubit system and environment, we
investigate system-environment (SE) quantum and classical correlations. The
coupling is chosen to represent a dephasing channel for one of the qubits and
the environment is a proper thermal bath. First we discuss the general issue of
dilation for qubit phase damping. Based on the usual thermal bath of harmonic
oscillators, we derive criteria of separability and entanglement between an
initial $X$ state and the environment. Applying these criteria to initial
Werner states, we find that entanglement between the system and environment is
built up in time for temperatures below a certain critical temperature
$T_{\mathrm{crit}}$. On the other hand, the total state remains separable
during those short times that are relevant for decoherence and loss of
entanglement in the two-qubit state. Close to $T_{\mathrm{crit}}$ the SE
correlations oscillate between separable and entangled. Even though these
oscillations are also observed in the entanglement between the two qubits, no
simple relation between the loss of entanglement in the two-qubit system and
the build-up of entanglement between the system and environment is found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04167</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04167</id><created>2016-04-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Gharibyan</keyname><forenames>Vahagn</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to &quot;Comment on Testing Planck-Scale Gravity with Accelerators&quot;</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Results of a 2012 PRL Letter have recently been questioned by T. Kalaydzhyan
in arXiv:1604.04486. Here we confirm our original results and conclusions by
addressing all concerns raised in the Comment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04168</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological constraints on Lorentz Invariance violation in gravity and
  dark matter</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages. To appear in the proceedings of the 51st Rencontres de
  Moriond on Cosmology 2016</comments><report-no>INR-TH-2016-013</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This brief contribution is devoted to phenomenological consequences of
deviations from Lorentz invariance in gravity and dark matter. We will discuss
main effects on cosmological observables and current constraints derived from
astrophysical and cosmological data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04169</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ballout</keyname><forenames>Fouad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xfc;ndermann</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Diedrich A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Havenith</keyname><forenames>Martina</forenames></author></authors><title>Design of a plasmonic near-field tip for super-resolution IR-imaging</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concepts of spoof surface plasmon polaritons and adiabatic field
compression are employed to design metallic near-field probes that allow
guiding and focusing of mid-infrared wavelength electromagnetic radiation and
provides subwavelength field confinements and a lateral optical resolution of
about 10 nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04173</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Modesto</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rachwal</keyname><forenames>Leslaw</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite Conformal Quantum Gravity and Nonsingular Spacetimes</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explicitly prove that a class of finite quantum gravitational theories (in
odd as well as in even dimension) is actually a range of anomaly-free
conformally invariant theories in the spontaneously broken phase of the
conformal Weyl symmetry. At classical level we show how the Weyl conformal
invariance is likely able to tame the spacetime singularities that plague not
only Einstein gravity, but also local and weakly non-local higher derivative
theories. This latter statement is rigorously proved by a singularity theorem
that applies to a large class of weakly non-local theories. Following the
seminal paper by Narlikar and Kembhavi, we provide an explicit construction of
singularity-free black hole exact solutions conformally equivalent to the
Schwarzschild metric. Furthermore, we show that the FRW cosmological solutions
and the Belinski, Khalatnikov, Lifshitz (BKL) spacetimes, which exactly solve
the classical equations of motion, are conformally equivalent to regular
spacetimes. Finally, we prove that the Oppenheimer-Volkov gravitational
collapse is a an exact (singularity-free) solution of the non-local conformally
invariant theory compatible with the bounce paradigm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04174</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Howland</keyname><forenames>Gregory A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneeloch</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lum</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howell</keyname><forenames>John C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simultaneous Measurement of Complementary Observables with Compressive
  Sensing</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.Lett.112:253602,2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.112.253602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The more information a measurement provides about a quantum system's position
statistics, the less information a subsequent measurement can provide about the
system's momentum statistics. This information trade-off is embodied in the
entropic formulation of the uncertainty principle. Traditionally, uncertainty
relations correspond to resolution limits; increasing a detector's position
sensitivity decreases its momentum sensitivity and vice-versa. However, this is
not required in general; for example, position information can instead be
extracted at the cost of noise in momentum. Using random, partial projections
in position followed by strong measurements in momentum, we efficiently
determine the transverse-position and transverse-momentum distributions of an
unknown optical field with a single set of measurements. The momentum
distribution is directly imaged, while the position distribution is recovered
using compressive sensing. At no point do we violate uncertainty relations;
rather, we economize the use of information we obtain.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04179</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04179</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Yun-Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Zhu-An</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Guang-Han</forenames></author></authors><title>Crystal Chemistry and Structural Design of Iron-Based Superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Chin. Phys. B 22(8), 087410(2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1056/22/8/087410</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The second class of high-temperature superconductors (HTSCs), iron-based
pnictides and chalcogenides, necessarily contain Fe$_2$$X_2$ (&quot;$X$&quot; refers to a
pnictogen or a chalcogen element) layers, just like the first class of HTSCs
which possess the essential CuO$_2$ sheets. So far, dozens of iron-based HTSCs,
classified into nine groups, have been discovered. In this article, the
crystal-chemistry aspects of the known iron-based superconductors are reviewed
and summarized by employing &quot;hard and soft acids and bases (HSAB)&quot; concept.
Based on these understandings, we propose an alternative route to exploring new
iron-based superconductors via rational structural design.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04188</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04188</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Strocchi</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heissenberg</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>Existence of quantum time crystals</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of quantum time crystals is investigated and shown to be
possible in pure phases defined by a state invariant under a group of space
translations, as displayed by explicit examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04189</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tsupko</keyname><forenames>O. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bisnovatyi-Kogan</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jefremov</keyname><forenames>P. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Parameters of Innermost Stable Circular Orbits of Spinning Test
  Particles: Numerical and Analytical Calculations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Paper is written for special issue of the journal dedicated to the
  centenary of Prof. K.P. Staniukovich. Some results of our previous paper
  arXiv:1503.07060 are used</comments><journal-ref>Gravitation and Cosmology, 22, 138-147 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0202289316020158</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The motion of classical spinning test particles in the equatorial plane of a
Kerr black hole is considered for the case where the particle spin is
perpendicular to the equatorial plane. We review some results of our recent
research of the innermost stable circular orbits (ISCO) [P.I. Jefremov, O.Yu.
Tsupko and G.S. Bisnovatyi-Kogan, Phys.Rev. D 91 124030 (2015)] and present
some new calculations. The ISCO radius, total angular momentum, energy, and
orbital angular frequency are considered. We calculate the ISCO parameters
numerically for different values of the Kerr parameter $a$ and investigate
their dependence on both black hole and test particle spins. Then we describe
in details how to calculate analytically small-spin corrections to the ISCO
parameters for an arbitrary values of $a$. The cases of Schwarzschild, slowly
rotating Kerr and extreme Kerr black hole are considered. The use of the
orbital angular momentum is discussed. We also consider the ISCO binding
energy. It is shown that the efficiency of accretion onto an extreme Kerr black
hole can be larger than the maximum known efficiency (42 %) if the test body
has a spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04196</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>David W</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weaver</keyname><forenames>Robert S</forenames></author></authors><title>On the construction of Tesla transformers. Period of oscillation and
  self-inductance of the coil. (Zur construction von Teslatransformatoren.
  Schwingungsdauer und Selbstinduction von Drahtspulen)</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>59 pages. Includes parts I and II</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  English Translation of Paul Drude's 1902 investigation into the factors
affecting the self-resonance of single-layer solenoid coils. The ratio of the
self-resonant half-wavelength to the conductor length is is found to be
principally dependent on the height-to diameter ratio of the coil and the
dielectric constants of any insulating materials involved in the construction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04198</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>de Aldecoa</keyname><forenames>Rafael Tiedra</forenames></author></authors><title>Degree, mixing, and absolutely continuous spectrum of cocycles with
  values in compact Lie groups</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP math.SP</categories><comments>38 pages</comments><msc-class>37A25, 37A30, 37C40, 47A35, 58J51</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider skew products $$T_\phi:X\times G\to X\times
G,~~(x,g)\mapsto(F_1(x),g\;\!\phi(x)),$$ where $X$ is a compact manifold with
probability measure, $G$ a compact Lie group with Lie algebra $\frak g$,
$F_1:X\to X$ the time-one map of a measure-preserving flow, and $\phi\in
C^1(X,G)$ a cocycle. Then, we define the degree of $\phi$ as a suitable
function $P_\phi M_\phi:X\to\frak g$, we show that it transforms in a natural
way under Lie group homomorphisms and under the relation of $C^1$-cohomology,
and we explain how it generalises previous definitions of degree of a cocycle.
For each finite-dimensional irreducible representation $\pi$ of $G$, and $\frak
g_\pi$ the Lie algebra of $\pi(G)$, we define in an analogous way the degree of
$\pi\circ\phi$ as a suitable function
$P_{\pi\circ\phi}M_{\pi\circ\phi}:X\to\frak g_\pi$. If $F_1$ is uniquely
ergodic and the functions $\pi\circ\phi$ diagonal, or if $T_\phi$ is uniquely
ergodic, then the degree of $\phi$ reduces to a constant in $\frak g$ given by
an integral over $X$. As a by-product, we obtain that there is no uniquely
ergodic skew product $T_\phi$ with nonzero degree if $G$ is a connected
semisimple compact Lie group.
  Next, we show that $T_\phi$ is mixing in the orthocomplement of the kernel of
$P_{\pi\circ\phi}M_{\pi\circ\phi}$, and under some additional assumptions we
show that $U_\phi$ has purely absolutely continuous spectrum in that
orthocomplement if $(iP_{\pi\circ\phi}M_{\pi\circ\phi})^2$ is strictly
positive. Summing up these results for each $\pi$, one obtains a global result
for the mixing and the absolutely continuous spectrum of $T_\phi$. As an
application, we present four explicit cases: when $G$ is a torus, $G=SU(2)$,
$G=SO(3,\mathbb R)$, and $G=U(2)$. In each case, the results we obtain are new,
or generalise previous results.
  Our proofs rely on new results on positive commutator methods for unitary
operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04213</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04213</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Yamaguchi</keyname><forenames>Takehiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriya</keyname><forenames>Rai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oki</keyname><forenames>Yoichiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masubuchi</keyname><forenames>Satoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamada</keyname><forenames>Kohei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machida</keyname><forenames>Tomoki</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin injection into multilayer graphene from highly spin-polarized
  Co2FeSi Heusler alloy</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Express 9, 063006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7567/APEX.9.063006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate electrical spin injection into multilayer graphene (MLG) in a
lateral spin valve device from a highly spin-polarized Co2FeSi (CFS) Huesler
electrode. Exfoliated MLG was transferred onto pre-patterned epitaxial CFS
wires grown on an Si(111) substrate by a polymer-based transfer method. This
method enabled us to fabricate multiple single-crystal CFS electrodes in
contact with MLG. Electrical spin injection from CFS to MLG was detected
through non-local magnetoresistance (MR) measurement. A non-local spin signal
of 430 ohm was observed; this is the largest value among all reported non-local
MR values in graphene-based devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04215</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04215</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez-Cuevas</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eberly</keyname><forenames>Joseph H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multipulse storage and manipulation via solitonic solutions</title><categories>quant-ph nlin.PS</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures, 1 table. \c{opyright} 2016 Optical Society of
  America. One print or electronic copy may be made for personal use only.
  Systematic reproduction and distribution, duplication of any material in this
  paper for a fee or for commercial purposes, or modifications of the content
  of this paper are prohibited</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B vol. 32, 2271-2280 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.32.002271</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solutions to the Maxwell-Bloch equations for a $\Lambda$ system are computed
using the single-soliton Darboux transformation and the nonlinear superposition
principle. These allow complete control of information deposited by a signal
pulse (with the help of an auxiliary control pulse) in the coherence of the
medium's ground states by injecting sub-sequential pulses. Additionally, we
study the encoding of two signal pulses and their manipulation by a control
pulse and show that multipulse storage and control are possible as long as the
imprints made by encoding the signal pulses are sufficiently separated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04229</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Suave</keyname><forenames>Rog&#xe9;rio Netto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nogueira</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9; Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>A discussion on approximations for the determination of the maximum
  period of a simple pendulum</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><journal-ref>Revista Brasileira de Ensino de F\{\i}sica, vol. 38, n^{o} 2,
  e2501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1590/S1806-11173822142</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we deal with the care one must have in adopting approximations
in regard with terms he chooses to leave behind in the particular case of the
expression valid for the maximum period of a long pendulum oscillating near
Earth's surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04241</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04241</id><created>2016-05-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Khwaja</keyname><forenames>Tariq Shamim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reza</keyname><forenames>Syed Azer</forenames></author></authors><title>Power Transmittance of a Laterally Shifted Gaussian Beam through a
  Circular Aperture</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>8 Pages, 1 Figure, 21 Equations</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gaussian beams are often used in optical systems. The fundamental Gaussian
TEM00 mode is the most common of the Gaussian modes present in various optical
devices, systems and equipment. Within an optical system, it is common that
this Gaussian TEM00 beam passes through a circular aperture of a finite
diameter. Such circular apertures include irises, spatial filters, circular
Photo-Detectors (PDs) and optical mounts with circular rims. The magnitude of
optical power passing through a finite-sized circular aperture is
well-documented for cases where the Gaussian beam passes through the center of
the clear circular aperture, and is chopped off symmetrically in all radial
directions on a given plane. More often than not, a non-axial incident Gaussian
Beam is not blocked in a radially uniform manner by a circular aperture. Such
situations arise due to a lateral displacement of the beam from tilted glass
blocks, manufacturing errors and imperfect surface flatness or parallelness of
surfaces. The fraction of optical power of a laterally-shifted Gaussian Beam
passing through a circular aperture is calculated in this paper through
conventional integration techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04249</id><created>2016-05-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Hedin</keyname><forenames>Eric R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Extra-dimensional confinement of quantum particles</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physics Essays, 25, No. 2, 177-190, 2012</journal-ref><doi>10.4006/0836-1398-25.2.177</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A basic theoretical framework is developed in which elementary particles have
a component of their wave function extending into higher spatial dimensions.
This model postulates an extension of the Schrodinger equation to include a 4th
and 5th spatial component. A higher-dimensional simple harmonic oscillator
confining potential localizes particles into 3-d space, characterizing the
brane tension which confines Standard Model particles to the sub-manifold.
Quantum effects allow a non-zero probability for a particle's evanescent
existence in the higher dimensions, and suggest an experimental test for the
validity of this model via particles being temporarily excited into the first
excited state of the extra-dimensional potential well, in which their
probability of existing in 3-d space transiently drops to zero. Several
consistency checks of the outcomes of this extra-dimensional model are included
in this paper. Among the outcomes of this model are: a match with the quantum
phenomenon of zitterbewegung; the predicted intrinsic spin angular momentum is
of order h/2Pi; the magnetic moment of the electron is determined with a
gyromagnetic ratio of 2; the nuclear force hard core radius is accurately
predicted; the ratio of the up and down quark masses is found to be mu/md=0.56,
consistent with QCD theory; a self-consistent derivation of special
relativistic effects is given; possible explanations of the Planck mass and
Planck length, and a possible explanation of the origin of electric charge. In
addition, a simple application of higher-dimensional particle effects to the
astrophysics of stars is briefly examined, showing that radical physical
inconsistencies are not evident. Finally, this model suggests a possible
explanation of dark matter as the fractional probability manifestations of a
ladder of the higher-dimensional symmetric excited states of ordinary
particles.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04251</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Turnage</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Darling</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rajagopalan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whittington</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tschopp</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peralta</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Solanki</keyname><forenames>K. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying structure-property relationships during resistance spot
  welding of an aluminum 6061-T6 joint</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microstructure-property relationships of resistance spot welded 6061-T6
aluminum alloy lap joints were investigated via mechanical testing and
microscopy techniques. Quasi-static tensile and novel shear punch tests were
employed to measure the mechanical properties of the distinct weld regions.
Quasi-static tensile and shear punch tests revealed constantly decreasing
strength and ductility as the weld center was approached. For instance, the
ultimate tensile strength of the fusion zone decreased by ~52% from the parent
material (341 MPa to 162 MPa) while the yield strength decreased by ~62% (312
MPa to 120 MPa). The process-induced microstructures were analyzed with
scanning electron microscopy and optical microscopy to elucidate the underlying
cause of the reduced mechanical properties. Fractography reveals void growth
from particles being the dominant damage mechanism in the parent material as
compared to void nucleation in the fusion zone. Overall, significant changes in
the mechanical behavior across the weld are the result of a change in
microstructure congruent with a loss of T6 condition (precipitate coarsening).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04260</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Rupp</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coito</keyname><forenames>Susana</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Beveren</keyname><forenames>Eef</forenames></author></authors><title>Unquenching the meson spectrum: a model study of excited $\rho$
  resonances</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 tables, Acta Physica Polonica B style, talk by G. Rupp at
  workshop &quot;Excited QCD 2016&quot;, Costa da Caparica, Portugal, March 6-12, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quark models taking into account the dynamical effects of hadronic decay
often produce very different predictions for mass shifts in the hadron
spectrum. The consequences for meson spectroscopy can be dramatic and
completely obscure the underlying confining force. Recent unquenched lattice
calculations of mesonic resonances that also include meson-meson interpolators
provide a touchstone for such models, despite the present limitations in
applicability. On the experimental side, the $\rho(770)$ meson and its several
observed radial recurrences are a fertile testing ground for both quark models
and lattice computations. Here we apply a unitarised quark model that has been
successful in the description of many enigmatic mesons to these vector $\rho$
resonances and the corresponding $P$-wave $\pi\pi$ phase shifts. This work is
in progress, with encouraging preliminary results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04264</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Nallamuthu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arun</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ilkovic</keyname><forenames>Sergej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curlik</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reiffers</keyname><forenames>Marian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagalakshmi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Competing magnetic interactions in the orthorhombic GdNiAl3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetization and heat capacity measurements of ternary rare earth
intermetallic compound GdNiAl3 demonstrate para to ferromagnetic transition at
Tc=165.5K. In addition multiple short range magnetic transitions observed below
Tc are suggestive of competing interactions in this compound. As a result of
this a weak Griffiths phase type behaviour is observed in the paramagnetic
region. This complex behaviour is rather supported by the random orientation of
Ni centered tricapped trigonal prisms with additional Al atoms in the
structure. Heat capacity and resistivity data display an interesting peak at 72
K, which is highly unaffected by magnetic fields up to 90KOe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04275</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Danka</keyname><forenames>Tivadar</forenames></author></authors><title>Universality limits for generalized Jacobi measures</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>55 pages</comments><msc-class>42C05, 31A99, 33C10, 33C45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper universality limits are studied in connection with measures
which exhibit power-type singular behavior somewhere in their support. We
extend the results of Lubinsky for Jacobi measures supported on $ [-1,1] $ to
generalized Jacobi measures supported on a compact subset of the real line,
where the singularity can be located in the interior or at an endpoint of the
support. The analysis is based upon the Riemann-Hilbert method, Christoffel
functions, the polynomial inverse image method of Totik and the normal family
approach of Lubinsky.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04277</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>del Castillo</keyname><forenames>G. F. Torres</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosa-S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solutions of the Schr\&quot;odinger equation given by solutions of the
  Hamilton--Jacobi equation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find the form of the potential depending on the coordinates and the time
such that a solution, $S$, of the Hamilton--Jacobi equation yields an exact
solution, $\exp ({\rm i} S/\hbar)$, of the corresponding Schr\&quot;odinger
equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04280</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04280</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sullivan</keyname><forenames>Zack</forenames></author></authors><title>Boosted-bottom jet tagging and BSM searches</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>4 pgs, 3 figs, Submission to Proceedings of the 51st Rencontres de
  Moriond</comments><report-no>IIT-CAPP-16-02</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  I present a new scheme for tagging boosted heavy flavor jets called &quot;$\mu_x$
tagging&quot; and its application to TeV-scale physics beyond the Standard Model.
Using muons from B hadron decay to define a particular combination &quot;x&quot; of
angular information, and jet substructure variables, we identify a clean
($\epsilon_{\mathrm{fake}}/\epsilon_b\sim 1/100$) good efficiency ($\epsilon_b
= 14\%$) tag. I demonstrate the usefulness of this new scheme by showing the
reach for discovery of leptophobic $Z^\prime\to b\bar b$ and $tH^\pm\to t t b$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04294</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Starrfield</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>ASU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Iliadis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames><affiliation>UNC</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hix</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames><affiliation>ORNL</affiliation><affiliation>UTK</affiliation></author></authors><title>The Thermonuclear Runaway and the Classical Nova Outburst</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Publications of the Astronomical Society of the Pacific,
  128:051001, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1538-3873/128/963/051001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nova explosions occur on the white dwarf component of a Cataclysmic Variable
binary stellar system that is accreting matter lost by its companion. When
sufficient material has been accreted by the white dwarf, a thermonuclear
runaway occurs and ejects material in what is observed as a Classical Nova
explosion. We describe both the recent advances in our understanding of the
progress of the outburst and outline some of the puzzles that are still
outstanding. We report on the effects of improving both the nuclear reaction
rate library and including a modern nuclear reaction network in our
one-dimensional, fully implicit, hydrodynamic computer code. In addition, there
has been progress in observational studies of Supernovae Ia with implications
about the progenitors and we discuss that in this review.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-05-16</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04295</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ridder</keyname><forenames>A. Gehrmann-De</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehrmann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glover</keyname><forenames>E. W. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huss</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morgan</keyname><forenames>T. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>The NNLO QCD corrections to Z boson production at large transverse
  momentum</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>16 pages, 11 figures</comments><report-no>IPPP/16/39, NSF-KITP-16-067, ZU-TH 18/16</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transverse momentum distribution of massive neutral vector bosons can be
measured to high accuracy at hadron colliders. The transverse momentum is
caused by a partonic recoil, and is determined by QCD dynamics. We compute the
single and double-differential transverse momentum distributions for fully
inclusive $Z/\gamma^*$ production including leptonic decay to
next-to-next-to-leading order (NNLO) in perturbative QCD. We also compute the
same distributions normalised to the cross sections for inclusive $Z/\gamma^*$
production, i.e. integrated over the transverse momentum of the lepton pair. We
compare our predictions for the fiducial cross sections to the 8 TeV data set
from the ATLAS and CMS collaborations, which both observed a tension between
data and NLO theory predictions, using the experimental cuts and binning. We
find that the inclusion of the NNLO QCD effects does not fully resolve the
tension with the data for the unnormalised $p^Z_T$ distribution. However, we
observe that normalising the NNLO $Z$-boson transverse momentum distribution by
the NNLO Drell-Yan cross section substantially improves the agreement between
experimental data and theory, and opens the way for precision QCD studies of
this observable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
