<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:21:41Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-01-02" from="2016-01-01" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1105.6220</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1105.6220</id><created>2011-05-31</created><updated>2012-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>Ryokichi</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydrodynamic limit for weakly asymmetric simple exclusion processes in
  crystal lattices</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages, 7 figures</comments><msc-class>60K35, 53C21</msc-class><journal-ref>Communications in Mathematical Physics, 2012, Volume 315, Number
  3, pp 603-641</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-012-1574-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the hydrodynamic limit for weakly asymmetric simple exclusion
processes in crystal lattices. We construct a suitable scaling limit by using a
discrete harmonic map. As we shall observe, the quasi-linear parabolic equation
in the limit is defined on a flat torus and depends on both the local structure
of the crystal lattice and the discrete harmonic map. We formulate the local
ergodic theorem on the crystal lattice by introducing the notion of local
function bundle, which is a family of local functions on the configuration
space. The ideas and methods are taken from the discrete geometric analysis to
these problems. Results we obtain are extensions of ones by Kipnis, Olla and
Varadhan to crystal lattices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1109.5417</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1109.5417</id><created>2011-09-25</created><updated>2012-06-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author></authors><title>A linear program for the finite block length converse of
  Polyanskiy-Poor-Verd\'u via non-signalling codes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures, submitted to IEEE Trans. Inf. T</comments><journal-ref>Information Theory, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 58, pp. 7036-7044
  (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2012.2210695</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent work on entanglement-assisted codes for sending messages
over classical channels, the larger, easily characterised class of
non-signalling codes is defined. Analysing the optimal performance of these
codes yields an alternative proof of the finite block length converse of
Polyanskiy, Poor and Verd\'u, and shows that they achieve this converse. This
provides an explicit formulation of the converse as a linear program which has
some useful features. For discrete memoryless channels, it is shown that
non-signalling codes attain the channel capacity with zero error probability if
and only if the dispersion of the channel is zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1210.4722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1210.4722</id><created>2012-10-17</created><updated>2014-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehner</keyname><forenames>Stephanie</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite blocklength converse bounds for quantum channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures (v2: improved notation; one mistake fixed;
  results unchanged)</comments><journal-ref>Information Theory, IEEE Transactions on, vol. 60, pp. 7317-7329
  (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2014.2353614</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive upper bounds on the rate of transmission of classical information
over quantum channels by block codes with a given blocklength and error
probability, for both entanglement-assisted and unassisted codes, in terms of a
unifying framework of quantum hypothesis testing with restricted measurements.
Our bounds do not depend on any special property of the channel (such as
memorylessness) and generalise both a classical converse of Polyanskiy, Poor,
and Verd\'{u} as well as a quantum converse of Renner and Wang, and have a
number of desirable properties. In particular our bound on
entanglement-assisted codes is a semidefinite program and for memoryless
channels its large blocklength limit is the well known formula for
entanglement-assisted capacity due to Bennett, Shor, Smolin and Thapliyal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.4457</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.4457</id><created>2013-01-18</created><updated>2013-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Capossoli</keyname><forenames>Eduardo Folco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boschi-Filho</keyname><forenames>Henrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Odd spin glueball masses and the odderon Regge trajectories from the
  holographic hardwall model</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures. Text improved. References added. Results
  unchanged. This version matches the published one in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 88, 026010 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.88.026010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the holographic hardwall model to calculate the masses of light
glueball states with odd spin and P= C= -1 associated with odderons.
Considering Dirichlet and Neumann boundary conditions we obtain expressions for
the odderon Regge trajectories consistent with those calculated using other
approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.6429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.6429</id><created>2013-12-22</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moroz</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shear and bulk viscosities of the hadron gas within relaxation time
  approximation and its test</title><categories>hep-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures; the latest version of the manuscript accepted to
  Ukr. J. Phys, including new minor comments and changes</comments><journal-ref>Ukr. J. Phys. 58, 1127 (2013)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We concentrate on calculation of the shear and bulk viscosities of the hadron
gas. They define its dissipative dynamics and influence its experimentally
measurable elliptic flow. Due to difficulty of this calculation the relaxation
time approximation (RTA) was used in previous works. As those results have
approached the realistic ones, there is a need to find out how accurate the RTA
is. For this sake we calculate the viscosities in the RTA using cross sections
extracted from the ultrarelativistic quantum molecular dynamics (UrQMD) model
and compare them with the same ones calculated without the RTA. This allows us
to find the estimates of errors due to the application of RTA in the
calculations of the viscosities, which are valid also for other similar models.
For instance, in the temperature region $100 MeV \lesssim T \lesssim 160 MeV$
at zero chemical potentials the shear viscosity becomes smaller up to $1.57$
times, or up to $1.45$ times if the averaged relaxation time is used. This has
important consequences for interpretation of the previously made calculations
of the viscosities and some other related calculations. Within the RTA, we also
find estimation of the enhancement of the bulk viscosity of the hadron gas
because of nonconservation of particle numbers. This is a little more extended
version in compare to the published paper, where we were limited in paper's
size and time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.7142</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.7142</id><created>2014-06-27</created><updated>2014-09-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leung</keyname><forenames>Debbie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matthews</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author></authors><title>On the power of PPT-preserving and non-signalling codes</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>IEEE Transactions of Information Theory, 61(8): 4486-4499, 2015</journal-ref><doi>10.1109/TIT.2015.2439953</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive one-shot upper bounds for quantum noisy channel codes. We do so by
regarding a channel code as a bipartite operation with an encoder belonging to
the sender and a decoder belonging to the receiver, and imposing constraints on
the bipartite operation. We investigate the power of codes whose bipartite
operation is non-signalling from Alice to Bob, positive-partial transpose (PPT)
preserving, or both, and derive a simple semidefinite program for the
achievable entanglement fidelity. Using the semidefinite program, we show that
the non-signalling assisted quantum capacity for memoryless channels is equal
to the entanglement-assisted capacity. We also relate our PPT-preserving codes
and the PPT-preserving entanglement distillation protocols studied by Rains.
Applying these results to a concrete example, the 3-dimensional Werner-Holevo
channel, we find that codes that are non-signalling and PPT-preserving can be
strictly less powerful than codes satisfying either one of the constraints, and
therefore provide a tighter bound for unassisted codes. Furthermore,
PPT-preserving non-signalling codes can send one qubit perfectly over two uses
of the channel, which has no quantum capacity. We discuss whether this can be
interpreted as a form of superactivation of quantum capacity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3608</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3608</id><created>2014-08-15</created><updated>2015-10-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Esposito</keyname><forenames>Massimiliano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ochoa</keyname><forenames>Maicol A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galperin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>On the nature of heat in strongly coupled open quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 235440 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.235440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study heat transfers in a single level quantum dot strongly coupled to
fermionic reservoirs and subjected to a time-dependent protocol modulating the
dot energy as well as the dot-reservoir coupling strength. The dynamics is
described using nonequilibrium Greens functions (NEGFs) evaluated to first
order beyond quasi-static driving. We show that any heat definition expressed
as an energy change in the reservoir energy plus any fraction of the
system-reservoir interaction is not an exact differential when evaluated along
reversible isothermal transformations, except when that fraction is zero.
However, even in that latter case the reversible heat divided by temperature,
namely the entropy, does not satisfy the third law of thermodynamics and
diverges in the low temperature limit. Our results cast doubts on the
possibility to define a thermodynamically consistent notion of heat expressed
as the expectation value of some Hamiltonian terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.3428</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.3428</id><created>2014-11-12</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Chao-Hsi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Hui-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Guo-Li</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jin-Mei</forenames></author></authors><title>Some of semileptonic and nonleptonic decays of $B_c$ meson in a
  Bethe-Salpeter relativistic quark model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci China-Phys Mech Astron, 2015, 58: 071001</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The semileptonic decays $B_c^+\rightarrow P(V) +\ell^++\bar{\nu}_\ell$ and
the nonleptonic decays $B_c^+\rightarrow P(V)+L$, where $P(V)$ denotes a
pseudoscalar (vector) charmonium or ($\bar{b}s$)-meson, and $L$ denotes a light
meson, are studied in the framework of improved instantaneous Bethe-Salpeter
(BS) equation and the Mandelstam formula. The numerical results (width and
branching ratio of the decays) are presented in tables, and in order to compare
conveniently, those obtained by other approaches are also put in the relevant
tables. Based on the fact that the ratio
$\frac{\mathcal{BR}(B_c^+\rightarrow\psi(2S)\pi^+)}{\mathcal{BR}(B_c^+\rightarrow
J/\psi \pi^+)}=0.24^{+0.023}_{-0.040}$ estimated here is in good agreement with
the observation by the LHCb $\frac{\mathcal{BR}(B_c^+\rightarrow
\psi(2S)\pi^+)}{\mathcal{BR}(B_c^+\rightarrow J/\psi
\pi^+)}=0.250\pm0.068(\mathrm{stat})\pm0.014(\mathrm{syst})\pm0.006(\mathcal{B})$,
one may conclude that with respect to the decays the present framework works
quite well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7202</id><created>2014-11-26</created><updated>2015-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Hui-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Li-Chun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ren</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-phase equilibrium properties in charged topological dilaton AdS
  black holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss phase transition of the charged topological dilaton
AdS black holes by Maxwell equal area law. The two phases involved in the phase
transition could be coexist and we depict the coexistence region in $P-v$
diagrams. The two-phase equilibrium curves in $P-T$ diagrams are plotted, the
Clapeyron equation for the black hole is derived, and the latent heat of
isothermal phase transition is investigated. We also analyze of the parameters
of the black hole that have an effect on the two phases coexistence. The
results show that the black hole may go through a small-large phase transition
similar to those of usual non-gravity thermodynamic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02599</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02599</id><created>2015-01-12</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Duetsch</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Massive vector bosons: is the geometrical interpretation as a
  spontaneously broken gauge theory possible at all scales?</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>54 pages, some typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Rev. Math. Phys. 27 (10), (2015), 15500245</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0129055X15500245</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The usual derivation of the Lagrangian of a model for massive vector bosons,
by spontaneous symmetry breaking of a gauge theory, implies that the prefactors
of the various interaction terms are uniquely determined functions of the
coupling constant(s) and the masses. Since, under the renormalization group
(RG) flow, different interaction terms get different loop-corrections, it is
uncertain, whether these functions remain fixed under this flow. We investigate
this question for the $U(1)$-Higgs-model to 1-loop order in the framework of
Epstein-Glaser renormalization. Our main result reads: choosing the
renormalization mass scale(s) in a way corresponding to the minimal subtraction
scheme, the geometrical interpretation as a spontaneously broken gauge theory
gets lost under the RG-flow. This holds also for the clearly stronger property
of BRST-invariance of the Lagrangian. On the other hand we prove that physical
consistency, which is a weak form of BRST-invariance of the time-ordered
products, is maintained under the RG-flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.03460</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.03460</id><created>2015-01-14</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pshirkov</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Postnov</keyname><forenames>K. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gamma-ray halo around the M31 galaxy as seen by the Fermi LAT</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures. Pass 8 Reprocessed reconstruction and the 3FGL
  catalogue is used in this version of the paper</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Theories of galaxy formation predict the existence of extended gas halo
around spiral galaxies. If there are 10-100 nG magnetic fields at several ten
kpc distances from the galaxies, extended galactic cosmic ray (CR) haloes could
also exist. Galactic CRs can interact with the tenuous hot halo gas to produce
observable gamma-rays. We have performed search for a gamma-ray halo around the
M31 galaxy -- the closest large spiral galaxy. Our analysis of almost 7 years
of the Fermi LAT data revealed the presence of a spatially extended diffuse
emission excess around M31. The data can be fitted using the simplest
morphology of a uniformly bright circle. The best fit gave a 4.7$\sigma$
significance for a $0.9^{\circ}$ (12 kpc) halo with a photon flux of $\sim
(3.2\pm1.0)\times 10^{-9} ~\mathrm{cm^{-2}s^{-1}}$ and a luminosity of
$(4.0\pm1.5)\times 10^{38} ~\mathrm{erg~s^{-1}}$ in the energy range 0.3--100
GeV. Our results also imply a low level of the flux from the disc of the M31
galaxy $(3.3 \pm 1.0) \times 10^{-10}~\mathrm{cm^{-2}s^{-1}}$. The
corresponding gamma-ray luminosity, $5\times10^{37} ~\mathrm{erg~s^{-1}}$ is
several times smaller than the luminosity of the Milky Way. This difference
could be explained by a lower star formation rate in M31: there are less CRs
and the level of the ISM turbulence is lower, which in turn leads to a shorter
time of CR containment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05554</id><created>2015-02-19</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bonetti</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barausse</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author></authors><title>Post-Newtonian constraints on Lorentz-violating gravity theories with a
  MOND phenomenology</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 2 figures; includes corrections listed in erratum submitted
  to PRD (i.e. typos corrected in a few equations; results unchanged)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 91, 084053 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.084053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the post-Newtonian expansion of a class of Lorentz-violating gravity
theories that reduce to khronometric theory (i.e. the infrared limit of Horava
gravity) in high-acceleration regimes, and reproduce the phenomenology of the
modified Newtonian dynamics (MOND) in the low-acceleration, non-relativistic
limit. Like in khronometric theory, Lorentz symmetry is violated in these
theories by introducing a dynamical scalar field (the &quot;khronon&quot;) whose gradient
is enforced to be timelike. As a result, hypersurfaces of constant khronon
define a preferred foliation of the spacetime, and the khronon can be thought
of as a physical absolute time. The MOND phenomenology arises as a result of
the presence, in the action, of terms depending on the acceleration of the
congruence orthogonal to the preferred foliation. We find that if the theory is
forced to reduce exactly to General Relativity (rather than to khronometric
theory) in the high-acceleration regime, the post-Newtonian expansion breaks
down at low accelerations, and the theory becomes strongly coupled.
Nevertheless, we identify a sizeable region of the parameter space where the
post-Newtonian expansion remains perturbative for all accelerations, and the
theory passes both solar-system and pulsar gravity tests, besides producing a
MOND phenomenology for the rotation curves of galaxies. We illustrate this
explicitly with a toy model of a system containing only baryonic matter but no
Dark Matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.05342</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.05342</id><created>2015-03-18</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dominy</keyname><forenames>Jason M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lidar</keyname><forenames>Daniel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond Complete Positivity</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>9 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a general and consistent formulation for linear subsystem quantum
dynamical maps, developed from a minimal set of postulates, primary among which
is a relaxation of the usual, restrictive assumption of uncorrelated initial
system-bath states. We describe the space of possibilities admitted by this
formulation, namely that, far from being limited to only completely positive
(CP) maps, essentially any $\mathbb{C}$-linear, Hermiticity-preserving,
trace-preserving subsystem map can arise as a legitimate subsystem dynamical
map from a joint unitary evolution of a system coupled to a bath. The price
paid for this added generality is a trade-off between the set of admissible
initial states and the allowed set of joint system-bath unitary evolutions. As
an application we present a simple example of a non-CP map constructed as a
subsystem dynamical map that violates some fundamental inequalities in quantum
information theory, such as the quantum data processing inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06304</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06304</id><created>2015-04-23</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jimenez-Delgado</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hobbs</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Londergan</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melnitchouk</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reply to Comment on &quot;New limits on intrinsic charm in the nucleon from
  global analysis of parton distributions&quot;</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>2 pages, to appear in PRL</comments><report-no>JLAB-THY-15-2031</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reply to the Comment of Brodsky and Gardner on our paper &quot;New limits on
intrinsic charm in the nucleon from global analysis of parton distributions&quot;
[Phys. Rev. Lett. 114, 082002 (2015)]. We address a number of incorrect claims
made about our fitting methodology, and elaborate how global QCD analysis of
all available high-energy data provides no evidence for a large intrinsic charm
component of the nucleon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00728</id><created>2015-05-04</created><updated>2015-12-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patankar</keyname><forenames>Shreyas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hinton</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Griesmar</keyname><forenames>Joel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orenstein</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodge</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kou</keyname><forenames>Xufeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kang L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bestwick</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fox</keyname><forenames>E. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goldhaber-Gordon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shou-Cheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Resonant magneto-optic Kerr effect in the magnetic topological insulator
  Cr:(Sb$_x$,Bi$_{1-x}$)$_2$Te$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 92, 214440 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.92.214440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report measurements of the polar Kerr effect, proportional to the
out-of-plane component of the magnetization, in thin films of the magnetically
doped topological insulator
$(\text{Cr}_{0.12}\text{Bi}_{0.26}\text{Sb}_{0.62})_2\text{Te}_3$. Measurements
of the complex Kerr angle, $\Theta_K$, were performed as a function of photon
energy in the range $0.8\text{ eV}&lt;\hbar\omega&lt;3.0\text{ eV}$. We observed a
peak in the real part of $\Theta_K(\omega)$ and zero crossing in the imaginary
part that we attribute to resonant interaction with a spin-orbit avoided
crossing located $\approx$ 1.6 eV above the Fermi energy. The resonant
enhancement allows measurement of the temperature and magnetic field dependence
of $\Theta_K$ in the ultrathin film limit, $d\geq2$ quintuple layers. We find a
sharp transition to zero remanent magnetization at 6 K for $d&lt;8$~QL, consistent
with theories of the dependence of impurity spin interactions on film thickness
and their location relative to topological insulator surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.00595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.00595</id><created>2015-06-01</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barnich</keyname><forenames>Glenn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bekaert</keyname><forenames>Xavier</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigoriev</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author></authors><title>Notes on conformal invariance of gauge fields</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>38 pages</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/50/505402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Lagrangian gauge systems, the vector space of global reducibility
parameters forms a module under the Lie algebra of symmetries of the action.
Since the classification of global reducibility parameters is generically
easier than the classification of symmetries of the action, this fact can be
used to constrain the latter when knowing the former. We apply this strategy
and its generalization for the non-Lagrangian setting to the problem of
conformal symmetry of various free higher spin gauge fields. This scheme allows
one to show that, in terms of potentials, massless higher spin gauge fields in
Minkowski space and partially-massless fields in (A)dS space are not conformal
for spin strictly greater than one, while in terms of curvatures, maximal-depth
partially-massless fields in four dimensions are also not conformal, unlike the
closely related, but less constrained, maximal-depth Fradkin--Tseytlin fields.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01444</id><created>2015-06-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahajan</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum spirals</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math-ph math.MP nlin.PS physics.flu-dyn</categories><msc-class>81T28, 81T08</msc-class><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016), 055501</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/5/055501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum systems often exhibit fundamental incapability to entertain vortex.
The Meissner effect, a complete expulsion of the magnetic field (the
electromagnetic vorticity), for instance, is taken to be the defining attribute
of the superconducting state. Superfluidity is another, close-parallel example;
fluid vorticity can reside only on topological defects with a limited
(quantized) amount. Recent developments in the Bose-Einstein condensates
produced by particle traps further emphasize this characteristic. We show that
the challenge of imparting vorticity to a quantum fluid can be met through a
nonlinear mechanism operating in a hot fluid corresponding to a thermally
modified Pauli-Schroedinger spinor field. In a simple field-free model, we show
that the thermal effect, represented by a nonlinear, non-Hermitian Hamiltonian,
in conjunction with spin vorticity, leads to new interesting quantum states; a
spiral solution is explicitly worked out.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.05089</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.05089</id><created>2015-06-16</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Malsom</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinski</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Rare Events, the Thermodynamic Action and the Continuous-Time Limit</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider diffusion-like paths that are explored by a particle moving via a
conservative force while being in thermal equilibrium with its surroundings. To
probe rare transitions, we use the Onsager-Machlup (OM) functional as a path
probability distribution function for double-ended paths that are constrained
to start and stop at predesignated points after a fixed time. We explore the
continuous-time limit where the OM functional has been commonly regularized by
using the Ito-Girsanov change of measure. When used as a path measure, the
Ito-Girsanov expression generates an ensemble of double-ended paths that are
unphysical. We expose the underlying reasons why this continuous-time limit
does not, and cannot, generate a thermodynamic ensemble of paths. Furthermore,
we show that the concept of the Most Probable Path and the Thermodynamic action
are incompatible with such measures for discrete or continuous time diffusion
processes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07030</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yi-Xiang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Jinwu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>CunLin</forenames></author></authors><title>Photon Berry phases, Instantons, Schrodinger Cats with oscillating
  parities and crossover from $ U(1) $ to $ Z_2 $ limit in cavity QED systems</title><categories>physics.atom-ph cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.str-el physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, REVTEX4-1, 8 Color figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we study the $ U(1)/Z_2 $ Dicke model at a finite $ N $ by
using the $ 1/J $ expansion and exact diagonization. This model includes the
four standard quantum optics model as its various special limits. The $ 1/J $
expansions is complementary to the strong coupling expansion used by the
authors in arXiv:1512.08581 to study the same model in its dual $ Z_2/U(1) $
representation. We identify 3 regimes of the system's energy levels: the
normal, $ U(1) $ and quantum tunneling (QT) regime. The system's energy levels
are grouped into doublets which consist of scattering states and Schrodinger
Cats with even ( e ) and odd ( o ) parities in the $ U(1) $ and quantum
tunneling (QT) regime respectively. In the QT regime, by the WKB method, we
find the emergencies of bound states one by one as the interaction strength
increases, then investigate a new class of quantum tunneling processes through
the instantons between the two bound states in the compact photon phase. It is
the Berry phase interference effects in the instanton tunneling event which
leads to Schrodinger Cats oscillating with even and odd parities in both ground
and higher energy bound states. We map out the energy level evolution from the
$ U(1) $ to the QT regime and also discuss some duality relations between the
energy levels in the two regimes. We also compute the photon correlation
functions, squeezing spectrum, number correlation functions in both regimes
which can be measured by various experimental techniques. The combinations of
the results achieved here by $ 1/J $ expansion and those in arXiv:1512.08581 by
strong coupling method lead to rather complete understandings of the $ U(1)/Z_2
$ Dicke model at a finite $ N $ and any anisotropy parameter $ \beta $.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01570</id><created>2015-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Garzelli</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moch</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigl</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Lepton fluxes from atmospheric charm revisited</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>40 pages, 24 figures</comments><report-no>DESY 15-107, MITP/15-049</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1510 (2015) 115</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2015)115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We update predictions for lepton fluxes from the hadroproduction of charm
quarks in the scattering of primary cosmic rays with the Earth's atmosphere.
The calculation of charm-pair hadroproduction applies the latest results from
perturbative QCD through next-to-next-to-leading order and modern parton
distributions, together with estimates on various sources of uncertainties. Our
predictions for the lepton fluxes turn out to be compatible, within the
uncertainty band, with recent results in the literature. However, by taking
into account contributions neglected in previous works, our total uncertainties
are much larger. The predictions are crucial for the interpretation of results
from neutrino experiments like IceCube, when disentangling signals of neutrinos
of astrophysical origin from the atmospheric background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06836</id><created>2015-07-24</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arrighi</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dowek</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author></authors><title>Discrete geodesics and cellular automata</title><categories>cs.DM gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 3 figures</comments><msc-class>53C22, 68Q80, 37B15, 37N20, 83C27</msc-class><acm-class>G.1.0; F.1.1; J.2</acm-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper proposes a dynamical notion of discrete geodesics, understood as
straightest trajectories in discretized curved spacetime. The notion is
generic, as it is formulated in terms of a general deviation function, but
readily specializes to metric spaces such as discretized pseudo-riemannian
manifolds. It is effective: an algorithm for computing these geodesics
naturally follows, which allows numerical validation---as shown by computing
the perihelion shift of a Mercury-like planet. It is consistent, in the
continuum limit, with the standard notion of timelike geodesics in a
pseudo-riemannian manifold. Whether the algorithm fits within the framework of
cellular automata is discussed at length. KEYWORDS: Discrete connection,
parallel transport, general relativity, Regge calculus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06974</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06974</id><created>2015-07-24</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yeats</keyname><forenames>Karen</forenames></author></authors><title>A few $c_2$ invariants of circulant graphs</title><categories>math.CO math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, minor corrections according to referee comments</comments><msc-class>05C31, 81T18</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $c_2$ invariant is an arithmetic graph invariant introduced by Schnetz
and developed by Brown and Schnetz in order to better understand Feynman
integrals.
  This document looks at the special case where the graph in question is a
4-regular circulant graph with one vertex removed; call such a graph a
decompletion of a circulant graph. The $c_2$ invariant for the prime $2$ is
computed in the case of the decompletion of circulant graphs $C_n(1,3)$ and
$C_{2k+2}(1,k)$. For any prime $p$ and for the previous two families of
circulant graphs along with the further families $C_n(1,4)$, $C_n(1,5)$,
$C_n(1,6)$, $C_n(2,3)$, $C_n(2,4)$, $C_n(2,5)$, and $C_n(3,4)$, the same
technique gives the $c_2$ invariant of the decompletions as the solution to a
finite system of recurrence equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.00071</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.00071</id><created>2015-07-31</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aryanpour</keyname><forenames>Karan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Tirthankar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huynh</keyname><forenames>Uyen N. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vardeny</keyname><forenames>Zeev Valy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazumdar</keyname><forenames>Sumit</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of Primary Photoexcitations in Donor-Acceptor Copolymers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 4 pages of Supplemental Material including 4
  figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 115, 267401 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.115.267401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a generic theory of primary photoexcitations in low band gap
donor-acceptor conjugated copolymers. Because of the combined effects of strong
electron correlations and broken symmetry, there is considerable mixing between
a charge-transfer exciton and an energetically proximate triplet-triplet state
with an overall spin singlet. The triplet-triplet state, optically forbidden in
homopolymers, is allowed in donor-acceptor copolymers. For an intermediate
difference in electron affinities of the donor and the acceptor, the
triplet-triplet state can have stronger oscillator strength than the
charge-transfer exciton. We discuss the possibility of intramolecular singlet
fission from the triplet-triplet state, and how such fission can be detected
experimentally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.03164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.03164</id><created>2015-09-10</created><updated>2015-11-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Storey</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeippen</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sochi</keyname><forenames>Taha</forenames></author></authors><title>Collision strengths and transition probabilities for Co II infrared
  forbidden lines</title><categories>physics.atom-ph astro-ph.SR physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, 7 tables</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, Vol. 456, pp. 1974-1981, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2785</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate collision strengths and their thermally-averaged Maxwellian
values for electron excitation and de-excitation between the fifteen lowest
levels of singly-ionised cobalt, Co+, which give rise to emission lines in the
near- and mid-infrared. Transition probabilities are also calculated and
relative line intensities predicted for conditions typical of supernova ejecta.
The diagnostic potential of the 10.52, 15.46 and 14.74 micro-metre transition
lines is briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08283</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cocks</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hofstetter</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>Polaronic effects in one- and two-band quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 92, 063635 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.063635</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we study the formation and dynamics of polarons in a system with
a few impurities in a lattice immersed in a Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC).
This system has been experimentally realized using ultracold atoms and optical
lattices. Here we consider a two-band model for the impurity atoms, along with
a Bogoliubov approximation for the BEC, with phonons coupled to impurities via
both intra- and inter-band transitions. We decouple this Fr\&quot;ohlich-like term
by an extended two-band Lang-Firsov polaron transformation using a variational
method. The new effective Hamiltonian with two (polaron) bands differs from the
original Hamiltonian by modified coherent transport, polaron energy shifts and
induced long-range interaction. A Lindblad master equation approach is used to
take into account residual incoherent coupling between polaron and bath. This
polaronic treatment yields a renormalized inter-band relaxation rate compared
to Fermi's Golden Rule. For a strongly coupled two-band Fr\&quot;ohlich Hamiltonian,
the polaron is tightly dressed in each band and can not tunnel between them,
leading to an inter-band self-trapping effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08797</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08797</id><created>2015-09-29</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robilotta</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electro-weak $\pi\pi$ form factor and $\pi\pi$ scattering: towards a
  phenomenological tool</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>revised version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The weak two-pion form factor $F_V^{\pi\pi}$ is described as the product of a
weak kernel $\cal{K}_W$ by a strong function $\Theta_{\pi\pi}^P$, determined
directly from $\pi\pi$ scattering data. As the latter accounts at once for all
effects associated with resonances, intermediate $K\bar{K}$ loops, and other
possible inelasticities present in $\pi\pi$ scattering, the need of modeling is
restricted to $\cal{K}_W$ only. The procedure proposed allows one to asses the
weak kernel directly, which has a dominant cut beginning at the $K\bar{K}$
threshold. Even the simplest vector-meson-dominance choice for $\cal{K}_W$
already yields a good qualitative description of $F_V^{\pi\pi}$. The energy
sector below $0.8$ GeV is quite well reproduced when a precise theoretical
chiral perturbation $\pi\pi$ amplitude is used as input, together with the
single free parameter $F_V G_V/F^2=1.20$. The inclusion of kaon loops, along
well established lines and using few parameters, produces a good description of
the form factor in the entire energy range allowed by $\tau$ decays. This
indicates that the replacement of modeling by direct empirical scattering
information can also be useful in the construction of theoretical tools to be
used in analysesof hadronic heavy meson decay data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03372</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2015-12-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Capossoli</keyname><forenames>Eduardo Folco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boschi-Filho</keyname><forenames>Henrique</forenames></author></authors><title>Glueball spectra and Regge trajectories from a modified holographic
  softwall model</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>V.2: 14 pages. Text improved. New appendix. Results unchanged. To
  appear in PLB</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B753 (2016) 419-423</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2015.12.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we propose a modified holographic softwall model, analytically
solvable, to calculate the masses of lightest scalar glueball and its radial
excitations and of higher spin glueball states for both even and odd spins.
From these results we obtain their respective Regge trajectories, associated
with the pomeron for even spins and with the odderon for odd spins. These
results are in agreement with those calculated using other approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03490</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03490</id><created>2015-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Scheiner</keyname><forenames>Brett</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baalrud</keyname><forenames>Scott D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yee</keyname><forenames>Benjamin T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hopkins</keyname><forenames>Matthew M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnat</keyname><forenames>Edward V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of the Electron Sheath and Presheath</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4939024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron sheaths are commonly found near Langmuir probes collecting the
electron saturation current. The common assumption is that the probe collects
the random flux of electrons incident on the sheath, which tacitly implies that
there is no electron presheath and that the flux collected is due to a velocity
space truncation of the electron velocity distribution function (EVDF). This
work provides a dedicated theory of electron sheaths, which suggests that they
are not so simple. Motivated by EVDFs observed in Particle-In-Cell (PIC)
simulations, a 1D model for the electron sheath and presheath is developed. In
the model, under low temperature plasma conditions ($T_e\gg T_i$), an electron
pressure gradient accelerates electrons in the presheath to a flow velocity
that exceeds the electron thermal speed at the sheath edge. This pressure
gradient generates large flow velocities compared to what would be generated by
ballistic motion in response to the electric field. It is found that in many
situations, under common plasma conditions, the electron presheath extends much
further into the plasma than an analogous ion presheath. PIC simulations reveal
that the ion density in the electron presheath is determined by a flow around
the electron sheath and that this flow is due to 2D aspects of the sheath
geometry. Simulations also indicate the presence of ion acoustic waves excited
by the differential flow between electrons and ions in the presheath which
result in sheath edge fluctuations. The 1D model and time averaged PIC
simulations are compared and it is shown that the model provides a good
description of the electron sheath and presheath.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.05090</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.05090</id><created>2015-10-17</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>De-Hone</forenames></author></authors><title>Transformation design approach to a fermionic spacetime cage</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is concerned with the application of a spacetime structure to a
three-dimensional quantum system. There are three components. First, the main
part of this paper presents the constraint conditions which build the relation
of a spacetime structure and a form invariance solution to the covariant Dirac
equation. The second is to devise a spacetime cage for fermions with chosen
constraints. The third part discusses the feasibility of the cage with an
experiment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07624</id><created>2015-10-26</created><updated>2015-12-17</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zamudio-Bayer</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirsch</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langenberg</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawicki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terasaki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Issendorff</keyname><forenames>B. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lau</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic ground states of Fe$_2^+$ and Co$_2^+$ as determined by x-ray
  absorption and x-ray magnetic circular dichroism spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.atm-clus</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 143, 244318 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4939078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $^6\Pi$ electronic ground state of the Co$_2^+$ diatomic molecular cation
has been assigned experimentally by x-ray absorption and x-ray magnetic
circular dichroism spectroscopy in a cryogenic ion trap. Three candidates,
$^6\Phi$, $^8\Phi$, and $^8\Gamma$, for the electronic ground state of Fe$_2^+$
have been identified. These states carry sizable orbital angular momenta that
disagree with theoretical predictions from multireference configuration
interaction and density functional theory. Our results show that the ground
states of neutral and cationic diatomic molecules of $3d$ transition elements
cannot generally be assumed to be connected by a one-electron process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04236</id><created>2015-11-13</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Puneet Kumar</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional time-reversible ergodic maps with provisions for
  dissipation</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Second version of time-reversible maps, 9 pages, 10 figures, written
  for the 2015 Ian Snook prize</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new discrete time-reversible map of a unit square onto itself is proposed.
The map comprises of piecewise linear two-dimensional operations, and is able
to represent the macroscopic features of both equilibrium and nonequilibrium
dynamical systems. Our operations are analogous to sinusoidally driven shear in
the two dimensions, and a radial compression/expansion of a point lying
outside/inside a circle centered around origin. Depending upon the radius, the
map transitions from being ergodic and nondissipative (like in equilibrium
situations) to a limit cycle through intermediate multifractal situations (like
in nonequilibrium situations). All dissipative cases of the proposed map
suggest that the Kaplan -- Yorke dimension is smaller than the embedding
dimension, a feature typically arising in nonequilibrium steady-states. The
proposed map differs from the existing maps like the Baker's map and Arnold's
cat map in the sense that (i) it is reversible, and (ii) it generates an
intricate multifractal phase-space portrait.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06926</id><created>2015-11-21</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gor'kov</keyname><forenames>Lev P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kresin</keyname><forenames>V. Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Pressure and high Tc superconductivity: applications to sulfur hydrides</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages + Supplemental Materials</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rapid variation of the superconductivity Tc in hydride sulfur (H3S) under
high pressure [A. Drozdov et al, Nature 525, 73 (2015); M. Einaga et al, arXiv:
1509.03156] in a vicinity Pcr=123GPa is interpreted in terms of the 1st order
transition, possibly related to a CDW-instability with a non-zero structural
vector. The superconductivity mechanisms in high-Tc phase be discussed,
ordinary methods of calculating Tc are shown not applicable in H3S because,
beside the acoustic branches, its phonon spectrum contains hydrogen modes with
much higher frequency. A modified approach provides realistic Tc values. The
isotope effect (change of Tc at the substitution of deuterium for hydrogen)
owes its origin to the high frequency of phonons and is different in different
phases. The decrease of Tc after reaching a maximum in high-T phase is due to
the interaction with the second gap arising on a hole-like pocket. The
phonon-mediated pairing on the latter is in a non-adiabatic regime of the
frequency omega of hydrogen modes comparable to the Fermi energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07262</id><created>2015-11-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Broin</keyname><forenames>Cathal &#xd3;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolopoulos</keyname><forenames>Lampros A. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>R-Matrix incorporating Time (RMT) method for H2+ in short and intense
  laser fields</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A, 92, 2015, 063428</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.063428</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we develop an approach for a molecular hydrogen ion (H2+) in the
Born-Oppenheimer approximation while exposed to intense short-pulse radiation.
Our starting point is the R-Matrix incorporating Time (RMT) formulation for
atomic hydrogen [L. A. A. Nikolopoulos et al, Phys. Rev. A 78, 063420 (2008)]
which has proven to be successful at treating multi-electron atomic systems
efficiently and to high accuracy [L. R. Moore et al J. Mod. Opt. 58,1132,
(2011)]. The present study on H2+ has been performed with a similar objective
of developing an ab initio method for solving the Time-dependent Schr\&quot;odinger
Equation (TDSE) for multi-electron diatomic molecules exposed to an external
time-dependent potential field. The theoretical formulation is developed in
detail for the molecular hydrogen ion where all the multi-electron and
inter-nuclei complications are absent. As in the atomic case, the configuration
space of the electron's coordinates are separated artificially over two
regions; the inner (I) and outer (II) regions. In the region I the
time-dependent wavefunction is expanded on the eigenstate basis corresponding
to the molecule's Hamiltonian augmented by Bloch operators, while in region II
a grid representation is used. We demonstrate the independence of our results
on the introduced artificial boundary-surface by calculating observables that
are directly accessed experimentally and also by showing gauge-dependent
quantities are also invariant with the region I box size. We also compare with
other theoretical works and emphasize cases where basis-set approaches are
currently very computationally expensive or intractable in terms of
computational resources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00430</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00430</id><created>2015-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Voytas</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Severin</keyname><forenames>G. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement of the Branching Ratio for the Beta Decay of $^{14}$O</title><categories>nucl-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 92, 065502 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.92.065502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new measurement of the branching ratio for the decay of $^{14}$O
to the ground state of $^{14}$N. The experimental result, $\lambda _0/\lambda
_{\rm total} = (4.934 \pm 0.040\kern 1pt{\rm (stat.)} \pm 0.061\kern 1pt{\rm
(syst.)}) \times 10^{-3}$, is significantly smaller than previous
determinations of this quantity. The new measurement allows an improved
determination of the partial halflife for the superallowed $0^+ \rightarrow
0^+$ Fermi decay to the $^{14}$N first excited state, which impacts the
determination of the $V_{ud}$ element of the CKM matrix. With the new
measurement in place, the corrected $^{14}$O ${\cal F} t $ value is in good
agreement with the average ${\cal F} t $ for other superallowed $0^+
\rightarrow 0^+$ Fermi decays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01861</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01861</id><created>2015-12-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avgoustidis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhengxiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Is the Universe Transparent?</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures. Accepted for publication in PRD</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 123539 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.123539</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our study on cosmic opacity, which relates to changes in photon
number as photons travel from the source to the observer. Cosmic opacity may be
caused by absorption/scattering due to matter in the universe, or by
extragalactic magnetic fields that can turn photons into unobserved particles
(e.g. light axions, chameleons, gravitons, Kaluza-Klein modes), and it is
crucial to correctly interpret astronomical photometric measurements like type
Ia supernovae observations. On the other hand, the expansion rate at different
epochs, i.e. the observational Hubble parameter data $H(z)$, are obtained from
differential ageing of passively evolving galaxies or from baryon acoustic
oscillations and thus are not affected by cosmic opacity. In this work, we
first construct opacity-free luminosity distances from $H(z)$ determinations,
taking correlations between different redshifts into consideration for our
error analysis. Moreover, we let the light-curve fitting parameters, accounting
for distance estimation in type Ia supernovae observations, free to ensure that
our analysis is authentically cosmological-model-independent and gives a robust
result. Any non-zero residuals between these two kinds of luminosity distances
can be deemed as an indication of the existence of cosmic opacity. While a
transparent universe is currently consistent with the data, our results show
that strong constraints on opacity (and consequently on physical mechanisms
that could cause it) can be obtained in a cosmological-model-independent
fashion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03628</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>F. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuo</keyname><forenames>P. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy dissipation processes in solar wind turbulence</title><categories>physics.space-ph astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, published in Astrophysical Journal Supplement
  Series</comments><doi>10.1088/0067-0049/221/2/34</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Turbulence is a chaotic flow regime filled by irregular flows. The
dissipation of turbulence is a fundamental problem in the realm of physics.
Theoretically, dissipation cannot be ultimately achieved without collisions,
and so how turbulent kinetic energy is dissipated in the nearly collisionless
solar wind is a challenging problem. Wave particle interactions and magnetic
reconnection are two possible dissipation mechanisms, but which mechanism
dominates is still a controversial topic. Here we analyze the dissipation
region scaling around a solar wind magnetic reconnection region. We find that
the magnetic reconnection region shows a unique multifractal scaling in the
dissipation range, while the ambient solar wind turbulence reveals a
monofractal dissipation process for most of the time. These results provide the
first observational evidences for the intermittent multifractal dissipation
region scaling around a magnetic reconnection site, and they also have
significant implications for the fundamental energy dissipation process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04911</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04911</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Galich</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rudykh</keyname><forenames>Stephan</forenames></author></authors><title>Manipulating P-and S-elastic waves in dielectric elastomers via external
  electric stimuli</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate elastic wave propagation in finitely deformed dielectric
elastomers in the presence of an electrostatic field. To analyze the
propagation of both longitudinal (P-) and transverse (S-) waves, we utilize
compressible material models. We derive explicit expressions of the generalized
acoustic tensor and phase velocities of elastic waves for the ideal and
enriched dielectric elastomer models. We analyze the slowness curves of the
elastic wave propagation, and find the P-S-mode disentangling phenomenon. In
particular, P- and S- waves are separated by the application of an electric
field. The divergence angle between P- and S-waves strongly depends on the
applied electrostatic excitation. The influence of the electric field is
sensitive to material models. Thus, for ideal dielectric model the in-plane
shear velocity increases with an increase in electric field, while for the
enriched model the velocity may decreases depending on material constants.
Similarly, the divergence angle gradually increases with an increase in
electric field, while for the enriched model, the angle may be bounded.
Material compressibility affects the P-wave velocity, and, for relatively
compressible materials, the slowness curves evolve from circular to elliptical
shapes manifesting in an increase of the reflection angle of P-waves. As a
results, the divergence angle decreases with an increase in material
compressibility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05434</id><created>2015-12-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Paliathanasis</keyname><forenames>Andronikos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vakili</keyname><forenames>Babak</forenames></author></authors><title>Closed-form solutions of the Wheeler-DeWitt equation in a scalar-vector
  field cosmological model by Lie symmetries</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures; to appear in Gen. Rel. Grav</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Rel. Grav. 48, 13, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-015-2010-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply as selection rule to determine the unknown functions of a
cosmological model the existence of Lie point symmetries for the Wheeler-DeWitt
equation of quantum gravity. Our cosmological setting consists of a flat
Friedmann-Robertson-Walker metric having the scale factor $a(t)$, a scalar
field with potential function $V(\phi)$ minimally coupled to gravity and a
vector field of its kinetic energy is coupled with the scalar field by a
coupling function $f(\phi)$. Then, the Lie symmetries of this dynamical system
are investigated by utilizing the behavior of the corresponding minisuperspace
under the infinitesimal generator of the desired symmetries. It is shown that
by applying the Lie symmetry condition the form of the coupling function and
also the scalar field potential function may be explicitly determined so that
we are able to solve the Wheeler-DeWitt equation. Finally, we show how we can
use the Lie symmetries in order to construct conservation laws and exact
solutions for the field equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07111</id><created>2015-12-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Twedt</keyname><forenames>Kevin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davanco</keyname><forenames>Marcelo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Srinivasan</keyname><forenames>Kartik</forenames></author><author><keyname>McClelland</keyname><forenames>Jabez J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aksyuk</keyname><forenames>Vladimir A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Imaging Nanophotonic Modes of Microresonators using a Focused Ion Beam</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>published online in Nature Photonics</comments><journal-ref>Nature Photon. 10, 35-39 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphoton.2015.248</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical microresonators have proven powerful in a wide range of applications,
including cavity quantum electrodynamics, biosensing, microfludics, and cavity
optomechanics. Their performance depends critically on the exact distribution
of optical energy, confined and shaped by the nanoscale device geometry.
Near-field optical probes can image this distribution, but the physical probe
necessarily perturbs the near field, which is particularly problematic for
sensitive high quality factor resonances. We present a new approach to mapping
nanophotonic modes that uses a controllably small and local optomechanical
perturbation introduced by a focused lithium ion beam. An ion beam (radius
about 50 nm) induces a picometer-scale dynamic deformation of the resonator
surface, which we detect through a shift in the optical resonance wavelength.
We map five modes of a silicon microdisk resonator (Q &gt; 20,000) with both high
spatial and spectral resolution. Our technique also enables in-situ observation
of ion implantation damage and relaxation dynamics in a silicon lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08901</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Pagnanini</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battistelli</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellini</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvo</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardani</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casali</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castellano</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Colantoni</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coppolecchia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cosmelli</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cruciani</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Bernardis</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Domizio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Addabbo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Masi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomei</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vignati</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>CALDER: cryogenic light detector for rare events search</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>XVI International Workshop on Neutrino Telescopes, Venice. in
  PoS(NEUTEL2015)076</comments><journal-ref>PoS (NEUTEL 2015) 076</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The CALDER project aims at developing cryogenic light detectors with high
sensitivity to UV and visible light, to be used for particle tagging in massive
bolometers. Indeed the sensitivity of CUORE can be increased by a factor of 3,
thanks to the reduction of the $\alpha$-background, obtained by detecting the
Cherenkov light (100 eV) emitted by $\beta/\gamma$ events. Currently used light
detectors have not the features required to address this task, so we decided to
develop a new light detector using Kinetic Inductance Detector as a sensor.
This approach is very challenging and requires an intensive R$\&amp;$D to be
satisfied. The first results of this activity are shown in the following.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09140</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09140</id><created>2015-12-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Libin</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakhlov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trinca</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct Method for Calculating the Inverse Radon Transform and Its
  Applications</title><categories>physics.gen-ph physics.med-ph</categories><comments>16 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The purpose of this report is a study of the algebraic approach possibilities
to reconstruct images. This approach is reduced to solution of the large system
of linear algebraic equations. We also point out some possible further
improvements of the mathematical approaches studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09166</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Jarv</keyname><forenames>Laur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuusk</keyname><forenames>Piret</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saal</keyname><forenames>Margus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilson</keyname><forenames>Ott</forenames></author></authors><title>The formalism of invariants in scalar-tensor and multiscalar-tensor
  theories of gravitation</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages; contributed to the proceedings of the 14th Marcel Grossmann
  Meeting on General Relativity, parallel session AT1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a brief summary of the formalism of invariants in general
scalar-tensor and multiscalar-tensor gravities without derivative couplings. By
rescaling of the metric and reparametrization of the scalar fields, the theory
can be presented in different conformal frames and parametrizations. Due to
this freedom in transformations, the scalar fields themselves do not carry
independent physical meaning (in a generic parametrization). However, there are
functions of the scalar fields and their derivatives which remain invariant
under the transformations, providing a set of physical variables for the
theory. We indicate how to construct such invariants and show how the
observables like parametrized post-Newtonian parameters and characteristics of
Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker cosmology can be neatly expressed in terms
of the invariants.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09181</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09181</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Baartman</keyname><forenames>Rick</forenames></author></authors><title>Space Charge Limits in the Dae$\delta$alus DIC Compact Cyclotron</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><report-no>TRI-BN-15-15</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Dae$\delta$alus DIC compact cyclotron is proposed to achieve an extracted
current of 5 mA of singly-charged hydrogen molecules, even though unlike other
compact cyclotrons, the extraction is not by stripping. The authors of the
proposal consistently use perveance as a scaling argument that such high
current is possible. The argument is shown to be incorrect and a realistic
limit is calculated. This limit is likely about 0.2 mA and certainly no higher
than 0.5 mA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09196</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09196</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xin</keyname><forenames>Xiangpeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit solutions, conservation laws of the extended (2+1)-dimensional
  Jaulent-Miodek equation</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  By applying the direct symmetry method, the symmetry reductions and some new
group invariant solutions were obtained, We have derived some exact solutions
by using the relationship between the new solutions and the old ones, which
include Weierstrass periodic solutions, elliptic periodic solutions, triangular
function solutions and so on. Also, in order to reflect the characteristics and
properties of this solutions, we give figures of some solutions. In addition,
we give the conservation laws of the extended (2+1)-dimensional Jaulent-Miodek
equation. At last, we draw conclusions and discuss it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09202</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09202</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Arnab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Manimala</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borah</keyname><forenames>Debasish</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimal Left-Right Symmetry Confronted with the 750 GeV Di-photon Excess
  at LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent results of 13 TeV ATLAS and CMS di-photon searches show an excess
at di-photon invariant mass of 750 GeV. We look for possible explanation of
this within minimal left right symmetric model (MLRSM). The possible candidate
is a neutral Higgs of mass 750 GeV that can decay to di-photon via charged
Higgs and right handed gauge boson loop. However, the cross-section is not
consistent with the ATLAS and CMS results. We then discuss one possible
variation of this model with universal seesaw for fermion masses that can
explain this excess.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09203</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guskov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author></authors><title>Charmed hadron photoproduction at COMPASS</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Proceedings of the Second International Symposium on Physics of
  Photons (ISPP 15), Lanzhou, China, July 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photoproduction of the charmonium-like state $Z_{c}(4200)$ and the charmed
baryon $\Lambda_{c}^{\ast }(2940)$ is investigated with an effective Lagrangian
approach and the Regge trajectories applying to the COMPASS experiment.
Combining the experimental data from COMPASS and our theoretical model we
estimate the upper limit of $\Gamma_{Z_{c}(4200)\rightarrow J/\psi \pi }$ to be
of about 37 MeV. Moreover, the possibility to produce $\Lambda_{c}^{\ast
}(2940)$ at COMPASS is discussed. It seems one can try to search for this
hadron in the missing mass spectrum since the $t$-channel is dominating for the
$\Lambda_{c}^{\ast }(2940)$ photoproduction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09221</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09221</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zi-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Jian-Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>A model of eternal accelerated expansion without particle horizon</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our previous paper \cite{8}, we proposed a cosmological model from the
emergence of space, which possesses a significant character of evaluating the
vacuum energy from the Hubble constant and the age of universe. And one problem
of this model is that there is no inflation in the early universe. In this
paper, we aim at resolving this problem which leads us to a rather surprising
conclusion that our cosmological model can avoid the horizon and flatness
problems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09242</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09242</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Thamali</keyname><forenames>R. J. K. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumbalatara</keyname><forenames>A. A. K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liyanage</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ukwatta</keyname><forenames>Ajith</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hewage</keyname><forenames>Jinasena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Witharana</keyname><forenames>Sanjeeva</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling and Understanding of Highly Energy Efficient Fluids</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Transactions of the Institution of Engineers Sri Lanka, Vol 1- Part B</comments><doi>10.13140/RG.2.1.4324.7449</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conventional heat carrier liquids have demonstrated remarkable enhancement in
heat and mass transfer when nanoparticles were suspended in them. These
liquid-nanoparticle suspensions are now known as Nanofluids. However the
relationship between nanoparticles and the degree of enhancement is still
unclear, thus hindering the large scale manufacturing of them. Understanding of
the energy and flow behaviour of nanofluids is therefore of wide interest in
both academic and industrial context. In this paper we first model the heat
transfer of a nanofluid in convection in a circular tube at macro-scale by
using CFD code of OpenFoam. Then we zoon into nano-scale behaviour using the
Molecular Dynamics (MD) simulation. In the latter we considered a system of
water and Gold nanoparticles. A systematic increase of convective heat transfer
was observed with increasing nanoparticle concentration. A maximum enhancement
of 7.0% was achieved in comparison to base fluid water. This occurred when the
gold volume fraction was 0.015. Subsequent MD simulations confirmed a dense
water layer formed 2nm away from the gold nanoparticle boundary. It is
speculated that the observed increase in thermal conductivity was principly
caused by this dense water layer formed around each nanoparticle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09243</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Mehraban</keyname><forenames>Saeed</forenames></author></authors><title>Computational Complexity of Some Quantum Theories in $1+1$ Dimensions</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CC</categories><comments>The material presented here is based on the author's Master's thesis,
  advised by Scott Aaronson, submitted to the department of electrical
  engineering and computer science at MIT on August 28, 2015. Editions and
  modifications has been made to the original thesis, also a new chapter,
  chapter 4 is added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the computational complexity of certain integrable quantum theories
in 1+1 dimensions. We formalize a model of quantum computation based on these
theories. In this model, distinguishable particles start out with known momenta
and initial superposition of different configurations. Then the label of these
particles are measured at the end. We prove that additive approximation to
single amplitudes of these models can be obtained by the one-clean-qubit model,
if no initial superpositions are allowed. However, if arbitrary initial states
and non-adaptive intermediate measurements are allowed, we show that
conditioned on infinite polynomial hierarchy assumption it is hard to sample
from the output distribution of these models on a classical randomized
computer. A classical analogue of this model is also formalized and its
computational power is pinned down within the complexity classes below BPP and
NP.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09246</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Jun-Kui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wu-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Wei-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>You-Wu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zong-Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Mao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pang</keyname><forenames>Cheng-Guo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Chong</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron Dose measurement in the carbon ion therapy area at HIRFL (IMP)
  as 12C ions with energies from 165 to 350MeV/u</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.ins-det</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The neutron dose distributions on observation distances and on observation
angles were measured using a Wendi-II neutron dose-meter at the deep tumor
therapy terminal at HIRFL (Heavy Ion Research Facility in Lanzhou) as 12C ions
with energies from 165 to 350 MeV/u bombarding on thick solid water targets
with different thickness according to the ion energies. The experimental
results were compared with those calculated by FLUKA code. It is found that the
experimental data was in good agreement with the calculated results. The
neutron energy spectra were also studied by using the FLUKA code. The results
are valuable for the shielding design of high energy heavy ion medical machines
and for the individual dose assessment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09256</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09256</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Lazariev</keyname><forenames>Andrii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arroyo-Camejo</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rahane</keyname><forenames>Ganesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavatamane</keyname><forenames>Vinaya Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balasubramanian</keyname><forenames>Gopalakrishnan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical sensitivity control of a single-spin quantum sensor</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Nitrogen-Vacancy (NV) defect in diamond is a unique quantum system that
offers precision sensing of nanoscale physical quantities beyond the current
state-of-the-art. Here we present a method to controllably encode the
interactions in the population of the spin states, thereby introducing a way to
control the sensitivity of a single spin as a continuum in contrast to
free-evolution based methods. By adopting this feature we demonstrate
high-accuracy NV magnetometry without 2pi ambiguities, enhance the dynamic
range by a factor of 4*10^3 achieve interaction times exceeding 2 ms in
off-the-shelf diamond. We perform nuclear spin-noise spectroscopy in the
frequency domain by dynamically controlling the NV spin's sensitivity piecewise
and in a smooth manner thereby precluding harmonic artefacts and undesired
interactions. On a broader perspective dynamical sensitivity control provides
an elegant handle on the inherent dynamics of quantum systems, while offering
decisive advantages for NV centre applications notably in quantum controls and
single molecule NMR/MRI.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09259</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Dimitrijevic</keyname><forenames>Dragoljub D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Djordjevic</keyname><forenames>Goran S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milosevic</keyname><forenames>Milan</forenames></author></authors><title>Classicalization and Quantization of Tachyon-like Matter on
  (non)Archimedean Spaces</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><journal-ref>Romanian Reports in Physics, Volume 68, Number 1, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a class of tachyon-like potentials, inspired by string theory,
D-brane dynamics and cosmology in the context of classical and quantum
mechanics. Motivated by the trans-Plankcian problem in the very early stage of
cosmological evolution of the Universe, we consider the theoretical role of
DBI-type tachyon scalar field, defined over the field of real as well as
$p$-adic numbers, i.e. archemedean and nonarchimedean spaces. To simplify the
equation of motion for the scalar field, canonical transformations are defined
and engaged. The corresponding quantum propagators in the Feynman path integral
approach on real and nonarchimedean spaces are calculated and discussed, as are
possibilities for a quantum adelic generalization and its application.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09265</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>Francis</forenames></author></authors><title>Periods and Feynman amplitudes</title><categories>math-ph hep-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Talk given at the ICMP, Santiago de Chile, July 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Feynman amplitudes in perturbation theory form the basis for most predictions
in particle collider experiments. The mathematical quantities which occur as
amplitudes include values of the Riemann zeta function and relate to
fundamental objects in number theory and algebraic geometry. This talk reviews
some of the recent developments in this field, and explains how new ideas from
algebraic geometry have led to much progress in our understanding of
amplitudes. In particular, the idea that certain transcendental numbers, such
as $\pi$, can be viewed as a representation of a group, provides a powerful
framework to study amplitudes which reveals many hidden structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09269</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09269</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Liangyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Zhenqiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Guangcan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Zhengfu</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurement-Device-Independent Quantum Coin Tossing</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Close to the published version</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review A 92, 062327(2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.92.062327</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum coin tossing (QCT) is an important primitive of quantum cryptography
and has received continuous interest. However, in practical QCT, Bob's
detectors can be subjected to detector-side channel attacks launched by
dishonest Alice, which will possibly make the protocol completely insecure.
Here, we report a simple strategy of a detector-blinding attack based on a
recent experiment. To remove all the detector side channels, we present a
solution of measurement-device-independent QCT (MDI-QCT). This method is
similar to the idea of MDI quantum key distribution (QKD). MDI-QCT is loss
tolerant with single-photon sources and has the same bias as the original
loss-tolerant QCT under a coherent attack. Moreover, it provides the potential
advantage of doubling the secure distance for some special cases. Finally,
MDI-QCT can also be modified to fit the weak coherent-state sources. Thus,
based on the rapid development of practical MDI-QKD, our proposal can be
implemented easily.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09270</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09270</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Maghrabi</keyname><forenames>Abdullrahnan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Enizy</keyname><forenames>Mohammed Al</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aldosari</keyname><forenames>A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Almuteri</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author></authors><title>A Small Multi-Wire Telescope for High Energy Cosmic Ray Muon Detection</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages; 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Different types of ground-based detectors have been developed and deployed
around the world to monitor and study CR variations. We have designed,
constructed and operated a three layer small (20x20 cm2) multiwire proportional
chamber MWPC telescope for cosmic ray muon observations. In this paper, the
technical aspects of this detector will be briefly discussed. The abilities of
the telescope in detecting high nergy cosmic ray muons (primaries higher than
20 GeV) were established. The telescope performs well in this sense and showed
comparable results with a 1 m2 scintillator detector.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09283</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09283</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Sogami</keyname><forenames>Ikuo S.</forenames><affiliation>Department of Physics, Kyoto Sangyo University and Yukawa Institute of Theoretical Physics, Kyoto University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Unified description of quarks and leptons in a multi-spinor field
  formalism</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>to appear in Proceedings of the 18th Bled Workshop &quot;What Comes Beyond
  Standard Models&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multi-spinor fields which behave as triple-tensor products of the Dirac
spinors and form reducible representations of the Lorentz group describe three
families of ordinary quarks and leptons in the visible sector and an additional
family of exotic dark quarks and leptons in the dark sector of the Universe.
Apart from the ordinary set of the gauge and Higgs fields in the visible
sector, another set of gauge and Higgs fields belonging to the dark sector are
assumed to exist. Two sectors possess channels of communication through gravity
and a bi-quadratic interaction between the two types of Higgs fields. A
candidate for the main component of the dark matter is a stable dark hadron
with spin 3/2, and the upper limit of its mass is estimated to be 15.1
GeV/c$^2$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09284</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09284</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Bediaga</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magalh&#xe3;es</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Final state interaction on $B^+ \to \pi^-\pi^+\pi^+$</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The large localized CP asymmetries observed by LHCb in three-body charmless
decays of $B$ mesons brings new challenge for experimentalists and their
traditional models to fit data. With higher statistics, rescattering and
three-body effects, previously ignored on data analysis, become more visible.
The time is ripe to use better theoretical assumptions as an ingredient in
order to improve the analysis. In this paper we address the issue of
rescattering effects in the charmless three-body decays of $B$ mesons. In
particular, we study the case of the $B^+ \to \pi^-\pi^+\pi^+$ decay and show
that the presence of hadronic loops shifts the P-wave phase near threshold to
below zero, and modify the position of the $\rho$-meson peak and it width, in
the Dalitz plot.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09309</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09309</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>J&#xf8;rgen Ellegaard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chekhov</keyname><forenames>Leonid O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norbury</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Penner</keyname><forenames>Robert C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological recursion for Gaussian means and cohomological field
  theories</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.AG math.GT math.MP</categories><comments>32 pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1501.05867</comments><msc-class>05A15 (Primary), 14N10, 32G15 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Theor. Math. Phys. Vol 185(3) (2015) 1685-1717</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the explicit relation between genus filtrated $s$-loop means of the
Gaussian matrix model and terms of the genus expansion of the
Kontsevich--Penner matrix model (KPMM), which is the generating function for
volumes of discretized (open) moduli spaces $M_{g,s}^{disc}$ (discrete
volumes), to express Gaussian means in all genera as polynomials in special
times weighted by ancestor invariants of an underlying cohomological field
theory. We translate topological recursion of the Gaussian model into recurrent
relations for coefficients of this expansion proving their integrality and
positivity. As an application, we find the coefficients in the first subleading
order for ${\mathcal M}_{g,1}$ for all $g$ in three ways: by using the refined
Harer--Zagier recursion, by exploiting the Givental-type decomposition of KPMM,
and by an explicit diagram counting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09322</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Pietrzyk</keyname><forenames>Monika E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanattsikov</keyname><forenames>Igor V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized Short Pulse Equation for Propagation of Few-Cycle Pulses in
  Metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that propagation of ultrashort (few-cycle) pulses in nonlinear Drude
metamaterials with both electric and magnetic Kerr nonlinearities is described
by coupled generalized Short Pulse Equations. The resulting system of equations
generalizes to the case of metamaterials both the Short Pulse Equation and its
vector generalizations which describe the few-cycle pulses in dielectric
optical fibers beyond the slowly varying envelope approximation leading to the
nonlinear Schroedinger equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09323</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09323</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Nikolova</keyname><forenames>Dessislava</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calhoun</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rumley</keyname><forenames>Sebastien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novack</keyname><forenames>Ari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baehr-Jones</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hochberg</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergman</keyname><forenames>Keren</forenames></author></authors><title>A highly scalable fully non-blocking silicon photonic switch fabric</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>25 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large port count spatial optical switches will facilitate flexible and energy
efficient data movement in future data communications systems, especially if
they are capable of nanosecond-order reconfiguration times. In this work, we
demonstrate an 8x8 microring-based silicon photonic switch with software
controlled switching. The proposed switch architecture is modular as it
assembles multiple identical components with multiplexing/demultiplexing
functionalities. The switch is fully non-blocking, has path independent
insertion loss, low crosstalk and is straightforward to control. A scalability
analysis shows that this architecture can scale to very large port counts. This
work represents the first demonstration of real-time firmware controlled
switching with silicon photonics devices integrated at the chip scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09326</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Fern&#xe1;ndez</keyname><forenames>Francisco M.</forenames></author></authors><title>On two exactly-solvable one-dimensional Hamiltonians with PT symmetry</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide an explanation to the behaviour of the spectra of two
exactly-solvable one-dimensional Hamiltonians with PT symmetry proposed
earlier. We calculate the branch points at which pairs of eigenvalues coalesce
and discuss the perturbation series.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09337</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09337</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Ryabov</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sokolov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kharlamova</keyname><forenames>Irina</forenames></author></authors><title>Explicit determination of certain periodic motions of a generalized
  two-field gyrostat</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>13 pages, 2 figures</comments><msc-class>70E17, 70G40, 70H06, 70E40</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The case of motion of a generalized two-field gyrostat found by V.V.Sokolov
and A.V.Tsiganov is known as a Liouville integrable Hamiltonian system with
three degrees of freedom. We find a set of points at which the momentum map has
rank 1. This set consists of special periodic motions which correspond to the
singular points of a bifurcation diagram on an iso-energetic surface. For such
motions the phase variables can be expressed in terms of algebraic functions of
a single auxiliary variable. These algebraic functions satisfy a differential
equation integrable in elliptic functions of time. It is shown that the
corresponding points in the three-dimensional space of the constants of the
integrals belong to the intersection of two sheets of the discriminant surface
of the Lax curve.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09355</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Pocanic</keyname><forenames>Dinko</forenames><affiliation>PEN Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Allowed rare pion and muon decays as tests of the Standard Model</title><categories>nucl-ex hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures, to appear in the proceedings of NuFact15, XVIIth
  International Workshop on Neutrino Factories and Future Neutrino Facilities,
  Centro Brasileiro de Pesquisas F\'isicas, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, 10-15
  August 2015</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Simple dynamics, few available decay channels, and extremely well controlled
radiative and loop corrections, make pion and muon decays a sensitive means for
testing the underlying symmetries, the universality of weak fermion couplings,
as well as for study of pion structure and chiral dynamics. We review the
current state of experimental study of the allowed rare decays of charged
pions: (a) electronic, $\pi^+ \to e^+\nu_e$, or $\pi_{e2}$, (b) radiative,
$\pi^+ \to e^+\nu_e\gamma$, or $\pi_{e2\gamma}$, and (c) semileptonic,
$\pi^+\to \pi^0 e^+ \nu$, or $\pi_{e3}$, as well as muon radiative decay,
$\mu^+\to e^+ \nu_{\text{e}}\bar{\nu}_{\mu}\gamma$. Taken together, these data
present an internally consistent picture that also agrees well with Standard
Model (SM) predictions. However, even following the great strides of the recent
decades, experimental accuracy is lagging far behind that of the theoretical
description for all above processes. We review the implications of the present
state of knowledge and prospects for further improvement in the near term.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09365</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Poplawski</keyname><forenames>Nikodem J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetization of scalar field by torsion</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>3 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a scalar field without a kinetic term in the Lagrangian density,
coupled to a covariant divergence of the torsion vector in the Einstein-Cartan
theory of gravity, becomes kinetic in its general-relativistic equivalent
formulation. Dynamical scalar fields may therefore be emergent.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09366</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09366</id><created>2015-12-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Turek</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author></authors><title>On quantum graph filters with flat passbands</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>81Q35, 81Q93, 81U40, 81U15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine transmission through a quantum graph vertex to which auxiliary
edges with constant potentials are attached. We find a characterization of
vertex couplings for which the transmission probability from a given &quot;input&quot;
line to a given &quot;output&quot; line shows a flat passband. The bandwidth is
controlled directly by the potential on the auxiliary edges. Vertices with such
couplings can thus serve as controllable band-pass filters. The paper extends
earlier works on the topic. The result also demonstrates the effectivity of the
$ST$-form of boundary conditions for a study of scattering in quantum graph
vertices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09372</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manz</keyname><forenames>Thomas A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Computationally Designed Zirconium Organometallic Catalyst for Direct
  Epoxidation of Alkenes without Allylic H Atoms: Aromatic Linkage Eliminates
  Formation of Inert Octahedral Complexes</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>41 pages, 16 figures, 6 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We used density functional theory to computationally design a Zr
organometallic catalyst for selectively oxidizing substrates using molecular
oxygen as oxidant without coreductant. Each selective oxidation cycle involves
four general steps: (a) a peroxo or weakly adsorbed O2 group releases an O atom
to substrate to form substrate oxide and an oxo group, (b) an oxygen molecule
adds to the oxo group to generate an eta2-ozone group, (c) the eta2-ozone group
rearranges to form an eta3-ozone group, and (d) the eta3-ozone group releases
an O atom to substrate to form substrate oxide and regenerate the peroxo or
weakly adsorbed O2 group. This catalyst could potentially be synthesized via
the condensation reaction Zr(N(R)R')4 + 2
C6H4-1,6-(N(C6H3-2',6'-(CH(CH3)2)2)OH)2 --&gt;
Zr(C6H4-1,6-(N(C6H3-2',6'-(CH(CH3)2)2)O)2)2 [aka Zr_Benzol catalyst] + 4
N(R)(R')H where R and R' are CH3, CH2CH3, or other alkyl groups. For direct
ethylene epoxidation, the computed enthalpic energetic span (i.e., effective
activation energy for the entire catalytic cycle) is 27.1 kcal/mol, which is
one of the lowest values for catalysts studied to date. We study reaction
mechanisms and the stability of different catalyst forms as a function of the
oxygen atom chemical potential. Notably, an aromatic linkage in each ligand
prevents this catalyst from deactivating to form an inactive octahedral-like
structure that contains the same atoms as the dioxo complex, Zr(Ligand)2(O)2.
Due to a side reaction that can transfer an allylic H atom from alkene to
catalyst, this catalyst is useful for directly epoxidizing alkenes such as
ethylene that do not contain allylic H atoms. To better understand the reaction
chemistry, we computed net atomic charges and bond orders for the two
catalytically relevant reaction cycles. These results quantify electron
transfer and bond forming and breaking during the catalytic process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09373</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09373</id><created>2015-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Skordas</keyname><forenames>Efthimios S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk moduli of PbS$_{x}$Se$_{1-x}$, PbS$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$ and
  PbSe$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$ from a thermodynamical model compared to generalized
  gradient approximation approach</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>16 pages, 1 figure, 3 tables. It has been accepted for publication in
  Materials Science in Semiconductor Processing</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Very recently, first-principle technique of full-potential linearized
augmented plane-wave method, by using for exchange-correlation potential the
generalized gradient approximation (GGA), was employed for the study of the
lead chalcogenide semiconductors' alloys PbS$_{x}$Se$_{1-x}$,
PbS$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$ and PbSe$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$. These density functional
calculations led to the determination of structural, electronic and optical
properties, including the values of lattice constants and bulk moduli as a
function of composition. Here, we investigate the latter properties, but by
employing a thermodynamical model which has been suggested for the formation
and migration of defects in solids including several recent applications in
semiconductors. The following crucial difference emerges when comparing the
present results with those deduced by density functional calculations: Among
the alloys studied, GGA calculations identify that PbS$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$ exhibits
the most evident non-linear variation of the bulk modulus versus the
composition, while according to the thermodynamical model such an evident
non-linear behavior -and maybe somewhat stronger- is also expected for
PbSe$_{x}$Te$_{1-x}$. A tentative origin of this diversity is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0202214</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0202214</id><created>2002-02-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong-Hoon</forenames><affiliation>Theoretische Chemie, TU Muenchen</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Staedele</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames><affiliation>Infineon Technologies AG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Goerling</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames><affiliation>Theoretische Chemie, TU Muenchen</affiliation></author></authors><title>Optical excitations of Si by time-dependent density-functional theory
  based on the exact-exchange Kohn-Sham band structure</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures; contribution to &quot;DFT 2001&quot;, Sep. 10-14, San
  Lorenzo de El Escorial, Spain; to be published in Int. J. Quantum. Chem</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Quantum Chem. 91, 257-262 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/qua.10411</doi><abstract>  We calculate the imaginary part of the frequency-dependent dielectric
function of bulk silicon by applying time-dependent density-functional theory
based on the exact-exchange (EXX) Kohn-Sham (KS) band structure and the
adiabatic local-density approximation (ALDA) kernel. The position of the E2
absorption peak calculated with the EXX band structure at the
independent-particle level is in excellent agreement with experiments, which
demonstrates the good quality of EXX `KS quasiparticles'. The excitonic E1 peak
that is missing at the independent-particle level remains absent if
two-particle interaction effects are taken into account within the
time-dependent LDA, demonstrating the incapability of the ALDA kernel to
describe excitonic effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0208093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0208093</id><created>2002-08-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goerling</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitonic optical spectrum of semiconductors obtained by time-dependent
  density-functional theory with the exact-exchange kernel</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. 4-page version will be published in Phys. Rev.
  Lett</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 89, 096402 (2002)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.89.096402</doi><abstract>  Applying the novel exact-exchange (EXX) Kohn-Sham method within
time-dependent density-functional theory, we obtained the optical absorption
spectrum of bulk silicon in good agreement with experiments including excitonic
features. Analysis of the EXX kernel shows that inclusion of the Coulomb
coupling of electron-hole pairs and the correct long-wavelength behavior in the
kernel is crucial for the proper description of excitonic effects in
semiconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/9911030</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/9911030</id><created>1999-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>In-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Richard</forenames></author></authors><title>One-way multigrid method in electronic structure calculations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures, to appear in Phys. Rev. B, Rapid Communications</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 61, 4397-4400 (2000)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.61.4397</doi><abstract>  We propose a simple and efficient one-way multigrid method for
self-consistent electronic structure calculations based on iterative
diagonalization. Total energy calculations are performed on several different
levels of grids starting from the coarsest grid, with wave functions
transferred to each finer level. The only changes compared to a single grid
calculation are interpolation and orthonormalization steps outside the original
total energy calculation and required only for transferring between grids. This
feature results in a minimal amount of code change, and enables us to employ a
sophisticated interpolation method and noninteger ratio of grid spacings.
Calculations employing a preconditioned conjugate gradient method are presented
for two examples, a quantum dot and a charged molecular system. Use of three
grid levels with grid spacings 2h, 1.5h, and h decreases the computer time by
about a factor of 5 compared to single level calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/9911031</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-01</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/9911031</id><created>1999-11-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Yong-Hoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>In-Ho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Richard M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Object-oriented construction of a multigrid electronic-structure code
  with Fortran 90</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>24 pages, 6 figures, to appear in Comput. Phys. Comm</comments><journal-ref>Comput. Phys. Commun. 131, 10-25 (2000)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/S0010-4655(00)00056-4</doi><abstract>  We describe the object-oriented implementation of a higher-order
finite-difference density-functional code in Fortran 90. Object-oriented models
of grid and related objects are constructed and employed for the implementation
of an efficient one-way multigrid method we have recently proposed for the
density-functional electronic-structure calculations. Detailed analysis of
performance and strategy of the one-way multigrid scheme will be presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
