<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T21:22:01Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-01-04" from="2016-01-03" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04386</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04386</id><created>2015-06-14</created><updated>2015-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grothaus</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stilgenbauer</keyname><forenames>Patrik</forenames></author></authors><title>A hypocoercivity related ergodicity method with rate of convergence for
  singularly distorted degenerate Kolmogorov equations and applications</title><categories>math.FA math-ph math.AP math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>Older preprint version of the paper (from 2014). The final
  publication is available at Springer via
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00020-015-2254-1 It was published under the name
  &quot;A hypocoercivity related ergodicity method for singularly distorted
  non-symmetric diffusions&quot;; see Integral Equations Oper. Theory 83, No. 3,
  Article ID 2254, 331-379 (2015)</comments><msc-class>37A25, 58J65</msc-class><journal-ref>Integral Equations Oper. Theory 83, No. 3, Article ID 2254,
  331-379 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00020-015-2254-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we develop a new abstract strategy for proving ergodicity
with explicit computable rate of convergence for diffusions associated with a
degenerate Kolmogorov operator L. A crucial point is that the evolution
operator L may have singular and nonsmooth coefficients. This allows the
application of the method e.g. to degenerate and singular particle systems
arising in Mathematical Physics. As far as we know in such singular cases the
relaxation to equilibrium can't be discussed with the help of existing
approaches using hypoellipticity, hypocoercivity or stochastic Lyapunov type
techniques. The method is formulated in an L2-Hilbert space setting and is
based on an interplay between Functional Analysis and Stochastics. Moreover, it
implies an ergodicity rate which can be related to L2-exponential convergence
of the semigroup. Furthermore, the ergodicity method shows up an interesting
analogy with existing hypocoercivity approaches. In the first application we
discuss ergodicity of the N-particle degenerate Langevin dynamics with singular
potentials. The dual to this equation is also called the kinetic Fokker-Planck
equation with an external confining potential. In the second example we apply
the method to the so-called (degenerate) spherical velocity Langevin equation
which is also known as the fiber lay-down process arising in industrial
mathematics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07129</id><created>2015-11-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Baier</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stricker</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on Hawking radiation and trapping horizons</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider dynamical black hole formation from a collapsing fluid described
by a symmetric and flat FRW metric. Using the Hamilton-Jacobi method the local
Hawking temperature for the formed trapping/apparent horizon is calculated. The
local Hawking temperature depends on the tunneling path, which we take to be
along a null direction $(\Delta s=0)$. We find that the local Hawking
temperature depends directly on the equation of state of the collapsing fluid.
We argue that Hawking radiation by quantum tunnelling from future inner and
future outer trapping horizons is possible. However, only radiation from a
space-like dynamical horizon has a chance to be observed by an external
observer. Some comparison to existing literature is made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-04</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02855</id><created>2015-12-09</created><updated>2015-12-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tavassoli</keyname><forenames>Arash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Montakhab</keyname><forenames>Afshin</forenames></author></authors><title>Microcanonical entropy: consistency and adiabatic invariance</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages and one figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Attempts to establish microcanonical entropy as an adiabatic invariant date
back to works of Gibbs and Hertz. More recently, a consistency relation based
on adiabatic invariance has been used to argue for the validity of Gibbs
(volume) entropy over Boltzmann (surface) entropy. Such consistency relation
equates derivatives of thermodynamic entropy to ensemble average of the
corresponding quantity in micro-state space (phase space or Hilbert space). In
this work we propose to re-examine such a consistency relation when the number
of particles ($N$) is considered as the independent thermodynamic variable. In
other words, we investigate the consistency relation for the chemical potential
which is a fundamental thermodynamic quantity. We show both by simple
analytical calculations as well as model example that neither definitions of
entropy satisfy the consistency condition when one considers such a relation
for the chemical potential. This remains true regardless of the system size.
Therefore, our results cast doubt on the validity of the adiabatic invariance
as a required property of thermodynamic entropy. We close by providing
commentary on the derivation of thermostatistics from mechanics which typically
leads to controversial and inconsistent results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-01-03</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08042</id><created>2015-12-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Di Staso</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clercx</keyname><forenames>H. J. H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Succi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toschi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>DSMC-LBM mapping scheme for rarefied and non-rarefied gas flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Submitted to Journal of Computational Science</comments><msc-class>76P05, 82B80, 82B40</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the formulation of a kinetic mapping scheme between the Direct
Simulation Monte Carlo (DSMC) and the Lattice Boltzmann Method (LBM) which is
at the basis of the hybrid model used to couple the two methods in view of
efficiently and accurately simulate isothermal flows characterized by variable
rarefaction effects. Owing to the kinetic nature of the LBM, the procedure we
propose ensures to accurately couple DSMC and LBM at a larger Kn number than
usually done in traditional hybrid DSMC-Navier-Stokes equation models. We show
the main steps of the mapping algorithm and illustrate details of the
implementation. Good agreement is found between the moments of the single
particle distribution function as obtained from the mapping scheme and from
independent LBM or DSMC simulations at the grid nodes where the coupling is
imposed. We also show results on the application of the hybrid scheme based on
a simpler mapping scheme for plane Poiseuille flow at finite Kn number.
Potential gains in the computational efficiency assured by the application of
the coupling scheme are estimated for the same flow.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
