<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:48:26Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-15" from="2016-12-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0712.4050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0712.4050</id><created>2007-12-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Shinzato</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabashima</keyname><forenames>Yoshiyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Perceptron capacity revisited: classification ability for correlated
  patterns</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/41/32/324013</doi><abstract>  In this paper, we address the problem of how many randomly labeled patterns
can be correctly classified by a single-layer perceptron when the patterns are
correlated with each other. In order to solve this problem, two analytical
schemes are developed based on the replica method and Thouless-Anderson-Palmer
(TAP) approach by utilizing an integral formula concerning random rectangular
matrices. The validity and relevance of the developed methodologies are shown
for one known result and two example problems. A message-passing algorithm to
perform the TAP scheme is also presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0806.2310</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0806.2310</id><created>2008-06-13</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bergshoeff</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chemissany</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ploegh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trigiante</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Riet</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generating Geodesic Flows and Supergravity Solutions</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>Fixed a typo in table 3, page 27, results unchanged</comments><journal-ref>Nucl.Phys.B812:343-401,2009</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nuclphysb.2008.10.023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the geodesic motion on the symmetric moduli spaces that arise
after timelike and spacelike reductions of supergravity theories. The geodesics
correspond to timelike respectively spacelike $p$-brane solutions when they are
lifted over a $p$-dimensional flat space. In particular, we consider the
problem of constructing \emph{the minimal generating solution}: A geodesic with
the minimal number of free parameters such that all other geodesics are
generated through isometries. We give an intrinsic characterization of this
solution in a wide class of orbits for various supergravities in different
dimensions. We apply our method to three cases: (i) Einstein vacuum solutions,
(ii) extreme and non-extreme D=4 black holes in N=8 supergravity and their
relation to N=2 STU black holes and (iii) Euclidean wormholes in $D\geq 3$. In
case (iii) we present an easy and general criterium for the existence of
regular wormholes for a given scalar coset.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0809.1978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0809.1978</id><created>2008-09-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shinzato</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabashima</keyname><forenames>Yoshiyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Learning of correlated patterns by simple perceptrons</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/42/1/015005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Learning behavior of simple perceptrons is analyzed for a teacher-student
scenario in which output labels are provided by a teacher network for a set of
possibly correlated input patterns, and such that teacher and student networks
are of the same type. Our main concern is the effect of statistical
correlations among the input patterns on learning performance. For this
purpose, we extend to the teacher-student scenario a methodology for analyzing
randomly labeled patterns recently developed in {\em J. Phys. A: Math. Theor.}
{\bf 41}, 324013 (2008). This methodology is used for analyzing situations in
which orthogonality of the input patterns is enhanced in order to optimize the
learning performance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0811.3341</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0811.3341</id><created>2008-11-20</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Berman</keyname><forenames>Robert J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Determinantal point processes and fermions on complex manifolds: Bulk
  universality</title><categories>math.CV math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2: Substantial revision. The CLT now holds for Lipschitz continuous
  test functions (thanks to the simple Remark 4.2). Moreover, a new section has
  been included, giving an outlook on relations to large deviatiations and
  phase transitions. The paper will appear in &quot;Algebraic and Analytic
  Microlocal Analysis&quot;, M. Hitrik, D. Tamarkin, B. Tsygan, and S. Zelditch,
  eds. Springer</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider determinantal point processes on a compact complex manifold X in
the limit of many particles. The correlation kernels of the processes are the
Bergman kernels associated to a a high power of a given Hermitian holomorphic
line bundle L over X. The empirical measure on X of the process, describing the
particle locations, converges in probability towards the pluripotential
equilibrium measure, expressed in term of the Monge-Amp\`ere operator. The
asymptotics of the corresponding fluctuations in the bulk are shown to be
asymptotically normal and described by a Gaussian free field and applies to
test functions (linear statistics) which are merely Lipschitz continuous.
Moreover, a scaling limit of the correlation functions in the bulk is shown to
be universal and expressed in terms of (the higher dimensional analog of) the
Ginibre ensemble. This geometric setting applies in particular to normal random
matrix ensembles, the two dimensional Coulomb gas, free fermions in a strong
magnetic field and multivariate orthogonal polynomials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1008.3746</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1008.3746</id><created>2010-08-23</created><updated>2010-09-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shinzato</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasuda</keyname><forenames>Muneki</forenames></author></authors><title>Belief Propagation Algorithm for Portfolio Optimization Problems</title><categories>q-fin.PM cond-mat.stat-mech cs.LG math.OC q-fin.RM</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, to submit to EPL</comments><doi>10.1371/journal.pone.0134968</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The typical behavior of optimal solutions to portfolio optimization problems
with absolute deviation and expected shortfall models using replica analysis
was pioneeringly estimated by S. Ciliberti and M. M\'ezard [Eur. Phys. B. 57,
175 (2007)]; however, they have not yet developed an approximate derivation
method for finding the optimal portfolio with respect to a given return set. In
this study, an approximation algorithm based on belief propagation for the
portfolio optimization problem is presented using the Bethe free energy
formalism, and the consistency of the numerical experimental results of the
proposed algorithm with those of replica analysis is confirmed. Furthermore,
the conjecture of H. Konno and H. Yamazaki, that the optimal solutions with the
absolute deviation model and with the mean-variance model have the same typical
behavior, is verified using replica analysis and the belief propagation
algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1207.1671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1207.1671</id><created>2012-07-06</created><updated>2013-09-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix Product Operators and Central Elements: Classical Description of
  a Quantum State</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures; final version in press (and a few more
  corrections)</comments><journal-ref>Geometry and Topology Monographs 18, 115 (2012)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study planar two-dimensional quantum systems on a lattice whose
Hamiltonian is a sum of local commuting projectors of bounded range. We
consider whether or not such a system has a zero energy ground state. To do
this, we consider the problem as a one-dimensional problem, grouping all sites
along a column into &quot;supersites&quot;; using $C^*$-algebraic methods (Bravyi and
Vyalyi), we can solve this problem if we can characterize the central elements
of the interaction algebra on these supersite. Unfortunately, these central
elements may be very complex, making brute force impractical. Instead, we show
a characterization of these elements in terms of matrix product operators with
bounded bond dimension. This bound can be interpreted as a bound on the number
of particle types in lattice theories with bounded Hilbert space dimension on
each site. Topological order in this approach is related to the existence of
certain central elements which cannot be &quot;broken&quot; into smaller pieces without
creating an end excitation. Using this bound on bond dimension, we prove that
several special cases of this problem are in NP, and we give part of a proof
that the general case is in NP. Further, we characterize central elements that
appear in certain specific models, including toric code and Levin-Wen models,
as either product operators in the Abelian case or matrix product operators
with low bond dimension in the non-Abelian case; this matrix product operator
representation may have practical application in engineering the complicated
multi-spin interactions in the Levin-Wen models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.0502</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.0502</id><created>2012-08-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>S. Yu.</forenames><affiliation>National Research Nuclear University &quot;MEPhI&quot;</affiliation></author></authors><title>TRTViewer: the ATLAS TRT detector monitoring and diagnostics tool</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures. Proc. of the 4th Workshop on Advanced Transition
  Radiation Detectors for Accelerator and Space Applications, Bari, Italy,
  Sept. 14-16, 2011. Submitted to Nucl. Instr. Meth. A</comments><report-no>CERN report no: ATL-INDET-PROC-2011-044</report-no><journal-ref>NIM A706 (2013) 90-92</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2012.05.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transition radiation tracker (TRT) is the outermost of the three
sub-systems of the ATLAS inner detector at the Large Hadron Collider (LHC) at
CERN. It is designed to combine the drift tube tracker with the transition
radiation detector, providing an important contribution to the charged
particles precise momentum measurement and particle (mainly electron)
identification. The TRT consists of a barrel section at small pseudorapidity
(eta) and two separate end-cap partitions at large eta. The detector
performance and its operational conditions were permanently monitored during
all commissioning and data-taking stages using various software tools, one of
which - TRTViewer - is described in the present paper. The TRTViewer is the
dedicated program for monitoring the TRT raw data quality and detector
performance at different hardware levels: individual straws, readout chips and
electronic boards. The data analysis results can be presented on the
event-by-event basis or in the form of color maps representing the operation
parameters (efficiencies, timing, occupancy, etc.) according to the real
geometrical position of the detector hardware elements. The paper describes the
TRTViewer software package as the event displaying tool, raw data processor and
histogram and operation parameters presenter, which works with the different
sources of input information: raw data files, online monitoring histograms,
offline analysis histograms and TRT DAQ Configuration database. The package
proved to be one of the main instruments for the fast and effective TRT
diagnostics during debugging and operation periods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1539</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1539</id><created>2014-03-06</created><updated>2014-03-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wecker</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troyer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improving Quantum Algorithms for Quantum Chemistry</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures; v2: minor corrections and clarifications</comments><journal-ref>QIC 15, 1 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present several improvements to the standard Trotter-Suzuki based
algorithms used in the simulation of quantum chemistry on a quantum computer.
First, we modify how Jordan-Wigner transformations are implemented to reduce
their cost from linear or logarithmic in the number of orbitals to a constant.
Our modification does not require additional ancilla qubits. Then, we
demonstrate how many operations can be parallelized, leading to a further
linear decrease in the parallel depth of the circuit, at the cost of a small
constant factor increase in number of qubits required. Thirdly, we modify the
term order in the Trotter-Suzuki decomposition, significantly reducing the
error at given Trotter-Suzuki timestep. A final improvement modifies the
Hamiltonian to reduce errors introduced by the non-zero Trotter-Suzuki
timestep. All of these techniques are validated using numerical simulation and
detailed gate counts are given for realistic molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.6259</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.6259</id><created>2014-09-22</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Damanik</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>Rice University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fillman</keyname><forenames>Jake</forenames><affiliation>Rice University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lukic</keyname><forenames>Milivoje</forenames><affiliation>University of Toronto and Rice University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yessen</keyname><forenames>William</forenames><affiliation>Rice University</affiliation></author></authors><title>Characterizations of Uniform Hyperbolicity and Spectra of CMV Matrices</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages; based on the appendices of arXiv:1404.7065, which were
  removed in passing from arXiv:1404.7065v1 to arXiv:1404.7065v2, the latter
  being the version accepted for publication in IMRN</comments><journal-ref>Discrete Contin. Dyn. Syst. S 9 (2016), 1009-1023</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide an elementary proof of the equivalence of various notions of
uniform hyperbolicity for a class of $\mathrm{GL}(2,\mathbb{C})$ cocycles and
establish a Johnson-type theorem for extended CMV matrices, relating the
spectrum to the points on the unit circle for which the associated Szeg\H{o}
cocycle is not uniformly hyperbolic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.09075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.09075</id><created>2015-03-31</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barkatou</keyname><forenames>Moulay A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maddah</keyname><forenames>Suzy S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Formal Solutions of Singularly Peturbed Linear Differential Systems</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>57 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we discuss formal invariants of singularly-perturbed linear
differential systems in neighborhood of turning points and give algorithms
which allow their computation. The algorithms proposed are implemented in the
computer algebra system Maple.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.02984</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.02984</id><created>2015-05-12</created><updated>2015-11-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Daskin</keyname><forenames>Anmer</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Eigenvalue Estimation for Irreducible Non-negative Matrices</title><categories>quant-ph cs.DS</categories><comments>A few typos are corrected</comments><doi>10.1142/S0219749916500052</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum phase estimation algorithm has been successfully adapted as a sub
frame of many other algorithms applied to a wide variety of applications in
different fields. However, the requirement of a good approximate eigenvector
given as an input to the algorithm hinders the application of the algorithm to
the problems where we do not have any prior knowledge about the eigenvector.
  In this paper, we show that the principal eigenvalue of an irreducible
non-negative operator can be determined by using an equal superposition initial
state in the phase estimation algorithm. This removes the necessity of the
existence of an initial good approximate eigenvector. Moreover, we show that
the success probability of the algorithm is related to the closeness of the
operator to a stochastic matrix. Therefore, we draw an estimate for the success
probability by using the variance of the column sums of the operator. This
provides a priori information which can be used to know the success probability
of the algorithm beforehand for the non-negative matrices and apply the
algorithm only in cases when the estimated probability reasonably high.
Finally, we discuss the possible applications and show the results for random
symmetric matrices and 3-local Hamiltonians with non-negative off-diagonal
elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.04580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.04580</id><created>2015-05-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>Isidoro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cascales</keyname><forenames>Juan Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andres</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aliev</keyname><forenames>Farkhad G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic state dependent transient lateral photovoltaic effect in
  patterned ferromagnetic metal-oxide-semiconductor films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1063/1.4935441</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the influence of an external magnetic field on the magnitude
and dephasing of the transient lateral photovoltaic effect (T-LPE) in
lithographically patterned Co lines of widths of a few microns grown over
naturally passivated p-type Si(100). The T-LPE peak-to-peak magnitude and
dephasing, measured by lock-in or through the characteristic time of laser OFF
exponential relaxation, exhibit a notable influence of the magnetization
direction of the ferromagnetic overlayer. We show experimentally and by
numerical simulations that the T-LPE magnitude is determined by the Co
anisotropic magnetoresistance. On the other hand, the magnetic field dependence
of the dephasing could be described by the influence of the Lorentz force
acting perpendiculary to both the Co magnetization and the photocarrier drift
directions. Our findings could stimulate the development of fast position
sensitive detectors with magnetically tuned magnitude and phase responses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.06468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.06468</id><created>2015-05-24</created><updated>2016-08-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>M. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Random MERA States and the Tightness of the Brandao-Horodecki Entropy
  Bound</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 7 figures; v2, final version in press, added some
  discussion of possible generalizations</comments><journal-ref>QIC 16, 1228 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a random MERA state with a bond dimension that varies with the
level of the MERA. This causes the state to exhibit a very different
entanglement structure from that usually seen in MERA, with neighboring
intervals of length $l$ exhibiting a mutual information proportional to
$\epsilon l$ for some constant $\epsilon$, up to a length scale exponentially
large in $\epsilon$. We express the entropy of a random MERA in terms of sums
over cuts through the MERA network, with the entropy in this case controlled by
the cut minimizing bond dimensions cut through. One motivation for this
construction is to investigate the tightness of the Brandao-Horodecki\cite{bh}
entropy bound relating entanglement to correlation decay. Using the random
MERA, we show that at least part of the proof is tight: there do exist states
with the required property of having linear mutual information between
neighboring intervals at all length scales. We conjecture that this state has
exponential correlation decay and that it demonstrates that the
Brandao-Horodecki bound is tight (at least up to constant factors), and we
provide some numerical evidence for this as well as a sketch of how a proof of
correlation decay might proceed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01231</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01231</id><created>2015-05-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Diamantini</keyname><forenames>M. Cristina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trugenberger</keyname><forenames>Carlo A.</forenames></author></authors><title>High-Capacity Quantum Associative Memories</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Review article, 43 pages, 2 figures, to appear in &quot;Quantum
  Computational Intelligence: Research and Applications&quot;, published by Elsevier</comments><journal-ref>JAMP Vol.4 No 11 (2016) 2079</journal-ref><doi>10.4236/jamp.2016.411207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review our models of quantum associative memories that represent the
&quot;quantization&quot; of fully coupled neural networks like the Hopfield model. The
idea is to replace the classical irreversible attractor dynamics driven by an
Ising model with pattern-dependent weights by the reversible rotation of an
input quantum state onto an output quantum state consisting of a linear
superposition with probability amplitudes peaked on the stored pattern closest
to the input in Hamming distance, resulting in a high probability of measuring
a memory pattern very similar to the input. The unitary operator implementing
this transformation can be formulated as a sequence of one-qubit and two-qubit
elementary quantum gates and is thus the exponential of an ordered quantum
Ising model with sequential operations and with pattern-dependent interactions,
exactly as in the classical case. Probabilistic quantum memories, that make use
of postselection of the measurement result of control qubits, overcome the
famed linear storage limitation of their classical counterparts because they
permit to completely {\it eliminate crosstalk and spurious memories}. The
number of control qubits plays the role of an inverse fictitious temperature,
the accuracy of pattern retrieval can be tuned by lowering the fictitious
temperature under a critical value for quantum content association while the
complexity of the retrieval algorithm remains polynomial for any number of
patterns polynomial in the number of qubits. These models solve thus the
capacity shortage problem of classical associative memories, providing a {\it
polynomial improvement} in capacity. The price to pay is the probabilistic
nature of information retrieval.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.03234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.03234</id><created>2015-06-10</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hurtado</keyname><forenames>Pablo I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrido</keyname><forenames>Pedro L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A violation of universality in anomalous Fourier's law</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft math-ph math.MP physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>10 pages + 6 figs + Supplementary Material (7 pages + 6 figs)</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 38823 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep38823</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the discovery of long-time tails, it has been clear that Fourier's law
in low dimensions is typically anomalous, with a size-dependent heat
conductivity, though the nature of the anomaly remains puzzling. The
conventional wisdom, supported by renormalization-group arguments and
mode-coupling approximations within fluctuating hydrodynamics, is that the
anomaly is universal in 1d momentum-conserving systems and belongs in the
Levy/Kardar-Parisi-Zhang universality class. Here we challenge this picture by
using a novel scaling method to show unambiguously that universality breaks
down in the paradigmatic 1d diatomic hard-point fluid. Hydrodynamic profiles
for a broad set of gradients, densities and sizes all collapse onto an
universal master curve, showing that (anomalous) Fourier's law holds even deep
into the nonlinear regime. This allows to solve the macroscopic transport
problem for this model, a solution which compares flawlessly with data and,
interestingly, implies the existence of a bound on the heat current in terms of
pressure. These results question the renormalization-group and mode-coupling
universality predictions for anomalous Fourier's law in 1d, offering a new
perspective on transport in low dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07607</id><created>2015-06-25</created><updated>2016-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Asvathaman</keyname><forenames>Asha</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyl</keyname><forenames>Jeremy S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hui</keyname><forenames>Lam</forenames></author></authors><title>E\&quot;otv\&quot;os Experiments with Supermassive Black Holes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, accepted by Monthly Notices</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By examining the locations of central black holes in two elliptical galaxies,
M\,32 and M\,87, we derive constraints on the violation of the strong
equivalence principle for purely gravitational objects, i.e. black holes, of
less than about two-thirds, $\eta_N&lt;0.68$ from the gravitational interaction of
M\,87 with its neighbours in the Virgo cluster. Although M\,32 appears to be a
good candidate for this technique, the high concentration of stars near its
centre substantially weakens the constraints. On the other hand, if a central
black hole is found in NGC 205 or one of the other satellite ellipticals of
M\,31, substantially better constraints could be obtained. In all cases the
constraints could improve dramatically with better astrometry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05676</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05676</id><created>2015-07-20</created><updated>2016-12-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Freedman</keyname><forenames>Michael H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>Matthew B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double semions in arbitrary dimension</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v2: Showed theory has different ground state degeneracy than twisted
  Dijkgraaf-Witten. Minor corrections</comments><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. 347, 389 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2604-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a generalization of the double semion topological quantum field
theory to higher dimensions, as a theory of $d-1$ dimensional surfaces in a $d$
dimensional ambient space. We construct a local Hamiltonian which is a sum of
commuting projectors and analyze the excitations and the ground state
degeneracy. Defining a consistent set of local rules requires the sign
structure of the ground state wavefunction to depend not just on the number of
disconnected surfaces, but also upon their higher Betti numbers through the
semicharacteristic. For odd $d$ the theory is related to the toric code by a
local unitary transformation, but for even $d$ the dimension of the space of
zero energy ground states is in general different from the toric code and for
even $d&gt;2$ it is also in general different from that of the twisted $Z_2$
Dijkgraaf-Witten model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06314</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06314</id><created>2015-07-22</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Merle</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platscher</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author></authors><title>Running of Radiative Neutrino Masses: The Scotogenic Model - REVISITED</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>44 pages, 13 figures; continuation of 1205.0008 [hep-ph]; content
  matches published version; v3 corrected a minor typo in Eq. (25)</comments><report-no>MPP-2015-162</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP11(2015)148</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A few years ago, it had been shown that effects stemming from renormalisation
group running can be quite large in the scotogenic model, where neutrinos
obtain their mass only via a 1-loop diagram (or, more generally, in many models
in which the light neutrino mass is generated via quantum corrections at
loop-level). We present a new computation of the renormalisation group
equations (RGEs) for the scotogenic model, thereby updating previous results.
We discuss the matching in detail, in particular in what regards the different
mass spectra possible for the new particles involved. We furthermore develop
approximate analytical solutions to the RGEs for an extensive list of
illustrative cases, covering all general tendencies that can appear in the
model. Comparing them with fully numerical solutions, we give a comprehensive
discussion of the running in the scotogenic model. Our approach is mainly
top-down, but we also discuss an attempt to get information on the values of
the fundamental parameters when inputting the low-energy measured quantities in
a bottom-up manner. This work serves the basis for a full parameter scan of the
model, thereby relating its low- and high-energy phenomenology, to fully
exploit the available information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.06774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.06774</id><created>2015-08-27</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jakovac</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaposvari</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patkos</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalar mass stability bound in a simple Yukawa-theory from
  renormalisation group equations</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 7 figures, lower mass bound derived with significantly
  extended operator set in FRGE's, version matching the article to appear in
  MPLA</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217732317500110</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Functional Renormalisation Group (FRG) equations are constructed for a simple
Yukawa-model with discrete chiral symmetry, including also the effect of a
nonzero composite fermion background beyond the conventional scalar condensate.
The evolution of the effective potential of the model, generically depending on
two invariants, is explored with help of power series expansions. Systematic
investigation of the effect of a class of irrelevant operators on the lower
(stability) bound allows a non-perturbative extension of the maximal cut-off
value consistent with any given mass of the scalar field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04593</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04593</id><created>2015-09-15</created><updated>2016-04-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maccari</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maiorano</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marinari</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz-Lorenzo</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>A numerical study of planar arrays of correlated spin islands</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in EPJ B</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2016) 89: 127</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70171-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our analysis of a system of interacting islands of XY spins on a
triangular lattice that has been introduced a few years ago by Eley et al. to
account for the phenomenology in experiments on tunable arrays of proximity
coupled long superconductor-normal metal-superconductor junctions. The main
features of the model are the separation of a local and a global interaction
energy scale and the mesoscopic character of the spin islands. Upon lowering
the temperature the model undergoes two crossovers corresponding to an
increasing phase coherence on a single island and to the onset of global
coherence across the array; the latter is a thermodynamical phase transition in
the Ising universality class. The dependence of the second transition on the
island edge-to-edge spacing is related to the proximity-effect of the coupling
constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07146</id><created>2015-10-24</created><updated>2016-10-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maiorino</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>Filippo Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Livi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rizzi</keyname><forenames>Antonello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadeghian</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author></authors><title>Data-driven detrending of nonstationary fractal time series with echo
  state networks</title><categories>physics.data-an cs.LG cs.NE</categories><comments>Revised version</comments><doi>10.1016/j.ins.2016.12.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we propose a novel data-driven approach for removing trends
(detrending) from nonstationary, fractal and multifractal time series. We
consider real-valued time series relative to measurements of an underlying
dynamical system that evolves through time. We assume that such a dynamical
process is predictable to a certain degree by means of a class of recurrent
networks called Echo State Network (ESN), which are capable to model a generic
dynamical process. In order to isolate the superimposed (multi)fractal
component of interest, we define a data-driven filter by leveraging on the ESN
prediction capability to identify the trend component of a given input time
series. Specifically, the (estimated) trend is removed from the original time
series and the residual signal is analyzed with the multifractal detrended
fluctuation analysis procedure to verify the correctness of the detrending
procedure. In order to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed technique,
we consider several synthetic time series consisting of different types of
trends and fractal noise components with known characteristics. We also process
a real-world dataset, the sunspot time series, which is well-known for its
multifractal features and has recently gained attention in the complex systems
field. Results demonstrate the validity and generality of the proposed
detrending method based on ESNs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.07354</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.07354</id><created>2015-10-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Bi</keyname><forenames>Yujiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhaofeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>Hao-Xue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Bo</forenames></author></authors><title>Diquark mass differences from unquenched lattice QCD</title><categories>hep-ph hep-lat</categories><comments>9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chin.Phys. C40 (2016) no.7, 073106</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/7/073106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate diquark correlation functions in the Landau gauge on the lattice
using overlap valence quarks and 2+1-flavor domain wall fermion configurations.
Quark masses are extracted from the scalar part of quark propagators in the
Landau gauge. Scalar diquark quark mass difference and axial vector scalar
diquark mass difference are obtained for diquarks composed of two light quarks
and of a strange and a light quark. Light sea quark mass dependence of the
results is examined. Two lattice spacings are used to check the discretization
effects. The coarse and fine lattices are of sizes $24^3\times64$ and
$32^3\times64$ with inverse spacings $1/a=1.75(4) {\rm~GeV}$ and $2.33(5)
{\rm~GeV}$, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09414</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bengaly</keyname><forenames>C. A. P.</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Bernui</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alcaniz</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing cosmological isotropy with Planck Sunyaev-Zeldovich galaxy
  clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures. Manuscript revised, main conclusions unchanged.
  Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3233</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We probe the statistical isotropy hypothesis of the large-scale structure
with the second Planck Sunyaev-Zeldovich (PSZ2) galaxy clusters data set. Our
analysis adopts a statistical-geometrical method which compares the 2-point
angular correlation function of objects in antipodal patches of the sky. Given
possible observational biases, such as the presence of anisotropic sky cuts and
the non-uniform exposure of Planck's instrumentation, ensembles of Monte Carlo
realisations are produced in order to assess the significance of our results.
When these observational effects are properly taken into account, we find
neither evidence for preferred directions in the sky nor signs of large-angle
features in the galaxy clusters celestial distribution. The PSZ2 data set is,
therefore, in good concordance with the fundamental hypothesis of large-angle
isotropy of cosmic objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03362</id><created>2015-12-10</created><updated>2016-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ageev</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aref'eva</keyname><forenames>I. Ya.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tikhanovskaya</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Dual to Conical Defects: I. Moving Massive Particle</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>Latex, 40 pages, 24 figures, comments added, some figures improved,
  refs added</comments><journal-ref>THEORETICAL AND MATHEMATICAL PHYSICS, 188, 2016, 1038</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S0040577916070060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study correlation functions of scalar operators on the boundary of the
$AdS_3$ space deformed by moving massive particles in the context of the
AdS/CFT duality. To calculate two-point correlation functions we use the
geodesic approximation and the renormalized image method. We compare results of
the renormalized image method with direct calculations using tracing of winding
geodesics around the cone singularities, and show on examples that they are
equivalent. We demonstrate that in the geodesic approximation the correlators
exhibit a zone structure. This structure substantially depends on the mass and
velocity of the particle.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04216</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brodsky</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruin</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borzi</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grigera</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perry</keyname><forenames>Robin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mackenzie</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hicks</keyname><forenames>Clifford</forenames></author></authors><title>Strain and Vector-Magnetic-Field Tuning of the Anomalous Phase in
  Sr3Ru2O7</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>30 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Symmetry is a basic paradigm for analysis of problems in solid state physics,
and to controllably break point-group symmetries is a powerful probe of novel
forms of order. In this work, we apply two methods, controlled lattice strain
and vector magnetic field, to study a well-known correlated electron phase that
appears at low temperatures in the layered material Sr3Ru2O7. This phase
responds strongly to C4-symmetry-breaking fields, suggesting spontaneous C4
symmetry breaking. However, in this work we find that the data are more easily
explained with microscopic coexistence of two orthogonal order parameter
components than spontaneous symmetry breaking. The techniques presented in this
work will be relevant for other systems where spontaneous C4 symmetry breaking
is suspected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04554</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Venderbos</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rn W. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozii</keyname><forenames>Vladyslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Odd-parity superconductors with two-component order parameters: nematic
  and chiral, full gap and Majorana node</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>4+ pages, 2 figures; 20 pages suppl mat + 4 figures; published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 180504(R) (2016), Editors' Suggestion</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.180504</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the recent experiment indicating that superconductivity in the
doped topological insulator Cu$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$ has an odd-parity pairing
symmetry with rotational symmetry breaking, we study the general class of
odd-parity superconductors with two-component order parameters in trigonal and
hexagonal crystal systems. In the presence of strong spin-orbit interaction, we
find two possible superconducting phases below $T_c$, a time-reversal-breaking
(i.e., chiral) phase and an anisotropic (i.e., nematic) phase, and determine
their relative energetics from the gap function in momentum space. The nematic
superconductor generally has a full quasi-particle gap, whereas the chiral
superconductor with a three-dimensional (3D) Fermi surface has point nodes with
lifted spin degeneracy, resulting in itinerant Majorana fermions in the bulk
and topological Majorana arcs on the surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09068</id><created>2015-12-30</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kersten</keyname><forenames>Joern</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Alexei Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Decoherence and oscillations of supernova neutrinos</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>32 pages + references; v2: added minor clarifications and references,
  matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016), 339</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4187-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supernova neutrinos have several exceptional features which can lead to
interesting physical consequences. At the production point their wave packets
have an extremely small size $\sigma_x \sim 10^{-11}$ cm; hence the energy
uncertainty can be as large as the energy itself, $\sigma_E \sim E$, and the
coherence length is short. On the way to the Earth the wave packets of mass
eigenstates spread to macroscopic sizes and separate. Inside the Earth the mass
eigenstates split into eigenstates in matter and oscillate again. The coherence
length in the Earth is comparable with the radius of the Earth. We explore
these features and their consequences. (i) We present new estimates of the wave
packet size. (ii) We consider the decoherence condition for the case of wave
packets with spatial spread and show that it is not modified by the spread.
(iii) We study the coherence of neutrinos propagating in a multi-layer medium
with density jumps at the borders of layers. In this case coherence can be
partially restored due to a &quot;catch-up effect&quot;, increasing the coherence length
beyond the usual estimate. This catch-up effect can occur for supernova
neutrinos as they cross the shock wave fronts in the exploding star or the core
of the Earth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01276</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01276</id><created>2016-02-03</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>X. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Normand</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Charge dynamics of the antiferromagnetically ordered Mott insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 103004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/10/103004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the charge dynamics of the half-filled Hubbard model on the square
lattice at zero temperature. We employ a slave-fermion formulation in which the
charge degrees of freedom are represented by fermionic holons and doublons and
the bosonic spin degrees of freedom are assumed to be described by the
antiferromagnetic Heisenberg model. The ground state has long-ranged magnetic
(N\'eel) order and its Mott-insulating characteristics are the consequence of
holon-doublon bound-state formation. Within this framework, we calculate the
average double occupancy, the electron density of states, and the spectral
function in the self-consistent Born approximation. The lower and upper Hubbard
bands are reproduced, there is spectral-weight transfer into a coherent
quasiparticle band at their lower edges, and the Mott gap, associated with
holon-doublon binding, is renormalized due to the interactions of the holons
and doublons with the magnons. We compute the zeros of the Green function at
the chemical potential to discuss the Luttinger volume and show that the poles
of the self-energy reflect the underlying quasiparticle dispersion with a
spin-renormalized hopping parameter. Optical conductivity results relate the
optical gap to the Mott gap of the insulating system. We conclude that a
self-consistent treatment of the spin fluctuation effects on the charge degrees
of freedom captures all the essential physics of the antiferromagnetic
Mott-Hubbard insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02351</id><created>2016-02-07</created><updated>2016-10-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoshiura</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimabukuro</keyname><forenames>Hayato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Keitaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsubara</keyname><forenames>Takahiko</forenames></author></authors><title>Studying topological structure in the epoch of reionization with
  3D-Minkowski functionals of 21cm line fluctuations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures, accepted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016 465 (1):
  394-402</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2701</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The brightness temperature of the redshifted 21cm line brings rich
information on the Inter Galactic Medium (IGM) from the Cosmic Dawn and Epoch
of Reionization (EoR). While the power spectrum is a useful tool to
statistically investigate the 21cm signal, the 21cm brightness temperature
field is highly non-Gaussian, and the power spectrum is inadequate to
characterize the non-Gaussianity. The Minkowski Functionals (MFs) are promising
tools to extract non-gaussian features of the 21cm signal and give topological
information such as morphology of ionized bubbles. In this work, we study the
21cm line signal in detail with MFs. To promote understanding of basic features
of the 21cm signal, we calculate the MFs of not only the hydrogen neutral
fraction but the matter density and spin temperature, which contribute to the
brightness temperature fluctuations. We find that the structure of the
brightness temperature depends mainly on the ionized fraction and the spin
temperature at late and early stages of the EoR, respectively. Further, we
investigate the redshift evolution of the MFs at $7 &lt; z &lt; 20$. Then, we find
that, after the onset of reionization, the MFs reflect mainly the ionized
bubble property. In addition, the MFs are sensitive to model parameters which
are related to the topology of ionized bubbles and we consider the possibility
of constraining the parameters by the future 21cm signal observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03738</id><created>2016-02-11</created><updated>2016-08-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yoshimatsu</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ara&#xfa;jo</keyname><forenames>N. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shinbrot</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Field Driven Charging Dynamics of a Fluidized Granular Bed</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1039/C6SM00357E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simplified model has previously described the inductive charging of
colliding identical grains in the presence of an external electric field. Here
we extend that model by including heterogeneous surface charge distributions,
grain rotations and electrostatic interactions between grains. We find from
this more realistic model that strong heterogeneities in charging can occur in
agitated granular beds, and we predict that shielding due to these
heterogeneities can dramatically alter the charging rate in such beds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04516</id><created>2016-02-14</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Test of CP Invariance in vector-boson fusion production of the Higgs
  boson using the Optimal Observable method in the ditau decay channel with the
  ATLAS detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>23 pages plus author list (40 pages total), 8 figures, 2 tables,
  published version, all figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  http://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/HIGG-2015-06</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-002</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76 (2016) 658</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4499-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A test of CP invariance in Higgs boson production via vector-boson fusion
using the method of the Optimal Observable is presented. The analysis exploits
the decay mode of the Higgs boson into a pair of $\tau$ leptons and is based on
20.3 fb$^{-1}$ of proton-proton collision data at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV collected
by the ATLAS experiment at the LHC. Contributions from CP-violating
interactions between the Higgs boson and electroweak gauge bosons are described
in an effective field theory framework, in which the strength of CP violation
is governed by a single parameter $\tilde{d}$. The mean values and
distributions of CP-odd observables agree with the expectation in the Standard
Model and show no sign of CP violation. The CP-mixing parameter $\tilde{d}$ is
constrained to the interval [-0.11,0.05] at 68% confidence level, consistent
with the Standard Model expectation of $\tilde{d}=0$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.05780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.05780</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xikun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shang</keyname><forenames>Jiangwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ng</keyname><forenames>Hui Khoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Englert</keyname><forenames>Berthold-Georg</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal error intervals for properties of the quantum state</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Very close to the published version; 22 pages, 10 figures, and 40
  references</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 062112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.062112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum state estimation aims at determining the quantum state from observed
data. Estimating the full state can require considerable efforts, but one is
often only interested in a few properties of the state, such as the fidelity
with a target state, or the degree of correlation for a specified bipartite
structure. Rather than first estimating the state, one can, and should,
estimate those quantities of interest directly from the data. We propose the
use of optimal error intervals as a meaningful way of stating the accuracy of
the estimated property values. Optimal error intervals are analogs of the
optimal error regions for state estimation [New J. Phys. 15, 123026 (2013)].
They are optimal in two ways: They have the largest likelihood for the observed
data and the pre-chosen size, and are the smallest for the pre-chosen
probability of containing the true value. As in the state situation, such
optimal error intervals admit a simple description in terms of the marginal
likelihood for the data for the properties of interest. Here, we present the
concept and construction of optimal error intervals, report on an iterative
algorithm for reliable computation of the marginal likelihood (a quantity
difficult to calculate reliably), explain how plausible intervals --- a notion
of evidence provided by the data --- are related to our optimal error
intervals, and illustrate our methods with single-qubit and two-qubit examples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00789</id><created>2016-03-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Jonas Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf6;rlitz</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arend</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markham</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becher</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrafast, all-optical coherent control of single silicon vacancy colour
  centres in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 13512 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13512</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, the negatively charged silicon vacancy centre (SiV) in diamond has
emerged as a novel promising system for quantum information processing (QIP)
due to its superior spectral properties and advantageous electronic structure:
The SiV offers an optically accessible {\Lambda}-type level structure with a
large orbital level splitting even without the need of an external magnetic
field and previous studies determined the ground state coherence time of the
centre to be on the order of 35-45ns. While these studies already indicate the
feasibility of an ultrafast all-optical coherent control of the SiV, no
experimental realization has been presented so far. Here, we report on optical
Rabi oscillations and Ramsey interference between the ground and the excited
state of the SiV using 12 ps long, resonant rotation pulses. Moreover,
utilizing a {\Lambda}-scheme, we demonstrate Raman-based coherent Rabi
rotations and Ramsey interference within the ground state manifold using a
single, 1ps long off-resonant pulse. These measurements prove the accessibility
of the complete set of single-qubit operations relying solely on optical fields
and pave the way for high-speed QIP applications using SiV centres.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01702</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01702</id><created>2016-03-05</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Measurement of total and differential $W^+W^-$ production cross sections
  in proton-proton collisions at $\sqrt{s}=$ 8 TeV with the ATLAS detector and
  limits on anomalous triple-gauge-boson couplings</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>61 pages plus author list (78 pages total), 16 figures, 36 tables,
  published version, all figures including auxiliary figures are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/STDM-2013-07/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-EP-2015-323</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 09 (2016) 029</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP09(2016)029</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The production of $W$ boson pairs in proton-proton collisions at $\sqrt{s}=$
8 TeV is studied using data corresponding to 20.3 fb$^{-1}$ of integrated
luminosity collected by the ATLAS detector during 2012 at the CERN Large Hadron
Collider. The $W$ bosons are reconstructed using their leptonic decays into
electrons or muons and neutrinos. Events with reconstructed jets are not
included in the candidate event sample. A total of 6636 $WW$ candidate events
are observed. Measurements are performed in fiducial regions closely
approximating the detector acceptance. The integrated measurement is corrected
for all acceptance effects and for the $W$ branching fractions to leptons in
order to obtain the total $WW$ production cross section, which is found to be
71.1$\pm1.1$(stat)$^{+5.7}_{-5.0}$(syst)$\pm1.4$ pb. This agrees with the
next-to-next-to-leading-order Standard Model prediction of
63.2$^{+1.6}_{-1.4}$(scale)$\pm1.2$(PDF) pb. Fiducial differential cross
sections are measured as a function of each of six kinematic variables. The
distribution of the transverse momentum of the leading lepton is used to set
limits on anomalous triple-gauge-boson couplings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02760</id><created>2016-03-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jeong San</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized entanglement constraints in multi-qubit systems in terms of
  Tsallis entropy</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, no figure</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 373, p.197 - 206 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide generalized entanglement constraints in multi-qubit systems in
terms of Tsallis entropy. Using quantum Tsallis entropy of order $q$, we first
provide a generalized monogamy inequality of multi-qubit entanglement for $q=2$
or $3$. This generalization encapsulates multi-qubit CKW-type inequality as a
special case. We further provide a generalized polygamy inequality of
multi-qubit entanglement in terms of Tsallis-$q$ entropy for $1 \leq q \leq2$
or $3 \leq q \leq 4$, which also contains the multi-qubit polygamy inequality
as a special case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03406</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03406</id><created>2016-03-10</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Venderbos</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rn W. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozii</keyname><forenames>Vladyslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification of nematic superconductivity from the upper critical
  field</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figs; 20 pages supplemental material; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 094522 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.094522</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent nuclear magnetic resonance and specific heat measurements have
provided concurring evidence of spontaneously broken rotational symmetry in the
superconducting state of the doped topological insulator Cu$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$.
This suggests that the pairing symmetry corresponds to a two-dimensional
representation of the $D_{3d}$ crystal point group, and that Cu$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$
is a nematic superconductor. In this work, we present a comprehensive study of
the upper critical field $H_{c2}$ of nematic superconductors within
Ginzburg-Landau (GL) theory. Contrary to typical GL theories which have an
emergent U(1) rotational symmetry obscuring the discrete symmetry of the
crystal, the theory of two-component superconductors in trigonal crystals
reflects the true $D_{3d}$ crystal symmetry. This has direct implications for
the upper critical field. First, $H_{c2}$ of trigonal superconductors exhibits
a sixfold anisotropy in the basal plane. Second, when the degeneracy of the two
components is lifted by, e.g., uniaxial strain, $H_{c2}$ exhibits a twofold
anisotropy with characteristic angle and temperature dependence. Our thorough
study shows that measurement of the upper critical field is a direct method of
detecting nematic superconductivity, which is directly applicable to
recently-discovered trigonal superconductors Cu$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$,
Sr$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$, Nb$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$, and Tl$_x$Bi$_2$Se$_3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03748</id><created>2016-03-11</created><updated>2016-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mehboudi</keyname><forenames>Mehrshad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fregoso</keyname><forenames>Benjamin M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yurong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Wenjuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zande</keyname><forenames>Arend</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrer</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bellaiche</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Pradeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barraza-Lopez</keyname><forenames>Salvador</forenames></author></authors><title>Structural phase transition and material properties of few-layer
  monochalcogenides</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Supplementary information included. Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 246802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.246802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  GeSe and SnSe monochalcogenide monolayers and bilayers undergo a
two-dimensional phase transition from a rectangular unit cell to a square unit
cell at a temperature $T_c$ well below the melting point. Its consequences on
material properties are studied within the framework of Car-Parrinello
molecular dynamics and density-functional theory. No in-gap states develop as
the structural transition takes place, so that these phase-change materials
remain semiconducting below and above $T_c$. As the in-plane lattice transforms
from a rectangle onto a square at $T_c$, the electronic, spin, optical, and
piezo-electric properties dramatically depart from earlier predictions. Indeed,
the $Y-$ and $X-$points in the Brillouin zone become effectively equivalent at
$T_c$, leading to a symmetric electronic structure. The spin polarization at
the conduction valley edge vanishes, and the hole conductivity must display an
anomalous thermal increase at $T_c$. The linear optical absorption band edge
must change its polarization as well, making this structural and electronic
evolution verifiable by optical means. Much excitement has been drawn by
theoretical predictions of giant piezo-electricity and ferroelectricity in
these materials, and we estimate a pyroelectric response of about $3\times
10^{-12}$ $C/K m$ here. These results uncover the fundamental role of
temperature as a control knob for the physical properties of few-layer group-IV
monochalcogenides
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04587</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-09-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alekseev</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Negative magnetoresistance in viscous flow of two-dimensional electrons</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 166601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.166601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At low temperatures, in very clean two-dimensional (2D) samples the electron
mean free path for collisions with static defects and phonons becomes greater
than the sample width. Under this condition, the electron transport occurs by
formation of a viscous flow of an electron fluid. We study the viscous flow of
2D electrons in a magnetic field perpendicular to the 2D layer. We calculate
the viscosity coefficients as the functions of magnetic field and temperature.
The off-diagonal viscosity coefficient determines the dispersion of the 2D
hydrodynamic waves. The decrease of the diagonal viscosity in magnetic field
leads to negative magnetoresistance which is temperature- and size dependent.
Our analysis demonstrates that the viscous mechanism is responsible for the
giant negative magnetoresistance recently observed in the ultra-high-mobility
GaAs quantum wells. We conclude that 2D electrons in that structures in
moderate magnetic fields should be treated as a viscous fluid.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06672</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2016-09-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jounghun</forenames><affiliation>Seoul National University</affiliation></author></authors><title>On the Universality of the Bound-Zone Peculiar Velocity Profile</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>accepted for publication in ApJ, a mistake in the calculation of the
  bound-zone peculiar velocity profile corrected</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 832 (2016) 123</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/2/123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A numerical evidence for the universality of the bound-zone peculiar velocity
profile in a LambdaCDM universe is presented. Analyzing the dark matter halo
catalogs from the Millennium-II simulation, we determine the average peculiar
velocity profiles of the objects located in the bound zones around massive
group-size halos at various redshifts and compare them to an analytic formula
characterized by two parameters, the amplitude and slope of the profile. The
best-fit values of the two parameters are found to be robust against the
changes of the mass scales and the key cosmological parameters. It is also
found that the amplitude and slope parameters of the bound-zone peculiar
velocity profile are constant but only in the limited ranges of redshifts. In
the dark matter dominated epoch corresponding to z&gt; 0.6 the two parameters have
constant values. In the transition period corresponding to 0.2=&lt; z=&lt; 0.6 when
the density of Lambda begins to exceed that of dark matter the two parameters
grow almost linearly with redshifts. At later epochs z&lt;0.2 when the
Lambda-domination prevails the two parameters regain constancy settling upon
higher constant values. Noting that the length of the transition period depends
on the amount of Lambda and speculating that the linear evolution of the
profile with redshifts in the transition period is a unique feature of the
Lambda-dominated universe, we suggest that the redshift evolution of the
bound-zone peculiar velocity profile should be a powerful local discriminator
of dark energy candidates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06774</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2016-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>NA61/SHINE</forenames></author><author><keyname>:</keyname></author><author><keyname>Abgrall</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aduszkiewicz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ajaz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andronov</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anti&#x107;i&#x107;</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antoniou</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baatar</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bay</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blondel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mer</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogomilov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bravar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brzychczyk</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bunyatov</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busygina</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christakoglou</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x106;irkovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Czopowicz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davis</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Debieux</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dembinski</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deveaux</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diakonos</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Luise</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dominik</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumarchez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dynowski</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Engel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ereditato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feofilov</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fodor</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garibov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ga&#x17a;dzicki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golubeva</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grebieszkow</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grzeszczuk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guber</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haesler</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herv&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hierholzer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Igolkin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivashkin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadija</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kapoyannis</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaptur</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisiel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolesnikov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolev</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondratiev</keyname><forenames>V. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korzenev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalik</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kowalski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koziel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krasnoperov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurepin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xe1;szl&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewicki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyubushkin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma&#x107;kowiak-Paw&#x142;owska</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maksiak</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malakhov</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manic</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcinek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marton</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mathes</keyname><forenames>H. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matulewicz</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matveev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melkumov</keyname><forenames>G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messerly</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mills</keyname><forenames>G. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morozov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mr&#xf3;wczy&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakadaira</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naskr&#x119;t</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nirkko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishikawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panagiotou</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petukhov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pistillo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#x142;aneta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posiada&#x142;a-Zezula</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pu&#x142;awski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Puzovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauch</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravonel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redij</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renfordt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richter-W&#x105;s</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>R&#xf6;hrich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rondio</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubbia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rumberger</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rustamov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rybczynski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadovsky</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakashita</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarnecki</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selyuzhenkov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seryakov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seyboth</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sgalaberna</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#x142;odkowski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staszel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stefanek</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stepaniak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Str&#xf6;bele</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x160;u&#x161;a</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szuba</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taranenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tefelska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tefelski</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tereshchenko</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsenov</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Turko</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ulrich</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vassiliou</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veberi&#x10d;</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vechernin</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vesztergombi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vinogradov</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilczek</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#x142;odarczyk</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wojtaszek-Szwarc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyszy&#x144;ski</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yarritu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zambelli</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmerman</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friend</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galymov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichikawa</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kubo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuoka</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murakami</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakaya</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Measurements of $\pi^{\pm}$ differential yields from the surface of the
  T2K replica target for incoming 31 GeV/c protons with the NA61/SHINE
  spectrometer at the CERN SPS</title><categories>hep-ex physics.ins-det</categories><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-057</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76: 617</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4440-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Measurements of particle emission from a replica of the T2K 90 cm-long carbon
target were performed in the NA61/SHINE experiment at CERN SPS, using data
collected during a high-statistics run in 2009. An efficient use of the
long-target measurements for neutrino flux predictions in T2K requires
dedicated reconstruction and analysis techniques. Fully-corrected differential
yields of $\pi^\pm$-mesons from the surface of the T2K replica target for
incoming 31 GeV/c protons are presented. A possible strategy to implement these
results into the T2K neutrino beam predictions is discussed and the propagation
of the uncertainties of these results to the final neutrino flux is performed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06351</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-04-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Landis</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mission to the Gravitational Focus of the Sun: A Critical Analysis</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM gr-qc physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 9 figures. Corrected typo in distance</comments><report-no>AIAA Science and Technology Forum and Exposition 2017, Grapevine TX,
  January 9-13, 2017</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gravitational field of the sun will focus light from a distant source to
a focal point at a minimal distance of 550 Astronomical Units from the sun. A
proposed mission to this gravitational focus could use the sun as a very large
lens, allowing (in principle) a large amplification of signal from the target,
and a very high magnification. This article discusses some of the difficulties
involved in using the sun as such a gravitational telescope for a candidate
mission, that of imaging the surface of a previously-detected exoplanet. These
difficulties include the pointing and focal length, and associated high
magnification; the signal to noise ratio associated with the solar corona, and
the focal blur. In addition, a method to calculate the signal gain and
magnification is derived using the first-order deflection calculation and
classical optics, showing that the gain is finite for an on-axis source of
non-zero area.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00786</id><created>2016-05-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Mo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum cloning attacks against PUF-based quantum authentication systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Inf. Process. 15, 3311 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1316-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the advent of Physical Unclonable Functions (PUFs), PUF-based quantum
authentication systems (QAS) have been proposed for security purposes and
recently proof-of-principle experiment has been demonstrated. As a further step
towards completing the security analysis, we investigate quantum cloning
attacks against PUF-based quantum authentication systems and prove that quantum
cloning attacks outperform the so-called challenge-estimation attacks. We
present the analytical expression of the false accept probability by use of the
corresponding optimal quantum cloning machines and extend the previous results
in the literature. In light of these findings, an explicit comparison is made
between PUF-based quantum authentication systems and quantum key distribution
(QKD) protocols in the context of cloning attacks. Moreover, from an
experimental perspective, a trade-off between the average photon number and the
detection efficiency is discussed in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01206</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moreva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramegna</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurischev</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental Exploration of Quantum Correlations: Discord versus
  Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This article has been withdrawn due to the drawing up of a paper with
  additional upgrades and modifications. A new submission will be performed at
  a later stage</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum correlations represent a fundamental tool for studies ranging from
basic science to quantum technologies. Different non-classical correlations
have been identified and studied, as entanglement and discord. In view of
future applications in this letter we explore experimentally the rich geometry
of Bell-diagonal states, measuring the values of entanglement and discord and
highlighting the effect of decoherence in real experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03597</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03597</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ziqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Doublon-holon binding as origin of Mott transition and fractionalized
  spin liquid -- Asymptotic solution of the Hubbard model in the limit of large
  coordination</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Revised Version, 5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An analytical solution of the Mott transition is obtained for the Hubbard
model on the Bethe lattice in the large coordination number ($z$) limit. The
excitonic binding of doublons (doubly occupied sites) and holons (empty sites)
is shown to be the origin of a continuous Mott transition between a metal and
an emergent quantum spin liquid insulator. The doublon-holon binding theory
enables a different large-$z$ limit and a different phase structure than the
dynamical meanfield theory by allowing intersite spinon correlations to lift
the $2^N$-fold degeneracy of the local moments in the insulating phase. We show
that the spinons are coupled to doublons/holons by a dissipative compact U(1)
gauge field that is in the deconfined phase, stabilizing the spin-charge
separated gapless spin liquid Mott insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03920</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bakas</keyname><forenames>Ioannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastras</keyname><forenames>Georgios</forenames></author></authors><title>On Elliptic String Solutions in AdS(3) and dS(3)</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>60 pages, 13 figures, v2: version to appear in JHEP after minor
  corrections</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1607 (2016) 070</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical string actions in AdS(3) and dS(3) can be connected to the
sinh-Gordon and cosh-Gordon equations through Pohlmeyer reduction. We show that
the problem of constructing a classical string solution with a given static or
translationally invariant Pohlmeyer counterpart is equivalent to solving four
pairs of effective Schrodinger problems. Each pair consists of a flat potential
and an n = 1 Lame potential whose eigenvalues are connected, and, additionally,
the four solutions satisfy a set of constraints. An approach for solving this
system is developed by employing an interesting connection between the specific
class of classical string solutions and the band structure of the Lame
potential. This method is used for the construction of several families of
classical string solutions, one of which turns out to be the spiky strings in
AdS(3). New solutions include circular rotating strings in AdS(3) with singular
time evolution of their radius and angular velocity as well as classical string
solutions in dS(3).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04159</id><created>2016-05-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Vacchini</keyname><forenames>Bassano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amato</keyname><forenames>Giulio</forenames></author></authors><title>Reduced dynamical maps in the presence of initial correlations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. vol. 6, 37328 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep37328</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a general framework for the construction of completely positive
dynamical evolutions in the presence of system-environment initial
correlations. The construction relies upon commutativity of the compatibility
domain obtained by considering the marginals with respect to the environmental
degrees of freedom of the considered class of correlated states. Our approach
allows to consider states whose discord is not necessarily zero and explicitly
show the non-uniqueness of the completely positive extensions of the obtained
dynamical map outside the compatibility domain. The relevance of such maps for
the treatment of open quantum system dynamics is discussed and connection to
previous literature is critically assessed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04860</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04860</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernando</keyname><forenames>Sharmanthie</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions of black holes in massive gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted to be published in Modern Physics Letters A. Three more
  references added</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Lettets A, Vol.31, No. 16, 1650096 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316500966</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we have studied thermodynamics of a black hole in massive
gravity in the canonical ensemble. The massive gravity theory in consideration
here has a massive graviton due to Lorentz symmetry breaking. The black hole
studied here has a scalar charge due to the massive graviton and is
asymptotically anti-de Sitter. We have computed various thermodynamical
quantities such as temperature, specific heat and free energy. Both the local
and global stability of the black hole are studied by observing the behavior of
the specific heat and the free energy. We have observed that there is a first
order phase transition between small and large black hole for a certain range
of the scalar charge. This phase transition is similar to the liquid/gas phase
transition at constant temperature for a Van der Waals fluid. The coexistence
curves for the small and large black hole branches are also discussed in
detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06098</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06098</id><created>2016-05-19</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jensen</keyname><forenames>Kristan</forenames></author></authors><title>Chaos in AdS$_2$ holography</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>11 pages; v2: minor improvements; v3: fixed typos, changed title to
  match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 111601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.111601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit AdS$_2$ holography with the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev models in mind. Our
main result is to rewrite a generic theory of gravity near an AdS$_2$ throat as
a novel hydrodynamics coupled to the correlation functions of a conformal
quantum mechanics. This gives a prescription for the computation of $n$-point
functions in the dual quantum mechanics. We thereby find that the dual is
maximally chaotic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06843</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06843</id><created>2016-05-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Shinzato</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Portfolio Optimization Problem with Non-identical Variances of Asset
  Returns using Statistical Mechanical Informatics</title><categories>q-fin.PM cond-mat.dis-nn math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>11 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062102</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The portfolio optimization problem in which the variances of the return rates
of assets are not identical is analyzed in this paper using the methodology of
statistical mechanical informatics, specifically, replica analysis. We define
two characteristic quantities of an optimal portfolio, namely, minimal
investment risk and concentrated investment level, in order to solve the
portfolio optimization problem and analytically determine their asymptotical
behaviors using replica analysis. Moreover, numerical experiments were
performed, and a comparison between the results of our simulation and those
obtained via replica analysis validated our proposed method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06902</id><created>2016-05-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Teo</keyname><forenames>Yong Siah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mogilevtsev</keyname><forenames>Dmitri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhalychev</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rehacek</keyname><forenames>Jaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hradil</keyname><forenames>Zdenek</forenames></author></authors><title>Crystallizing highly-likely subspaces that contain an unknown quantum
  state of light</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, submitted to Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 38123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep38123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In continuous-variable tomography, with finite data and limited computation
resources, reconstruction of a quantum state of light is performed on a
finite-dimensional subspace. No systematic method was ever developed to assign
such a reconstruction subspace---only ad hoc methods that rely on
hard-to-certify assumptions about the source and strategies. We provide a
straightforward and numerically feasible procedure to uniquely determine the
appropriate reconstruction subspace for any given unknown quantum state of
light and measurement scheme. This procedure makes use of the celebrated
statistical principle of maximum likelihood, along with other validation tools,
to grow an appropriate seed subspace into the optimal reconstruction subspace,
much like the nucleation of a seed into a crystal. Apart from using the
available measurement data, no other spurious assumptions about the source or
ad hoc strategies are invoked. As a result, there will no longer be
reconstruction artifacts present in state reconstruction, which is a usual
consequence of a bad choice of reconstruction subspace. The procedure can be
understood as the maximum-likelihood reconstruction for quantum subspaces,
which is an analog to, and fully compatible with that for quantum states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07858</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-10-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Usenko</keyname><forenames>Sergey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;ler</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Azima</keyname><forenames>Armin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jakob</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazzarino</keyname><forenames>Leslie L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlyukh</keyname><forenames>Yaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przystawik</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drescher</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laarmann</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berakdar</keyname><forenames>Jamal</forenames></author></authors><title>Femtosecond dynamics of correlated many-body states in C$_{60}$
  fullerenes</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><comments>20 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 113055 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/11/113055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Fullerene complexes may play a key role in the design of future molecular
electronics and nanostructured devices with potential applications in light
harvesting using organic solar cells. Charge and energy flow in these systems
is mediated by many-body effects. We studied the structure and dynamics of
laser-induced multi-electron excitations in isolated C$_{60}$ by two-photon
photoionization as a function of excitation wavelength using a tunable fs UV
laser and developed a corresponding theoretical framework on the basis of
\emph{ab initio} calculations. The measured resonance line width gives direct
information on the excited state lifetime. From the spectral deconvolution we
derive a lower limit for purely electronic relaxation on the order of
$\tau_\mathrm{el}=10^{+5}_{-3}$ fs. Energy dissipation towards nuclear degrees
of freedom is studied in time-resolved techniques. The evaluation of the
non-linear autocorrelation trace gives a characteristic time constant of
$\tau_\mathrm{vib}=400\pm100$ fs for the exponential decay. In line with the
experiment, the observed transient dynamics is explained theoretically by
nonadiabatic (vibronic) couplings involving the correlated electronic, the
nuclear degrees of freedom (accounting for the Herzberg-Teller coupling), and
their interplay.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01375</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01375</id><created>2016-06-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Logan</keyname><forenames>David E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galpin</keyname><forenames>Martin R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mannouch</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Mott transitions in the Periodic Anderson Model</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>20 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28, 455601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/45/455601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The periodic Anderson model (PAM) is studied within the framework of
dynamical mean-field theory, with particular emphasis on the interaction-driven
Mott transition it contains, and on resultant Mott insulators of both
Mott-Hubbard and charge-transfer type. The form of the PAM phase diagram is
first deduced on general grounds using two exact results, over the full range
of model parameters and including metallic, Mott, Kondo and band insulator
phases.The effective low-energy model which describes the PAM in the vicinity
of a Mott transition is then shown to be a one-band Hubbard model, with
effective hoppings that are not in general solely nearest neighbour, but decay
exponentially with distance. This mapping is shown to have a range of
implications for the physics of the problem, from phase boundaries to
single-particle dynamics; all of which are confirmed and supplemented by NRG
calculations. Finally we consider the locally degenerate, non-Fermi liquid Mott
insulator, to describe which requires a two-self-energy description. This is
shown to yield a number of exact results for the associated local moment,
charge, and interaction-renormalised levels, together with a generalisation of
Luttinger's theorem to the Mott insulator.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06113</id><created>2016-06-20</created><updated>2016-11-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saka</keyname><forenames>Yasushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacPherson</keyname><forenames>Murray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giuraniuc</keyname><forenames>Claudiu V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation and precise control of dynamic biochemical gradients for
  cellular assays</title><categories>q-bio.QM physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Main text 18 pages (7 figures), Supplementary information 10 pages (7
  supplementary figures)</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 470 (2017) 132-145</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.11.134</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spatial gradients of diffusible signalling molecules play crucial roles in
controlling diverse cellular behaviour such as cell differentiation, tissue
patterning and chemotaxis. In this paper, we report the design and testing of a
microfluidic device for diffusion-based gradient generation for cellular
assays. A unique channel design of the device eliminates cross-flow between the
source and sink channels, thereby stabilising gradients by passive diffusion.
The platform also enables quick and flexible control of chemical concentration
that makes highly dynamic gradients in diffusion chambers. A model with the
first approximation of diffusion and surface adsorption of molecules
recapitulates the experimentally observed gradients. Budding yeast cells
cultured in a gradient of a chemical inducer expressed a reporter fluorescence
protein in a concentration-dependent manner. This microfluidic platform serves
as a versatile prototype applicable to a broad range of biomedical
investigations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06738</id><created>2016-06-21</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Jong Soo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rolbiecki</keyname><forenames>Krzysztof</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruiz</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tattersall</keyname><forenames>Jamie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>Torsten</forenames></author></authors><title>Prospects for natural SUSY</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>19 pages, 13 figures, minor changes, Phys.Rev.D version</comments><report-no>IFT-16-054, TTK-16-17</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 095013 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.095013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As we anticipate the first results of the 2016 run, we assess the discovery
potential of the LHC to `natural supersymmetry'. To begin with, we explore the
region of the model parameter space that can be excluded with various
centre-of-mass energies (13 TeV and 14 TeV) and different luminosities (20
fb$^{-1}$, 100 fb$^{-1}$, 300 fb$^{-1}$ and 3000 fb$^{-1}$). We find that the
bounds at 95% CL on stops vary from $m_{\tilde{t}_1}\gtrsim 900$ GeV expected
this summer to $m_{\tilde{t}_1}\gtrsim 1500$ GeV at the end of the high
luminosity run, while gluino bounds are expected to range from
$m_{\tilde{g}}\gtrsim 1700$ GeV to $m_{\tilde{g}}\gtrsim 2500$ GeV over the
same time period. However, more pessimistically we find that if no signal
begins to appear this summer, only a very small region of parameter space can
be discovered with 5-$\sigma$ significance. For this conclusion to change, we
find that both theoretical and systematic uncertainties will need to be
significantly reduced.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07897</id><created>2016-06-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Hendrik M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Breyer</keyname><forenames>Moritz</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xf6;hl</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Monolayer graphene as dissipative membrane in an optical resonator</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. B, 122:290 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00340-016-6564-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally demonstrate coupling of an atomically thin, free-standing
graphene membrane to an optical cavity. By changing the position of the
membrane along the standing-wave field of the cavity we tailor the dissipative
coupling between the membrane and the cavity, and we show that the dissipative
coupling can outweigh the dispersive coupling. Such a system, for which
controlled dissipation prevails dispersion, will prove useful for novel
laser-cooling schemes in optomechanics. In addition, we have determined the
continuous-wave optical damage threshold of free-standing monolayer graphene of
1.8(4)~MW/cm$^2$ at 780nm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09356</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mi</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jianli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>West</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldwin</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chi</forenames></author></authors><title>Photovoltage Detection of Edge Magnetoplasmon Oscillations and Giant
  Magnetoplasmon Resonances in A Two-Dimensional Hole System</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 125411 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.125411</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In our high mobility p-type AlGaAs/GaAs two-dimensional hole samples, we
originally observe the B-periodic oscillation induced by microwave (MW) in
photovoltage (PV) measurements. In the frequency range of our measurements (5 -
40 GHz), the period ({\Delta}B) is inversely proportional to the microwave
frequency (f). The distinct oscillations come from the edge magnetoplasmon
(EMP) in the high quality heavy hole system. In our hole sample with a very
large effective mass, the observation of the EMP oscillations is in neither the
low frequency limit nor the high frequency limit, and the damping of the EMP
oscillations is very weak under high magnetic fields. Simultaneously, we
observe the giant plasmon resonance signals in our measurements on the shallow
two-dimensional hole system (2DHS).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00764</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00764</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hindmarsh</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rummukainen</keyname><forenames>Kari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weir</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>New solutions for non-Abelian cosmic strings</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures. We dedicate this paper to Tom Kibble; v2: some
  references added, typos fixed, phrasing changed in places; accepted by PRL</comments><report-no>HIP-2016-21/TH</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 251601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.251601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the properties of classical vortex solutions in a non-Abelian gauge
theory. A system of two adjoint Higgs fields breaks the SU(2) gauge symmetry to
$Z_2$, producing 't Hooft-Polyakov monopoles trapped on cosmic strings, termed
beads; there are two charges of monopole and two degenerate string solutions.
The strings break an accidental discrete $Z_2$ symmetry of the theory,
explaining the degeneracy of the ground state. Further symmetries of the model,
not previously appreciated, emerge when the masses of the two adjoint Higgs
fields are degenerate. The breaking of the enlarged discrete symmetry gives
rise to additional string solutions and splits the monopoles into four types of
`semipole': kink solutions that interpolate between the string solutions,
classified by a complex gauge invariant magnetic flux and a $Z_4$ charge. At
special values of the Higgs self-couplings, the accidental symmetry broken by
the string is continuous, giving rise to supercurrents on the strings. The
SU(2) theory can be embedded in a wide class of Grand Unified Theories,
including SO(10). We argue that semipoles and supercurrents are generic on GUT
strings.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05482</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Engelnkemper</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilczek</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurevich</keyname><forenames>Svetlana V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiele</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author></authors><title>Morphological transitions of sliding drops: Dynamics and bifurcations</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Fluids, 1:073901, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevFluids.1.073901</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study fully three-dimensional droplets that slide down an incline by
employing a thin-film equation that accounts for capillarity, wettability, and
a lateral driving force in small-gradient (or long-wave) approximation. In
particular, we focus on qualitative changes in the morphology and behavior of
stationary sliding drops. We employ the inclination angle of the substrate as
control parameter and use continuation techniques to analyze for several fixed
droplet sizes the bifurcation diagram of stationary droplets, their linear
stability, and relevant eigenmodes. The obtained predictions on existence
ranges and instabilities are tested via direct numerical simulations that are
also used to investigate a branch of time-periodic behavior (corresponding to
repeated breakup-coalescence cycles, where the breakup is also denoted as
pearling) which emerges at a global instability, the related hysteresis in
behavior, and a period-doubling cascade. The nontrivial oscillatory behavior
close to a Hopf bifurcation of drops with a finite-length tail is also studied.
Finally, it is shown that the main features of the bifurcation diagram follow
scaling laws over several decades of the droplet size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05616</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Delay</keyname><forenames>Erwann</forenames><affiliation>LMA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fougeirol</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xe9;mie</forenames><affiliation>LMA, IMAG</affiliation></author></authors><title>Hilbert manifold structure for asymptotically hyperbolic relativistic
  initial data</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a Hilbert manifold structure {\`a} la Bartnik for the space of
asymptotically hyperbolic initial data for the vacuum constraint equations. The
adaptation led us to prove new weighted Poincar{\'e} and Korn type inequalities
for AH manifolds with inner boundary and weakly regular metric.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06971</id><created>2016-07-23</created><updated>2016-11-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hammer</keyname><forenames>I. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanhart</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefediev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on meson loop effects on quark models</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>15 pages, 17 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 330</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16330-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of meson loops on the spectrum of quark states. We
demonstrate that in general quark states do not tend to get very broad if their
coupling to the continuum increases, but instead they decouple from the latter
in the large coupling limit. We ascribe this effect to the essentially
nonperturbative unitarization procedure involved. In the meantime, some quark
resonances behave very differently and demonstrate collectivity in the sense
that their pole trajectories span a wide, as compared to the level spacing,
region therefore acquiring contributions from multiple bare poles rather than
from the closest neighbors. While the actual calculations are done within
particular, very simplified models, it is argued that the findings might well
be general.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07372</id><created>2016-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jacobsen</keyname><forenames>Christian S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schafermeier</keyname><forenames>Clemens</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gehring</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weedbrook</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andersen</keyname><forenames>Ulrik L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Practical quantum computing on encrypted data</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Main text (6 pages) plus Appendices (14 pages), 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Comm. 7, 13795 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms13795</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ability to perform computations on encrypted data is a powerful tool for
protecting a client's privacy, especially in today's era of cloud and
distributed computing. In terms of privacy, the best solutions that classical
techniques can achieve are unfortunately not unconditionally secure in the
sense that they are dependent on a hacker's computational power. Here we
theoretically investigate, and experimentally demonstrate with Gaussian
displacement and squeezing operations, a quantum solution that achieves the
unconditional security of a user's privacy using the practical technology of
continuous variables. We demonstrate losses of up to 10 km both ways between
the client and the server and show that security can still be achieved. Our
approach offers a number of practical benefits, which can ultimately allow for
the potential widespread adoption of this quantum technology in future
cloud-based computing networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08118</id><created>2016-07-27</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wilczek</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chi</keyname><forenames>Lifeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thiele</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gurevich</keyname><forenames>Svetlana V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dip-coating with prestructured substrates: transfer of simple liquids
  and Langmuir-Blodgett monolayers</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter, 29:014002, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/29/1/014002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When a plate is withdrawn from a liquid bath, either a static meniscus forms
in the transition region between the bath and the substrate or a liquid film of
finite thickness (a Landau-Levich film) is transferred onto the moving
substrate. If the substrate is inhomogeneous, e.g., has a prestructure
consisting of stripes of different wettabilities, the meniscus can be deformed
or show a complex dynamic behavior. Here we study the free surface shape and
dynamics of a dragged meniscus occurring for striped prestructures with two
orientations, parallel and perpendicular to the transfer direction. A thin film
model is employed that accounts for capillarity through a Laplace pressure and
for the spatially varying wettability through a Derjaguin (or disjoining)
pressure. Numerical continuation is used to obtain steady free surface profiles
and corresponding bifurcation diagrams in the case of substrates with different
homogeneous wettabilities. Direct numerical simulations are employed in the
case of the various striped prestructures. The final part illustrates the
importance of our findings for particular applications that involve complex
liquids by modeling a Langmuir-Blodgett transfer experiment. There, one
transfers a monolayer of an insoluble surfactant that covers the surface of the
bath onto the moving substrate. The resulting pattern formation phenomena can
be crucially influenced by the hydrodynamics of the liquid meniscus that itself
depends on the prestructure on the substrate. In particular, we show how
prestructure stripes parallel to the transfer direction lead to the formation
of bent stripes in the surfactant coverage after transfer and present similar
experimental results.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01069</id><created>2016-08-02</created><updated>2016-12-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poulshock</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>An Abstract Model of Historical Processes</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theoretical model is presented which provides a way to simulate, at a very
abstract level, power struggles in the social world. In the model, agents can
benefit or harm each other, to varying degrees and with differing levels of
influence. The agents interact over time, using the power they have to try to
get more of it, while being constrained in their strategic choices by social
inertia. The outcomes of the model are probabilistic. More research is needed
to determine whether the model has any empirical validity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.01422</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.01422</id><created>2016-08-04</created><updated>2016-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Jounghun</forenames><affiliation>Seoul National University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yepes</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames><affiliation>Universidad Autonoma de Madrid</affiliation></author></authors><title>Turning Around along the Cosmic Web</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>accepted for publication in ApJ, revised version, minor mistakes
  corrected, 12 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys.J. 832 (2016) 185</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/832/2/185</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A bound-violation designates a case that the turn-around radius of a bound
object exceeds the upper limit put by the spherical collapse model based on the
standard $\Lambda$CDM paradigm. Given that the turn-around radius of a bound
object is a stochastic quantity and that the spherical model overly simplifies
the true gravitational collapse which actually proceeds anisotropically along
the cosmic web, the rarity of the occurrence of a bound violation may depend on
the web environment. Assuming a Planck cosmology, we numerically construct the
bound-zone peculiar velocity profiles along the cosmic web (filaments and
sheets) around the isolated groups with virial mass $M_{\rm v}\ge 3\times
10^{13}\,h^{-1}M_{\odot}$ identified in the Small MultiDark Planck simulations
and determine the radial distances at which their peculiar velocities equal the
Hubble expansion speed as the turn-around radii of the groups. It is found that
although the average turn-around radii of the isolated groups are well below
the spherical bound-limit on all mass scales, the bound violations are not
forbidden for individual groups and that the cosmic web has an effect of
reducing the rarity of the occurrence of a bound violation. Explaining that the
spherical bound limit on the turn-around radius in fact represents the
threshold distance up to which the intervention of the external gravitational
field in the bound-zone peculiar velocity profiles around the non-isolated
groups stays negligible, we discuss the possibility of using the threshold
distance scale to constrain locally the equation of state of dark energy .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03273</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03273</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Baffou</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Houndjo</keyname><forenames>M. J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tossa</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring stable models in $f(R; T; R_{\mu\nu} T^{\mu\nu})$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Astrophys Space Sci (2016) 361:1-8</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10509-016-2958-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine in this paper the stability analysis in $f(R; T;
R_{\mu\nu}T^{\mu\nu})$ modified gravity, where $R$ and $T$ are the Ricci scalar
and the trace of the energy-momentum tensor, respectively. By considering the
flat Friedmann universe, we obtain the corresponding generalized Friedmann
equations and we evaluate the geometrical and matter perturbation functions.
The stability is developed using the de Sitter and power-law solutions. We
search for application the stability of two particular cases of $f(R; T;
R_{\mu\nu}T^{\mu\nu})$ model by solving numerically the perturbation functions
obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05954</id><created>2016-08-21</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Apertet</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Causality in thermoelectric systems: Insights from block diagrams</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131: 434</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16434-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While Carnot's model engines demonstrate ideal performances regarding
conversion efficiency, they cannot be actually used as energy converters since
they are non causal systems. Such an unphysical behavior indeed restrains the
working conditions to a single point where, in the case of a refrigerator
(generator), the cooling power (output power) vanishes. Focusing on the example
of a thermoelectric refrigerator, we study the impact of different dissipation
sources on the causality of such systems. Basing our analysis on the block
diagram description of this system, we discuss particularly the fact that heat
conduction cannot ensure causality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.06786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.06786</id><created>2016-08-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Cobo</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eremin</keyname><forenames>Ilya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akbari</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic spin fluctuations in Sr$_2$RuO$_4$: role of spin-orbit
  coupling and induced strain</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 224507 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.224507</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the spin anisotropy of the magnetic susceptibility of Sr$_2$RuO$4$
in presence of spin-orbit coupling and anisotropic strain using
quasi-two-dimensional tight-binding parametrization fitted to the ARPES
results. Similar to the previous observations we find the in-plane polarization
of the low ${\bf q}$ magnetic fluctuations and the out-of-plane polarization of
the incommensurate magnetic fluctuation at the nesting wave vector ${\bf Q}_1 =
(2/3 \pi ,2/3 \pi)$ but also nearly isotropic fluctuations near ${\bf
Q}_2=(\pi/6,\pi/6)$. Furthermore, one finds that apart from the high-symmetry
direction of the tetragonal Brillouin zone the magnetic anisotropy is maximal,
i.e. $\chi^{xx} \neq \chi^{yy} \neq \chi^{zz}$. This is the consequence of the
orbital anisotropy of the $xz$ and $yz$ orbitals in the momentum space. We also
study how the magnetic anisotropy evolves in the presence of the strain and
find strong Ising-like ferromagnetic fluctuations near the Lifshitz transition
for the $xy$-band.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.00174</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.00174</id><created>2016-09-01</created><updated>2016-10-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Funo</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shitara</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>Work fluctuation and total entropy production in nonequilibrium
  processes</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Work fluctuation and total entropy production play crucial roles in small
thermodynamic systems subject to large thermal fluctuations. We investigate a
trade-off relation between them in a nonequilibrium situation in which a system
starts from an arbitrary nonequilibrium state. We apply the variational method
to study this problem and find a stationary solution against variations over
protocols that describe the time dependence of the Hamiltonian of the system.
Using the stationary solution, we find the minimum of the total entropy
production for a given amount of work fluctuation. An explicit protocol that
achieves this is constructed from an adiabatic process followed by a
quasi-static process. The obtained results suggest how one can control the
nonequilibrium dynamics of the system while suppressing its work fluctuation
and total entropy production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.01554</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.01554</id><created>2016-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Marelic</keyname><forenames>Jakov</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>Benjamin T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nyman</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase-space views into dye-microcavity thermalised and condensed photons</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A, vol. 94, 063812 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.063812</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We have observed momentum- and position-resolved spectra and images of the
photoluminescence from thermalised and condensed dye-microcavity photons. The
spectra yield the dispersion relation and the potential energy landscape for
the photons. From this dispersion relation, we find that the effective mass is
that of a free photon not a polariton. We place an upper bound on the
dimensionless two-dimensional interaction strength of $\tilde{g}\lesssim
10^{-3}$, which is compatible with existing estimates. Both photon-photon and
photon-molecule interactions are weak. The temperature is found to be
independent of momentum, but dependent on pump spot size, indicating that the
system is ergodic but not perfectly at thermal equilibrium. Condensation always
happens first in the mode with lowest potential and lowest kinetic energy,
although at very high pump powers multimode condensation occurs into other
modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06912</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06912</id><created>2016-09-22</created><updated>2016-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kotikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teber</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical behaviour of ($2+1$)-dimensional QED: $1/N_f$-corrections in an
  arbitrary non-local gauge</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>(v2) Accepted for publication in PRD. 8 pages, 2 figures; 2
  references added. (v1) LaTeX file with feynMF package. 6 pages, 2 figures;
  includes Supplemental Material (3 pages). arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1605.01911</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dynamical chiral symmetry breaking (D$\chi$SB) is studied within
($2+1$)-dimensional QED with $N$ four-component fermions. The leading and
next-to-leading orders of the $1/N$ expansion are computed exactly. The
analysis is carried out in an arbitrary non-local gauge. Resumming the
wave-function renormalization constant at the level of the gap equation yields
a strong suppression of the gauge dependence of the critical fermion flavour
number, $N_c(\xi)$ where $\xi$ is the gauge fixing parameter, which is such
that D$\chi$SB takes place for $N&lt;N_c(\xi)$. Neglecting the weak
gauge-dependent terms yields $N_c = 2.8469$ while, in the general case, it is
found that: $N_c(1) = 3.0084$ in the Feynman gauge, $N_c(0) = 3.0844$ in the
Landau gauge and $N_c(2/3)= 3.0377$ in the $\xi=2/3$ gauge where the leading
order fermion wave function is finite. These results suggest that D$\chi$SB
should take place for integer values $N \leq 3$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.00934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.00934</id><created>2016-10-04</created><updated>2016-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kotikov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teber</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical behaviour of reduced QED$_{4,3}$ and dynamical fermion gap
  generation in graphene</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>(v2) Accepted for publication in PRD. Short discussion and some
  references added at the end of Sec V (per referee's comments). No change in
  results. 7 pages. (v1) 7 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamical generation of a fermion gap in graphene is studied at the
infra-red Lorentz-invariant fixed point where the system is described by an
effective relativistic-like field theory: reduced QED$_{4,3}$ with $N$ four
component fermions ($N=2$ for graphene), where photons are $(3+1)$-dimensional
and mediate a fully retarded interaction among $(2+1)$-dimensional fermions. A
correspondence between reduced QED$_{4,3}$ and QED$_3$ allows us to derive an
exact gap equation for QED$_{4,3}$ up to next-to-leading order. Our results
show that a dynamical gap is generated for $\alpha &gt; \alpha_c$ where $1.03 &lt;
\alpha_c &lt; 1.08$ in the case $N=2$ or for $N &lt; N_c$ where $N_c$ is such that
$\alpha_c \to \infty$ and takes the values $3.24 &lt; N_c &lt; 3.36$. The striking
feature of these results is that they are in good agreement with values found
in models with instantaneous Coulomb interaction. At the fixed point: $\alpha =
1/137 \ll \alpha_c$, and the system is therefore in the semi-metallic regime in
accordance with experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.02429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.02429</id><created>2016-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Ben-Naim</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krapivsky</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetics of Aggregation with Choice</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 062119 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.062119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We generalize the ordinary aggregation process to allow for choice. In
ordinary aggregation, two random clusters merge and form a larger aggregate. In
our implementation of choice, a target cluster and two candidate clusters are
randomly selected, and the target cluster merges with the larger of the two
candidate clusters. We study the long-time asymptotic behavior, and find that
as in ordinary aggregation, the size density adheres to the standard scaling
form. However, aggregation with choice exhibits a number of novel features.
First, the density of the smallest clusters exhibits anomalous scaling. Second,
both the small-size and the large-size tails of the density are overpopulated,
at the expense of the density moderate-size clusters. We also study the
complementary case where the smaller candidate clusters participates in the
aggregation process, and find abundance of moderate clusters at the expense of
small and large clusters. Additionally, we investigate aggregation processes
with choice among multiple candidate clusters, and a symmetric implementation
where the choice is between two pairs of clusters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03562</id><created>2016-10-11</created><updated>2016-11-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gumrukcuoglu</keyname><forenames>A. Emir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koyama</keyname><forenames>Kazuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mukohyama</keyname><forenames>Shinji</forenames></author></authors><title>Role of matter in extended quasidilaton massive gravity</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>17 pages, accepted for publication in PRD</comments><report-no>Imperial-TP-2016-AEG-4, YITP-16-112, IPMU16-0145</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 123510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.123510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The extended quasidilaton theory is one of the simplest Lorentz-invariant
massive gravity theories which can accommodate a stable self-accelerating
vacuum solution. In this paper we revisit this theory and study the effect of
matter fields. For a matter sector that couples minimally to the physical
metric, we find hints of a Jeans type instability in the IR. In the analogue
k-essence field set-up, this instability manifests itself as an IR ghost for
the scalar field perturbation, but this can be interpreted as a classical
instability that becomes relevant below some momentum scale in terms of matter
density perturbations. We also consider the effect of the background evolution
influenced by matter on the stability of the gravity sector perturbations. In
particular, we address the previous claims of ghost instability in the IR
around the late time attractor. We show that, although the matter-induced
modification of the evolution potentially brings tension to the stability
conditions, one goes beyond the regime of validity of the effective theory well
before the solutions become unstable. We also draw attention to the fact that
the IR stability conditions are also enforced by the existence requirements of
consistent background solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06578</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06578</id><created>2016-10-20</created><updated>2016-10-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Okamoto</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames><affiliation>Hokkaido University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nagashima</keyname><forenames>Masahiro</forenames><affiliation>Bunkyo University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lacey</keyname><forenames>Cedric G.</forenames><affiliation>Durham University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Frenk</keyname><forenames>Carlos S.</forenames><affiliation>Durham University</affiliation></author></authors><title>The metal enrichment of passive galaxies in cosmological simulations of
  galaxy formation</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures, accepted for publication in MNRAS, added
  references</comments><journal-ref>Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 464, 4866-4874, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2729</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Massive early-type galaxies have higher metallicities and higher ratios of
$\alpha$ elements to iron than their less massive counterparts. Reproducing
these correlations has long been a problem for hierarchical galaxy formation
theory, both in semi-analytic models and cosmological hydrodynamic simulations.
We show that a simulation in which gas cooling in massive dark haloes is
quenched by radio-mode active galactic nuclei (AGNs) feedback naturally
reproduces the observed trend between $\alpha$/Fe and the velocity dispersion
of galaxies, $\sigma$. The quenching occurs earlier for more massive galaxies.
Consequently, these galaxies complete their star formation before $\alpha$/Fe
is diluted by the contribution from type Ia supernovae. For galaxies more
massive than $\sim 10^{11}~M_\odot$ whose $\alpha$/Fe correlates positively
with stellar mass, we find an inversely correlated mass-metallicity relation.
This is a common problem in simulations in which star formation in massive
galaxies is quenched either by quasar- or radio-mode AGN feedback. The early
suppression of gas cooling in progenitors of massive galaxies prevents them
from recapturing enriched gas ejected as winds. Simultaneously reproducing the
[$\alpha$/Fe]-$\sigma$ relation and the mass-metallicity relation is, thus,
difficult in the current framework of galaxy formation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.09122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.09122</id><created>2016-10-28</created><updated>2016-12-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Deflorian</keyname><forenames>Sergio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Efros</keyname><forenames>Victor D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leidemann</keyname><forenames>Winfried</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculation of the astrophysical S-factor S_12 with the Lorentz integral
  transform</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in Few-Body Syst.,
  corrected typos in text and in Eqs. (7), (11), (12), (15)</comments><journal-ref>Few-Body Syst (2017) 58: 3</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00601-016-1167-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The LIT approach is tested for the calculation of astrophysical S-factors. As
an example the S-factor of the reaction 2H(p,gamma)3He is considered. It is
discussed that a sufficiently high density of LIT states at low energies is
necessary for a precise determination of S-factors. In particular it is shown
that the hyperspherical basis is not very well suited for such a calculation
and that a different basis system is much more advantageous. A comparison of
LIT results with calculations, where continuum wave functions are explicitly
used, shows that the LIT approach leads to reliable results. It is also shown
how an error estimate of the LIT inversion can be obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.00701</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.00701</id><created>2016-11-02</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anand</keyname><forenames>Sampurn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Atreya</keyname><forenames>Abhishek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhatt</keyname><forenames>Jitesh R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological Implications of QGP Bulk Viscosity</title><categories>hep-ph gr-qc hep-th nucl-th</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn. The results presented were artifacts
  of an error in the numerical code</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies of the hot QCD matter indicate that the bulk viscosity
($\zeta$) of quark-gluon plasma (QGP) rises sharply near the critical point of
the QCD phase transition. In this work, we show that such a sharp rise of the
bulk viscosity will lead to an effective negative pressure near the critical
temperature, $T_{c}$ which in turn drives the Universe to inflate. This
inflation has a natural graceful exist when the viscous effect evanesce. We
estimate that, depending upon the peak value of $\zeta$, universe expands by a
factor of $10$ to $80$ times in a very short span ($\Delta t\sim 10^{-8}$
seconds). Another important outcome of the bulk viscosity dominated dynamics is
the cavitation of QGP around $T \sim 1.5T_{c}$. This would lead to the
phenomenon of formation of cavitation bubbles within the QGP phase. The above
scenario is independent of the order of QCD phase transition. We delineate some
of the important cosmological consequences of the inflation and the cavitation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01150</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01150</id><created>2016-11-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Vacchini</keyname><forenames>Bassano</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized master equations leading to completely positive dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, to appear on PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. vol. 117, 230401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.230401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide a general construction of quantum generalized master equations
with memory kernel leading to well defined, that is completely positive and
trace preserving, time evolutions. The approach builds on an operator
generalization of memory kernels appearing in the description of non-Markovian
classical processes, and puts into evidence the non uniqueness of the
relationship arising due to the typical quantum issue of operator ordering. The
approach provides a physical interpretation of the structure of the kernels,
and its connection with the classical viewpoint allows for a trajectory
description of the dynamics. Previous apparently unrelated results are now
connected in a unified framework, which further allows to phenomenologically
construct a large class of non-Markovian evolutions taking as starting point
collections of time dependent maps and instantaneous transformations describing
the microscopic interaction dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.05294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.05294</id><created>2016-11-16</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Buividovich</keyname><forenames>P. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valgushev</keyname><forenames>S. N.</forenames></author></authors><title>First experience with classical-statistical real-time simulations of
  anomalous transport with overlap fermions</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages PoS style, 6 figures, to appear in the proceedings of the
  Lattice 2016 conference (July 24-30, 2016, Southampton, UK); v2: references
  updated</comments><journal-ref>PoS(LATTICE2016)253</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present first results of classical-statistical real-time simulations of
anomalous transport phenomena with overlap fermions. We find that even on small
lattices overlap fermions reproduce the real-time anomaly equation with much
better precision than Wilson-Dirac fermions on an order of magnitude larger
lattices. The difference becomes much more pronounced for quickly changing
electromagnetic fields, especially if one takes into account the back-reaction
of fermions on electromagnetism. As test cases, we consider chirality pumping
in parallel electric and magnetic fields and mixing between the plasmon and the
Chiral Magnetic Wave.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07923</id><created>2016-11-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Elbistan</keyname><forenames>Mahmut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Pengming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balog</keyname><forenames>Janos</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective potential for relativistic scattering</title><categories>nucl-th hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider quantum inverse scattering with singular potentials and calculate
the Sine-Gordon model effective potential in the laboratory and centre-of-mass
frames. The effective potentials are frame dependent but closely resemble the
zero-momentum potential of the equivalent Ruijsenaars-Schneider model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.01780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.01780</id><created>2016-12-06</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thurgood</keyname><forenames>J. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsiklauri</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle-in-cell simulations of the relaxation of electron beams in
  inhomogeneous solar wind plasmas</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph astro-ph.SR physics.space-ph</categories><comments>Animations can be found at
  https://jonathanthurgood.wordpress.com/myresearch/thurgood-and-tsiklauri-2016-movies/</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Plasma Physics, Volume 82, Issue 6 December 2016,
  905820604</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/S0022377816000970</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Previous theoretical considerations of electron beam relaxation in
inhomogeneous plasmas have indicated that the effects of the irregular solar
wind may account for the poor agreement of homogeneous modelling with the
observations. Quasi-linear theory and Hamiltonian models based on Zakharov's
equations have indicated that when a level of density fluctuations is above a
given threshold, density irregularities act to de-resonate the beam-plasma
interaction, restricting Langmuir wave growth on the expense of beam energy.
This work presents the first fully kinetic particle-in-cell (PIC) simulations
of beam relaxation under the influence of density irregularities. We aim to
independently determine the influence of background inhomogeneity on the
beam-plasma system, and to test theoretical predictions and alternative models
using a fully kinetic treatment. We carry out 1D PIC simulations of a
bump-on-tail unstable electron beam in the presence of increasing levels of
background inhomogeneity using the fully electromagnetic, relativistic EPOCH
PIC code. We find that in the case of homogeneous background plasma density,
Langmuir wave packets are generated at the resonant condition and then
quasi-liear relaxation leads to a dynamic increase of wavenumbers generated. No
electron acceleration is seen - unlike in the inhomogeneous experiments, all of
which produce high-energy electrons. For the inhomogeneous experiments we also
observe the generation of backwards propagating Langmuir waves, which is shown
directly to be due to the refraction of the packets off the density gradients.
Our fully kinetic PIC simulations broadly confirm the findings of quasi-linear
theory and the Hamiltonian model based on Zakharov's equations. Strong density
fluctuations modify properties of excited Langmuir waves altering their
dispersion properties.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02463</id><created>2016-11-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jihui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Zhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Longfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Weibing</forenames></author></authors><title>Community detection by label propagation with compression of flow</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal B, 89(12), 1-11 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2016-70264-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The label propagation algorithm (LPA) has been proved to be a fast and
effective method for detecting communities in large complex networks. However,
its performance is subject to the non-stable and trivial solutions of the
problem. In this paper, we propose a modified label propagation algorithm LPAf
to efficiently detect community structures in networks. Instead of the majority
voting rule of the basic LPA, LPAf updates the label of a node by considering
the compression of a description of random walks on a network. A multi-step
greedy agglomerative strategy is employed to enable LPAf to escape the local
optimum. Furthermore, an incomplete update condition is also adopted to speed
up the convergence. Experimental results on both synthetic and real-world
networks confirm the effectiveness of our algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02568</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Rojas</keyname><forenames>Jorge</forenames><affiliation>Instituto de Astrof&#xed;sica de Canarias, Spain</affiliation><affiliation>Univ. La Laguna, Spain</affiliation></author></authors><title>Chemical abundances in Galactic planetary nebulae from faint emission
  lines</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Invited review in workshop &quot;Chemical abundances in ionized nebulae&quot;
  held in Campos do Jordao, Brazil between 3-5 November 2016. To be published
  in BAAA. G. H\&quot;agele, M. Cardaci and E. P\'erez-Montero eds. 10 pages, 2
  figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Deep spectrophotometry has proved to be a fundamental tool to improve our
knowledge on the chemical content of planetary nebulae. With the arrival of
very efficient spectrographs installed in the largest ground-based telescopes,
outstanding spectra have been obtained. These data are essential to constrain
state-of-the-art nucleosynthesis models in asymptotic giant branch stars and,
in general, to understand the chemical evolution of our Galaxy. In this paper
we review the last advances on the chemical composition of the ionized gas in
planetary nebulae based on faint emission lines observed through very deep
spectrophotometric data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03730</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03730</id><created>2016-11-28</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nemiroff</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemiroff</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author></authors><title>Dreidel Fairness Study</title><categories>physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 1 figure, 1 table, v2: 2 minor typos corrected, a serious
  study with a few humorous commments</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Are dreidels fair? In other words, does the average dreidel have an equal
chance of turning up any one of its four sides? To explore this hypothesis,
three different dreidels were each spun hundreds of times with the number of
occurrences of each side recorded. It was found that all three dreidels tested
-- a cheap plastic dreidel, an old wooden dreidel, and a dreidel that came
embossed with a picture of Santa Claus -- were not fair. Statistically, for
each dreidel, some sides came up significantly more often than others. Although
an unfair dreidel does not necessarily make the game itself unfair, it is
conjectured that hundreds of pounds of chocolate have been distributed during
Chanukah under false pretenses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03987</id><created>2016-12-12</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alarc&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valeriani</keyname><forenames>Chantal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagonabarraga</keyname><forenames>Ignacio</forenames></author></authors><title>Morphology of clusters of attractive dry and wet self-propelled
  spherical particle suspensions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Accepted in Soft Matter Journal</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01752E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to asses the effect of hydrodynamics in the assembly of active
attractive spheres, we simulate a semi-dilute suspension of attractive
self-propelled spherical particles in a quasi two dimensional geometry
comparing the case with and without hydrodynamics interactions. To start with,
independently on the presence of hydrodynamics, we observe that depending on
the ratio between attraction and propulsion, particles either coarsen or
aggregate forming finite-size clusters. Focusing on the clustering regime, we
characterize two different clusters parameters, i.e. their morphology and
orientational order, and compare the case when active particles behave either
as pushers or pullers (always in the regime where inter-particles attractions
competes with self-propulsion). Studying cluster phases for squirmers with
respect to those obtained for active Brownian disks (indicated as ABP), we have
shown that hydrodynamics alone can sustain a cluster phase of active swimmers
(pullers), while ABP form cluster phases due to the competition between
attraction and self propulsion. The structural properties of the cluster phases
of squirmers and ABP are similar, although squirmers show sensitivity to active
stresses. Active Brownian disks resemble weakly pusher squirmer suspensions in
terms of cluster size distribution, structure of the radius of gyration on
cluster size and degree of cluster polarity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04368</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Rychtarikova</keyname><forenames>Renata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>Georg</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Michael B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stys</keyname><forenames>Dalibor</forenames></author></authors><title>Information limits of optical microscopy: application to fluorescently
  labelled tissue section</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The article demonstrates some less known principles of image build-up in
diffractive microscopy and their usage in analysis unravelling the smallest
localized information about the original object - an electromagnetic centroid.
In fluorescence, the electromagnetic centroid is naturally at the position of
the fluorophore. The usage of an information-entropic variable - a point
divergence gain - is demonstrated for finding the most localized position of
the object's representation, generally of the size of a voxel (3D pixel). These
spatial pixels can be qualitatively classified and used for reconstruction of
the 3D structures with precision comparable with electron microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04369</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04369</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Diep</keyname><forenames>Hung The</forenames><affiliation>LPTM</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kaufman</keyname><forenames>Miron</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaufman</keyname><forenames>Sanda</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of two-group conflicts: A statistical physics model</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Physica A: Statistical Mechanics and its Applications, Elsevier,
  2017, 469, pp.183 - 199</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.10.072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a &quot;social physics&quot; model for two-group conflict. We consider two
disputing groups. Each individual i in each of the two groups has a preference
si regarding the way in which the conflict should be resolved. The individual
preferences span a range between +M (prone to protracted conflict) and --M
(prone to settle the conflict). The noise in this system is quantified by a
&quot;social temperature.&quot; Individuals interact within their group and with
individuals of the other group. A pair of individuals (i, j) within a group
contributes-si * sj to the energy. The inter-group energy of individual i is
taken to be proportional to the product between si and the mean value of the
preferences from the other group's members. We consider an equivalent-neighbor
Renyi-Erdos network where everyone interacts with everyone. We present some
examples of conflicts that may be described with this model.
  PACS numbers: 89.65.-s Social and economic system, 89.75.-k Complex systems,
05.90.+m Other topics in statistical physics, thermodynamics, and nonlinear
dynamical systems
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04382</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Bryant</keyname><forenames>B. Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poh</keyname><forenames>Zijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raby</keyname><forenames>Stuart</forenames></author></authors><title>Reheating and Leptogenesis after Pati-Salam F-term Subcritical Hybrid
  Inflation</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>44 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we extend the analysis of a Pati-Salam subcritical hybrid
$F$-term inflation model, proposed by two of us, by studying the reheating and
the baryogenesis (via leptogenesis) of the model. This SUSY GUT model is able
to fit low energy electroweak precision data, LHC data, $b$-physics data, in
addition to inflation observables such as the tensor-to-scalar ratio and the
scalar spectral index. The reheating mechanism of this model is instant
preheating due to the bosonic and fermionic broad parametric resonance, while
the baryon-to-entropy ratio is obtained from the CP asymmetric right-handed
(s)neutrinos decay. The phases in the neutrino Yukawa matrices are fixed by
fitting to the low energy observables. With these phases, the heaviest
right-handed (s)neutrinos decay to produce a lepton asymmetry with the correct
sign, while the two lighter right-handed (s)neutrinos decay to produce the
wrong sign. Consequently, the baryogenesis analysis is necessarily performed by
including all three families of the right-handed (s)neutrinos.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04398</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Magnuson</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mattesini</keyname><forenames>Maurizio</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical bonding and electronic-structure in MAX phases as viewed by
  X-ray spectroscopy and density functional theory</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>46 Pages, 23 Figures, 6 Tables</comments><journal-ref>Thin Solid Films. 621, 108-130 (2017).
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.tsf.2016.11.005</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.tsf.2016.11.005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a critical review of MAX-phase carbides and nitrides from an
electronic-structure and chemical bonding perspective. This large group of
nanolaminated materials is of great scientific and technological interest and
exhibit a combination of metallic and ceramic features. These properties are
related to the special crystal structure and bonding characteristics with
alternating strong M-C bonds in high-density MC slabs, and relatively weak M-A
bonds between the slabs. Here, we review the trend and relationship between the
chemical bonding, conductivity, elastic and magnetic properties of the MAX
phases in comparison to the parent binary MX compounds with the underlying
electronic structure probed by polarized X-ray spectroscopy. Spectroscopic
studies constitute important tests of the results of state-of-the-art
electronic structure density functional theory that is extensively discussed
and are generally consistent. By replacing the elements on the M, A, or X-sites
in the crystal structure, the corresponding changes in the conductivity,
elasticity, magnetism and other materials properties makes it possible to
tailor the characteristics of this class of materials by controlling the
strengths of their chemical bonds.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04429</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04429</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Acosta-Hum&#xe1;nez</keyname><forenames>Primitivo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giraldo</keyname><forenames>Hern&#xe1;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piedrahita</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Differential Galois Groups and Representation of Quivers for Seismic
  Models with Constant Hessian of Square of Slowness</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><msc-class>12H05, 16G20, 34E05, 34E20, 35C20, 35Q60, 35L05, 86A15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The trajectory of energy is modeled by the solution of the Eikonal equation,
which can be solved by solving a Hamiltonian system. This system is amenable of
treatment from the point view of the theory of Differential Algebra. In
particular, by Morales-Ramis theory it is possible to analyze integrable
Hamiltonian systems through the abelian structure of their variational
equations. In this paper we obtain the abelian differential Galois groups and
the representation of the quiver, that allow us to obtain such abelian
differential Galois groups, for some seismic models with constant Hessian of
square of slowness, proposed in Cerveny 2001, which are equivalent to linear
Hamiltonian systems with three uncoupled harmonic oscillators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04434</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04434</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Arkhipov</keyname><forenames>Ievgen I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pe&#x159;ina</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames><suffix>Jr.</suffix></author><author><keyname>Haderka</keyname><forenames>Ond&#x159;ej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mich&#xe1;lek</keyname><forenames>V&#xe1;clav</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental detection of nonclassicality of single-mode fields via
  intensity moments</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Express 24, 29496-29505 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OE.24.029496</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonclassicality criteria based on intensity moments and derived from the
usual matrix approach are compared to those provided by the majorization
theory. The majorization theory is shown to give a greater number of more
suitable nonclassicality criteria. Fifteen experimentally useful criteria of
the majorization theory containing the intensity moments up to the fifth order
are identified. Their performance is experimentally demonstrated on the set of
eleven potentially nonclassical states generated from a twin beam by
postselection based on detecting a given number of photocounts in one arm by
using an iCCD camera.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04436</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04436</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Cartas-Fuentevilla</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Escalante-Hernandez</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrera-Aguilar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Hyperbolic deformation of a gauge field theory and the hierarchy problem</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>34 pages in latex, 21 figures</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. A31 (2016) no.34, 1650177</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16501773</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The problem of the gauge hierarchy is brought up in a hypercomplex scheme for
a U(1) field theory; in such a scheme a compact gauge group is deformed through
a \gamma-parameter that varies along a non-compact internal direction,
transverse to the U(1) compact one, and thus an additional SO(1,1) gauge
symmetry is incorporated. This transverse direction can be understood as an
extra internal dimension, which will control the spontaneous symmetry
breakdown, and will allow us to establish a mass hierarchy. In this mechanism
there is no brane separation to be stabilized as in the braneworld paradigm,
however, a different kind of fine-tuning is needed in order to generate the
wished electroweak/Planck hierarchy. By analyzing the effective
self-interactions and mass terms of the theory, an interesting duality is
revealed between the real and hybrid parts of the effective potential. This
duality relates the weak and strong self-interaction regimes of the theory, due
to the fact that both mass terms and self-coupling constants appear as
one-parameter flows in \gamma. Additionally the \gamma-deformation will
establish a flow for the electromagnetic coupling that mimics the
renormalization group flow for the charge in QED.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04444</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Zuhuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yajun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Sui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares</keyname><forenames>Julio A N T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Apgar</keyname><forenames>Brent A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Ran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Ruijuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Yeonbae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>Lane W</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Assembled, Nanostructured, Tunable Metamaterials via Spinodal
  Decomposition</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>30 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>ACS Nano, 10, 10237 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acsnano.6b05736</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Self-assembly via nanoscale phase-separation offers an elegant route to
fabricate nanocomposites with physical properties unattainable in
single-component systems. One important class of nanocomposites are optical
metamaterials which exhibit exotic properties and lead to opportunities for
agile control of light propagation. Such metamaterials are typically fabricated
via expensive and hard-to-scale top-down processes requiring precise
integration of dissimilar materials. In turn, there is a need for alternative,
more efficient routes to fabricate large-scale metamaterials for practical
applications with deep-subwavelength resolution. Here, we demonstrate a
bottom-up approach to fabricate scalable nanostructured metamaterials via
spinodal decomposition. To demonstrate the potential of such an approach, we
leverage the innate spinodal decomposition of the VO2-TiO2 system, the
metal-to-insulator transition in VO2, and thin-film epitaxy, to produce
self-organized nanostructures with coherent interfaces and a structural unit
cell down to 15 nm (tunable between horizontally- and vertically-aligned
lamellae) wherein the iso-frequency surface is temperature-tunable from
elliptic- to hyperbolic-dispersion producing metamaterial behavior. These
results provide an efficient route for the fabrication of nanostructured
metamaterials and other nanocomposites for desired functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04446</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04446</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>Mamata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>A M</forenames></author></authors><title>Transport coherence in a time-asymmetric rocked ratchet model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>8 pages, 8figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the dynamics of an over damped Brownian particle in a saw tooth
potential in the presence of a temporal asymmetric driving force. We observe
that in the deterministic limit, the transport coherence, which is determined
by a dimensionless quantity called Peclet number, $Pe$ is quite high for larger
spatial asymmetry in the ratchet potential. For all the regime of parameter
space of this model, $Pe$ follows the nature of current like Stokes efficiency.
Diffusion as a function of amplitude of drive shows a minimum exactly at which
the current shows a maximum. Unlike the previously studied models, the $Pe$ as
a function of temperature shows a peaking behavior and the coherence in
transport decreases for high temperatures. In the nonadiabatic regime, the $Pe$
as a function of amplitude of drive decreases and the peak gets broader as a
result the transport becomes unreliable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04455</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04455</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yu-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Yu-Hsin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yung-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Shih-Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuo</keyname><forenames>Chie-Tong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Ming-Yen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Yung-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hsieh</keyname><forenames>Ya-Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hsiang-Chen</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanostructure analysis of InGaN/GaN quantum wells based on
  semi-polar-faced GaN nanorods</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.optics</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate a series of InGaN/GaN double quantum well nanostructure
elements. We grow a layer of 2 {\mu}m undoped GaN template on top of a
(0001)-direction sapphire substrate. A 100 nm SiO2 thin film is deposited on
top as a masking pattern layer. This layer is then covered with a 300 nm
aluminum layer as the anodic aluminum oxide (AAO) hole pattern layer. After
oxalic acid etching, we transfer the hole pattern from the AAO layer to the
SiO2 layer by reactive ion etching. Lastly, we utilize metal-organic chemical
vapor deposition to grow GaN nanorods approximately 1.5 {\mu}m in size. We then
grow two layers of InGaN/GaN double quantum wells on the semi-polar face of the
GaN nanorod substrate under different temperatures. We then study the
characteristics of the InGaN/GaN quantum wells formed on the semi-polar faces
of GaN nanorods. We report the following findings from our study: first, using
SiO2 with repeating hole pattern, we are able to grow high-quality GaN nanorods
with diameters of approximately 80-120 nm; second, photoluminescence (PL)
measurements enable us to identify Fabry-Perot effect from InGaN/GaN quantum
wells on the semi-polar face. We calculate the quantum wells' cavity thickness
with obtained PL measurements. Lastly, high resolution TEM images allow us to
study the lattice structure characteristics of InGaN/GaN quantum wells on GaN
nanorod and identify the existence of threading dislocations in the lattice
structure that affects the GaN nanorod's growth mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04465</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Knutson</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zinn-Justin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Grassmann-Grassmann conormal varieties, integrability, and plane
  partitions</title><categories>math.AG math-ph math.CO math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give a conjectural formula for sheaves supported on (irreducible) conormal
varieties inside the cotangent bundle of the Grassmannian, such that their
equivariant $K$-class is given by the partition function of an integrable loop
model, and furthermore their $K$-theoretic pushforward to a point is a solution
of the level $1$ quantum Knizhnik-Zamolodchikov equation. We prove these
results in the case that the Lagrangian is smooth (hence is the conormal bundle
to a subGrassmannian). To compute the pushforward to a point, or equivalently
to the affinization, we simultaneously degenerate the Lagrangian and sheaf
(over the affinization); the sheaf degenerates to a direct sum of cyclic
modules over the geometric components, which are in bijection with plane
partitions, giving a geometric interpretation to the Razumov-Stroganov
correspondence satisfied by the loop model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04477</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04477</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Putnam</keyname><forenames>Gray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Guin-Dar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yelin</keyname><forenames>Susanne</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective induced superradiant lineshifts</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superradiant decay is accompanied by two kinds of collective lineshifts, an
induced shift and the spontaneous &quot;collective Lamb shift.&quot; Both form as sum of
dipole-dipole interaction-induced level shifts between atoms in the system. We
have developed a procedure to obtain numerical results on this model that
self-consistently incorporates the shifts. The induced shift displays large
non-zero values early in the system evolution. In addition, its effect on the
superradiant system is studied: there is only a very small dephasing effect on
the decay rate. While the induced shift is largely absent in not-too strongly
driven systems, this parameter region might provide a good experimental regime
for measuring the collective Lamb shift. These results can have important
consequences for highly sensitive systems, such as quantum information science
or atomic clocks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04482</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Shi-Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Dong-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Bao-Sen</forenames></author></authors><title>Generation and reverse transformation of twisted light by spatial light
  modulator</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>primary manscript, comments are welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A spatial light modulator (SLM) is one of the most useful and convenient
device to generate structural light beams such as twisted light and complexed
images used in modern optical science. The unbounded dimension of twisted light
makes it promising in harnessing information carrying ability of a single
photon, which greatly enhances the channel capacity in optical communications.
We perform a detail theoretical study of the birth, evolution and reverse
transformation of twisted light generated from a phase-only SLM based on
diffraction theory, analytical expressions are obtained to show the special
evolution behaviors of the light beam with the propagation distance. Beam
intensity distributions calculated theoretically are in well agreement with
experimental observations. Our findings clearly reveal how twisted light
gradually emerges from a Gaussian spatial shape to a ring shape, and also the
ring shape will gradually evolve to a quasi-Gaussian shape conversely, in the
reverse transformation. These results will provide guidelines for using SLM in
many optical experiments and OAM-mode multiplexing in optical communications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04489</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Hintz</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear stability of the Kerr-Newman-de Sitter family of charged
  black holes</title><categories>math.AP gr-qc math-ph math.DG math.MP</categories><comments>111 pages, 8 figures</comments><msc-class>Primary 83C57, Secondary 83C22, 35B40, 83C35</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the global non-linear stability, without symmetry assumptions, of
slowly rotating charged black holes in de Sitter spacetimes in the context of
the initial value problem for the Einstein-Maxwell equations: If one perturbs
the initial data of a slowly rotating Kerr-Newman-de Sitter (KNdS) black hole,
then in a neighborhood of the exterior region of the black hole, the metric and
the electromagnetic field decay exponentially fast to their values for a
possibly different member of the KNdS family. This is a continuation of recent
work of the author with Vasy on the stability of the Kerr-de Sitter family for
the Einstein vacuum equations. Our non-linear iteration scheme automatically
finds the final black hole parameters as well as the gauge in which the global
solution exists; we work in a generalized wave coordinate/Lorenz gauge, with
gauge source functions lying in a suitable finite-dimensional space.
  We include a self-contained proof of the linear mode stability of
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om-de Sitter black holes, building on work by
Kodama-Ishibashi. In the course of our non-linear stability argument, we also
obtain the first proof of the linear (mode) stability of slowly rotating KNdS
black holes using robust perturbative techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04495</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04495</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fukazawa</keyname><forenames>Taro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Akai</keyname><forenames>Hisazumi</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimized effective potential method and application to static RPA
  correlation</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 pages, 3 figures. This is an author-created, un-copyedited version
  of an article accepted for publication in Journal of Physics: Condensed
  Matter. The publisher is not responsible for any errors or omissions in this
  version of the manuscript or any version derived from it. The Version of
  Record is available online at
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/27/11/115502</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 27 115502 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/27/11/115502</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The optimized effective potential (OEP) method is a promising technique for
calculating the ground state properties of a system within the density
functional theory. However, it is not widely used as its computational cost is
rather high and, also, some ambiguity remains in the theoretical framework. In
order to overcome these problems, we first introduced a method that accelerates
the OEP scheme in a static RPA-level correlation functional. Second, the
Krieger-Li-Iafrate (KLI) approximation is exploited to solve the OEP equation.
Although seemingly too crude, this approximation did not reduce the accuracy of
the description of the magnetic transition metals (Fe, Co, and Ni) examined
here, the magnetic properties of which are rather sensitive to correlation
effects. Finally, we reformulated the OEP method to render it applicable to the
direct RPA correlation functional and other, more precise, functionals.
Emphasis is placed on the following three points of the discussion: i)
Level-crossing at the Fermi surface is taken into account; ii) eigenvalue
variations in a Kohn-Sham functional are correctly treated; and iii) the
resultant OEP equation is different from those reported to date.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04497</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04497</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lofy</keyname><forenames>Josh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gasparian</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gevorkian</keyname><forenames>Zhyrair</forenames></author></authors><title>Complex Faraday and Kerr Rotations in Right and Left Handed Films</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By studying the rotations of the polarization of light propagating in right
and left handed films, with emphasis on the transmission (Faraday effect) and
reflec- tions (Kerr effect) of light and through the use of complex values
representing the rotations, it can be shown that the real portions of the
complex angle of Faraday and Kerr rotations are odd functions with respect to
the refractive index n and that the respective imaginary portions of the angles
are an even function of n. Multiple reflections within the medium lead to the
maximums of the real portions of Faraday and Kerr effects to not coincide with
zero ellipticity. It will also be shown that in the thin film case with left
handed materials there are large resonant enhancements of the reflected Kerr
angle that could be obtained experimentally.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04516</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kien</keyname><forenames>Fam Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rauschenbeutel</keyname><forenames>Arno</forenames></author></authors><title>Nanofiber-mediated chiral radiative coupling between two atoms</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 30 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the radiative coupling between two two-level atoms with
arbitrarily polarized dipoles in the vicinity of a nanofiber. We present a
systematic derivation for the master equation, the single- and cross-atom decay
coefficients, and the dipole-dipole interaction coefficients for the atoms
interacting with the vacuum of the field in the guided and radiation modes of
the nanofiber. We study numerically the case where the atomic dipoles are
circularly polarized. In this case, the rate of emission depends on the
propagation direction, that is, the radiative interaction between the atoms is
chiral. We examine the time evolution of the atoms for different initial
states. We calculate the fluxes and mean numbers of photons spontaneously
emitted into guided modes in the positive and negative directions of the fiber
axis. We show that the chiral radiative coupling modifies the collective
emission of the atoms. We observe that the modifications strongly depend on the
initial state of the atomic system, the radiative transfer direction, the
distance between the atoms, and the distance from the atoms to the fiber
surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04528</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04528</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zdravkovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zekovi&#x107;</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Applications of the series expansion unknown functions method in
  nonlinear dynamics of microtubules</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Microtubules (MTs) are the most important part of cytoskeleton. In this paper
we deal with two basic nonlinear differential equations coming from the two
known models describing nonlinear dynamics of MTs. These equations are solved
using the series expansion unknown functions method (SEUFM). Trying to
recognize the most general mathematical procedure for solving these equations
the solutions are compared with those obtained earlier using the tangent
hyperbolic function method (THFM) and the simplest equation method (SEM). In
all these three approaches we express the solutions of these equations as
series expansions. In the cases of THFM and SEM the functions existing in the
series are known while SEUFM assumes unknown functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04534</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Panda</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panigrahi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Mahesh K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Evidence of a proton halo in $^{23}$Al: A mean field analysis</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have studied the nuclear structure properties like binding energy, charge
radius, quadrupole deformation parameter for various isotopes of Al from the
valley of stability to drip line region using the well known relativistic mean
field formalism (RMF) with NL3 parameter set. We have compared our results with
experimental data and found reasonable agreement. Further, we have taken
spherical and deformed RMF densities to estimate the reaction dynamics of
$^{23-28}$Al isotopes as projectiles and $^{12}$C as target by conjunction in
Glauber model. The estimated results are also compared with the experimental
data. The analysis of angular elastic differential and one proton removal cross
sections are also studied with Glauber model many body system to investigate
the structural feature of $^{23}$Al. The evidence of enhanced total reaction
cross section, higher value of rms radius, narrow longitudinal momentum
distribution and small proton separation energy of $^{23}$Al support its proton
halo structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04537</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04537</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cleven</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magas</keyname><forenames>Volodymyr K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramos</keyname><forenames>Angels</forenames></author></authors><title>Properties of $J/\psi$ in light quark matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at VIII International Workshop On Charm Physics, Bologna,
  Italy; 5-9 September 2016; 6 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With various experiments studying heavy-ion collisions a demand exists in the
hadron physics community for theoretical predictions of hadronic properties at
temperatures and densities far from equilibrium. In this work we will study the
$J/\psi$ vector meson at finite temperatures surrounded by light quark matter.
We will apply a chiral unitary approach to account for coupled channels, most
importantly channels with open charm. The in-medium solution accounts for the
change in self-energy that the $J/\psi$ acquires from interacting with the
surrounding light quark matter, most notably pions and rho mesons. The results
are preliminary and clearly show the importance of using dressed charmed
mesons. Ultimately, the solutions to the corresponding Lippmann-Schwinger
Equations are used to calculate observables such as the spectral function of
the $J/\psi$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04544</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04544</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Naganawa</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Awano</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hino</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirose</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirota</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kawahara</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kitaguchi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishima</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagae</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shimizu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasaki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Umemoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A neutron detector with spatial resolution of submicron using
  fine-grained nuclear emulsion</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, proceedings of 8th International Topical Meeting
  on Neutron Radiography, ITMNR-8, 4-8 September 2016, Beijing, China. To be
  published by Physics Procedia</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have been developing a neutron detector with spatial resolution of
submicron by loading 6Li into fine-grained nuclear emulsion. By exposure to
thermal neutrons, tracks from neutron capture events were observed. From their
grain density, spatial resolution was estimated. Detection efficiency was also
measured by an experiment with cold neutrons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04547</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04547</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakare</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Study of Electric Quadrupole Perturbation at Multiple Probe Sites in
  Hf-doped Rutile in a Single Perturbed {\gamma}-{\gamma} Angular Correlation
  Measurement</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two different probes, viz., 111In/111Cd and 181Hf/181Ta, simultaneously have
been incorporated in both pure rutile and Hafnium (Hf) -doped rutile Titanium
Dioxide (TiO2) systems following a soft chemical method. The local information
around two different probe sites in the same sample could be extracted in a
single Time Differential Perturbed Angular Correlation (TDPAC) measurement
using LIST mode data acquisition. The two probes were incorporated in the
rutile samples by co-precipitation technique and then annealed at 1273K for 10h
to get the rutile structure. The rutile structure was identified by the
hyperfine parameters, viz., quadrupole frequency ({\omega}Q) and asymmetry
(eta). At 111Cd site, {\omega}Q=16.8(1) Mrad/s and eta=0.19(1) while at 181Ta
site, {\omega}Q=127.2(2) Mrad/s and eta=0.56(1). Due to the doping of Hf at 5
and 10 atom%, the sample partially lost the purity of the crystal and the fact
has been reflected at both the probe sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04552</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Kikuchi</keyname><forenames>Ken</forenames></author></authors><title>First-class constraints and the BV formalism</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>17 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Employing the Batalin-Vilkovisky (BV) formalism, we present a systematic and
simple prescription to derive (first-class) constraints including the
Hamiltonian constraint (a.k.a. flow equation), which plays pivotal role in
holographic computation of Weyl anomalies. In this method, you do not have to
compute canonical momenta nor Hamiltonians. Thus it may equip us with a
`Lagrangian treatment' of constrained systems. We also point out an interesting
analogy between antifields and first-class constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04565</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Maciel</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>R. D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavichia</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical abundances of photoionized nebulae in the Local Group</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 figures, 9 pages, proceedings of the Chemical Abundances in Gaseous
  Nebulae Workshop. To be published in AAA Workshop Series 12, 2016, G.
  H\&quot;agele, M. Cardaci &amp; E. P\'erez-Montero, eds, also available at
  http://www.astro.iag.usp.br/~maciel/research/research.html</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photoionized nebulae comprise basically HII regions and planetary nebulae,
and their abundances give important clues on the nucleosynthesis and chemical
evolution of their host galaxies. There is presently a large amount of data on
these objects, especially for the elements He and N, which are strongly
affected by the evolution of intermediate mass stars, as well as O, Ne, S, and
Ar, which are essentially synthesized in stars with larger masses. The
abundances of these elements in several systems in the Local Group are
discussed on the basis of distance-independent correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04575</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antoci</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korhonen</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jessen-Hansen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lehtinen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikbakhsh</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Viuho</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Do A-type stars flare?</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>19 pages, 17 figures, 9 tables, published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3226</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  For flares to be generated, stars have to have a sufficiently deep outer
convection zone (F5 and later), strong large--scale magnetic fields (Ap/Bp-type
stars) or strong, radiatively driven winds (B5 and earlier). Normal A-type
stars possess none of these and therefore should not flare. Nevertheless,
flares have previously been detected in the Kepler lightcurves of 33 A-type
stars and interpreted to be intrinsic to the stars. Here we present new and
detailed analyses of these 33 stars, imposing very strict criteria for the
flare detection. We confirm the presence of flare-like features in 27 of the 33
A-type stars. A study of the pixel data and the surrounding field-of-view (FOV)
reveals that 14 of these 27 flaring objects have overlapping neighbouring stars
and 5 stars show clear contamination in the pixel data. We have obtained
high-resolution spectra for 2/3 of the entire sample and confirm that our
targets are indeed A-type stars. Detailed analyses revealed that 11 out of 19
stars with multiple epochs of observations are spectroscopic binaries.
Furthermore, and contrary to previous studies, we find that the flares can
originate from a cooler, unresolved companion. We note the presence of
H$\alpha$ emission in eight stars. Whether this emission is circumstellar or
magnetic in origin is unknown. In summary, we find possible alternative
explanations for the observed flares for at least 19 of the 33 A-type stars,
but find no truly convincing target to support the hypothesis of flaring A-type
stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04580</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04580</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Leo</keyname><forenames>Yannick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleury</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarez-Hamelin</keyname><forenames>J. Ignacio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarraute</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karsai</keyname><forenames>M&#xe1;rton</forenames></author></authors><title>Socioeconomic correlations and stratification in social-communication
  networks</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Roy. Soc. Interface, 13 125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1098/rsif.2016.0598</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The uneven distribution of wealth and individual economic capacities are
among the main forces which shape modern societies and arguably bias the
emerging social structures. However, the study of correlations between the
social network and economic status of individuals is difficult due to the lack
of large-scale multimodal data disclosing both the social ties and economic
indicators of the same population. Here, we close this gap through the analysis
of coupled datasets recording the mobile phone communications and bank
transaction history of one million anonymised individuals living in a Latin
American country. We show that wealth and debt are unevenly distributed among
people in agreement with the Pareto principle; the observed social structure is
strongly stratified, with people being better connected to others of their own
socioeconomic class rather than to others of different classes; the social
network appears with assortative socioeconomic correlations and tightly
connected &quot;rich clubs&quot;; and that egos from the same class live closer to each
other but commute further if they are wealthier. These results are based on a
representative, society-large population, and empirically demonstrate some
long-lasting hypotheses on socioeconomic correlations which potentially lay
behind social segregation, and induce differences in human mobility.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04585</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Duclou&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lappi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe4;ntysaari</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Forward $J/\psi$ and $D$ meson nuclear suppression at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures. Hard Probes 2016 proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the color glass condensate formalism, we study the nuclear modification
of forward $J/\psi$ and $D$ meson production in high energy proton-nucleus
collisions at the LHC. We show that relying on the optical Glauber model to
obtain the dipole cross section of the nucleus from the one of the proton
fitted to HERA DIS data leads to a smaller nuclear suppression than in the
first study of these processes in this formalism and a better agreement with
experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04589</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04589</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Moreva</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramegna</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yurischev</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Exploring Quantum Correlations from Discord to Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum correlations represent a fundamental tool for studies ranging from
basic science to quantum technologies. Different non-classical correlations
have been identified and studied, as entanglement and discord. In this Paper we
explore experimentally the rich geometry of polarization Bell-diagonal states.
By taking advantage of the statistical method of generation, the values of
entanglement and discord along different trajectories in the space of the
parameters of density matrix have been measured. The effects of sudden death of
entanglement and complete &quot;freeze&quot; of discord were investigated in order to
detect the domains with different domination of one type of quantum correlation
against to other. A geometric interpretation for each considered phenomena is
addressed. The observed good agreement between experiment and theory for all
investigated trajectories ensures the reliability of this method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04591</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04591</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Messina</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millward</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buccino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Medhi</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jofre'</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrucci</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pi</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hambsch</keyname><forenames>F. -J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kehusmaa</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harlingten</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Artemenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Curtis</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hentunen</keyname><forenames>V. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malo</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Monard</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Serrano</keyname><forenames>M. Muro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naves</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santallo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savuskin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The beta Pictoris association: Catalog of photometric rotational periods
  of low-mass members and candidate members</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Forthcoming article, Received: 20 June 2016 / Accepted: 09 September
  2016; 40 pages, 2 figures. The online figures A1-A73 are available at CDS</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy and Astrophysics, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201629152</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We intended to compile the most complete catalog of bona fide members and
candidate members of the beta Pictoris association, and to measure their
rotation periods and basic properties from our own observations, public
archives, and exploring the literature. We carried out a multi-observatories
campaign to get our own photometric time series and collected all archived
public photometric data time series for the stars in our catalog. Each time
series was analyzed with the Lomb-Scargle and CLEAN periodograms to search for
the stellar rotation periods. We complemented the measured rotational
properties with detailed information on multiplicity, membership, and projected
rotational velocity available in the literature and discussed star by star. We
measured the rotation periods of 112 out of 117 among bona fide members and
candidate members of the beta Pictoris association and, whenever possible, we
also measured the luminosity, radius, and inclination of the stellar rotation
axis. This represents to date the largest catalog of rotation periods of any
young loose stellar association. We provided an extensive catalog of rotation
periods together with other relevant basic properties useful to explore a
number of open issues, such as the causes of spread of rotation periods among
coeval stars, evolution of angular momentum, and lithium-rotation connection.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04604</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Blake</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Germani</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perch</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pf&#xfc;tzner</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitehead</keyname><forenames>L. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>CHIPS Event Reconstruction and Design Optimisation</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>20 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The CHIPS experiment will comprise a 10 kton water Cherenkov detector in an
open mine pit in northern Minnesota, USA. The detector has been simulated using
a full GEANT4 simulation and a series of event reconstruction algorithms have
been developed to exploit the charge and time information from all of the PMTs.
A comparison of simulated CCQE nu_mu and nu_e interactions using 10 inch and 3
inch PMTs is presented, alongside a comparison of 10% and 6% photocathode
coverage for 3 inch PMTs. The studies demonstrate that the required selection
efficiency and purity of charged-current nu_e interactions can be achieved
using a photocathode coverage of 6% with 3 inch PMTs. Finally, a dedicated
pi-zero fitter is shown to successfully reconstruct a clean sample of pi-zero
mesons despite the low 6% photocathode coverage with 3 inch PMTs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04605</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Komm</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kocan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carralero</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stockel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herrmann</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panek</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>ExB analyzer for fast ion temperature measurements in scrape-off layer
  of the ASDEX Upgrade and COMPASS tokamaks</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ion temperature in the scrape-off layer is an important quantity but rarely
measured at high temporal resolution. In order to achieve fast measurements
during intermittent events such as blobs, a novel ExB analyzer has been
designed. The measurement with the E$\times$B analyzer does not require voltage
sweeping but records ion current on DC biased collectors, meaning that the
temporal resolution is only limited by the sampling frequency of the data
acquisition system and electronics of the amplifiers, which exceeds the typical
timescale of events of interest (~10 microseconds).
  The analyzer is equipped with entrance slit of optimized knife-edge shape,
which reduces selective ion losses and improves overall ion transmission. The
design of the analyzer is presented together with first acquired signals and
reconstructed temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04611</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04611</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Carusela</keyname><forenames>M. Florencia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rub&#xed;</keyname><forenames>J. Miguel</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic rectification and current inversion in a pulsating channel</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show the existence of a resonant behavior of the current of Brownian
particles confined in a pulsating channel. The interplay between the periodic
oscillations of the shape of the channel and a force applied along its axis
leads to an increase of the particle current as a function of the noise level.
A regime of current inversion is also observed for particular values of the
oscillation frequency and the applied force. The model proposed to obtain these
new behaviors of the current is based on the Fick-Jacobs equation in which the
entropic barrier and the effective diffusion coefficient depend on time. The
phenomenon observed could be used to optimize transport in microfluidic devices
or biological channels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04614</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04614</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Auger</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Del Tutto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ereditato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fleming</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goeldi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gramellini</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guenette</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ketchum</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kreslo</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laube</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorca</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luethi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>von Rohr</keyname><forenames>C. Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soleti</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Novel Cosmic Ray Tagger System for Liquid Argon TPC Neutrino Detectors</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Fermilab Short Baseline Neutrino (SBN) program aims to observe and
reconstruct thousands of neutrino-argon interactions with its three detectors
(SBND, MicroBooNE and ICARUS-T600), using their hundred of tonnes Liquid Argon
Time Projection Chambers to perform a rich physics analysis program, in
particular focused in the search for sterile neutrinos. Given the relatively
shallow depth of the detectors, the continuos flux of cosmic ray particles
which crossing their volumes introduces a constant background which can be
falsely identified as part of the event of interest. Here we present the Cosmic
Ray Tagger (CRT) system, a novel technique to tag and identify these crossing
particles using scintillation modules which measure their time and coordinates
relative to events internal to the neutrino detector, mitigating therefore
their effect in the event tracking reconstruction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04620</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Shutov</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larichkin</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shutov</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling of cyclic creep in the finite strain range using a nested
  multiplicative split</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>74C20, 74D10, 74E10, 74S05</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new phenomenological model of cyclic creep is proposed which is suitable
for applications involving finite creep deformations of the material. The model
accounts for the the effect of the transient increase of the creep strain rate
upon the load reversal. In order to extend the applicability range of the
model, the creep process is fully coupled to the classical Kachanov-Rabonov
damage evolution. As a result, the proposed model describes all the three
stages of creep. Large strain kinematics is described in a geometrically exact
manner using the assumption of a nested multiplicative split, originally
proposed by Lion for finite strain plasticity. The model is thermodynamically
admissible, objective, and w-invariant. Implicit time integration of the
proposed evolution equations is discussed. The corresponding numerical
algorithm is implemented into the commercial FEM code MSC.MARC. Using this
code, the model is validated using real experimental data on cyclic torsion of
a thick-walled tubular specimen made of the D16T aluminium alloy. The
numerically computed stress distribution exhibits a &quot;skeletal point&quot; within the
specimen.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04626</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04626</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Rajesh</keyname><forenames>Asam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bandyopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Malay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jayannavar</keyname><forenames>A. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Control of Decoherence in different environments : A case study for
  dissipative magneto-oscillator</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>18 Pages, 11 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we analyze two different techniques based on reservoir
engineering method and quantum Zeno effect for controlling decoherence of a
dissipative charged oscillator in the presence of an external magnetic field.
Our main focus is to investigate the sensitiveness of these decoherence control
techniques on the details of different environmental spectrum ($J(\omega)$),
and on the crucial role played by different system and reservoir parameters,
e.g., external magnetic field ($r_c$), confinement length ($r_0$), temperature
(T), cut-off frequency of reservoir spectrum ($\omega_{cut}$), and measurement
interval ($\tau$). First, we consider the charged quantum oscillator in an
initial nonclassical Schrodinger cat state and analyze the non-Markovian
dynamics for the magneto-oscillator in contact with Ohmic, sub-Ohmic, and
super-Ohmic environments. We show the procedure to control the quantumness of
the Schrodinger cat state by tuning the parameters $r_c$, $r_0$, and
$J(\omega)$. On the other hand, we investigate the effect of nonselective
energy measurement process on the mortification of quantumness of an initial
Fock-Darwin state of the charged magneto-oscillator. We investigate in details
the strategy to manipulate the continuous passage from decay suppression to
decay acceleration by engineered reservoirs and by tuning the system or
reservoir parameters, e.g., $r_c$, $r_0$, T or $\tau$. As a result of that one
can control environment induced decoherence (EID).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04628</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Shufang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Zheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>Honghua</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet control of the gain and loss in a PT-symmetric optical coupler</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Controlling the balanced gain and loss in a PT-symmetric system is a rather
challenging task. Utilizing Floquet theory, we explore the constructive role of
periodic modulation in controlling the gain and loss of a PT-symmetric optical
coupler. It is found that the gain and loss of the system can be manipulated by
applying a periodic modulation. Further, such an original non-Hermitian system
can even be modulated into an effective Hermitian system derived by the
high-frequency Floquet method. Therefore, compared with other PT symmetry
control schemes, our protocol can modulate the unbroken PT-symmetric range to a
wider parameter region. Our results provide a promising approach for
controlling the gain and loss of a realistic system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04633</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bourgeois</keyname><forenames>Olivier</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tainoff</keyname><forenames>Dimitri</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Tavakoli</keyname><forenames>Adib</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yanqing</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Blanc</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Boukhari</keyname><forenames>Mustapha</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Barski</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Hadji</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames><affiliation>SP2M - UMR 9002</affiliation></author></authors><title>Reduction of phonon mean free path: from low temperature physics to room
  temperature applications in thermoelectricity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Comptes Rendus Physique, Elsevier Masson, 2016, Thermoelectric
  mesoscopic phenomena / Ph{\'e}nom{\`e}nes thermo{\'e}lectriques
  m{\'e}soscopiques, 17, pp.1154</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been proposed for a long time now that the reduction of the thermal
conductivity by reducing the phonon mean free path is one of the best way to
improve the current performance of thermoelectrics. By measuring the thermal
conductance and thermal conductivity of nanowires and thin films, we show
different ways of increasing the phonon scattering from low temperature up to
room temperature experiments. It is shown that playing with the geometry
(constriction, periodic structures, nano-inclusions), from the ballistic to the
diffusive limit, the phonon thermal transport can be severely altered in single
crystalline semiconducting structures; the phonon mean free path being in
consequence reduced. The diverse implications on thermoelectric properties will
be eventually discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04634</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04634</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Fanbing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jian</forenames></author></authors><title>Electronic transport close to boundaries of semi-infinite graphene and
  their interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transport properties of 2D materials especially close to their boundary has
received much attention after the successful fabrication of graphene and other
fascinating materials afterwards. While most previous work is devoted to the
conventional lead-device-lead setup with a finite size center area, this
project investigates real space transport properties of infinite and
semi-infinite 2D system under the framework of Non-equilibrium Green function.
The commonly used method of calculating the Green function by inverting a
matrix in the real space directly can be unstable in dealing with large systems
as sometimes it gives non-converging result. Not to mention that the
calculation error and time increase drastically with size of the system. By
transforming from the real space to momentum space, we managed to replace the
matrix inverting process by Brillouin Zone integral process which can be
greatly simplified by the application of contour integral. Combining this
methodology with Dyson equations, we are able to calculate transport properties
of semi-infinite graphene close to its zigzag boundary and its combination with
other material including s-wave superconductor. Interference pattern of
transmitted and reflected electrons, graphene lensing effects and difference
between Specular Andreev reflection and normal Andreev reflection are verified
through our calculation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04643</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04643</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Alexey L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Traversable intra-Universe wormholes and timeholes in General
  Relativity: two new solutions</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>23 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 33 (2016) 225005</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/22/225005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using thin shell formalism we construct two solutions of intra-universe
wormholes. The first model is a cosmological analog of the Aichelburg-Schein
timehole, while another one is an intra-universe form of the Bronnikov-Ellis
solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04655</id><created>2016-12-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Berezowski</keyname><forenames>Marek</forenames></author></authors><title>Predictability of a system with transitional chaos</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chaotic Modeling and Simulation, An International Journal of
  Nonlinear Science, pp 43-50, 1, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The paper is focused on the discussion of the phenomenon of transitional
chaos in dynamic autonomous and non-autonomous systems. This phenomenon
involves the disappearance of chaotic oscillations in specific time periods and
the system becoming predictable. Variable dynamics of the system may be used to
control the process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04656</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04656</id><created>2016-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Qiu-he</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Men-quan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Chich-gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Origin of Strong Magnetic Fields of Magnetars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>four papgs, no figule</comments><journal-ref>Universal Journal of Physics and Application 10(3): 68-71, 2016
  http://www.hrpub.org</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since there is 3P2 neutron superfluid in neutron star interior, it can be
treated as a system of magnetic dipoles. Under the presence of background
magnetic field, the magnetic dipoles tend to align in the same direction. When
the temperature is lower than 10**7K, the strong magnetic fields of the
magnetars may originate from the induced magnetic moment of the 3P2 neutron
Cooper pairs in the anisotropic neutron superfluid. And this gives a convenient
explanation of the strong magnetic field of magnetars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04657</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04657</id><created>2016-12-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>Qiu-he</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chou</keyname><forenames>Chih-kang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Zhi-fu</forenames></author></authors><title>The Physics of Magnetars II - The Electron Fermi Energy of and the
  Origin of High X-ray Luminosity of Magnetars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, three figures</comments><journal-ref>Universal Journal of Physics and Application 10(3): 72-79, 2016</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we discuss in detail the quantization of Landau energy levels
of a strongly magnetized and completely degenerate relativistic electron gas in
neutron stars. In particular, we focus on the Fermi energy dependence of the
magnetic field for a relativistic electron gas in the superstrong magnetic
field of magnetars. We would like to point out that some of the results
concerning the microscopic number density of states of a strongly magnetized
electron gas given by well-known statistical physics text books are incorrect.
The repeated use of these results in the last five decades probably seriously
affects the physics of neutron stars and magnetars. The quantization of Landau
energy levels is accurately delineated in terms of the Dirac (delta) function.
Relatively simple calculation shows that the Fermi energy of relativistic
electron gas in magnetars with superstrong magnetic fields( B &gt; Bcr , here Bcr
is the Landau critical magnetic field) increases with magnetic fieldstrength as
B**(1/4). On the basis of this simple but importantnew result we are leading
naturally to propose a new mechanism for the production of high X-ray
luminosity from magnetars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04658</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04658</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>Dennis D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koenigstein</keyname><forenames>Adrian</forenames></author></authors><title>Schwinger's proper time and worldline holographic renormalisation</title><categories>hep-th hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Worldline holography states that within the framework of the worldline
approach to quantum field theory, sources of a quantum field theory over
Mink$_4$ naturally form a field theory over AdS$_5$ {\sl to all orders} in the
elementary fields and in the sources of arbitrary spin. (Such correspondences
are also available for other pairs of spacetimes, not only
Mink$_4\leftrightarrow\mathrm{AdS}_5$.) Schwinger's proper time of the
worldline formalism is automatically grouped with the physical four spacetime
dimensions into an AdS$_5$ geometry. We show that the worldline holographic
effective action in general and the proper-time profiles of the sources in
particular solve a renormalisation group equation and, reversely, can be
defined as solution to the latter. This fact also ensures regulator
independence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04663</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Landa-Marb&#xe1;n</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radu</keyname><forenames>Florin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nordbotten</keyname><forenames>Jan M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling and simulation of microbial enhanced oil recovery including
  interfacial area</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math.NA</categories><comments>22 pages, 9 figures and 1 table</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The focus of this paper is the derivation of a non-standard model for
microbial enhanced oil recovery (MEOR) that includes the interfacial area (IFA)
between the oil and water. We consider the continuity equations for water and
oil, a balance equation for the oil-water interface and advective-dispersive
transport equations for bacteria, nutrients and surfactants. Surfactants lower
the interfacial tension (IFT), which improves the oil recovery. Therefore, we
include in the model parameterizations of the IFT reduction and residual oil
saturation as a function of the surfactant concentration. We consider for the
first time in context of MEOR, the role of IFA in enhanced oil recovery (EOR).
The motivation to include the IFA in the model is to reduce the hysteresis in
the capillary pressure relationship, include the effects of observed bacteria
migration towards the oil-water interface and biological production of
surfactants at the oil-water interface. An efficient and robust linearization
scheme was implemented, in which we use an implicit scheme that considers a
linear approximation of the capillary pressure gradient, resulting in an
efficient and stable scheme. A comprehensive, 2D implementation based on
two-point flux approximation (TPFA) has been achieved. Illustrative numerical
simulations are presented. We give an explanation of the differences in the oil
recovery profiles obtained when we consider the IFA and MEOR effects. The model
can also be used to design new experiments in order to gain a better
understanding and optimization of MEOR.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04667</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04667</id><created>2016-12-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Tessarotto</keyname><forenames>Massimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cremaschini</keyname><forenames>Claudio</forenames></author></authors><title>Principles of kinetic theory for granular fluids</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Highlights are presented regarding recent developments of the kinetic theory
of granular matter. These concern the discovery of an exact kinetic equation
and a related exact H-theorem both holding for finite $N-$body systems formed
by smooth hard-spheres systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04672</id><created>2016-12-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Ofengeim</keyname><forenames>D. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fortin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haensel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yakovlev</keyname><forenames>D. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zdunik</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic approximations of neutrino luminosities and heat capacities of
  neutron stars with nucleon cores</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive analytic approximations of neutrino luminosities and heat
capacities of neutron stars with nucleon cores valid for a wide class of
equations of state of dense nucleon matter. The neutrino luminosities are
approximated for the three cases in which they are produced by (i) direct Urca
or (ii) modified Urca processes in non-superfluid matter, or (iii)
neutrino-pair bremsstrahlung in neutron-neutron collisions (when other neutrino
reactions are suppressed by strong proton superfluidity). The heat capacity is
approximated for the two cases of (i) non-superfluid cores and (ii) the cores
with strong proton superfluidity. The results can greatly simplify numerical
simulations of cooling neutron stars with isothermal interiors at the neutrino
and photon cooling stages as well as simulations of quasi-stationary internal
thermal states of neutron stars in X-ray transients. For illustration, a
model-independent analysis of thermal states of the latter sources is outlined.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04680</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04680</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gr&#xe4;ff</keyname><forenames>Dominik</forenames></author></authors><title>Upgrade and Characterization of the SPIFFI/SINFONI optics</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>This is a Master's Thesis written at the Max Planck Institute For
  Extraterrestrial Physics and the Technical University of Munich. The working
  title of the thesis was: &quot;Upgrade of the SPIFFI instrument with new optics,
  and characterization of the upgraded instrument&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The SPIFFI integral field spectrometer is operated as a subunit of the AO
instrument SINFONI on the VLT. It will be upgraded and reused as SPIFFIER in
the new VLT instrument ERIS. In January 2016 an early upgrade of several
optical components was carried out to make use of new technological
developments before ERIS will be commissioned in 2020.
  This Master's thesis focuses on the determination and detailed description of
the gain in performance due to the upgrade, with a particular focus on
measurements of the exchanged diamond turned mirrors of SPIFFI. An analysis of
the surface deformation of these mirrors is done, followed by a determination
of the resulting collimator wavefront and its influence on the line spread
function of the spectrometer. A careful analysis on the shapes, the variations
and the changes of the spectral line profiles due to the upgrade is done.
Furthermore, the spectral resolution, the image quality an the relative pre-
and post- upgrade throughput ratio are evaluated. Finally these observed
quantities are linked to critical optical components that limit the performance
of the instrument.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04684</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Boehner</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plewa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langer</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Imprints of the ejecta-companion interaction in Type Ia supernovae: main
  sequence, subgiant, and red giant companions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE physics.comp-ph physics.flu-dyn physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, version as published</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 465, 2060-2075 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2737</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study supernova ejecta-companion interactions in a sample of realistic
semidetached binary systems representative of Type Ia supernova progenitor
binaries in a single-degenerate scenario. We model the interaction process with
the help of a high-resolution hydrodynamic code assuming cylindrical symmetry.
We find that the ejecta hole has a half-opening angle of 40--50$^\circ$ with
the density by a factor of 2-4 lower, in good agreement with the previous
studies. Quantitative differences from the past results in the amounts and
kinematics of the stripped companion material and levels of contamination of
the companion with the ejecta material can be explained by different model
assumptions and effects due to numerical diffusion.We analyse and, for the
first time, provide simulation-based estimates of the amounts and of the
thermal characteristics of the shock-heated material responsible for producing
a prompt, soft X-ray emission. Besides the shocked ejecta material, considered
in the original model by Kasen, we also account for the stripped, shock-heated
envelope material of stellar companions, which we predict partially contributes
to the prompt emission. The amount of the energy deposited in the envelope is
comparable to the energy stored in the ejecta. The total energy budget
available for the prompt emission is by a factor of about 2-4 smaller than
originally predicted by Kasen. Although the shocked envelope has a higher
characteristic temperature than the shocked ejecta, the temperature estimates
of the shocked material are in good agreement with the Kasen's model. The
hottest shocked plasma is produced in the subgiant companion case.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04707</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04707</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Gauzzi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisula</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karppinen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saadaoui</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morenzoni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manuel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khalyavin</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marezio</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geballe</keyname><forenames>T. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk superconductivity at 84 K in the strongly overdoped regime of
  cuprates</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 Figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 180509(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.180509</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of magnetization, specific heat and muon-spin relaxation
measurements, we investigate high-pressure oxidized \mohpo, in which overdoping
is achieved up to $p \sim 0.45$ hole/Cu, well beyond the $T_c - p$
superconducting dome of cuprates, where Fermi liquid behavior is expected.
Surprisingly, we find bulk superconductivity with $T_c$=84 K and superfluid
density similar to those of optimally doped Y123. On the other hand, specific
heat data display a large electronic contribution at low temperature,
comparable to that of nonsuperconducting overdoped La214. These results point
at an unusual high-$T_c$ phase with a large fraction of unpaired holes. Further
experiments may assess the Fermi liquid properties of the present phase, which
would put into question the paradigm that the high $T_c$ of cuprates originates
from a non-Fermi liquid ground state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04709</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04709</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Krishnan</keyname><forenames>Sridevi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brenet</keyname><forenames>Gilles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machado-Charry</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caliste</keyname><forenames>Damien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Genovese</keyname><forenames>Luigi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deutsch</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pochet</keyname><forenames>Pascal</forenames></author></authors><title>Revisiting the domain model for lithium intercalated graphite</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Appl. Phys. Lett. 2013, 103 (25), 251904</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4850877</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we study the stability of the domain model for lithium
intercalated graphite in stages III and II by means of Density Functional
Theory and Kinetic Lattice Monte Carlo simulations. We find that the domain
model is either thermodynamically or kinetically stable when compared to the
standard model in stages III and II. The existence of domains in the
intercalation sequence is well supported by recent high resolution transmission
electron microscope observations in lithiated graphite. Moreover, we predict
that such domain staging sequences leads to a wide range of diffusivity as
reported in experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04712</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04712</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Valbuena</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chudzinski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pons</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Conejeros</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alemany</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canadell</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frantzeskakis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avila</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asensio</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giamarchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grioni</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emerging one-dimensionality from self-organization of electrons in
  NbSe$_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures; Supplementary Material (14 pages) available upon
  request</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Materials where the electron filling is close to commensurate filling provide
one of the great challenges in materials science. Several proposals of
unconventional orderings, where the electronic liquid self-organizes into
components with distinct properties, were recently put forward, in particular
in cuprates and pnictides where electronic nematic orders have been observed.
The electrons self-organization is expected to yield complex intra and inter
unit cell patterns, and a reduction of dimensionality. Nevertheless, an
unambiguous experimental proof of such complex orders, namely the direct
observation of distinct dispersions, is still missing. Here we report a Nano
Angle Resolved Photo-emission Spectroscopy (Nano-ARPES) study of NbSe$_3$, a
material that has been considered a paradigm of charge order. The new data
(Fig.1) invalidate the canonical picture of imperfect nesting and reveals the
emergence of a novel order. The electrons self-organization uncovers the
one-dimensional (1D) physics hidden in a material which naively should be the
most 3D of all columnar chalcogenides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04714</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Paunzen</keyname><forenames>Ernst</forenames><affiliation>BEST</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Rode-Paunzen</keyname><forenames>Monika</forenames><affiliation>BEST</affiliation></author></authors><title>BRITE photometry of seven B-type stars</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures, Proceedings of the 3rd BRITE Science Meeting</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the time series analysis of seven B-type stars (HD 121790, HD
122980, HD 129116, HD 133242, HD 144294, HD 145482, and HD 145502) observed
with the BRITE satellites. Furthermore, we located these stars in the
Hertzsprung-Russell-diagram. One rotational induced variable (HD 122980, P~80
d) and one binary (HD 145502, P~5.6 d) showing variability due to ellipsoidal
variation and/or reflection were detected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04731</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04731</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bols</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Roeck</keyname><forenames>Wojciech</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymptotic Localization in the Bose-Hubbard Model</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages, 1 figure. The proofs in section 5.3 are almost identical to
  the analogous proofs in arXiv:1305.5127</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the Bose-Hubbard model. Our focus is on many-body localization,
which was described by many authors in such models, even in the absence of
disorder. Since our work is rigorous, and since we believe that the
localization in this type of models is not strictly valid in the infinite-time
limit, we necessarily restrict our study to 'asymptotic localization': We prove
that transport and thermalization are small beyond perturbation theory in the
limit of large particle density. Our theorem takes the form of a many-body
Nekhoroshev estimate. An interesting and new aspect of this model is the
following: even though our analysis proceeds by perturbation in the hopping,
the localization can not be inferred from a lack of hybridization between
zero-hopping eigenstates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04735</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Srivastav</keyname><forenames>Shubham</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anupama</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahu</keyname><forenames>D. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravikumar</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author></authors><title>SN 2015bp: adding to the growing population of transitional type Ia
  supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>16 pages, 16 figures, MNRAS accepted</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw3263</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Photometric and spectroscopic observations of type Ia supernova 2015bp are
presented, spanning $\sim -6$ to $\sim +141$ days since $B$-band maximum. Also
presented are unpublished HCT spectra of type Ia iPTF13ebh between $-11$ to +34
days since $B$-band maximum. SN 2015bp shows rapidly declining light curves
with $\Delta m_{15}(B)=1.72 \pm 0.04$. The $I$-band light curve shows a clear
secondary maximum and peaks before the $B$-band maximum, placing SN 2015bp in
the transitional category of SNe Ia. The spectral evolution of SN 2015bp
resembles other transitional SNe Ia rather than 1991bg-like events. The C~{\sc
ii} $\lambda 6580$ feature is detected in both SN 2015bp and iPTF13ebh, though
it is present till the epoch of $B$-band maximum in the case of SN 2015bp. The
velocity gradients of Si~{\sc ii} $\lambda 6355$ place SN 2015bp and iPTF13ebh
in the FAINT subclass, whereas pseudo-equivalent widths of Si~{\sc ii} features
place them in the Cool (CL) subclass of SNe Ia. The bolometric light curve of
SN 2015bp indicates that $\sim 0.2$ M$_{\odot}$ of $^{56}$Ni was synthesized in
the explosion, with a total ejected mass of $\sim 0.9$ M$_{\odot}$, suggesting
a sub-Chandrasekhar mass white dwarf progenitor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04756</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04756</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Kaixin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Haotian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Weidong</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic Distributions in Topological Insulator Bi$_2$Se$_{3-x}$Te$_x$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bi$_2$Se$_3$ is a topological insulator and it is often doped with Te to
compensate the $n$-type carriers due to Se vacancies. Different doping patterns
of Te would influence the transport characteristics of the surface states. We
study the Te atom distribution in Bi$_2$Se$_3$ with different Te
concentrations, using first-principles density-functional-theory calculations.
We show that Te prefer the outer layer, until the composition becomes
Bi$_2$SeTe$_2$ and the outer layer is full of Te. And for a fixed ratio of Se
and Te atoms within a single layer, we find that the structures with less
number of adjacent Te-Se pairs tend to have lower energies. This might result
in the formation of local Te clusters under low annealing temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04785</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohzeki</keyname><forenames>Masayuki</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Monte Carlo simulation of a particular class of non-stoquastic
  Hamiltonians in quantum annealing</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech stat.ML</categories><comments>9 pages, published in Scientifc Reports</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum annealing is a generic solver of the optimization problem that uses
fictitious quantum fluctuation. Its simulation in classical computing is often
performed using the quantum Monte Carlo simulation via the Suzuki--Trotter
decomposition. However, the negative sign problem sometimes emerges in the
simulation of quantum annealing with an elaborate driver Hamiltonian, since it
belongs to a class of non-stoquastic Hamiltonians. In the present study, we
propose an alternative way to avoid the negative sign problem involved in a
particular class of the non-stoquastic Hamiltonians. To check the validity of
the method, we demonstrate our method by applying it to a simple problem that
includes the anti-ferromagnetic XX interaction, which is a typical instance of
the non-stoquastic Hamiltonians.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:hep-ph/9411275</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>hep-ph/9411275</id><created>1994-11-11</created><updated>2016-12-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Grinstein</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author></authors><title>An Introduction To The Theory Of Heavy Mesons And Baryons</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Re-posted: there are requests, and previous version not processing
  under modern TeX. Figures included. 70 pages, harvmac, 15 figures</comments><report-no>UCSD/PTH 94-24</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Introductory lectures (delivered at TASI, June 1994) on heavy quarks and
heavy quark effective field theory. Applications to inclusive semileptonic
decays and to interactions with light mesons are covered in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
