<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T23:47:37Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-12-12" from="2016-12-12" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0707.1897</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0707.1897</id><created>2007-07-12</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximum Entropy, the Collective Welfare Principle and the Globalization
  Process</title><categories>q-fin.GN physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Econophysics Colloquium &amp; Beyond (Ancona, Italy, 2007), 7 pages.
  arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:0705.0029,
  arXiv:physics/0609088, arXiv:physics/0609245; text overlap with
  arXiv:quant-ph/0510238</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although both systems analyzed are described through two theories apparently
different (quantum mechanics and game theory) it is shown that both are
analogous and thus exactly equivalents. The quantum analogue of the replicator
dynamics is the von Neumann equation. Quantum mechanics could be used to
explain more correctly biological and economical processes. It could even
encloses theories like games and evolutionary dynamics. We can take some
concepts and definitions from quantum mechanics and physics for the best
understanding of the behavior of economics and biology. Also, we could maybe
understand nature like a game in where its players compete for a common welfare
and the equilibrium of the system that they are members. All the members of our
system will play a game in which its maximum payoff is the equilibrium of the
system. They act as a whole besides individuals like they obey a rule in where
they prefer to work for the welfare of the collective besides the individual
welfare. A system where its members are in Nash Equilibrium (or ESS) is exactly
equivalent to a system in a maximum entropy state. A system is stable only if
it maximizes the welfare of the collective above the welfare of the individual.
If it is maximized the welfare of the individual above the welfare of the
collective the system gets unstable an eventually collapses. The results of
this work shows that the &quot;globalization&quot; process has a behavior exactly
equivalent to a system that is tending to a maximum entropy state and predicts
the apparition of big common markets and strong common currencies that will
find its &quot;equilibrium&quot; by decreasing its number until they get a state
characterized by only one common currency and only one common market around the
world.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0710.1307</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0710.1307</id><created>2007-10-05</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Common Markets, Strong Currencies &amp; the Collective Welfare</title><categories>q-fin.GN physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>9 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:0705.0029, arXiv:physics/0609088, arXiv:quant-ph/0606045,
  arXiv:physics/0609245; text overlap with arXiv:quant-ph/0510238</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The so called &quot;globalization&quot; process (i.e. the inexorable integration of
markets, currencies, nation-states, technologies and the intensification of
consciousness of the world as a whole) has a behavior exactly equivalent to a
system that is tending to a maximum entropy state. This globalization process
obeys a collective welfare principle in where the maximum payoff is given by
the equilibrium of the system and its stability by the maximization of the
welfare of the collective besides the individual welfare. This let us predict
the apparition of big common markets and strong common currencies. They will
reach the &quot;equilibrium&quot; by decreasing its number until they reach a state
characterized by only one common currency and only one big common community
around the world.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0803.0292</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0803.0292</id><created>2008-03-03</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Games and the Relationships between Quantum Mechanics and Game
  Theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>19 pages in Game Theory: Strategies, Equilibria, And Theorems by I.
  Haugen and A. Nilsen. Nova Science Publishers, 83-115, (2009). arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:physics/0609088, arXiv:physics/0609245</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum games have proposed a new point of view for the solution of the
classical problems and dilemmas in game theory. Certain quantization
relationships can be proposed with the objective that a game can be generalized
into a quantum domain where the linear superposition of actions is allowed.
This quantization let us describe and solution problems originated by
conflicting or cooperative behaviors among the members of a system from the
point of view of quantum mechanical interactions. This leads us to interesting
aspects which only can be observed through the quantization of a game like the
possibility of the entanglement between players, the definition of a
socioeconomical temperature in a system, the collective welfare principle,the
analysis of a game through elements of quantum information theory and the
globalization process. The relationships between quantum mechanics and game
theory are also studied and its shown how although both systems analyzed are
described through two theories apparently different (quantum mechanics and game
theory) both are analogous and thus exactly equivalents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0904.1034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0904.1034</id><created>2009-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Eltschka</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siewert</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>Possibility of generalized monogamy relations for multipartite
  entanglement beyond three qubits</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 80, 032313 (2009)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.80.032313</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the possibility to interpret the residual entanglement for more
than three qubits in terms of distributed multipartite entanglement, or, in
other words, possible extensions of the Coffman-Kundu-Wootters monogamy
equality to higher qubit numbers. Existing knowledge on entanglement in
multipartite systems puts narrow constraints on the form of such extensions. We
study various examples for families of pure four-qubit states for which the
characterization of three-qubit and four-qubit entanglement in terms of
polynomial invariants is known. These examples indicate that, although families
with such extensions do exist, a generalized monogamy equality cannot be found
along those lines.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0908.3818</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0908.3818</id><created>2009-08-26</created><updated>2010-04-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siewert</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The invariant-comb approach and its relation to the balancedness of
  multipartite entangled states</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, revtex4. Substantially extended manuscript (e.g. proofs
  have been added); title and abstract modified.</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 12, 075025 (2010)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/12/7/075025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The invariant-comb approach is a method to construct entanglement measures
for multipartite systems of qubits. The essential step is the construction of
an antilinear operator that we call {\em comb} in reference to the {\em
hairy-ball theorem}. An appealing feature of this approach is that for qubits
(or spins 1/2) the combs are automatically invariant under $SL(2,\CC)$, which
implies that the obtained invariants are entanglement monotones by
construction. By asking which property of a state determines whether or not it
is detected by a polynomial $SL(2,\CC)$ invariant we find that it is the
presence of a {\em balanced part} that persists under local unitary
transformations. We present a detailed analysis for the maximally entangled
states detected by such polynomial invariants, which leads to the concept of
{\em irreducibly balanced} states. The latter indicates a tight connection with
SLOCC classifications of qubit entanglement. \\ Combs may also help to define
measures for multipartite entanglement of higher-dimensional subsystems.
However, for higher spins there are many independent combs such that it is
non-trivial to find an invariant one. By restricting the allowed local
operations to rotations of the coordinate system (i.e. again to the
$SL(2,\CC)$) we manage to define a unique extension of the concurrence to
general half-integer spin with an analytic convex-roof expression for mixed
states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1003.4862</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1003.4862</id><created>2010-03-25</created><updated>2012-09-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siewert</keyname><forenames>Jens</forenames></author></authors><title>Invariant-based entanglement monotones as expectation values and their
  experimental detection</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, revtex4-1. An erroneous formula has been repaired. Several
  concepts are explained better. Updated references. To be published in Phys.
  Rev. A</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 86, 042302 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.86.042302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Characterization and quantification of multipartite entanglement is one of
the challenges in state-of-the-art experiments in quantum information
processing. According to theory, this is achieved via entanglement monotones,
that is, functions that do not increase under stochastic local operations and
classical communication (SLOCC). Typically such monotones include the wave
function and its time-reversal (antilinear-operator formalism) or they are
based on not completely positive maps (e.g., partial transpose). Therefore,
they are not directly accessible to experimental observations. We show how
entanglement monotones derived from polynomial local SL$(2,\CC)$ invariants can
be re-written in terms of expectation values of observables. Consequently, the
amount of entanglement---of specific SLOCC classes---in a given state can be
extracted from the measurement of correlation functions of local operators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1106.1363</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1106.1363</id><created>2011-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Arbey</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author></authors><title>AlterBBN: A program for calculating the BBN abundances of the elements
  in alternative cosmologies</title><categories>astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>15 pages, 1 figure, 1 table. AlterBBN can be obtained from
  https://alterbbn.hepforge.org/</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-TH-2011-135, LYCEN-2011-06</report-no><journal-ref>Comput.Phys.Commun.183:1822-1831,2012</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cpc.2012.03.018</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe AlterBBN, a public C program for evaluating the abundances of the
elements generated by Big-Bang nucleosynthesis (BBN). This program enables the
user to compute the abundances of the elements in the standard model of
cosmology, and additionally provides possibilities to alter the assumptions of
the cosmological model in order to study their consequences on the abundances
of the elements. In particular the baryon-to-photon ratio and the effective
number of neutrinos, as well as the expansion rate and the entropy content of
the Universe during BBN can be modified in AlterBBN. Such features allow the
user to test the cosmological models by confronting them to BBN constraints. A
presentation of the physics of BBN and the features of AlterBBN is provided
here under the form of a manual.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1205.2012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1205.2012</id><created>2012-05-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Saeedghalati</keyname><forenames>Mohammadkarim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbassian</keyname><forenames>Abdolhossein</forenames></author></authors><title>The effect of temporal pattern of injury on disability in learning
  networks</title><categories>q-bio.NC cond-mat.dis-nn q-bio.TO</categories><comments>Latex, 17 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><doi>10.3389/fncom.2015.00130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How networks endure damage is a central issue in neural network research.
This includes temporal as well as spatial pattern of damage. Here, based on
some very simple models we study the difference between a slow-growing and
acute damage and the relation between the size and rate of injury. Our result
shows that in both a three-layer and a homeostasis model a slow-growing damage
has a decreasing effect on network disability as compared with a fast growing
one. This finding is in accord with clinical reports where the state of
patients before and after the operation for slow-growing injuries is much
better that those patients with acute injuries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1206.4519</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1206.4519</id><created>2012-06-20</created><updated>2013-04-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bermudez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>C</keyname><forenames>David J. Fernandez</forenames></author></authors><title>Factorization method and new potentials from the inverted oscillator</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables. The new version has a new section for
  the algebras of the harmonic and inverted oscillators, a new appendix, and
  color figures</comments><journal-ref>Ann. Phys. 333 (2013) 290-306</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2013.02.015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we will apply the first- and second-order supersymmetric
quantum mechanics to obtain new exactly-solvable real potentials departing from
the inverted oscillator potential. This system has some special properties; in
particular, only very specific second-order transformations produce
non-singular real potentials. It will be shown that these transformations turn
out to be the so-called complex ones. Moreover, we will study the factorization
method applied to the inverted oscillator and the algebraic structure of the
new Hamiltonians.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1310.5628</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1310.5628</id><created>2013-10-21</created><updated>2013-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>C</keyname><forenames>David J. Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales-Salgado</keyname><forenames>VS</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric partners of the harmonic oscillator with an infinite
  potential barrier</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A 47 (2014) 035304</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/47/3/035304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supersymmetry transformations of first and second order are used to generate
Hamiltonians with known spectra departing from the harmonic oscillator with an
infinite potential barrier. It is studied also the way in which the
eigenfunctions of the initial Hamiltonian are transformed. The first and
certain second order supersymmetric partners of the initial Hamiltonian possess
third-order differential ladder operators. Since systems with this kind of
operators are linked with the Painlev\'e IV equation, several solutions of this
non-linear second-order differential equation will be simply found.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.0647</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.0647</id><created>2013-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Bermudez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>C</keyname><forenames>David J. Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersymmetric quantum mechanics and Painleve equations</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 20 figures. Lecture presented at the XLIII Latin American
  School of Physics: ELAF 2013 in Mexico City</comments><journal-ref>AIP Conf. Proc. 1575 (2014) 50-88</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4861699</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In these lecture notes we shall study first the supersymmetric quantum
mechanics (SUSY QM), specially when applied to the harmonic and radial
oscillators. In addition, we will define the polynomial Heisenberg algebras
(PHA), and we will study the general systems ruled by them: for zero and first
order we obtain the harmonic and radial oscillators, respectively; for second
and third order PHA the potential is determined by solutions to Painleve IV
(PIV) and Painleve V (PV) equations. Taking advantage of this connection, later
on we will find solutions to PIV and PV equations expressed in terms of
confluent hypergeometric functions. Furthermore, we will classify them into
several solution hierarchies, according to the specific special functions they
are connected with.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.7318</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.7318</id><created>2013-11-28</created><updated>2015-06-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chithrabhanu</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aadhi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reddy</keyname><forenames>Salla Gangi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prabhakar</keyname><forenames>Shashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samanta</keyname><forenames>G. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paul</keyname><forenames>Goutam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Three particle Hyper Entanglement: Teleportation and Quantum Key
  Distribution</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR</categories><comments>8 pages, 8 figures, 2 tables, To appear in Quantum Information
  Processing Journal (accepted on June 22, 2015)</comments><journal-ref>Quantum Information Processing, October 2015, Volume 14, Issue 10,
  pp 3813-3826</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11128-015-1056-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a scheme to generate three particle hyper-entanglement utilizing
polarization and orbital angular momentum (OAM) of a photon. We show that the
generated state can be used to teleport a two-qubit state described by the
polarization and the OAM. The proposed quantum system has also been used to
describe a new efficient quantum key distribution (QKD) protocol. We give a
sketch of the experimental arrangement to realize the proposed teleportation
and the QKD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.5926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.5926</id><created>2014-02-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Bermudez</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Contreras-Astorga</keyname><forenames>Alonso</forenames></author><author><keyname>C</keyname><forenames>David J. Fern&#xe1;ndez</forenames></author></authors><title>Painlev\'e IV Coherent States</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Ann Phys 350 (2014) 615-634</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2014.07.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple way to find solutions of the Painlev\'e IV equation is by
identifying Hamiltonian systems with third-order differential ladder operators.
Some of these systems can be obtained by applying supersymmetric quantum
mechanics (SUSY QM) to the harmonic oscillator. In this work, we will construct
families of coherent states for such subset of SUSY partner Hamiltonians which
are connected with the Painlev\'e IV equation. First, these coherent states are
built up as eigenstates of the annihilation operator, then as displaced
versions of the extremal states, both involving the third-order ladder
operators, and finally as extremal states which are also displaced but now
using the so called linearized ladder operators. To each SUSY partner
Hamiltonian corresponds two families of coherent states: one inside the
infinite subspace associated with the isospectral part of the spectrum and
another one in the finite subspace generated by the states created through the
SUSY technique.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1404.1834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1404.1834</id><created>2014-04-07</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Clampitt</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>Bhuvnesh</forenames></author></authors><title>Lensing Measurements of the Mass Distribution in SDSS Voids</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures; matches version published in MNRAS; void catalog
  available at http://josephclampitt.com/catalogs.html</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2215</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measure weak lensing mass profiles of voids from a volume-limited sample
of SDSS Luminous Red Galaxies (LRGs). We find voids using an algorithm designed
to maximize the lensing signal by dividing the survey volume into 2D slices,
and then finding holes in this 2D distribution of LRGs. We perform a stacked
shear measurement on about 20,000 voids with radii between 15-55 Mpc/h and
redshifts between 0.16-0.37. We measure the characteristic radial shear signal
of voids with a signal-to-noise of 7. The mass profile corresponds to a
fractional underdensity of about -0.4 inside the void radius and a slow
approach to the mean density indicating a partially compensated void structure.
We compare our measured shape and amplitude with the predictions of Krause et
al 2013. Voids in the galaxy distribution have been extensively modeled using
simulations and measured in the SDSS. We discuss how the addition of void mass
profiles can enable studies of galaxy formation and cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1406.5780</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1406.5780</id><created>2014-06-22</created><updated>2016-08-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brody</keyname><forenames>Dorje C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughston</keyname><forenames>Lane P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of Quantum Heat Bath</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>26 pages; version to appear in J. Phys. A</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 425302</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/42/425302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model for the thermodynamics of a quantum heat bath is introduced. Under
the assumption that the bath molecules have finitely many degrees of freedom
and are weakly interacting, we present a general derivation of the equation of
state of the bath in the thermodynamic limit. The relation between the
temperature and the specific energy of the bath depends on (i) the spectral
properties of the molecules, and (ii) the choice of probability measure on the
state space of a representative molecule. The results obtained illustrate how
the microscopic features of the molecular constituents determine the
macroscopic thermodynamic properties of the bath. Our findings can thus be used
to compare the merits of different hypotheses for the equilibrium states of
quantum systems. Two examples of plausible choices for the probability measure
are considered in detail.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.5777</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.5777</id><created>2014-11-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Kan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiaoyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jianping</forenames></author></authors><title>WS2 as a saturable absorber for ultrafast photonic applications of
  mode-locked and Q-switched lasers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>15 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optics Express 23(9), 11453 (2015)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two-dimensional (2D) nanomaterials, especially the transition metal sulfide
semiconductors, have drawn great interests due to their potential applications
in viable photonic and optoelectronic devices, such as saturable absorbers
(SAs) and optical switches, etc. In this work, tungsten disulfide (WS2) based
SA for ultrafast photonic applications was demonstrated. WS2 nanosheets were
prepared using liquid-phase exfoliation method and embedded in polyvinyl
alcohol (PVA) thin film for the practical usage. Saturable absorption was
observed in the WS2-PVA SA at the telecommunication waveband near 1550 nm. By
incorporating WS2-PVA SA into a fiber laser cavity, both stable mode locking
operation and Q-switching operation were achieved. In the mode locking
operation, the laser obtained femtosecond output pulse width and high spectral
purity in the radio frequency spectrum. In the Q-switching operation, the laser
had tunable repetition rate and output pulse energy of a few tens of nano
joule. Our findings suggest that few-layer WS2 nanosheets embedded in PVA thin
film are promising nonlinear optical materials for ultrafast photonic
applications as a mode locker or Q-switcher.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.02274</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.02274</id><created>2015-03-08</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Doubrov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferapontov</keyname><forenames>Eugene</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruglikov</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novikov</keyname><forenames>Vladimir</forenames></author></authors><title>On the integrability in Grassmann geometries: integrable systems
  associated with fourfolds Gr(3, 5)</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>This is an elaborated version of the main part concerning
  dispersionless integrable systems in 3D, reflected in the title of the paper.
  We omitted the last two sections on systems in 4D and higher dimensional
  Monge-Ampere equations that will be expanded and posted in arXiv separately
  in the near future. These parts, as well as supplementary materials, are
  still accessible via arXiv:1503.02274v1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate dispersionless integrable systems in 3D associated with
fourfolds in the Grassmannian Gr(3,5). Such systems appear in numerous
applications in continuum mechanics, general relativity and differential
geometry, and include such well-known examples as the dispersionless
Kadomtsev-Petviashvili equation, the Boyer-Finley equation, etc. We prove the
equivalence of the four different approaches to integrability, revealing a
remarkable correspondence with Einstein-Weyl geometry and the theory of GL(2,R)
structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.06143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.06143</id><created>2015-03-20</created><updated>2015-11-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Varholm</keyname><forenames>Kristoffer</forenames></author></authors><title>Solitary gravity-capillary water waves with point vortices</title><categories>math.AP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>36 pages, 4 figures. As accepted for publication in Discrete Cont.
  Dyn. Syst</comments><msc-class>35Q31 (Primary) 35C07, 76B25 (Secondary)</msc-class><journal-ref>Discrete Contin. Dyn. Syst. 36 (2016), no. 7, 3927-3959</journal-ref><doi>10.3934/dcds.2016.36.3927</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct small-amplitude solitary traveling gravity-capillary water waves
with a finite number of point vortices along a vertical line, on finite depth.
This is done using a local bifurcation argument. The properties of the
resulting waves are also examined: We find that they depend significantly on
the position of the point vortices in the water column.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05296</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05296</id><created>2015-04-21</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mampusti</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whittaker</keyname><forenames>Michael F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Fractal spectral triples on Kellendonk's $C^*$-algebra of a substitution
  tiling</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.DS math.MP</categories><comments>Updated to agree with published version</comments><msc-class>46L55</msc-class><journal-ref>Journal of Geometry and Physics 112 (2017), 224--239</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.geomphys.2016.11.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a new class of noncommutative spectral triples on Kellendonk's
$C^*$-algebra associated with a nonperiodic substitution tiling. These spectral
triples are constructed from fractal trees on tilings, which define a geodesic
distance between any two tiles in the tiling. Since fractals typically have
infinite Euclidean length, the geodesic distance is defined using
Perron-Frobenius theory, and is self-similar with scaling factor given by the
Perron-Frobenius eigenvalue. We show that each spectral triple is
$\theta$-summable, and respects the hierarchy of the substitution system. To
elucidate our results, we construct a fractal tree on the Penrose tiling, and
explicitly show how it gives rise to a collection of spectral triples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.06723</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.06723</id><created>2015-06-22</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sambou</keyname><forenames>Diomba</forenames></author></authors><title>On eigenvalue accumulation for non-self-adjoint magnetic operators</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we use regularized determinant approach to study the discrete
spectrum generated by relatively compact non-self-adjoint perturbations of the
magnetic Schr\&quot;odinger operator $(-i\nabla - \textbf{\textup{A}})^{2} - b$ in
dimension $3$ with constant magnetic field of strength $b&gt;0$. The situation
near the Landau levels $2bq$, $q \in \mathbb{N}$, is more interesting since
they play the role of thresholds of the spectrum of the free operator. First,
we obtain sharp upper bounds on the number of the complex eigenvalues near the
Landau levels. Under appropriate hypothesis, we then prove the presence of an
infinite number of complex eigenvalues near each Landau level $2bq$, $q \in
\mathbb{N}$, and the existence of sectors free of complex eigenvalues. We also
prove that the eigenvalues are localized in certain sectors adjoining the
Landau levels. In particular, we provide an adequate answer to the open problem
from [34] about the existence of complex eigenvalues accumulating near the
Landau levels. Furthermore, we prove that the Landau levels are the only
possible accumulation points of the complex eigenvalues.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07969</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07969</id><created>2015-06-26</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fitzner</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Hofstad</keyname><forenames>Remco</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalized approach to the non-backtracking lace expansion</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>82B27, 82B41, 82B43, 82C41 (Primary), 60K35 (Secondary)</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The lace expansion is a powerful perturbative technique to analyze the
critical behavior of random spatial processes such as the self-avoiding walk,
percolation and lattice trees and animals. The non-backtracking lace expansion
(NoBLE) is a modification that allows us to improve its applicability in the
nearest-neighbor setting on the $\mathbb Z^d$-lattice for percolation, lattice
trees and lattice animals.
  The NoBLE gives rise to a recursive formula that we study in this paper at a
general level. We state assumptions that guarantee that the solution of this
recursive formula satisfies the infrared bound. In two related papers, we show
that these conditions are satisfied for percolation in $d\geq 11$, for lattice
trees in $d\geq 16$ and for lattice animals in $d\geq 21$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01351</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01351</id><created>2015-07-06</created><updated>2015-12-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Daowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>Xiangfu</forenames></author></authors><title>Improvement of a quantum broadcasting multiple blind signature scheme
  based on quantum teleportation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages</comments><doi>10.1007/s11128-016-1289-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, a broadcasting multiple blind signature scheme based on quantum
teleportation has been proposed for the first time. It is claimed to have
unconditional security and properties of quantum multiple signature and quantum
blind signature. In this paper, we analyze the security of the protocol and
show that the signatory Ui can learn the signed message m by a single particle
measurement and the signed message m can be modified at random by anyone
according to the scheme. Furthermore, there are some participant attacks and
external attacks existing in the scheme. Finally we present an improved
protocol and show that the improved scheme can resist all of the mentioned
attacks. Meanwhile, the secret keys can be used again and again, which will
make it more efficient and practical.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.01953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.01953</id><created>2015-07-07</created><updated>2015-11-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Reischke</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maturi</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartelmann</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Extreme value statistics of weak lensing shear peak counts</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures, Accepted for publication in MNRAS, one figure
  added, little changes in the manuscript, added references</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016 456 (1):
  641-653</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stv2677</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The statistics of peaks in weak gravitational lensing maps is a promising
technique to constrain cosmological parameters in present and future surveys.
Here we investigate its power when using general extreme value statistics which
is very sensitive to the exponential tail of the halo mass function. To this
end, we use an analytic method to quantify the number of weak lensing peaks
caused by galaxy clusters, large-scale structures and observational noise.
Doing so, we further improve the method in the regime of high signal-to-noise
ratios dominated by non-linear structures by accounting for the embedding of
those counts into the surrounding shear caused by large scale structures. We
derive the extreme value and order statistics for both over-densities (positive
peaks) and under-densities (negative peaks) and provide an optimized criterion
to split a wide field survey into sub-fields in order to sample the
distribution of extreme values such that the expected objects causing the
largest signals are mostly due to galaxy clusters. We find good agreement of
our model predictions with a ray-tracing $N$-body simulation. For a Euclid-like
survey, we find tight constraints on $\sigma_8$ and $\Omega_\text{m}$ with
relative uncertainties of $\sim 10^{-3}$. In contrast, the equation of state
parameter $w_0$ can be constrained only with a $10\%$ level, and $w_\text{a}$
is out of reach even if we include redshift information.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07379</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07379</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Procacci</keyname><forenames>Aldo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuhjtman</keyname><forenames>Sergio A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Convergence of Mayer and Virial expansions and the Penrose tree-graph
  identity</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>Final version, to be published in Letters in Mathematical Physics</comments><msc-class>82B21</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s11005-016-0918-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We establish new lower bounds for the convergence radius of the Mayer series
and the Virial series of a continuous particle system interacting via a stable
and tempered pair potential. Our bounds considerably improve those given by
Penrose and Ruelle in 1963 for the Mayer series and by Lebowitz and Penrose in
1964 for the Virial series. To get our results we exploit the tree-graph
identity given by Penrose in 1967 using a new partition scheme based on minumum
spanning trees.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.07738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.07738</id><created>2015-09-25</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Turchetti</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinigardi</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Servizi</keyname><forenames>Graziano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panichi</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaienti</keyname><forenames>Sandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Errors, Correlations and Fidelity for noisy Hamilton flows. Theory and
  numerical examples</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>22 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyse the asymptotic growth of the error for Hamiltonian flows due to
small random perturbations. We compare the forward error with the reversibility
error, showing their equivalence for linear flows on a compact phase space. The
forward error, given by the root mean square deviation $\sigma(t)$ of the noisy
flow, grows according to a power law if the system is integrable and according
to an exponential law if it is chaotic.
  The autocorrelation and the fidelity, defined as the correlation of the
perturbed flow with respect to the unperturbed one, exhibit an exponential
decay as $\exp\left(-\sigma^2(t)\right)$. Some numerical examples such as the
anharmonic oscillator and the H\'enon Heiles model confirm these results. We
finally consider the effect of the observational noise on an integrable system,
and show that the decay of correlations can only be observed after a sequence
of measurements and that the multiplicative noise is more effective if the
delay between two measurements is large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.09177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.09177</id><created>2015-09-30</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Griesshammer</keyname><forenames>Harald W.</forenames><affiliation>George Washington U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>McGovern</keyname><forenames>Judith A.</forenames><affiliation>U. of Manchester</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>Daniel R.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Compton Scattering and Nucleon Polarisabilities in Chiral EFT: Update
  and Future</title><categories>nucl-th hep-lat hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>6 pages LaTeX2e (pdflatex) including 11 figures as .pdf files. First
  presented by Griesshammer at the 12th Conference on the Intersections of
  Nuclear and Particle Physics CIPANP2015, 19-24 May 2015, Vail (CO), USA;
  updated for 22nd International Spin Symposium (SPIN 2016), University of
  Illinois, Urbana (USA), 26-30 September 2016. Corrected 2 figures, added
  clarifying text</comments><report-no>CIPANP2015-Griesshammer</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review theoretical progress and prospects for determining the nucleon's
static dipole polarisabilities from Compton scattering on few-nucleon targets,
including new values; see Refs. [1-5] for details and a more thorough
bibliography.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06728</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drischler</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hebeler</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwenk</keyname><forenames>Achim</forenames></author></authors><title>Asymmetric nuclear matter based on chiral two- and three-nucleon
  interactions</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.SR nucl-ex</categories><comments>minor changes, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 93, 054314 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.93.054314</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the properties of isospin-asymmetric nuclear matter based on
chiral nucleon-nucleon (NN) and three-nucleon (3N) interactions. To this end,
we develop an improved normal-ordering framework that allows to include general
3N interactions starting from a plane-wave partial-wave-decomposed form. We
present results for the energy per particle for general isospin asymmetries
based on a set of different Hamiltonians, study their saturation properties,
the incompressibility, symmetry energy, and also provide an analytic
parametrization for the energy per particle as a function of density and
isospin asymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.07278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.07278</id><created>2015-11-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mej&#xed;a</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zapata</keyname><forenames>Camilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Botero</keyname><forenames>Alonso</forenames></author></authors><title>The difference between two random mixed quantum states: exact and
  asymptotic spectral analysis</title><categories>math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>34 pages, 7 figures. Paper has been restructured with first section
  presenting all the results, with proofs in subsequent sections</comments><doi>10.1088/1751-8121/50/2/025301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spectral statistics of the difference of two density
matrices, each of which is independently obtained by partially tracing a random
bipartite pure quantum state. We first show how a closed-form expression for
the exact joint eigenvalue probability density function for arbitrary
dimensions can be obtained from the joint probability density function of the
diagonal elements of the difference matrix, which is straightforward to
compute. Subsequently, we use standard results from free probability theory to
derive a relatively simple analytic expression for the asymptotic eigenvalue
density (AED) of the difference matrix ensemble, and using Carlson's theorem,
we obtain an expression for its absolute moments. These results allow us to
quantify the typical asymptotic distance between the two random mixed states
using various distance measures; in particular, we obtain the almost sure
asymptotic behavior of the operator norm distance and the trace distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08378</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08378</id><created>2015-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Rajasekaran</keyname><forenames>Srivats</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casandruc</keyname><forenames>Eliza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laplace</keyname><forenames>Yannis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicoletti</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Genda D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Stephen R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaksch</keyname><forenames>Dieter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cavalleri</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Parametric Amplification of a Terahertz Quantum Plasma Wave</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con physics.optics</categories><comments>25 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Phys. 12, 1012, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3819</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many applications in photonics require all-optical manipulation of plasma
waves, which can concentrate electromagnetic energy on sub-wavelength length
scales. This is difficult in metallic plasmas because of their small optical
nonlinearities. Some layered superconductors support weakly damped plasma
waves, involving oscillatory tunneling of the superfluid between capacitively
coupled planes. Such Josephson plasma waves (JPWs) are also highly nonlinear,
and exhibit striking phenomena like cooperative emission of coherent terahertz
radiation, superconductor-metal oscillations and soliton formation. We show
here that terahertz JPWs in cuprate superconductors can be parametrically
amplified through the cubic tunneling nonlinearity. Parametric amplification is
sensitive to the relative phase between pump and seed waves and may be
optimized to achieve squeezing of the order parameter phase fluctuations or
single terahertz-photon devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02877</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02877</id><created>2015-12-09</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mitter</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>On a Finite Range Decomposition of the Resolvent of a Fractional Power
  of the Laplacian</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages, 1 figure, errors corrected, references added, two new
  appendices</comments><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1507-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the existence as well as regularity of a finite range decomposition
for the resolvent $G_{\alpha} (x-y,m^2) = ((-\Delta)^{\alpha\over 2} +
m^{2})^{-1} (x-y) $, for $0&lt;\alpha&lt;2$ and all real $m$, in the lattice
${\mathbf Z}^{d}$ as well as in the continuum ${\mathbf R}^{d}$ for dimension
$d\ge 2$. This resolvent occurs as the covariance of the Gaussian measure
underlying weakly self- avoiding walks with long range jumps (stable L\'evy
walks) as well as continuous spin ferromagnets with long range interactions in
the long wavelength or field theoretic approximation. The finite range
decomposition should be useful for the rigorous analysis of both critical and
off-critical renormalisation group trajectories. The decomposition for the
special case $m=0$ was known and used earlier in the renormalisation group
analysis of critical trajectories for the above models below the critical
dimension $d_c =2\alpha$. This revised version makes some changes, adds new
material, and also corrects some errors in the previous version. It refers to
the author's published article with the same title in J Stat Phys (2016) 163:
1235-1246, as well as to an erratum to be published in J Stat Phys.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06054</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06054</id><created>2015-12-18</created><updated>2016-07-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shapeev</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Moment Tensor Potentials: a class of systematically improvable
  interatomic potentials</title><categories>physics.comp-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci math.NA</categories><comments>22 pages; method re-implemented, numerical experiments updated,
  exposition improved, typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>Multiscale Modeling and Simulation, volume 14, pages 1153-1173,
  2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1137/15M1054183</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Density functional theory offers a very accurate way of computing materials
properties from first principles. However, it is too expensive for modelling
large-scale molecular systems whose properties are, in contrast, computed using
interatomic potentials.
  The present paper considers, from a mathematical point of view, the problem
of constructing interatomic potentials that approximate a given
quantum-mechanical interaction model. In particular, a new class of
systematically improvable potentials is proposed, analyzed, and tested on an
existing quantum-mechanical database.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01594</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Le Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imoto</keyname><forenames>Nobuyuki</forenames></author></authors><title>An interpretation and understanding of complex modular values</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In contrast to that a weak value of an observable is usually divided into
real and imaginary parts, here we show that separation into modulus and
argument is important for modular values. We first show that modular values are
expressed by the average of dynamic phase factors with complex conditional
probabilities. We then relate, using the polar decomposition, the modulus of
the modular value to the relative change in the qubit pointer post-selection
probabilities, and relate the argument of the modular value to the summation of
a geometric phase and an intrinsic phase.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00075</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-11-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>Jonah M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schnetter</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author></authors><title>An Operator-Based Local Discontinuous Galerkin Method Compatible With
  the BSSN Formulation of the Einstein Equations</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Incorporated referee comments during peer-review. Added several
  references pointed out to us. Added a figure and discussion comparing
  pointwise error for 4th- and 5th-order stencils for wave equation</comments><msc-class>83-08</msc-class><acm-class>G.1.8</acm-class><journal-ref>Class. Quantum Grav. 34 (2017) 1</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1361-6382/34/1/015003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discontinuous Galerkin Finite Element (DGFE) methods offer a mathematically
beautiful, computationally efficient, and efficiently parallelizable way to
solve hyperbolic partial differential equations. These properties make them
highly desirable for numerical calculations in relativistic astrophysics and
many other fields. The BSSN formulation of the Einstein equations has
repeatedly demonstrated its robustness. The formulation is not only stable but
allows for puncture-type evolutions of black hole systems. To-date no one has
been able to solve the full (3+1)-dimensional BSSN equations using DGFE
methods. This is partly because DGFE discretization often occurs at the level
of the equations, not the derivative operator, and partly because DGFE methods
are traditionally formulated for manifestly flux-conservative systems. By
discretizing the derivative operator, we generalize a particular flavor of DGFE
methods, Local DG methods, to solve arbitrary second-order hyperbolic
equations. Because we discretize at the level of the derivative operator, our
method can be interpreted as either a DGFE method or as a finite differences
stencil with non-constant coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08264</id><created>2016-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Mastropietro</keyname><forenames>Vieri</forenames></author></authors><title>Localization in interacting fermionic chains with quasi-random disorder</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Comm, Math. Phys 1-27 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2773-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a system of fermions with a quasi-random almost-Mathieu disorder
interacting through a many-body short range potential. We establish exponential
decay of the zero temperature correlations, indicating localization of the
interacting ground state, for weak hopping and interaction and almost
everywhere in the frequency and phase; this extends the analysis in \cite{M} to
chemical potentials outside spectral gaps. The proof is based on
Renormalization Group and is inspired by techniques developed to deal with KAM
Lindstedt series.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03435</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03435</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kenton</keyname><forenames>Zachary</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mulryne</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Separate Universe Approach to Soft Limits</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>28 pages, 7 figures. This is an author-created, un-copyedited version
  of an article published in JCAP. IOP Publishing Ltd is not responsible for
  any errors or omissions in this version of the manuscript or any version
  derived from it. The Version of Record is available online at the DOI below.
  v3: Updated to match version published in JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/10/035</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a formalism for calculating soft limits of $n$-point inflationary
correlation functions using separate universe techniques. Our method naturally
allows for multiple fields and leads to an elegant diagrammatic approach. As an
application we focus on the trispectrum produced by inflation with multiple
light fields, giving explicit formulae for all possible single- and double-soft
limits. We also investigate consistency relations and present an infinite tower
of inequalities between soft correlation functions which generalise the
Suyama-Yamaguchi inequality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01041</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maruyoshi</keyname><forenames>Kazunobu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yagi</keyname><forenames>Junya</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface defects as transfer matrices</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>58 pages. v2: minor changes, references added. v3: published version</comments><report-no>IMPERIAL-TP-16-KM-01</report-no><journal-ref>Prog. Theor. Exp. Phys. (2016) 113B01</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/ptep/ptw151</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The supersymmetric index of the 4d $\mathcal{N} = 1$ theory realized by a
brane tiling coincides with the partition function of an integrable 2d lattice
model. We argue that a class of half-BPS surface defects in brane tiling models
are represented on the lattice model side by transfer matrices constructed from
L-operators. For the simplest surface defects in theories with $\mathrm{SU}(2)$
flavor groups, we identify the relevant L-operator as that discovered by
Sklyanin in the context of the eight-vertex model. We verify this
identification by computing the indices of class-$\mathcal{S}$ and
-$\mathcal{S}_k$ theories in the presence of the surface defects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07774</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07774</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tiranov</keyname><forenames>Alexey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strassmann</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavoie</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brunner</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Varun B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nam</keyname><forenames>Sae Woo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirin</keyname><forenames>Richard P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lita</keyname><forenames>Adriana E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsili</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Afzelius</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bussi&#xe8;res</keyname><forenames>F&#xe9;lix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gisin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Temporal multimode storage of entangled photon pairs</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 240506 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.240506</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Multiplexed quantum memories capable of storing and processing entangled
photons are essential for the development of quantum networks. In this context,
we demonstrate the simultaneous storage and retrieval of two entangled photons
inside a solid-state quantum memory and measure a temporal multimode capacity
of ten modes. This is achieved by producing two polarization entangled pairs
from parametric down conversion and mapping one photon of each pair onto a
rare-earth-ion doped (REID) crystal using the atomic frequency comb (AFC)
protocol. We develop a concept of indirect entanglement witnesses, which can be
used as Schmidt number witness, and we use it to experimentally certify the
presence of more than one entangled pair retrieved from the quantum memory. Our
work puts forward REID-AFC as a platform compatible with temporal multiplexing
of several entangled photon pairs along with a new entanglement certification
method useful for the characterisation of multiplexed quantum memories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09207</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09207</id><created>2016-06-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Reischke</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pace</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meyer</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xe4;fer</keyname><forenames>Bj&#xf6;rn Malte</forenames></author></authors><title>Spherical collapse of dark matter haloes in tidal gravitational fields</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures, submitted to MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2016 463(1):
  429-440</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1989</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the spherical collapse model in the presence of external
gravitational tidal shear fields for different dark energy scenarios and
investigate the impact on the mass function and cluster number counts. While
previous studies of the influence of shear and rotation on $\delta_\mathrm{c}$
have been performed with heuristically motivated models, we try to avoid this
model dependence and sample the external tidal shear values directly from the
statistics of the underlying linearly evolved density field based on first
order Lagrangian perturbation theory. Within this self-consistent approach, in
the sense that we restrict our treatment to scales where linear theory is still
applicable, only fluctuations larger than the scale of the considered objects
are included into the sampling process which naturally introduces a mass
dependence of $\delta_\mathrm{c}$. We find that shear effects are predominant
for smaller objects and at lower redshifts, i. e. the effect on
$\delta_\mathrm{c}$ is at or below the percent level for the $\Lambda$CDM
model. For dark energy models we also find small but noticeable differences,
similar to $\Lambda$CDM. The virial overdensity $\Delta_\mathrm{V}$ is nearly
unaffected by the external shear. The now mass dependent $\delta_c$ is used to
evaluate the mass function for different dark energy scenarios and afterwards
to predict cluster number counts, which indicate that ignoring the shear
contribution can lead to biases of the order of $1\sigma$ in the estimation of
cosmological parameters like $\Omega_\mathrm{m}$, $\sigma_8$ or $w$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00841</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00841</id><created>2016-07-04</created><updated>2016-10-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chandola</keyname><forenames>Yogesh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saikia</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>HI absorption towards low luminosity radio-loud AGNs of different
  accretion modes and WISE colours</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures, this updated version is accepted for publication
  in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2017 465 (1):
  997-1007</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw2705</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  H{\sc i} absorption studies of active galaxies enable us to probe their
circumnuclear regions and the general interstellar medium, and study the supply
of gas which may trigger the nuclear activity. In this paper, we investigate
the detection rate of H{\sc i} absorption on the nature of radio galaxies based
on their emission-line spectra, nature of the host galaxies based on the
\textit{WISE} colours and their radio structure, which may help understand the
different accretion modes. We find significant difference in distributions of
W2$-$W3 colour for sources with H{\sc i} absorption detections and
non-detections. We report a high detection rate of H{\sc i} absorption in the
galaxies with \textit{WISE} infrared colours W2$-$W3 $&gt;$ 2, which is typical of
gas-rich systems, along with a compact radio structure. The H{\sc i} detection
rate for low-excitation radio galaxies (LERGs) with W2$-$W3 $&gt;$ 2 and compact
radio structure is high (70.6$\pm$20.4 \%). In HERGs, compact radio structure
in the nuclear or circumnuclear region could give rise to absorption by gas in
the dusty torus in addition to gas in the interstellar medium. However, higher
specific star formation rate (sSFR) for the LERGs with W2$-$W3 $&gt;$ 2 suggests
that H{\sc i} absorption may be largely due to star-forming gas in their hosts.
LERGs with extended radio structure tend to have significantly lower values of
W2$-$W3 compared to those with compact structure. Extended radio sources and
those with W2$-$W3 $&lt;$ 2 have low H{\sc i} detection rates.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05621</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05621</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>ATLAS Collaboration</keyname></author></authors><title>Search for new resonances decaying to a $W$ or $Z$ boson and a Higgs
  boson in the $\ell^+ \ell^- b\bar b$, $\ell \nu b\bar b$, and $\nu\bar{\nu}
  b\bar b$ channels with $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt s = 13$ TeV with the ATLAS
  detector</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>18 pages (plus author list + cover pages: 36 pages total), 13
  figures, 1 table. Submitted to PLB. All figures including auxiliary figures
  are available at
  https://atlas.web.cern.ch/Atlas/GROUPS/PHYSICS/PAPERS/EXOT-2015-18/</comments><report-no>CERN-EP-2016-148</report-no><journal-ref>Physics Letters B 765(2017) 32-52</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A search is presented for new resonances decaying to a $W$ or $Z$ boson and a
Higgs boson in the $\ell^+ \ell^- b\bar b$, $\ell\nu b\bar b$, and
$\nu\bar{\nu} b\bar b$ channels in $pp$ collisions at $\sqrt s = 13$ TeV with
the ATLAS detector at the Large Hadron Collider using a total integrated
luminosity of 3.2 fb$^{-1}$. The search is conducted by looking for a localized
excess in the $WH$/$ZH$ invariant or transverse mass distribution. No
significant excess is observed, and the results are interpreted in terms of
constraints on a simplified model based on a phenomenological Lagrangian of
heavy vector triplets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07149</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07149</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient quantum circuits for dense and non-unitary operators</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>An example application in solving the equation of motion for a
  vibrating system with cyclic symmetry is added in Section 7</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Circulant matrices are an important family of operators, which have a wide
range of applications in science and engineering related fields. They are in
general non-sparse and non-unitary. In this paper, we present efficient quantum
circuits to implement circulant operators using fewer resources and with lower
complexity than existing methods. Moreover, our quantum circuits can be readily
extended to the implementation of Toeplitz, Hankel, and block circulant
matrices. Efficient quantum algorithms to implement the inverses and products
of circulant operators are also provided.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.00463</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.00463</id><created>2016-08-01</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gintner</keyname><forenames>Mikulas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Juran</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author></authors><title>The limits on the strong Higgs sector parameters in the presence of new
  vector resonances</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Published in The European Physical Journal C; the new section on the
  vector resonance mass limits and the upper bounds on the vector production
  cross section times the branching ratio has been added; new references added;
  Conclusions extended; other minor changes in the text; 17 pages, 10 figures,
  4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 651</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4484-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we investigate how the LHC data limit the Higgs-related
couplings in the effective description of a strongly interacting extension of
the Standard model. The Higgs boson is introduced as a scalar composite state
and it is followed in the mass hierarchy by an $SU(2)$ triplet of vector
composites. The limits are calculated from the constraints obtained in the
recent ATLAS+CMS combined analysis of the data from 2011 and 2012. We find that
the data prefer the scenario where the Higgs couplings to the electroweak gauge
bosons differ from its couplings to the vector triplet. We also investigate the
unitarity limits of the studied effective model for the experimentally
preferred values of the Higgs couplings. We find from the
$\pi\pi\rightarrow\pi\pi$ scattering amplitudes that for the vector resonance
masses between one and two TeV significant portions of the experimentally
allowed regions are well below the unitarity limit. We also evaluate how the
existing ATLAS and CMS Run-2 data restrict our model with the upper bounds on
the resonance production cross section times its branching ratio for various
decay channels. The masses in the range $1\;\mbox{TeV}\leq M_\rho\leq
2\;\mbox{TeV}$ are not excluded in parts or even full parameter space of our
theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.03496</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.03496</id><created>2016-08-10</created><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf6;rlich</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalomenopoulos</keyname><forenames>Marios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savvidy</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savvidy</keyname><forenames>George</forenames></author></authors><title>Distribution of periodic trajectories of Anosov C-system</title><categories>nlin.CD hep-lat hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 14 figures</comments><report-no>NRCPS-HE-52-2016</report-no><doi>10.1142/S0129183117500322</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The hyperbolic Anosov C-systems have a countable set of everywhere dense
periodic trajectories which have been recently used to generate pseudorandom
numbers. The asymptotic distribution of periodic trajectories of C-systems with
periods less than a given number is well known, but a deviation of this
distribution from its asymptotic behaviour is less known. Using fast
algorithms, we are studying the exact distribution of periodic trajectories and
their deviation from asymptotic behaviour for hyperbolic C-systems which are
defined on high dimensional tori and are used for Monte-Carlo simulations. A
particular C-system which we consider in this article is the one which was
implemented in the MIXMAX generator of pseudorandom numbers. The generator has
the best combination of speed, reasonable size of the state, and availability
for implementing the parallelization and is currently available generator in
the ROOT and CLHEP software packages at CERN.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.05615</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.05615</id><created>2016-08-19</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drischler</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carbone</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hebeler</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwenk</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutron matter from chiral two- and three-nucleon calculations up to
  N$^3$LO</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>minor changes, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 054307 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.054307</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutron matter is an ideal laboratory for nuclear interactions derived from
chiral effective field theory since all contributions are predicted up to
next-to-next-to-next-to-leading order (N$^3$LO) in the chiral expansion. By
making use of recent advances in the partial-wave decomposition of three-
nucleon (3N) forces, we include for the first time N$^3$LO 3N interactions in
many-body perturbation theory (MBPT) up to third order and in self-consistent
Green's function theory (SCGF). Using these two complementary many-body
frameworks we provide improved predictions for the equation of state of neutron
matter at zero temperature and also analyze systematically the many-body
convergence for different chiral EFT interactions. Furthermore, we present an
extension of the normal-ordering framework to finite temperatures. These
developments open the way to improved calculations of neutron-rich matter
including estimates of theoretical uncertainties for astrophysical
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.07805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.07805</id><created>2016-08-28</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongqi</forenames></author></authors><title>Photospheric Magnetic Free Energy Density of Solar Active Regions</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>submit 20 pages, 12 figures, Solar Physics, 2016</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-1009-8</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  We present the photospheric energy density of magnetic fields in two solar
active regions inferred from observational vector magnetograms, and compare it
with the possible different defined energy parameters of magnetic fields in the
photosphere. We analyze the magnetic fields in active region NOAA
6580-6619-6659 and 11158. It is noticed that the quantity 1/4pi Bn.Bp is an
important energy parameter that reflects the contribution of magnetic shear on
the difference between the potential magnetic field (Bp) and non-potential one
(Bn), and also the contribution to the free magnetic energy near the magnetic
neutral lines in the active regions. It is found that the photospheric mean
magnetic energy density changes obviously before the powerful solar flares in
the active region NOAA 11158, it is consistent with the change of magnetic
fields in the lower atmosphere with flares.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06087</id><created>2016-09-20</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Povarov</keyname><forenames>K. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheludev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiferroic phases of the frustrated quantum spin-chain compound
  linarite</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>11 pages, 18 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 214409 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.214409</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dielectric properties of the prototypical frustrated ferromagnetic
spin-chain compound PbCuSO$_4$(OH)$_2$ known as linarite, are studied across
its strongly anisotropic magnetic phase diagram in single crystal samples. The
ferroelectric character of the principal low-field spin spiral phase is
confirmed. The measured polarization is fully consistent with the previously
proposed magnetic structure. Spontaneous polarization is also detected in two
other field-induced phases but in some cases is incompatible with previously
suggested models for the spin arrangement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07992</id><created>2016-09-23</created><updated>2016-10-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Farrugia</keyname><forenames>Christine R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sultana</keyname><forenames>Joseph</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamic Geodesics of a Reissner Nordstr\&quot;om Black Hole</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, 4 figures</comments><msc-class>Primary 83C57, Secondary 80M30</msc-class><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2169-4</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Starting from a Geometrothermodynamics metric for the space of thermodynamic
equilibrium states in the mass representation, we use numerical techniques to
analyse the thermodynamic geodesics of a supermassive Reissner Nordstr\&quot;{o}m
black hole in isolation. Appropriate constraints are obtained by taking into
account the processes of Hawking radiation and Schwinger pair--production. We
model the black hole in line with the work of Hiscock and Weems. It can be
deduced that the relation which the geodesics establish between the entropy $S$
and electric charge $Q$ of the black hole extremises changes in the black
hole's mass. Indeed, the expression for the entropy of an extremal black hole
is an exact solution to the geodesic equation. We also find that in certain
cases, the geodesics describe the evolution brought about by the constant
emission of Hawking radiation and charged-particle pairs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09311</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09311</id><created>2016-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmidt-B&#xf6;cking</keyname><forenames>Horst</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Lothar</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;dde</keyname><forenames>Hans J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trageser</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauer</keyname><forenames>Tilman</forenames></author></authors><title>The Stern-Gerlach Experiment Revisited</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>50pp, 17 figs</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. H 41, 327-364 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjh/e2016-70053-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Stern-Gerlach-Experiment (SGE) of 1922 is a seminal benchmark experiment
of quantum physics providing evidence for several fundamental properties of
quantum systems. Based on today's knowledge we illustrate the different
benchmark results of the SGE for the development of modern quantum physics and
chemistry.
  The SGE provided the first direct experimental evidence for angular momentum
quantization in the quantum world and thus also for the existence of
directional quantization of all angular momenta in the process of measurement.
It measured for the first time a ground state property of an atom, it produced
for the first time a `spin-polarized' atomic beam, it almost revealed the
electron spin. The SGE was the first fully successful molecular beam experiment
with high momentum-resolution by beam measurements in vacuum. This technique
provided a new kinematic microscope with which inner atomic or nuclear
properties could be investigated.
  The original SGE is described together with early attempts by Einstein,
Ehrenfest, Heisenberg, and others to understand directional quantization in the
SGE. Heisenberg's and Einstein's proposals of an improved multi-stage SGE are
presented. The first realization of these proposals by Stern, Phipps, Frisch
and Segr\`e is described. The set-up suggested by Einstein can be considered an
anticipation of a Rabi-apparatus. Recent theoretical work is mentioned in which
the directional quantization process and possible interference effects of the
two different spin states are investigated.
  In full agreement with the results of the new quantum theory directional
quantization appears as a general and universal feature of quantum
measurements. One experimental example for such directional quantization in
scattering processes is shown. Last not least, the early history of the
`almost' discovery of the electron spin in the SGE is revisited.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.09402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.09402</id><created>2016-09-29</created><updated>2016-11-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>Stephen F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Jue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Shun</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalisation Group Corrections to the Littlest Seesaw Model and
  Maximal Atmospheric Mixing</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 4 figures, 5 tables; v2: references added, include the
  scenario where both mass scales of right-handed neutrinos are varied, version
  to be published in JHEP</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 12 (2016) 023</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP12(2016)023</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Littlest Seesaw (LS) model involves two right-handed neutrinos and a very
constrained Dirac neutrino mass matrix, involving one texture zero and two
independent Dirac masses, leading to a highly predictive scheme in which all
neutrino masses and the entire PMNS matrix is successfully predicted in terms
of just two real parameters. We calculate the renormalisation group (RG)
corrections to the LS predictions, with and without supersymmetry, including
also the threshold effects induced by the decoupling of heavy Majorana
neutrinos both analytically and numerically. We find that the predictions for
neutrino mixing angles and mass ratios are rather stable under RG corrections.
For example we find that the LS model with RG corrections predicts close to
maximal atmospheric mixing, $\theta_{23}=45^\circ \pm 1^\circ$, in most
considered cases, in tension with the latest NOvA results. The techniques used
here apply to other seesaw models with a strong normal mass hierarchy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.04532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.04532</id><created>2016-10-14</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bonivento</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorbunov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaposhnikov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokareva</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polarization of photons emitted by decaying dark matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><report-no>INR-TH-2016-039</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.11.048</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Radiatively decaying dark matter may be searched through investigating the
photon spectrum of galaxies and galaxy clusters. We explore whether the
properties of dark matter can be constrained through the study of a
polarization state of emitted photons. Starting from the basic principles of
quantum mechanics we show that the models of symmetric dark matter are
indiscernible by the photon polarization. However, we find that the asymmetric
dark matter consisted of Dirac fermions is a source of circularly polarized
photons, calling for the experimental determination of the photon state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.06177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.06177</id><created>2016-10-19</created><updated>2016-11-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cortijo</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic field-Induced Nonlinear Optical Responses in Inversion
  Symmetric Dirac Semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Expanded version with new results added</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 235123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.235123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that, under the effect of an external magnetic field, a photogalvanic
effect and the generation of second harmonic wave can be induced in
inversion-symmetric and time reversal invariant Dirac semimetals. The mechanism
responsible of these non linear optical responses is the magnetochiral effect.
The origin of this magnetochiral effect is the band bending of the dispersion
relation in real Dirac semimetals. Some observable consequences of this
phenomenon are the appearance of a dc current on the surface of the system when
it is irradiated with linearly polarized light or a rotation of the
polarization plane of the reflected second harmonic wave.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.07399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.07399</id><created>2016-10-24</created><updated>2016-11-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stillinger</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torquato</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Perfect Glass Paradigm: Disordered Hyperuniform Glasses Down to
  Absolute Zero</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 36963 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep36963</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rapid cooling of liquids below a certain temperature range can result in a
transition to glassy states. The traditional understanding of glasses includes
their thermodynamic metastability with respect to crystals. However, here we
present specific examples of interactions that eliminate the possibilities of
crystalline and quasicrystalline phases, while creating mechanically stable
amorphous glasses down to absolute zero temperature. We show that this can be
accomplished by introducing a new ideal state of matter called a &quot;perfect
glass.&quot; A perfect glass represents a soft-interaction analog of the maximally
random jammed (MRJ) packings of hard particles. These latter states can be
regarded as the epitome of a glass since they are out of equilibrium, maximally
disordered, hyperuniform, mechanically rigid with infinite bulk and shear
moduli, and can never crystallize due to configuration-space trapping. Our
model perfect glass utilizes two-, three-, and four-body soft interactions
while simultaneously retaining the salient attributes of the MRJ state. These
models constitute a theoretical proof of concept for perfect glasses and
broaden our fundamental understanding of glass physics. A novel feature of
equilibrium systems of identical particles interacting with the perfect-glass
potential at positive temperature is that they have a non-relativistic speed of
sound that is infinite.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.08678</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.08678</id><created>2016-10-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bleicher</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>St&#xf6;cker</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Csernai</keyname><forenames>L. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>$\Lambda$ polarization in peripheral collisions at moderate relativistic
  energies</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.054907</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The polarization of $\Lambda$ hyperons from relativistic flow vorticity is
studied in peripheral heavy ion reactions at FAIR and NICA energies, just above
the threshold of the transition to the Quark-Gluon Plasma. Previous
calculations at higher energies with larger initial angular momentum, predicted
significant $\Lambda$ polarization based on the classical vorticity term in the
polarization, while relativistic modifications decreased the polarization and
changed its structure in the momentum space. At the lower energies studied
here, we see the same effect namely that the relativistic modifications
decrease the polarization arising from the initial shear flow vorticity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01282</id><created>2016-11-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Jizba</keyname><forenames>Petr</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korbel</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Generalized Shannon--Khinchin axioms and uniqueness theorem
  for pseudo-additive entropies&quot; [Physica A 411 (2014) 138]</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech math.MP</categories><journal-ref>Physica A 468 (2017) 238-243</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2016.11.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently in [Physica A 411 (2014) 138] Ili\'{c} and Stankovi\'{c} have
suggested that there may be problem for the class of hybrid entropies
introduced in [P.~Jizba and T.~Arimitsu, Physica A 340 (2004) 110]. In this
Comment we point out that the problem can be traced down to the $q$-additive
entropic chain rule and to a peculiar behavior of the DeFinetti--Kolmogorov
relation for escort distributions. However, despite this, one can still safely
use the proposed hybrid entropies in most of the statistical-thermodynamics
considerations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01316</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01316</id><created>2016-11-04</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaunt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double parton scattering in the ultraviolet: addressing the double
  counting problem</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures. To appear in the proceedings of the QCD Evolution
  Workshop 2016, Amsterdam, the Netherlands, May 30 - June 3, 2016. v2: fixed a
  typo in eq. 3.6 (values transposed between h_g and h_q), inserted missing
  factor 2pi in all curves in figure 3</comments><report-no>DESY 16-208</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An important question in the theory of double parton scattering is how to
incorporate the possibility of the parton pairs being generated perturbatively
via $1 \to 2$ splitting into the theory, whilst avoiding double counting with
single parton scattering loop corrections. Here, we describe a consistent
approach for solving this problem, which retains the notion of double parton
distributions (DPDs) for individual hadrons. Further, we discuss the
construction of appropriate model DPDs in our framework, and the use of these
to compute the DPS part, presenting DPS 'luminosities' from our model DPDs for
a few sample cases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.06826</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.06826</id><created>2016-11-21</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Assili</keyname><forenames>Sanam</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffusion and Perfusion Magnetic Resonance Imaging:Fundamentals and
  Advances</title><categories>physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Over the past few decades, magnetic resonance imaging has been utilized as a
powerful imaging modality to evaluate the structure and function of various
organs in the human body,such as the brain. Additionally, diffusion and
perfusion MR imaging have been increasingly used in neurovascular clinical
applications. In diffusion-weighted magnetic resonance imaging, the mobility of
water molecules is explored in order to obtain information about the
microscopic behavior of the tissues. In contrast, perfusion weighted imaging
uses tracers to exploit hemodynamic status, which enables researchers and
clinicians to consider this imaging modality as an early biomarker of certain
brain diseases. In this review, the fundamentals of physics for diffusion and
perfusion MR imaging both of which are highly sensitive to microenvironmental
alterations at the cellular level as well as their application in the treatment
of aging, Alzheimer's disease, brain tumors and cerebral ischemic injury were
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.07587</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.07587</id><created>2016-11-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Tatara</keyname><forenames>Gen</forenames></author></authors><title>Green's function representation of spin pumping effect</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 224412 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.224412</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this study, current pumping by an external potential is studied on the
basis of the Keldysh Green's function method, and a pumping formula written in
terms of retarded and advanced Green's functions is obtained. It is shown that
pumping is essentially driven by a change of particle distribution before and
after an external perturbation. The formula is used to study the spin pumping
effect in the case of strong sd exchange interaction, and the driving field is
identified to be the spin gauge field. At the lowest order in the precession
frequency of magnetization, the spin gauge field works as a constant potential,
and the system is shown to reduce to a static problem of spin current
generation by a time-independent potential with off-diagonal spin components.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.10066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.10066</id><created>2016-11-30</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kalashnikova</keyname><forenames>Yu. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefediev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD string in excited heavy-light mesons and heavy-quark hybrids</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat</categories><comments>LaTeX2e, 10 pages, 1 figures, 9 tables, version published in
  Phys.Rev.D</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 114007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.114007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The QCD string model is employed to evaluate the masses of orbitally and
radially excited heavy-light mesons and lightest hybrids in the spectrum of
charmonium and bottomonium. The number of parameters of the model is reduced to
only seven which are the string tension, the two values of the strong coupling
constant (one for heavy-light and $\bar{c}c$ mesons and one for $\bar{b}b$
mesons), and the four overall spectrum shift constants which depend on the
quark contents of the particular meson or hybrid family. A few well-established
states in the spectrum of heavy-light and heavy-heavy mesons are used to fix
these parameters, and then the masses of other mesons and hybrids come out as
predictions of the model which are confronted with the existing experimental
data, and a few suggestions are made concerning yet not measured quantum
numbers of some states in the spectrum of charmonium and bottomonium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00141</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00141</id><created>2016-11-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Mukhopadhyay</keyname><forenames>Ayan</forenames></author></authors><title>Understanding the holographic principle via RG flow</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>19 pages; invited review to IJMPA</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics A Vol. 31, No. 34 (2016)
  1630059</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16300593</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This is a review of some recent works which demonstrate how the classical
equations of gravity in AdS themselves hold the key to understanding their
holographic origin in the form of a strongly coupled large $N$ QFT whose
algebra of local operators can be generated by a few (single-trace) elements. I
discuss how this can be realised by reformulating Einstein's equations in AdS
in the form of a non-perturbative RG flow that further leads to a new approach
towards constructing strongly interacting QFTs. In particular, the RG flow can
self-determine the UV data that are otherwise obtained by solving classical
gravity equations and demanding that the solutions do not have naked
singularities. For a concrete demonstration, I focus on the hydrodynamic limit
in which case this RG flow connects the AdS/CFT correspondence with the
membrane paradigm, and also reproduces the known values of the dual QFT
transport coefficients.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.00573</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.00573</id><created>2016-12-02</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhdanov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bondar</keyname><forenames>Denys I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seideman</keyname><forenames>Tamar</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum friction: environment engineering perspectives</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>12 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a generalization of the Lindblad's fundamental no-go result: A
quantum system cannot be completely frozen and, in some cases, even thermalized
via translationally invariant dissipation -- the quantum friction.
Nevertheless, a practical methodology is proposed for engineering nearly
perfect quantum analogs of classical friction within the Doppler cooling
framework. These findings pave the way for hallmark dissipative engineering
(e.g. nonreciprocal couplings) with atoms and molecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02086</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02086</id><created>2016-12-06</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kimura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster states in stable and unstable nuclei</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><comments>23 pages, to be published in the ebook &quot;Progress of time-dependent
  nuclear reaction theory&quot; (Betham Science Publishers 2016) honoring Prof.
  Joachim Maruhn's retirement</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this contribution, I will discuss two topics related to the clustering of
atomic nuclei. The first is dual character of the ground state. Recently, it
was pointed out that the ground states of atomic nuclei have dual character of
shell and cluster implying that both of the single-particle excitation and
cluster excitation occur as the fundamental excitation modes. The isoscalar
monopole and dipole transitions are regarded as the triggers to induce the
cluster excitation. By referring the Hartree-Fock and antisymmetrized molecular
dynamics calculations, the dual character and those transitions are explained.
The second is the linear-chain state of $^{16}{\rm C}$ in which the linearly
aligned 3$\alpha$ particles are sustained by the valence neutrons. The rather
convincing evidences for this exotic state are very recently reported by
several experiments. Here, I introduce a couple of theoretical analysis and
predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02288</id><created>2016-12-03</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Handley</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasenby</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hobson</keyname><forenames>M. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Runge-Kutta-Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin Method</title><categories>physics.comp-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, submitted to the Journal of Computational Physics</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate the effectiveness of a novel scheme for numerically solving
linear differential equations whose solutions exhibit extreme oscillation. We
take a standard Runge-Kutta approach, but replace the Taylor expansion formula
with a Wentzel-Kramers-Brillouin method. The method is demonstrated by
application to the Airy equation, along with a more complicated
burst-oscillation case. Finally, we compare our scheme to existing approaches.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02289</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02289</id><created>2016-12-03</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shu</keyname><forenames>Liangsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Xiaokang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Suyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>Shiping</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermodynamics of static: Observers in Gibbs paradox</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, Gibbs paradox was discussed from the view of observer. The
limitations of real observer are analyzed quantitatively. The entropy of mixing
was found to be determined by both the identification ability and the
information already in hand of an observer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02418</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02418</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Minaev</keyname><forenames>Pavel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pozanenko</keyname><forenames>Alexei</forenames></author></authors><title>Precursors of Short Gamma-Ray Bursts in the SPI-ACS/INTEGRAL Experiment</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>33 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1134/S1063773717010017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have analyzed the light curves of 519 short gamma-ray bursts (GRBs)
detected in the SPI-ACS/INTEGRAL experiment from December 2002 to May 2014 to
search for precursors. Both the light curves of 519 individual events and the
averaged light curve of 372 brightest bursts have been analyzed. In a few
cases, we have found and thoroughly studied precursor candidates based on
SPI-ACS/INTEGRAL, GBM/Fermi, and LAT/Fermi data. A statistical analysis of the
averaged light curve for the entire sample of short bursts has revealed no
regular precursor. Upper limits for the relative intensity of precursors have
been estimated. No convincing evidence for the existence of precursors of short
GRBs has been found. We show that the fraction of short GRBs with precursors is
less than 0.4% of all short bursts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02690</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Adepoju</keyname><forenames>Adenike Grace</forenames></author><author><keyname>Falaye</keyname><forenames>Babatunde James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Guo-Hua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camacho-Nieto</keyname><forenames>Oscar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shi-Hai</forenames></author></authors><title>Joint remote state preparation (JRSP) of two-qubit equatorial state in
  quantum noisy channels</title><categories>quant-ph cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1609.01538</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physleta.2016.12.021</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This letter reports the influence of noisy channels on JRSP of two-qubit
equatorial state. We present a scheme for JRSP of two-qubit equatorial state.
We employ two tripartite Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) entangled states as
the quantum channel linking the parties. We find the success probability to be
$1/4$. However, this probability can be ameliorated to $3/4$ if the state
preparers assist by transmitting individual partial information through
classical channel to the receiver non-contemporaneously. Afterward, we
investigate the effects of five quantum noises: the bit-flip noise, bit-phase
flip noise, amplitude-damping noise, phase-damping noise and depolarizing noise
on the JRSP process. We obtain the analytical derivation of the fidelities
corresponding to each quantum noisy channel, which is a measure of information
loss as the qubits are being distributed in these quantum channels. We find
that the system loses some of its properties as a consequence of unwanted
interactions with environment. For instance, within the domain
$0&lt;\lambda&lt;0.65$, the information lost via transmission of qubits in amplitude
channel is most minimal, while for $0.65&lt;\lambda\leq1$, the information lost in
phase flip channel becomes the most minimal. Also, for any given $\lambda$, the
information transmitted through depolarizing channel has the least chance of
success.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02798</id><created>2016-12-08</created><updated>2016-12-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Slater</keyname><forenames>Paul B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Octonionic two-qubit separability probability conjectures</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><comments>8 pages. The formula for P_{2}(\alpha) needed--due to an oversight to
  be multiplied by 2 (as Charles Dunkl pointed out)</comments><msc-class>17A35, 81P40, 81P45</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study, further, a conjectured formula for generalized two-qubit
Hilbert-Schmidt separability probabilities that has recently been proven by
Lovas and Andai (https://arxiv.org/pdf/1610.01410.pdf) for its real (two-rebit)
asserted value ($\frac{29}{64}$), and that has also been very strongly
supported numerically for its complex ($\frac{8}{33}$), and quaternionic
($\frac{26}{323}$) counterparts. Now, we seek to test the presumptive
octonionic value of $\frac{44482}{4091349} \approx 0.0108722$. We are somewhat
encouraged by certain numerical computations, indicating that this
(51-dimensional) instance of the conjecture might be fulfilled by setting a
certain determinantal-power parameter $a$, introduced by Forrester
(https://arxiv.org/pdf/1610.08081.pdf), to 0 (or possibly near to 0).
Hilbert-Schmidt measure being the case $k=0$ of random induced measure, for
$k=1$, the corresponding octonionic separability probability conjecture is
$\frac{7612846}{293213345} \approx 0.0259635$, while for $k=2$, it is
$\frac{4893392}{95041567} \approx 0.0514869, \ldots$. The relation between the
parameters $a$ and $k$ is explored.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02824</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02824</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Best</keyname><forenames>William M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Michael C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnier</keyname><forenames>Eugene A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deacon</keyname><forenames>Niall R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aller</keyname><forenames>Kimberly M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redstone</keyname><forenames>Joshua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burgett</keyname><forenames>W. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chambers</keyname><forenames>K. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Draper</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flewelling</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hodapp</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaiser</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metcalfe</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tonry</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wainscoat</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Search for L/T Transition Dwarfs With Pan-STARRS1 and WISE. II. L/T
  Transition Atmospheres and Young Discoveries</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>90 pages, 23 figures, 14 tables. Published in ApJ 2015 December 1</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 814, 188 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/814/2/118</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The evolution of brown dwarfs from L to T spectral types is one of the least
understood aspects of the ultracool population, partly for lack of a large,
well-defined, and well-characterized sample in the L/T transition. To improve
the existing census, we have searched $\approx$28,000 deg$^2$ using the
Pan-STARRS1 and WISE surveys for L/T transition dwarfs within 25 pc. We present
130 ultracool dwarf discoveries with estimated distances $\approx9-130$ pc,
including 21 that were independently discovered by other authors and 3 that
were previously identified as photometric candidates. Seventy-nine of our
objects have near-IR spectral types of L6-T4.5, the most L/T transition dwarfs
from any search to date, and we have increased the census of L9-T1.5 objects
within 25 pc by over 50%. The color distribution of our discoveries provides
further evidence for the &quot;L/T gap,&quot; a deficit of objects with $(J-K)_{\rm
MKO}\approx0.0-0.5$ mag in the L/T transition, and thus reinforces the idea
that the transition from cloudy to clear photospheres occurs rapidly. Among our
discoveries are 31 candidate binaries based on their low-resolution spectral
features. Two of these candidates are common proper motion companions to nearby
main sequence stars; if confirmed as binaries, these would be rare benchmark
systems with the potential to stringently test ultracool evolutionary models.
Our search also serendipitously identified 23 late-M and L dwarfs with
spectroscopic signs of low gravity implying youth. Finally, we identify 10
candidate members of nearby young moving groups (YMG) with spectral types
L7-T4.5, including three showing spectroscopic signs of low gravity. If
confirmed, any of these would be among the coolest known YMG members and would
help to determine the effective temperature at which young brown dwarfs cross
the L/T transition. (Abridged)
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02855</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yi-Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glatzmaier</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Keh-Fei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>The 1-loop correction of the QCD energy momentum tensor with the overlap
  fermion and HYP smeared Iwasaki gluon</title><categories>nucl-th hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the 1-loop renormalization of the energy momentum tensor using the
overlap fermion and a HYP-smeared Iwasaki gauge action. We also calculate the
1-loop matching coefficient that convert the lattice simulation results
renormalized in the RI/MOM scheme to the $\overline{\textrm{MS}}$ scheme. The
dependence of the renormalization on the gauge action and the number of HYP
smearing steps are also investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02865</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02865</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>St&#xfc;eken</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kipp</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koehler</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwieterman</keyname><forenames>E. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buick</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling pN2 through Geological Time: Implications for Planetary
  Climates and Atmospheric Biosignatures</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>33 pages, 11 figures, 2 tables (includes appendix), published in
  Astrobiology</comments><journal-ref>Astrobiology, Volume 16, Number 12, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1089/ast.2016.1537</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nitrogen is a major nutrient for all life on Earth and could plausibly play a
similar role in extraterrestrial biospheres. The major reservoir of nitrogen at
Earth's surface is atmospheric N2, but recent studies have proposed that the
size of this reservoir may have fluctuated significantly over the course of
Earth's history with particularly low levels in the Neoarchean - presumably as
a result of biological activity. We used a biogeochemical box model to test
which conditions are necessary to cause large swings in atmospheric N2
pressure. Parameters for our model are constrained by observations of modern
Earth and reconstructions of biomass burial and oxidative weathering in deep
time. A 1-D climate model was used to model potential effects on atmospheric
climate. In a second set of tests, we perturbed our box model to investigate
which parameters have the greatest impact on the evolution of atmospheric pN2
and consider possible implications for nitrogen cycling on other planets. Our
results suggest that (a) a high rate of biomass burial would have been needed
in the Archean to draw down atmospheric pN2 to less than half modern levels,
(b) the resulting effect on temperature could probably have been compensated by
increasing solar luminosity and a mild increase in pCO2, and (c) atmospheric
oxygenation could have initiated a stepwise pN2 rebound through oxidative
weathering. In general, life appears to be necessary for significant
atmospheric pN2 swings on Earth-like planets. Our results further support the
idea that an exoplanetary atmosphere rich in both N2 and O2 is a signature of
an oxygen-producing biosphere.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02883</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02883</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>Qiran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Aijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Guoping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mateti</keyname><forenames>Srikanth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cowie</keyname><forenames>Bruce C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Yuerui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Lan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taniguchi</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Shaoming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruoff</keyname><forenames>Rodney S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lu Hua</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecule-Induced Conformational Change in Boron Nitride Nanosheets with
  Enhanced Surface Adsorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Adv. Funct. Mater. 26, 8202-8210 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/adfm.201603160</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Surface interaction is extremely important to both fundamental research and
practical application. Physisorption can induce shape and structural distortion
(i.e. conformational changes) in macromolecular and biomolecular adsorbates,
but such phenomenon has rarely been observed on adsorbents. Here, we
demonstrate theoretically and experimentally that atomically thin boron nitride
(BN) nanosheets as an adsorbent experience conformational changes upon surface
adsorption of molecules, increasing adsorption energy and efficiency. The study
not only provides new perspectives on the strong adsorption capability of BN
nanosheets and many other two-dimensional nanomaterials but also opens up
possibilities for many novel applications. For example, we demonstrate that BN
nanosheets with the same surface area as bulk hBN particles are more effective
in purification and sensing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02890</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02890</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyeong-Seok D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>Yubo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rappe</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Adsorption of Benzene on the RuO2(110) Surface</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hydrocarbon tribopolymer, a type of polymer formed due to friction between
surfaces, is a major impediment to the development of micro- and
nanoelectromechanical systems (MEMS/NEMS) devices for industrial application.
Tribopolymer buildup can prevent MEMS and NEMS from making or breaking
electrical contact. We describe the adsorption of benzene (C6H6) on the
RuO2(110) surface using density functional theory. This adsorption is an
important initial step in the mechanism of hydrocarbon tribopolymer layer
formation on MEMS and NEMS devices. The adsorption interaction is studied by
considering three oxygen coverages of RuO2(110) and all the possible adsorption
sites for benzene. We find that adsorption of benzene on O-poor RuO2(110) via
C-Ru bonds is stronger than adsorption on the O-rich RuO2(110) via H-O bonds.
For an in-depth study of the adsorption behavior, we include the van der Waals
interaction for a holistic investigation. By incorporating the thermodynamic
chemical potentials into the adsorption simulations, we describe a model that
can provide guidance for realistic situations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02899</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02899</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Ru</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Ben-Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing cold nuclear matter effects with weak gauge boson production in
  ultra-relativistic heavy-ion collisions</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>4 pages, 7 figures. Proceedings for the 8th International Conference
  on Hard and Electromagnetic Probes of High-energy Nuclear Collisions (Hard
  Probes 2016), 22-27 September 2016, Wuhan, China</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within the framework of pQCD, we systematically study the $W^{\pm}/Z^0$ boson
production as a probe of cold nuclear matter effects and nuclear parton
distributions in p+Pb and Pb+Pb collisions at the LHC and future colliders. A
detailed analysis at partonic level is performed. Moreover, with a
semi-microscopic KP model of NPDFs, in which several nuclear effects (e.g.
Fermi motion and nuclear binding, the off-shell correction, the nuclear
coherent correction, and the nuclear meson correction) are included, we study
the vector boson rapidity distribution in p+Pb collisions at the LHC, and a
very good agreement with the latest data is found, including the $W$-boson
charge asymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02908</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02908</id><created>2016-12-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Rajendran</keyname><forenames>Karthikeyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kattis</keyname><forenames>Assimakis A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holiday</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondor</keyname><forenames>Risi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>Ioannis G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Data mining when each data point is a network</title><categories>cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1306.3524</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the problem of extending data mining approaches to cases in which
data points arise in the form of individual graphs. Being able to find the
intrinsic low-dimensionality in ensembles of graphs can be useful in a variety
of modeling contexts, especially when coarse-graining the detailed graph
information is of interest. One of the main challenges in mining graph data is
the definition of a suitable pairwise similarity metric in the space of graphs.
We explore two practical solutions to solving this problem: one based on
finding subgraph densities, and one using spectral information. The approach is
illustrated on three test data sets (ensembles of graphs); two of these are
obtained from standard graph generating algorithms, while the graphs in the
third example are sampled as dynamic snapshots from an evolving network
simulation. We further incorporate these approaches with equation free
techniques, demonstrating how such data mining approaches can enhance
scientific computation of network evolution dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02924</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02924</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Vergados</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames><affiliation>University of Ioannina, Ioannina, Greece</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ejiri</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>RCNP, Osaka University, Osaka, Japan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>&#x160;imkovic</keyname><forenames>F</forenames><affiliation>Laboratory of Theoretical Physics, JINR, Dubna, Moscow Russia</affiliation></author></authors><title>Neutrinoless double beta decay and neutrino mass</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Review Article 63 pages, 9 figures, 10 tables</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. E Vol. 25, 1630007 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218301316300071</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The observation of neutrinoless double beta decay will have important
consequences. First it will signal that lepton number is not conserved and the
neutrinos are Majorana particles. Second, it represents our best hope for
determining the absolute neutrino mass scale at the level of a few tens of meV.
To achieve the last goal, however, certain hurdles have to be overcome
involving particle, nuclear and experimental physics. Particle physics is
important since it provides the mechanisms for neutrinoless double beta decay.
In this review we emphasize the light neutrino mass mechanism. Nuclear physics
is important for extracting the useful information from the data. One must
accurately evaluate the relevant nuclear matrix elements, a formidable task. To
this end, we review the recently developed sophisticated nuclear structure
approaches, employing different methods and techniques of calculation. We also
examine the question of quenching of the axial vector coupling constant, which
may have important consequences on the size of the nuclear matrix elements.
From an experimental point of view it is challenging, since the life times are
extremely long and one has to fight against formidable backgrounds. One needs
large isotopically enriched sources and detectors with good energy resolution
and very low background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02959</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zalamea</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author></authors><title>Chasing Individuation: Mathematical Description of Physical Systems</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>Ph.D. Thesis, 350 pages, Universit\'e Paris Diderot (Paris 7) , 23
  Nov 2016</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  This work is a conceptual analysis of certain recent developments in the
mathematical foundations of Classical and Quantum Mechanics which have allowed
to formulate both theories in a common language. From the algebraic point of
view, the set of observables of a physical system, be it classical or quantum,
is described by a \emph{Jordan-Lie algebra}. From the geometric point of view,
the space of states of any system is described by a \emph{uniform Poisson space
with transition probability}. Both these structures are here perceived as
formal translations of \emph{the fundamental twofold role of properties in
Mechanics}: they are at the same time quantities and transformations. The
question becomes then to understand the precise articulation between these two
roles. The analysis will show that Quantum Mechanics can be thought as
distinguishing itself from Classical Mechanics by a compatibility condition
between properties-as-quantities and properties-as-transformations.
  Moreover, this dissertation shows the existence of a tension between a
certain &quot;abstract way&quot; of conceiving mathematical structures, used in the
practice of mathematical physics, and the necessary capacity to specify
particular states or observables. It then becomes important to understand how,
within the formalism, one can construct a \emph{labelling scheme}. The &quot;Chase
for Individuation&quot; is the analysis of different mathematical techniques which
attempt to overcome this tension. In particular, we discuss how group theory
furnishes a partial solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02973</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Buhot</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallais</keyname><forenames>Yann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cazayous</keyname><forenames>Maximilien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sacuto</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piekarz</keyname><forenames>Przemys&#x142;aw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lapertot</keyname><forenames>G&#xe9;rard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Dai</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe9;asson</keyname><forenames>Marie-Aude</forenames></author></authors><title>Raman Active High Energy Excitations in URu$_2$Si$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><doi>10.1016/j.physb.2016.10.034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have performed Raman scattering measurements on URu$_2$Si$_2$ single
crystals on a large energy range up to $\sim$ 1300 cm$^{-1}$ and in all the
Raman active symmetries as a function of temperature down to 15 K. A large
excitation, active only in the E$_{g}$ symmetry, is reported. It has been
assigned to a crystal electric field excitation on the Uranium site. We discuss
how this constrains the crystal electric field scheme of the Uranium ions.
Furthermore, three excitations in the A$_{1g}$ symmetry are observed. They have
been associated to double Raman phonon processes consistently with ab initio
calculations of the phonons dispersion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02976</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02976</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Stangl</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilhelm</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Remmerssen</keyname><forenames>Klaas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoeger</keyname><forenames>Sigurd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsang</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupton</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Mesoscopic Quantum Emitters from Deterministic Aggregates of Conjugated
  Polymers</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An appealing definition of the term &quot;molecule&quot; arises from consideration of
the nature of fluorescence, with discrete molecular entities emitting a stream
of single photons. We address the question of how large a molecular object may
become by growing deterministic aggregates from single conjugated polymer
chains. Even particles containing dozens of individual chains still behave as
single quantum emitters due to efficient excitation energy transfer, while the
brightness is raised due to the increased absorption cross-section of the
suprastructure. Excitation energy can delocalize between individual polymer
chromophores in these aggregates by both coherent and incoherent coupling,
which are differentiated by their distinct spectroscopic fingerprints. Coherent
coupling is identified by a ten-fold increase in excited-state lifetime and a
corresponding spectral red shift. Exciton quenching due to incoherent FRET
becomes more significant as aggregate size increases, resulting in
single-aggregate emission characterized by strong blinking. This mesoscale
approach allows us to identify intermolecular interactions which do not exist
in isolated chains and are inaccessible in bulk films where they are present
but masked by disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02977</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Gopal</keyname><forenames>Radha Krishna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambast</keyname><forenames>Deepak K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Sourabh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Jit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Bipul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Chiranjib</forenames></author></authors><title>Bulk Saturable absorption in Topological Insulator thin Films</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present nonlinear optical absorption properties of pulsed laser deposited
thin films of topological insulator (TI), Bi2Se3 on quartz substrate, using
open aperture Z - scan technique. The saturable intensity of as-deposited thin
films has been found remarkably improved by an order of magnitude compared to
the values reported earlier in the literature. Past results from the literature
are inconclusive in establishing whether the saturable absorption is coming
from surface states or the bulk. Specifically designed experiments with
magnetically doped TI samples allow us to attribute the saturable absorption
characteristic of TI to the bulk states. Detailed experimental procedures and
possible explanation of observed results have been discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02980</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Grussmayer</keyname><forenames>Kristin S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steiner</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupton</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herten</keyname><forenames>Dirk-Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsang</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Differentiation between shallow and deep charge trap states on single
  poly(3-hexylthiophene) chains through fluorescence photon statistics</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Blinking of the photoluminescence (PL) emitted from individual conjugated
polymer chains is one of the central observations made by single-molecule
spectroscopy (SMS). Important information, e.g., regarding excitation energy
transfer, can be extracted by evaluating dynamic quenching. However, the nature
of trap states, which are responsible for PL quenching, often remains obscured.
We present a detailed investigation of the photon statistics of single
poly(3-hexylthiophene) (P3HT) chains obtained by SMS. The photon statistics
provide a measure of the number and brightness of independently emitting areas
on a single chain. These observables can be followed during blinking. A
decrease in PL intensity is shown to be correlated with either (i) a decrease
in the average brightness of the emitting sites; or (ii) a decrease in the
number of emitting regions. We attribute these phenomena to the formation of
(i) shallow charge traps, which can weakly affect all emitting areas of a
single chain at once; and (ii) deep traps, which have a strong effect on small
regions within the single chains.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02992</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mendelev</keyname><forenames>M. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Underwood</keyname><forenames>T. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ackland</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of an Interatomic Potential for the Simulation of Defects,
  Plasticity and Phase Transformations in Titanium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 154102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4964654</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  New interatomic potentials describing defects, plasticity and high
temperature phase transitions for Ti are presented. Fitting the martensitic
hcp-bcc phase transformation temperature requires an efficient and accurate
method to determine it. We apply a molecular dynamics (MD) method based on
determination of the melting temperature of competing solid phases, and
Gibbs-Helmholtz integration, and a lattice-switch Monte Carlo method (LSMC):
these agree on the hcp-bcc transformation temperatures to within 2 K. We were
able to develop embedded atom potentials which give a good fit to either low or
high temperature data, but not both. The first developed potential (Ti1)
reproduces the hcp-bcc transformation and melting temperatures and is suitable
for the simulation of phase transitions and bcc Ti. Two other potentials (Ti2
and Ti3) correctly describe defect properties, and can be used to simulate
plasticity or radiation damage in hcp Ti. The fact that a single EAM potential
cannot describe both low and high temperature phases may be attributed to
neglect of electronic degrees of freedom, notably bcc has a much higher
electronic entropy. A temperature-dependent potential obtained from the
combination of potentials Ti1 and Ti2 may be used to simulate Ti properties at
any temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02993</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Pi</keyname><forenames>Qing-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Li-Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Xian-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Hong-Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xi-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dai-Mei</forenames></author></authors><title>Chromospheric activity on the late-type star V1355 Ori using Lijiang
  1.8-m and 2.4-m telescopes</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 page, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>RAA, 16, 153 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-4527/16/10/153</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We obtained new high-resolution spectra using the Lijiang 1.8-m and 2.4-m
telescopes to investigate the chromospheric activities of V1355 Ori as
indicated in the behaviors of Ca ii H&amp;K, Hdelta, Hgamma, Hbeta, Na i D1, D2,
Halpha and Ca ii infrared triplet (IRT) lines. The observed spectra show
obvious emissions above the continuum in Ca ii H&amp;K lines, absorptions in the
Hdelta, Hgamma, Hbeta and Na i D1, D2 lines, variable behavior (filled-in
absorption, partial emission with a core absorption component or emission above
the continuum) in the Halpha line, and weak self-reversal emissions in the
strong filled-in absorptions of the Ca ii IRT lines. We used a spectral
subtraction technique to analyze our data. The results show no excess emission
in the Hdelta and Hgamma lines, very weak excess emissions in the Na i D1, D2
lines, excess emission in the Hbeta line, clear excess emission in the Halpha
line, and excess emissions in the Ca ii IRT lines. The value of the ratio of
EW8542/EW8498 is in the range 0.9 to 1.7, which implies that chromospheric
activity might have been caused by plage events. The value of the ratio E
Halpha/E Hbeta is above 3, indicating that the Balmer lines would arise from
prominence-like material. We also found time variations in light curves
associated with equivalent widths of chromospheric activity lines in the Na i
D1, D2, Ca ii IRT and Halpha lines in particular. These phenomena can be
explained by plage events, which are consistent with the behavior of
chromospheric activity indicators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02994</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Leonard</keyname><forenames>Jean Leo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinsalu</keyname><forenames>Els</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patriarca</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Kiran</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborti</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author></authors><title>Patterns of Linguistic Diffusion in Space and Time: The Case of Mazatec</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 9 figures. A similar version was submitted to the
  Proceedings of Econophys-2015 to be published in &quot;Econophysics and
  Sociophysics: Recent Progress and Future Directions&quot; Editors: Abergel, F.,
  Aoyama, H., Chakrabarti, B.K., Chakraborti, A., Deo, N., Raina, D., Vodenska,
  I</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the framework of complexity theory, which provides a unified framework for
natural and social sciences, we study the complex and interesting problem of
the internal structure, similarities, and differences between the Mazatec
dialects, an endangered Otomanguean language spoken in south-east Mexico. The
analysis is based on some databases, which are used to compute linguistic
distances between the dialects. The results are interpreted in the light of
linguistics as well as statistical considerations and used to infer the history
of the development of the observed pattern of diversity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.02997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.02997</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Fl&#xf6;h</keyname><forenames>Kevin</forenames><affiliation>for the CMS Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Reconstruction and Selection of Single Top + Higgs to
  $\mathrm{b}\overline{\mathrm{b}}$ events at CMS in pp Collisions at
  $\sqrt{s}$ = 13 TeV</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>Proceeding Top 2016</comments><report-no>CMS CR-2016/406</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The associated production of a single top quark together with a Higgs boson
at the LHC can be used to lift the degeneracy regarding the sign of the top
quark Yukawa coupling. Therefore, t-channel and tW-channel production where the
Higgs boson is decaying into a $\mathrm{b}\overline{\mathrm{b}}$ pair is
inspected. Boosted decision trees are used to assign jets to the quarks in the
final state and classify the events. To maximize the separation between the
signal and the dominating $\mathrm{t}\overline{\mathrm{t}}$ background each
event is reconstructed under a signal and a $\mathrm{t}\overline{\mathrm{t}}$
hypothesis. The poster focuses on the event selection and the reconstruction of
events.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03001</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Wuersch</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>May</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiederer</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jester</keyname><forenames>S. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoeger</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lupton</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactions between pi-conjugated chromophores in a giant molecular
  spoked wheel</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the intriguing photophysics of a giant molecular spoked wheel of
pi-conjugated arylenealkynylene chromophores on the single-molecule level. This
&quot;molecular mesoscopic&quot; tructure, C1878H2682, shows fast switching between the
12 identical chromophores since the fluorescence is unpolarised but only one
chromophore emits at a time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03003</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Mitton</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Georges Lema\^itre: Life, Science and Legacy</title><categories>physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>Talk given on 11 November 2026 at the Ordinary Meeting of the Royal
  Astronomical Society</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper celebrates the remarkable life, science and legacy of Abb\'e
Georges Lema\^itre, the Belgian cleric and professor of physics; he was the
architect of the fireworks model for the origin of the universe. He died half a
century ago, three days after learning that Arno Penzias and Robert Wilson had
discovered the cosmic microwave background. Despite being gravely ill from
leukaemia, Lema\^itre lucidly praised this news, which confirmed the explosive
genesis of our universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03004</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Plechinger</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagler</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arora</keyname><forenames>Ashish</forenames></author><author><keyname>del &#xc1;guila</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s Granados</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ballottin</keyname><forenames>Mariana V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frank</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinleitner</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gmitra</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabian</keyname><forenames>Jaroslav</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christianen</keyname><forenames>Peter C. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bratschitsch</keyname><forenames>Rudolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korn</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author></authors><title>Excitonic valley effects in monolayer WS$_2$ under high magnetic fields</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b04171</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transition-metal dichalcogenides can be easily produced as atomically thin
sheets, exhibiting the possibility to optically polarize and read out the
valley pseudospin of extremely stable excitonic quasiparticles present in these
2D semiconductors. Here, we investigate a monolayer of tungsten disulphide in
high magnetic fields up to 30\,T via photoluminescence spectroscopy at low
temperatures. The valley degeneracy is lifted for all optical features,
particularly for excitons, singlet and triplet trions, for which we determine
the g factor separately. While the observation of a diamagnetic shift of the
exciton and trion resonances gives us insight into the real-space extension of
these quasiparticles, magnetic field induced valley polarization effects shed
light onto the exciton and trion dispersion relations in reciprocal space. The
field dependence of the trion valley polarizations is in line with the
predicted trion splitting into singlet and triplet configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03006</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03006</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Feierabend</keyname><forenames>Maja</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergh&#xe4;user</keyname><forenames>Gunnar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knorr</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malic</keyname><forenames>Ermin</forenames></author></authors><title>Out of the dark and into the light: towards dark-state based chemical
  sensors</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The rapidly increasing use of sensors throughout different research
disciplines and the demand for more efficient devices with less power
consumption depends critically on the emergence of new sensor materials and
novel sensor concepts. Atomically thin transition metal dichalcogenides have a
huge potential for sensor development within a wide range of applications.
Their optimal surface-to-volume ratio combined with strong light-matter
interaction results in a high sensitivity to changes in their surrounding.
Here, we present a novel, highly efficient sensing mechanism to detect
molecules based on dark excitons in these materials. We show that the presence
of molecules with a dipole moment transforms dark states into bright excitons
resulting in an additional pronounced peak in easy accessible optical spectra.
This effect exhibits a huge potential for sensor applications, since it offers
an unambiguous optical finger print for the detection of molecules - in
contrast to common sensing schemes relying on small peak shifts and intensity
changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03020</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03020</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Cecot</keyname><forenames>Monika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karwacki</keyname><forenames>Lukasz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skowronski</keyname><forenames>Witold</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanak</keyname><forenames>Jaroslaw</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wrona</keyname><forenames>Jerzy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zywczak</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Lide</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Dijken</keyname><forenames>Sebastiaan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnas</keyname><forenames>Jozef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stobiecki</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of intermixing at the Ta/CoFeB interface on spin Hall angle in
  Ta/CoFeB/MgO heterostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the spin Hall effect in perpendicularly magnetized
Ta/Co40Fe40B20/MgO trilayers with Ta underlayers thicker than the spin
diffusion length. The crystallographic structures of the Ta layer and Ta/CoFeB
interface are examined in detail using X-ray diffraction and transmission
electron microscopy. The thinnest Ta underlayer is amorphous, whereas for
thicker Ta layers a disoriented tetragonal beta-phase appears. Effective
spin-orbit torques are calculated based on harmonic Hall voltage measurements
performed in a temperature range between 15 and 300 K. To account for the
temperature dependence of damping-like and field-like torques, we extend the
spin diffusion model by including an additional contribution from the Ta/CoFeB
interface. Based on this approach, the temperature dependence of the spin Hall
angle in the Ta underlayer and at Ta/CoFeB interface are determined separately.
The results indicate an almost temperature-independent spin Hall angle of
theta_SH-N = -0.2 in Ta and a strongly temperature-dependent theta_SH-I for the
intermixed Ta/CoFeB interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03023</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03023</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Gusev</keyname><forenames>Yuri V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite temperature quantum field theory in the heat kernel method</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>20 pages</comments><msc-class>81T28, 82B30, 51P05, 58J40</msc-class><journal-ref>Russ. J. Math. Phys. 22 (1), 9-19 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1061920815010033</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The trace of the heat kernel in a (D+1)-dimensional Euclidean spacetime
(integer D &gt; 1) is used to derive the free energy in finite temperature field
theory. The spacetime presents a D-dimensional compact space (domain) with a
(D-1)-dimensional boundary, and a closed dimension, whose volume is
proportional the Planck's inverse temperature. The thermal sum appears due to
topology of the closed Euclidean time. The obtained free energy in (3+1) and
(2+1) dimensions contain two contributions defined by the volume of a domain
and by the volume of the domain's boundary. This functional is finite and valid
for arbitrary values of the Planck's inverse temperature. The absolute zero of
thermodynamic temperature is forbidden topologically, and no universal low
temperature asymptotics of the free energy can exist.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03041</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03041</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Akkoyun</keyname><forenames>Serkan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayram</keyname><forenames>Tuncay</forenames></author></authors><title>Surface energy coefficient determination in global mass formula from
  fission barrier energy</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 1 Table, 1 Figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Semi-empirical mass formula of the atomic nucleus describe binding energies
of the nuclei. In the simple form of this formula, there are five terms related
to the properties of the nuclear structure. The coefficients in each terms can
be determined by various approach such as fitting on experimental binding
energy values. In this study, the surface energy coefficient in the formula
which is a correction on total binding energy has been obtained by a method
that is not previously described in the literature. The experimental fission
barrier energies of nuclei have been used for this task. According to the
results, surface energy coefficient in one of the most conventional formula has
been improved by a factor 3.4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03046</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Bayin</keyname><forenames>Sel&#xe7;uk &#x15e;.</forenames></author></authors><title>Definition of the Riesz Derivative and its Application to Space
  Fractional Quantum Mechanics</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Mathematical Physics, v.57, 123501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4968819</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate and compare different representations of the Riesz derivative,
which plays an important role in anomalous diffusion and space fractional
quantum mechanics. In particular, we show that a certain representation of the
Riesz derivative that is generally given as also valid for order alpha equals
1, behaves no differently than the other definition given in terms of its
Fourier transform. In the light of this, we discuss the alpha goes to 1 limit
of the space fractional quantum mechanics and its consistency.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03056</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>C. -L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Walk in Periodic Potential on a Line and a Model of Interacting
  Opinions</title><categories>quant-ph physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1601.00570, arXiv:1307.3186</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two subjects are discussed in this work: localisation and recurrence in a
model of quantum walk in a periodic potential, and a model of opinion dynamics
with multiple choices of opinions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03060</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Guoren</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorelov</keyname><forenames>Evgeny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarvestani</keyname><forenames>Esmaeel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavarini</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author></authors><title>The Fermi surface of Sr2RuO4: spin-orbit and anisotropic Coulomb
  interaction effects</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 106402 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.106402</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The topology of the Fermi surface of Sr2RuO4 is well described by
local-density approximation calculations with spin-orbit interaction, but the
relative size of its different sheets is not. By accounting for many-body
effects via dynamical mean-field theory, we show that the standard isotropic
Coulomb interaction alone worsens or does not correct this discrepancy. In
order to reproduce experiments, it is essential to account for the Coulomb
anisotropy. The latter is small but has strong effects; it competes with the
Coulomb-enhanced spin-orbit coupling and the isotropic Coulomb term in
determining the Fermi surface shape. Its effects are likely sizable in other
correlated multi-orbital systems. In addition, we find that the low-energy
self-energy matrix -- responsible for the reshaping of the Fermi surface --
sizably differ from the static Hartree-Fock limit. Finally, we find a strong
spin-orbital {entanglement}; this supports the view that the conventional
description of Cooper pairs via factorized spin and orbital part might not
apply to Sr2RuO4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03085</id><created>2016-12-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Momeni</keyname><forenames>Naghmeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalorazi</keyname><forenames>Amir Tohidi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rabbat</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fotouhi</keyname><forenames>Babak</forenames></author></authors><title>An Epidemiological Mechanistic Model of Box Office Dynamics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we propose a mechanistic model that links micro social
interactions to macro observables in the case of diffusion of film-going
decisions. We devise a generalized epidemic model to capture the temporal
evolution of box office revenues. The model adds social influence and memory
effects to conventional epidemic models. Fitting the model to a temporal data
set containing domestic weekly revenue of the 5000 top US-grossing films of all
time, we find that a two-parameter model can capture a remarkable portion of
the observed variance in the data. Using the distribution of the estimated
parameters for different genres, we then present a predictive model which
provides reasonable a-priori estimates of future sale as a function of time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03111</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Cerrito</keyname><forenames>Lucio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Millar</keyname><forenames>Declan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Span&#xf2;</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Discriminating Z' signals in semileptonic top pair production at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure, 1 table. arXiv admin note: substantial text
  overlap with arXiv:1610.04074</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the sensitivity of top pair production to the properties of
different Beyond the Standard Model theories embedding a new neutral boson. We
include six-fermion decay, and account for the full tree-level Standard Model
ttbar interference, with all intermediate particles allowed off-shell. We focus
on those observables best suited to the lepton-plus-jets final state at the
LHC, and simulate the resulting experimental conditions, including kinematic
requirements and top quark pair reconstruction in the presence of missing
transverse energy and combinatorial ambiguity in quark-top assignment. In
particular, we demonstrate the use of asymmetry observables to probe the
coupling structure of a new neutral resonance, in addition to cases in which
these asymmetries may even form complementary discovery observables in
combination with the differential cross section.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03134</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03134</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Rochman</keyname><forenames>Nash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Sean X.</forenames></author></authors><title>&quot;Inchworm Filaments&quot;: Motility and Pattern Formation</title><categories>q-bio.SC cond-mat.soft physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>8 pages 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In a previous paper, we examined a class of possible conformations for
helically patterned filaments in contact with a bonding surface. In particular,
we investigated geometries where contact between the pattern and the surface
was improved through a periodic twisting and lifting of the filament. A
consequence of this lifting is that the total length of the filament projected
onto the surface decreases after bonding. When the bonding character of the
surface is actuated, this phenomenon can lead to both lifelike &quot;inchworm&quot;
behavior of the filaments and ensemble movement. We illustrate, through
simulation, how pattern formation may be achieved through this mechanism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03135</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Geier</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupfer</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heber</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemeth</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziegerer</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irrgang</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schindewolf</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>T. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xe4;nsicke</keyname><forenames>B. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barlow</keyname><forenames>B. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bloemen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Close binary progenitors and ejected companions of thermonuclear
  supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5 pages, to be published by Astronomical Society of the Pacific
  Conference Series in the proceedings of the 20th European Workshop on White
  Dwarfs. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with arXiv:1604.05469</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hot subdwarf stars (sdO/Bs) are evolved core helium-burning stars with very
thin hydrogen envelopes, which can be formed by common envelope ejection. Close
sdB binaries with massive white dwarf (WD) companions are potential progenitors
of thermonuclear supernovae type Ia (SN~Ia). We discovered such a progenitor
candidate as well as a candidate for a surviving companion star, which escapes
from the Galaxy. More candidates for both types of objects have been found by
crossmatching known sdB stars with proper motion and light curve catalogues. We
found 72 sdO/B candidates with high Galactic restframe velocities, 12 of them
might be unbound to our Galaxy. Furthermore, we discovered the second-most
compact sdB+WD binary known. However, due to the low mass of the WD companion,
it is unlikely to be a SN\,Ia progenitor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03137</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Boito</keyname><forenames>Diogo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golterman</keyname><forenames>Maarten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maltman</keyname><forenames>Kim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peris</keyname><forenames>Santiago</forenames></author></authors><title>The status of the strong coupling from tau decays in 2016</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex hep-lat</categories><comments>4 pages, contribution to the 14th International Workshop on Tau
  Lepton Physics, 19-23 September, 2016, IHEP,Beijing, China</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  While the idea of using the operator product expansion (OPE) to extract the
strong coupling from hadronic $\tau$ decay data is not new, there is an ongoing
controversy over how to include quark-hadron &quot;duality violations&quot; (i.e.,
resonance effects) which are not described by the OPE. One approach attempts to
suppress duality violations enough that they might become negligible, but pays
the price of an uncontrolled OPE truncation. We critically examine a recent
analysis using this approach and show that it fails to properly account for
non-perturbative effects, making the resulting determination of the strong
coupling unreliable. In a different approach duality violations are taken into
account with a model, avoiding the OPE truncation. This second approach
provides a self-consistent determination of the strong coupling from $\tau$
decays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03143</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Eznaveh</keyname><forenames>Zeinab Sanjabi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez-Galmiche</keyname><forenames>Gisela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Correa</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo Amezcua</forenames></author></authors><title>Increasing Modal Instabilities Threshold Through Bidirectional Pumping
  In High Power Fiber Amplifiers</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures, presented in Photonic West 2015 SPIE</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, the impact of pump configuration on the modal instabilities
(MI) threshold of high power fiber amplifiers is investigated. Using a time
dependent computer model based on the optical beam propagation method (BPM),
the effect of bidirectional pumping on the MI threshold of high power fiber
amplifiers is explored and compared to that of a co-pumped configuration.
Simulation results indicate that the bidirectional pumping increases the
instabilities threshold by a factor of 30% with respect to the co-pumped
scheme. We attribute this threshold enhancement to a weaker strength of the
temperature induced refractive index grating due to a more homogeneous pump
profile along the fiber length. This technique demonstrates that the
engineering pump scheme is a promising approach leading to an appreciable
threshold enhancement of fiber amplifiers designed for high power applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03145</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03145</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Duo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Di</forenames></author></authors><title>CH as a Molecular Gas Tracer and C-Shock Tracer Across a Molecular Cloud
  Boundary in Taurus</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1601.03165</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Published, volume 833, page 90, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/833/1/90</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present new observations of all three ground-state transitions of the
methylidyne (CH) radical and all four ground-state transitions of the hydroxyl
(OH) radical toward a sharp boundary region of the Taurus molecular cloud.
These data were analyzed in conjunction with existing CO and dust images. The
derived CH abundance is consistent with previous observations of translucent
clouds ($0.8\le A_{v} \le 2.1$ mag). The $X({\rm CH})$-factor is nearly a
constant at $(1.0\pm0.06)\times 10^{22}$ $\rm {cm^{-2}~K^{-1}~km^{-1}~s}$ in
this extinction range, with less dispersion than that of the more widely used
molecular tracers CO and OH. CH turns out be a better tracer of total column
density in such an intermediate extinction range than CO or OH. Compared with
previous observations, CH is overabundant below 1 mag extinction. Such an
overabundance of CH is consistent with the presence of a C-shock. CH has two
kinematic components, one of which shifts from 5.3 to 6 km s$^{-1}$, while the
other stays at 6.8 km s$^{-1}$ when moving from outside toward inside of the
cloud. These velocity behaviors exactly match with previous OH observation. The
shifting of the two kinematic components indicates colliding streams or gas
flow at the boundary region, which could be the cause of the C-shock.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03146</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03146</id><created>2016-12-07</created><authors><author><keyname>George</keyname><forenames>Jonathan K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haghshenas</keyname><forenames>Hamed</forenames></author><author><keyname>DHemecourt</keyname><forenames>Duncan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Lijie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorger</keyname><forenames>Volker J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering and Absorption Control in Biocompatible Fibers towards
  Equalized Photobiomodulation</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transparent tissue scaffolds enable illumination of growing tissue to
accelerate cell proliferation and improve other cell functions through
photobiomodulation. The biphasic dose response of cells exposed to
photobiomodulating light dictates that the illumination to be evenly
distributed across the scaffold such that the cells are neither under nor over
exposed to light. However, equalized illumination has not been sufficiently
addressed. Here we analyze and experimentally demonstrate spatially equalizing
illumination by three methods, namely, engineered surface scattering,
reflection by a gold mirror, and traveling-waves in a ring mesh. Our results
show that nearly equalized illumination is achievable by controlling the light
scattering-to-loss ratio. This demonstration opens opportunities for
dose-optimized photobiomodulation in tissue regeneration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.03158</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.03158</id><created>2016-12-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Michel</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on Rindler Quantization</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>9+5 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review the quantization of scalar and gauge fields using Rindler
coordinates with an emphasis on the physics of the Rindler horizon. In the
thermal state at the Unruh temperature, correlators match their Minkowski
vacuum values and the renormalized stress tensor vanishes, while at any other
temperature the renormalized stress-energy diverges on the horizon. After
giving a new derivation of some of these results using canonical quantization
in the thermofield double state, we comment on the relevance of fluxes and
boundary conditions at the horizon, which have arisen in calculations of
entanglement entropy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/0609088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/0609088</id><created>2006-09-11</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>The Why of the Applicability of Statistical Physics to Economics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-fin.ST</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the relationships between game theory and quantum mechanics and
the extensions to statistical physics and information theory. We use certain
quantization relationships to assign quantum states to the strategies of a
player. These quantum states are contained in a density operator which
describes the new quantum system. The system is also described through an
entropy over its states, its evolution equation which is the quantum replicator
dynamics and a criterion of equilibrium based on the Collective Welfare
Principle. We show how the density operator and entropy are the bonds between
game theories, quantum information theory and statistical physics. We propose
the results of the study of these relationships like a reason of the
applicability of physics in economics and the born of econophysics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:physics/0609245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>physics/0609245</id><created>2006-09-28</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Econophysics</title><categories>physics.soc-ph q-fin.GN</categories><comments>9 pages. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:physics/0609088, arXiv:quant-ph/0510238, arXiv:quant-ph/0606045</comments><journal-ref>AAAI PRESS Technical Report SS-07-08, 158-163 (2007)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The relationships between game theory and quantum mechanics let us propose
certain quantization relationships through which we could describe and
understand not only quantum but also classical, evolutionary and the biological
systems that were described before through the replicator dynamics. Quantum
mechanics could be used to explain more correctly biological and economical
processes and even it could encloses theories like games and evolutionary
dynamics. This could make quantum mechanics a more general theory that we had
thought. Although both systems analyzed are described through two apparently
different theories (quantum mechanics and game theory) it is shown that both
systems are analogous and thus exactly equivalents. So, we can take some
concepts and definitions from quantum mechanics and physics for the best
understanding of the behavior of economics and biology. Also, we could maybe
understand nature like a game in where its players compete for a common welfare
and the equilibrium of the system that they are members.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0510238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0510238</id><created>2005-10-31</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Replicator Dynamics</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 369/2, 393-407 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2006.02.017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose quantization relationships which would let us describe and
solution problems originated by conflicting or cooperative behaviors among the
members of a system from the point of view of quantum mechanical interactions.
The quantum analogue of the replicator dynamics is the equation of evolution of
mixed states from quantum statistical mechanics. A system and all its members
will cooperate and rearrange its states to improve their present condition.
They strive to reach the best possible state for each of them which is also the
best possible state for the whole system. This led us to propose a quantum
equilibrium in which a system is stable only if it maximizes the welfare of the
collective above the welfare of the individual. If it is maximized the welfare
of the individual above the welfare of the collective the system gets unstable
and eventually it collapses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0604170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0604170</id><created>2006-04-24</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Introduction to the study of entropy in Quantum Games</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The present work is an introductory study about entropy its properties and
its role in quantum information theory. In a next work, we will use these
results to the analysis of a quantum game described by a density operator and
with its entropy equal to von Neumann's.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:quant-ph/0606045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-12-12</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>quant-ph/0606045</id><created>2006-06-06</created><updated>2016-12-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>Esteban Guevara</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Games Entropy</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 383/2, 797-804 (2007)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2007.05.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose the study of quantum games from the point of view of quantum
information theory and statistical mechanics. Every game can be described by a
density operator, the von Neumann entropy and the quantum replicator dynamics.
There exists a strong relationship between game theories, information theories
and statistical physics. The density operator and entropy are the bonds between
these theories. The analysis we propose is based on the properties of entropy,
the amount of information that a player can obtain about his opponent and a
maximum or minimum entropy criterion. The natural trend of a physical system is
to its maximum entropy state. The minimum entropy state is a characteristic of
a manipulated system i.e. externally controlled or imposed. There exist tacit
rules inside a system that do not need to be specified or clarified and search
the system equilibrium under the collective welfare principle. The other rules
are imposed over the system when one or many of its members violate this
principle and maximize its individual welfare at the expense of the group.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
