<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:43:02Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-28" from="2016-07-28" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0806.0402</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0806.0402</id><created>2008-06-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Saurya</forenames><affiliation>Lethbridge U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shankaranarayanan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Portsmouth U., ICG</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sur</keyname><forenames>Sourav</forenames><affiliation>Lethbridge U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Black hole entropy from entanglement: A review</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>Invited Review. To appear in the edited book: Classical and Quantum
  Gravity Research Progress, Nova Publishers (2008).
  https://www.novapublishers.com/catalog/product_info.php?products_id=9063</comments><journal-ref>Horizons in World Physics, Volume 268 (2009) Editors: Michael
  Everett and Louis Pedroza</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review aspects of the thermodynamics of black holes and in particular take
into account the fact that the quantum entanglement between the degrees of
freedom of a scalar field, traced inside the event horizon, can be the origin
of black hole entropy. The main reason behind such a plausibility is that the
well-known Bekenstein-Hawking entropy-area proportionality -- the so-called
`area law' of black hole physics -- holds for entanglement entropy as well,
provided the scalar field is in its ground state, or in other minimum
uncertainty states, such as a generic coherent state or squeezed state.
However, when the field is either in an excited state or in a state which is a
superposition of ground and excited states, a power-law correction to the area
law is shown to exist. Such a correction term falls off with increasing area,
so that eventually the area law is recovered for large enough horizon area. On
ascertaining the location of the microscopic degrees of freedom that lead to
the entanglement entropy of black holes, it is found that although the degrees
of freedom close to the horizon contribute most to the total entropy, the
contributions from those that are far from the horizon are more significant for
excited/superposed states than for the ground state. Thus, the deviations from
the area law for excited/superposed states may, in a way, be attributed to the
far-away degrees of freedom. Finally, taking the scalar field (which is traced
over) to be massive, we explore the changes on the area law due to the mass.
Although most of our computations are done in flat space-time with a
hypothetical spherical region, considered to be the analogue of the horizon, we
show that our results hold as well in curved space-times representing static
asymptotically flat spherical black holes with single horizon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.7343</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.7343</id><created>2014-02-28</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Macedo</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ansorg</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author></authors><title>Axisymmetric fully spectral code for hyperbolic equations</title><categories>physics.comp-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>Match published version</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Computational Physics 276, 357-379 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2014.07.040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a fully pseudo-spectral scheme to solve axisymmetric hyperbolic
equations of second order. With the Chebyshev polynomials as basis functions,
the numerical grid is based on the Lobbato (for two spatial directions) and
Radau (for the time direction) collocation points. The method solves two issues
of previous algorithms which were restricted to one spatial dimension, namely,
(i) the inversion of a dense matrix and (ii) the acquisition of a sufficiently
good initial-guess for non-linear systems of equations. For the first issue, we
use the iterative bi-conjugate gradient stabilized method, which we equip with
a pre-conditioner based on a singly diagonally implicit Runge-Kutta (&quot;SDIRK&quot;-)
method. The SDIRK-method also supplies the code with a good initial-guess. The
numerical solutions are correct up to machine precision and we do not observe
any restriction concerning the time step in comparison with the spatial
resolution. As an application, we solve general-relativistic wave equations on
a black-hole space-time in so-called hyperboloidal slices and reproduce some
recent results available in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1260</id><created>2014-03-05</created><updated>2014-10-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leclercq</keyname><forenames>Florent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pisani</keyname><forenames>Alice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wandelt</keyname><forenames>Benjamin D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmology: from theory to data, from data to theory</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>49 pages, 22 figures. Lectures given at the International School of
  Physics Enrico Fermi &quot;New Horizons for Observational Cosmology&quot;, June 30-July
  6, 2013, Varenna, Italy and at the Paris Ecole Doctorale for Astronomy and
  Astrophysics. Proceedings of the Enrico Fermi School (eds A. Cooray, A.
  Melchiorri, E. Komatsu, Italian Physical Society). Updated figures and
  references wrt published version</comments><doi>10.3254/978-1-61499-476-3-189</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Cosmology has come a long way from being based on a small number of
observations to being a data-driven precision science. We discuss the questions
&quot;What is observable?&quot;, &quot;What in the Universe is knowable?&quot; and &quot;What are the
fundamental limits to cosmological knowledge?&quot;. We then describe the
methodology for investigation: theoretical hypotheses are used to model,
predict and anticipate results; data is used to infer theory. We illustrate
with concrete examples of principled analysis approaches from the study of
cosmic microwave background anisotropies and surveys of large-scale structure,
culminating in a summary of the highest precision probe to date of the physical
origin of cosmic structures: the Planck 2013 constraints on primordial
non-Gaussianity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.2468</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.2468</id><created>2014-10-09</created><updated>2016-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mouloudakis</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kominis</keyname><forenames>I. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Revealing the properties of the radical-pair magnetoreceptor using
  pulsed photo-excitation timed with pulsed rf</title><categories>physics.bio-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Biosystems 147, 35 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.biosystems.2016.07.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The radical-pair mechanism is understood to underlie the magnetic navigation
capability of birds and possibly other species. Experiments with birds have
provided indirect and in cases conflicting evidence on the actual existence of
this mechanism. We here propose a new experiment that can unambiguously
identify the presence of the radical-pair magnetoreceptor in birds and unravel
some of its basic properties. The proposed experiment is based on modulated
light excitation with a pulsed laser, combined with delayed radio-frequency
magnetic field pulses. We predict a resonance effect in the birds' magnetic
orientation versus the rf-pulse delay time. The resonance's position reflects
the singlet-triplet mixing time of the magnetoreceptor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1412.0485</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1412.0485</id><created>2014-12-01</created><updated>2015-03-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Pardeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Shubhrangshu</forenames></author></authors><title>Estimation of temporal separation of slow light pulses in atomic vapors
  by weak measurement</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review A 91, 043803 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.91.043803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show how two circular polarization components of a linearly polarized
pulse, propagating through a coherently driven dilute atomic vapor, can be well
resolved in time domain by weak measurement. Slower group velocity of one of
the components due to electromagnetically induced transparency leads to a
differential group delay between the two components. For low number density,
this delay may not be large enough to temporally resolve the two components. We
show how this can be enhanced in terms of mean time of arrival of the output
pulse through a post-selected polarizer. We demonstrate the idea with all the
analytical and numerical results, with a specific example of alkali atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04042</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04042</id><created>2015-04-15</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>Bhaskar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Britton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glover</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Natarajan</keyname><forenames>Priyamvada</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khochfar</keyname><forenames>Sadegh</forenames></author></authors><title>New constraints on direct collapse black hole formation in the early
  Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw929</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Direct collapse black holes (DCBH) have been proposed as a solution to the
challenge of assembling supermassive black holes by $z&gt;6$ to explain the bright
quasars observed at this epoch. The formation of a DCBH seed with $\rm
M_{BH}\sim10^{4-5}\ \rm M_{\odot}$ requires a pristine atomic-cooling halo to
be illuminated by an external radiation field that is sufficiently strong to
entirely suppress H$_{2}$ cooling in the halo. Many previous studies have
attempted to constrain the critical specific intensity that is likely required
to suppress H$_{2}$ cooling, denoted as $J_{\rm crit}$. However, these studies
have typically assumed that the incident external radiation field can be
modeled with a black-body spectrum. Under this assumption, it is possible to
derive a {unique} value for $J_{\rm crit}$ that depends only on the temperature
of the black-body. In this study we consider a more realistic spectral energy
distribution (SED) for the external source of radiation that depends entirely
on its star formation history and age. The rate of destruction of the species
responsible for suppressing molecular hydrogen cooling depends on the detailed
shape of the SED. Therefore the value of $J_{\rm crit}$ is tied to the shape of
the incident SED of the neighbouring galaxy. We fit a parametric form to the
rates of destruction of H$_2$ and H$^-$ that permit direct collapse. Owing to
this, we find that $J_{\rm crit}$ is not a fixed threshold but can lie anywhere
in the range $J_{\rm crit} \sim 0.5$--$10^{3}$, depending on the details of the
source stellar population.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01111</id><created>2015-06-02</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stoecklein</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Chueh-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Donghyuk</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Carlo</keyname><forenames>Dino</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ganapathysubramanian</keyname><forenames>Baskar</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimization of micropillar sequences for fluid flow sculpting</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inertial fluid flow deformation around pillars in a microchannel is a new
method for controlling fluid flow. Sequences of pillars have been shown to
produce a rich phase space with a wide variety of flow transformations.
Previous work has successfully demonstrated manual design of pillar sequences
to achieve desired transformations of the flow cross-section, with experimental
validation. However, such a method is not ideal for seeking out complex
sculpted shapes as the search space quickly becomes too large for efficient
manual discovery. We explore fast, automated optimization methods to solve this
problem. We formulate the inertial flow physics in microchannels with different
micropillar configurations as a set of state transition matrix operations.
These state transition matrices are constructed from experimentally validated
streamtraces. This facilitates modeling the effect of a sequence of
micropillars as nested matrix-matrix products, which have very efficient
numerical implementations. With this new forward model, arbitrary micropillar
sequences can be rapidly simulated with various inlet configurations, allowing
optimization routines quick access to a large search space. We integrate this
framework with the genetic algorithm and showcase its applicability by
designing micropillar sequences for various useful transformations. We
computationally discover micropillar sequences for complex transformations that
are substantially shorter than manually designed sequences. We also determine
sequences for novel transformations that were difficult to manually design.
Finally, we experimentally validate these computational designs by fabricating
devices and comparing predictions with the results from confocal microscopy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.07159</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.07159</id><created>2015-06-23</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alvarez-Quiceno</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabrera-Baez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avila</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dalpian</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osorio-Guill&#xe9;n</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergence of competing magnetic interactions induced by Ge doping in the
  semiconductor FeGa3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>See &quot;Note added to arXiv version&quot; in text</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014432 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014432</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  FeGa$_3$ is an unusual intermetallic semiconductor that presents intriguing
magnetic responses to the tuning of its electronic properties. When doped with
Ge, the system evolves from diamagnetic to paramagnetic to ferromagnetic ground
states that are not well understood. In this work, we have performed a joint
theoretical and experimental study of FeGa$_{3-x}$Ge$_x$ using Density
Functional Theory and magnetic susceptibility measurements. For low Ge
concentrations we observe the formation of localized moments on some Fe atoms
and, as the dopant concentration increases, a more delocalized magnetic
behavior emerges. The magnetic configuration strongly depends on the dopant
distribution, leading even to the appearance of antiferromagnetic interactions
in certain configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04356</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04356</id><created>2015-07-15</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Favole</keyname><forenames>Ginevra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Comparat</keyname><forenames>Johan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prada</keyname><forenames>Francisco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yepes</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jullo</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niemiec</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kneib</keyname><forenames>Jean-Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodr&#xed;guez-Torres</keyname><forenames>Sergio A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klypin</keyname><forenames>Anatoly</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skibba</keyname><forenames>Ramin A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McBride</keyname><forenames>Cameron K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eisenstein</keyname><forenames>Daniel J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schlegel</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nuza</keyname><forenames>Sebasti&#xe1;n E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chuang</keyname><forenames>Chia-Hsun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delubac</keyname><forenames>Timoth&#xe9;e</forenames></author><author><keyname>Y&#xe8;che</keyname><forenames>Christophe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Donald P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Clustering properties of $g$-selected galaxies at $z\sim0.8$</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures, 2 tables</comments><msc-class>85A05, 85A40</msc-class><journal-ref>MNRAS (2016), 461, 3421</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1483</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Current and future large redshift surveys, as the Sloan Digital Sky Survey IV
extended Baryon Oscillation Spectroscopic Survey (SDSS-IV/eBOSS) or the Dark
Energy Spectroscopic Instrument (DESI), will use emission-line galaxies (ELG)
to probe cosmological models by mapping the large-scale structure of the
Universe in the redshift range $0.6 &lt; z &lt; 1.7$. With current data, we explore
the halo-galaxy connection by measuring three clustering properties of
$g$-selected ELGs as matter tracers in the redshift range $0.6 &lt; z &lt; 1$: (i)
the redshift-space two-point correlation function using spectroscopic redshifts
from the BOSS ELG sample and VIPERS; (ii) the angular two-point correlation
function on the footprint of the CFHT-LS; (iii) the galaxy-galaxy lensing
signal around the ELGs using the CFHTLenS. We interpret these observations by
mapping them onto the latest high-resolution MultiDark Planck N-body
simulation, using a novel (Sub)Halo-Abundance Matching technique that accounts
for the ELG incompleteness. ELGs at $z\sim0.8$ live in halos of $(1\pm
0.5)\times10^{12}\,h^{-1}$M$_{\odot}$ and 22.5$\pm2.5$% of them are satellites
belonging to a larger halo. The halo occupation distribution of ELGs indicates
that we are sampling the galaxies in which stars form in the most efficient
way, according to their stellar-to-halo mass ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05588</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05588</id><created>2015-07-20</created><updated>2016-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vromans</keyname><forenames>Arthur J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giomi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>Orientational properties of nematic disclinations</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures, supplementary movies at
  http://wwwhome.lorentz.leidenuniv.nl/~giomi/sup_mat/20150720/</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 6490 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01146B</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Topological defects play a pivotal role in the physics of liquid crystals and
represent one of the most prominent and well studied aspects of mesophases.
While in two-dimensional nematics, disclinations are traditionally treated as
point-like objects, recent experimental studies on active nematics have
suggested that half-strength disclinations might in fact possess a polar
structure. In this article, we provide a precise definition of polarity for
half-strength nematic disclinations, we introduce a simple and robust method to
calculate this quantity from experimental and numerical data and we investigate
how the orientational properties of half-strength disclinations affect their
relaxational dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.05598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.05598</id><created>2015-07-20</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Troxel</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>MacCrann</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krause</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eifler</keyname><forenames>T. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friedrich</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicola</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Refregier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amara</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bacon</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernstein</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonnett</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bridle</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Busha</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dodelson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erickson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evrard</keyname><forenames>A. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frieman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaztanaga</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartley</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jain</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarvis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kacprzak</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirk</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kravtsov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leistedt</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rykoff</keyname><forenames>E. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sabiu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seo</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheldon</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wechsler</keyname><forenames>R. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zuntz</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abbott</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdalla</keyname><forenames>F. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allam</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armstrong</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerji</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bauer</keyname><forenames>A. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benoit-Levy</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brooks</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buckley-Geer</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burke</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Capozzi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosell</keyname><forenames>A. Carnero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kind</keyname><forenames>M. Carrasco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carretero</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castander</keyname><forenames>F. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crocce</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cunha</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Andrea</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Costa</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DePoy</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Desai</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>H. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dietrich</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Doel</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neto</keyname><forenames>A. Fausti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fernandez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finley</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flaugher</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fosalba</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerdes</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gruendl</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gutierrez</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Honscheid</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>James</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuehn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuropatkin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahav</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maia</keyname><forenames>M. A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>March</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melchior</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miller</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miquel</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohr</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nichol</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nord</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogando</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plazas</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reil</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Romer</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roodman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sako</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scarpine</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schubnell</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sevilla-Noarbe</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>R. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soares-Santos</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobreira</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suchyta</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swanson</keyname><forenames>M. E. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarle</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thaler</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vikram</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collaboration</keyname><forenames>The DES</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmic Shear Measurements with DES Science Verification Data</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>measurements and covariance matrices in machine readable format are
  available as ancillary data on the arXiv; high-resolution versions of figures
  can be downloaded from http://deswl.github.io</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 022002 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.022002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present measurements of weak gravitational lensing cosmic shear two-point
statistics using Dark Energy Survey Science Verification data. We demonstrate
that our results are robust to the choice of shear measurement pipeline, either
ngmix or im3shape, and robust to the choice of two-point statistic, including
both real and Fourier-space statistics. Our results pass a suite of null tests
including tests for B-mode contamination and direct tests for any dependence of
the two-point functions on a set of 16 observing conditions and galaxy
properties, such as seeing, airmass, galaxy color, galaxy magnitude, etc. We
furthermore use a large suite of simulations to compute the covariance matrix
of the cosmic shear measurements and assign statistical significance to our
null tests. We find that our covariance matrix is consistent with the halo
model prediction, indicating that it has the appropriate level of halo sample
variance. We compare the same jackknife procedure applied to the data and the
simulations in order to search for additional sources of noise not captured by
the simulations. We find no statistically significant extra sources of noise in
the data. The overall detection significance with tomography for our highest
source density catalog is 9.7sigma. Cosmological constraints from the
measurements in this work are presented in a companion paper (DES et al. 2015).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.09295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.09295</id><created>2015-09-30</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chanda</keyname><forenames>Titas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Tamoghna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sadhukhan</keyname><forenames>Debasis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Amit Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Aditi Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Ujjwal</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistics of leading digits leads to unification of quantum
  correlations</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>v1: 11 pages, 5 figures, 2 tables; v2: 11 pages, 6 figures, 2 tables,
  new results added, extended version of the published paper</comments><journal-ref>Europhys. Lett. 114, 30004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/30004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the frequency distribution of the first significant digits of
the numbers in the data sets generated from a large class of measures of
quantum correlations, which are either entanglement measures, or belong to the
information-theoretic paradigm, exhibit a universal behaviour. In particular,
for Haar uniformly simulated arbitrary two-qubit states, we find that the
first-digit distribution corresponding to a collection of chosen computable
quantum correlation quantifiers tend to follow the first-digit law, known as
the Benford's law, when the rank of the states increases. Considering a
two-qubit state which is obtained from a system governed by paradigmatic spin
Hamiltonians, namely, the XY model in a transverse field, and the XXZ model, we
show that entanglement as well as information theoretic measures violate the
Benford's law. We quantitatively discuss the violation of the Benford's law by
using a violation parameter, and demonstrate that the violation parameter can
signal quantum phase transitions occurring in these models. We also comment on
the universality of the statistics of first significant digits corresponding to
appropriate measures of quantum correlations in the case of multipartite
systems as well as systems in higher dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.00679</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.00679</id><created>2015-10-02</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halavanau</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piot</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of a cascaded longitudinal space charge amplifier for
  broadband radiation production using a superconducting linac</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-15-426-APC</report-no><journal-ref>NIM A 2016 819 144-153</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.03.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Longitudinal space charge (LSC) effects are generally considered harmful in
free-electron lasers as they can seed unfavorable energy modulations that can
result in density modulations with associated emittance dilution. It was
pointed out, however, that such &quot;micro-bunching instabilities&quot; could be
potentially useful to support the generation of broadband coherent radiation.
Therefore there has been an increasing interest in devising accelerator beam
lines capable of controlling LSC induced density modulations. In the present
paper we augment these previous investigations by combining a grid-less space
charge algorithm with the popular particle-tracking program Elegant. This
high-fidelity model of the space charge is used to benchmark conventional LSC
models. We finally employ the developed model to optimize the performance of a
cascaded longitudinal space charge amplifier using beam parameters comparable
to the ones achievable at Fermilab Accelerator Science &amp; Technology (FAST)
facility currently under commissioning at Fermilab.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01637</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01637</id><created>2015-10-06</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maurer</keyname><forenames>L. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mei</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knezevic</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Rayleigh waves, surface disorder, and phonon localization in
  nanostructures</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.other</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 94, 045312 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045312</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a technique to calculate thermal conductivity in disordered
nanostructures: a finite-difference time-domain (FDTD) solution of the elastic
wave equation combined with the Green-Kubo formula. The technique captures
phonon wave behavior and scales well to nanostructures that are too large or
too surface disordered to simulate with many other techniques. We investigate
the role of Rayleigh waves and surface disorder on thermal transport by
studying graphenelike nanoribbons with free edges (allowing Rayleigh waves) and
fixed edges (prohibiting Rayleigh waves). We find that free edges result in a
significantly lower thermal conductivity than fixed ones. Free edges both
introduce Rayleigh waves and cause all low-frequency modes (bulk and surface)
to become more localized. Increasing surface disorder on free edges draws
energy away from the center of the ribbon and toward the disordered edges,
where it gets trapped in localized surface modes. These effects are not seen in
ribbons with fixed boundary conditions and illustrate the importance of phonon
surface modes in nanostructures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06409</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06409</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Corbin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boylan-Kolchin</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torrey</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogelsberger</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernquist</keyname><forenames>Lars</forenames></author></authors><title>The Mass Profile of the Milky Way to the Virial Radius from the
  Illustris Simulation</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures; matches version published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>Mon.Not.Roy.Astron.Soc. 461: 3483-3493, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1522</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use particle data from the Illustris simulation, combined with individual
kinematic constraints on the mass of the Milky Way (MW) at specific distances
from the Galactic center, to infer the radial distribution of the MW's dark
matter halo mass. Our method allows us to convert any constraint on the mass of
the MW within a fixed distance to a full circular velocity profile to the MW's
virial radius. As primary examples, we take two recent (and discrepant)
measurements of the total mass within 50 kpc of the Galaxy and find they imply
very different mass profiles and stellar masses for the Galaxy. The
dark-matter-only version of the Illustris simulation enables us to compute the
effects of galaxy formation on such constraints on a halo-by-halo basis; on
small scales, galaxy formation enhances the density relative to
dark-matter-only runs, while the total mass density is approximately 20% lower
at large Galactocentric distances. We are also able to quantify how current and
future constraints on the mass of the MW within specific radii will be
reflected in uncertainties on its virial mass: even a measurement of M(&lt;50 kpc)
with essentially perfect precision still results in a 20% uncertainty on the
virial mass of the Galaxy, while a future measurement of M(&lt;100 kpc) with 10%
errors would result in the same level of uncertainty. We expect that our
technique will become even more useful as (1) better kinematic constraints
become available at larger distances and (2) cosmological simulations provide
even more faithful representations of the observable Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06473</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06473</id><created>2015-10-21</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xi</keyname><forenames>Zhengjun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Mingliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yongming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>Heng</forenames></author></authors><title>Entropic characterization of coherence in quantum evolutions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, new title, new section and references added, updated version
  minor typos corrected. Comments are welcome!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By using relative entropy of coherence, we characterize the coherence gain
induced by some quantum evolutions, including the cohering power of unitary
operations and the decohering power of quantum operations. We find that the
cohering power of the controlled unitary operation can be reduced to the
cohering power of the corresponding unitary operation. We observe that the
global coherence generated via incoherent operation applied to the system and
an incoherent ancilla do not exceed the amount of coherence contained in the
initial system. Our result provides a much tighter lower bound of coherence for
the initial quantum state, and give an interesting chain of inequalities for
coherence, quantum correlation and entanglement. We also strengthen the
relations between quantum correlations and coherence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01051</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01051</id><created>2015-11-03</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Miravet</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Proetto</keyname><forenames>C. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolcatto</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Coulomb and tunneling coupled trilayer systems at zero magnetic field</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 085305 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.085305</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The ground-state electronic configuration of three coupled bidimensional
electron gases has been determined using a variational Hartree-Fock approach,
at zero magnetic field. The layers are Coulomb coupled, and tunneling is
present between neighboring layers. In the limit of small separation between
layers, the tunneling becomes the dominant energy contribution, while for large
distance between layers the physics is driven by the Hartree electrostatic
energy. Transition from tunneling to hartree dominated physics is shifted
towards larger layer separation values as the total bidimensional density of
the trilayers decreases. The inter-layer exchange helps in stabilize a
&quot;balanced&quot; configuration, where the three layers are approximately equally
occupied; most of the experiments are performed in the vicinity of this
balanced configuration. Several ground-state configurations are consequence of
a delicate interplay between tunneling and inter-subband exchange.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02739</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02739</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-02-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Pardeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deb</keyname><forenames>Bimalendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dasgupta</keyname><forenames>Shubhrangshu</forenames></author></authors><title>Probing vacuum-induced coherence via magneto-optical rotation in
  molecular systems</title><categories>quant-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review A 93, 063826 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.063826</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate theoretically the effects of vacuum-induced coherence (VIC) on
magneto-optical rotation (MOR). We carry out a model study to show that VIC in
the presence of a control laser and a magnetic field can lead to large
enhancement in the rotation of the plane of polarization of a linearly
polarized weak laser with vanishing circular dichroism. This effect can be
realized in cold molecular gases and may be used as a sensitive probe for VIC.
Such a large MOR angle can also be used to detect weak magnetic field with
large measurement sensitivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02892</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02892</id><created>2015-11-09</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alexandrov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pioline</keyname><forenames>Boris</forenames></author></authors><title>Theta series, wall-crossing and quantum dilogarithm identities</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP math.QA</categories><comments>26 pages; v2: added discussion on relation to complex Chern-Simons,
  misprints corrected</comments><report-no>L2C:15-197, CERN-PH-TH-2015-262</report-no><journal-ref>Lett.Math.Phys. 106 (2016) no.8, 1037-1066</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11005-016-0857-3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by mathematical structures which arise in string vacua and gauge
theories with N=2 supersymmetry, we study the properties of certain generalized
theta series which appear as Fourier coefficients of functions on a twisted
torus. In Calabi-Yau string vacua, such theta series encode instanton
corrections from $k$ Neveu-Schwarz five-branes. The theta series are determined
by vector-valued wave-functions, and in this work we obtain the transformation
of these wave-functions induced by Kontsevich-Soibelman symplectomorphisms.
This effectively provides a quantum version of these transformations, where the
quantization parameter is inversely proportional to the five-brane charge $k$.
Consistency with wall-crossing implies a new five-term relation for Faddeev's
quantum dilogarithm $\Phi_b$ at $b=1$, which we prove. By allowing the torus to
be non-commutative, we obtain a more general five-term relation valid for
arbitrary $b$ and $k$, which may be relevant for the physics of five-branes at
finite chemical potential for angular momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04028</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04028</id><created>2015-11-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lavery</keyname><forenames>Domanic</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ives</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liga</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvarado</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savory</keyname><forenames>Seb J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bayvel</keyname><forenames>Polina</forenames></author></authors><title>The Benefit of Split Nonlinearity Compensation for Optical Fiber
  Communications</title><categories>physics.optics cs.IT math.IT</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, 1 tables, Letter</comments><doi>10.1109/LPT.2016.2572359</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this Letter we analyze the benefit of digital compensation of fiber
nonlinearity, where the digital signal processing is divided between the
transmitter and receiver. The application of the Gaussian noise model indicates
that, where there are two or more spans, it is always beneficial to split the
nonlinearity compensation. The theory is verified via numerical simulations,
investigating transmission of single channel 50 GBd polarization division
multiplexed 256-ary quadrature amplitude modulation over 100 km standard single
mode fiber spans, using lumped amplification. For this case, the additional
increase in mutual information achieved over transmitter- or receiver-side
nonlinearity compensation is approximately 1 bit for distances greater than
2000 km. Further, it is shown, theoretically, that the SNR gain for long
distances and high bandwidth transmission is 1.5 dB versus transmitter- or
receiver-based nonlinearity compensation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04946</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-04-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Doslu</keyname><forenames>Metin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bingol</keyname><forenames>Haluk O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Context Sensitive Article Ranking with Citation Context Analysis</title><categories>cs.DL cs.IR cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><acm-class>H.3.3; H.3.1</acm-class><journal-ref>Scientometrics (2016) 108:653-671</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s11192-016-1982-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is hard to detect important articles in a specific context. Information
retrieval techniques based on full text search can be inaccurate to identify
main topics and they are not able to provide an indication about the importance
of the article. Generating a citation network is a good way to find most
popular articles but this approach is not context aware.
  The text around a citation mark is generally a good summary of the referred
article. So citation context analysis presents an opportunity to use the wisdom
of crowd for detecting important articles in a context sensitive way. In this
work, we analyze citation contexts to rank articles properly for a given topic.
The model proposed uses citation contexts in order to create a directed and
weighted citation network based on the target topic. We create a directed and
weighted edge between two articles if citation context contains terms related
with the target topic. Then we apply common ranking algorithms in order to find
important articles in this newly created network. We showed that this method
successfully detects a good subset of most prominent articles in a given topic.
The biggest contribution of this approach is that we are able to identify
important articles for a given search term even though these articles do not
contain this search term. This technique can be used in other linked documents
including web pages, legal documents, and patents.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05170</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Englert</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kogler</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schulz</keyname><forenames>Holger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spannowsky</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>Higgs coupling measurements at the LHC</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Matches published version; extended discussion on Run 1 constraints,
  added tables with Higgs coupling measurements, results unchanged. 24 pages,
  11 figures</comments><report-no>IPPP/15/66, DCPT/15/132</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C76, 393 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4227-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to the absence of tantalising hints for new physics during the LHC's run
1, the extension of the Higgs sector by dimension six operators will provide
the new phenomenological standard for searches of non-resonant extensions of
the Standard Model. Using all dominant and subdominant Higgs production
mechanisms at the LHC, we compute the constraints on Higgs physics-relevant
dimension six operators in a global and correlated fit. We show in how far
these constraints can be improved by new Higgs channels becoming accessible at
higher energy and luminosity, both through inclusive cross sections as well as
through highly sensitive differential distributions. This allows us to discuss
the sensitivity to new effects in the Higgs sector that can be reached at the
LHC if direct hints for physics beyond the SM remain elusive and the impact of
these constraints on well-motivated BSM scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03100</id><created>2015-12-07</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Haro</keyname><forenames>Jaume</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Supriya</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitationally induced adiabatic particle production: From Big Bang to
  de Sitter</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures, Published version in Classical and Quantum
  Gravity</comments><journal-ref>Classical and Quantum Gravity 33 (2016) 165007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/16/165007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the background of a flat homogeneous and isotropic space-time, we consider
a scenario of the universe driven by the gravitationally induced `adiabatic'
particle production with constant creation rate. We have shown that this
universe attains a big bang singularity in the past and at late-time it
asymptotically becomes de Sitter. To clarify this model universe, we perform a
dynamical analysis and found that the universe attains a thermodynamic
equilibrium in this late de Sitter phase. Finally, for the first time, we have
discussed the possible effects of `adiabatic' particle creations in the context
of Loop Quantum Cosmology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04665</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04665</id><created>2015-12-15</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mahapatro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lahiri</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Bharat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mishra</keyname><forenames>R. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>S. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nuclear structure and decay properties of even-even nuclei in $Z=70-80$
  drip-line region</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>10 figures, 6 tables</comments><journal-ref>IJMPE Vol.25 (2016) 1650062</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218301316500622</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study nuclear structure properties for various isotopes of Ytterbium (Yb),
Hafnium(Hf), Tungsten(W), Osmium(Os), Platinum(Pt) and Mercury(Hg) in $Z = 70 -
80$ drip-line region starting from $N =80$ to $N=170$ within the formalism of
relativistic mean field (RMF) theory. The pairing correlation is taken care by
using BCS approach. We compared our results with Finite Range Droplet
Model(FRDM) and experimental data and found that the calculated results are in
good agreement. Neutron shell closure are obtained at $N=82$ and $126$ in this
region. We have also studied probable decay mechanisms of these elements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07190</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07190</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zechlin</keyname><forenames>Hannes-S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cuoco</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donato</keyname><forenames>Fiorenza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fornengo</keyname><forenames>Nicolao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vittino</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Unveiling the Gamma-ray Source Count Distribution Below the Fermi
  Detection Limit with Photon Statistics</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>28 pages, 20 figures, 6 tables; v2: minor changes and additions,
  accepted for publication in ApJS</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP 1034/15</report-no><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, Volume 225, Number 2,
  18 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/225/2/18</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The source-count distribution as a function of their flux, dN/dS, is one of
the main quantities characterizing gamma-ray source populations. We employ
statistical properties of the Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT) photon counts
map to measure the composition of the extragalactic gamma-ray sky at high
latitudes (|b|&gt;30 deg) between 1 GeV and 10 GeV. We present a new method,
generalizing the use of standard pixel-count statistics, to decompose the total
observed gamma-ray emission into (a) point-source contributions, (b) the
Galactic foreground contribution, and (c) a truly diffuse isotropic background
contribution. Using the 6-year Fermi-LAT data set (P7REP), we show that the
dN/dS distribution in the regime of so far undetected point sources can be
consistently described with a power law of index between 1.9 and 2.0. We
measure dN/dS down to an integral flux of ~2x10^{-11} cm^{-2}s^{-1}, improving
beyond the 3FGL catalog detection limit by about one order of magnitude. The
overall dN/dS distribution is consistent with a broken power law, with a break
at 2.1^{+1.0}_{-1.3}x10^{-8} cm^{-2}s^{-1}. The power-law index
n_1=3.1^{+0.7}_{-0.5} for bright sources above the break hardens to
n_2=1.97+-0.03 for fainter sources below the break. A possible second break of
the dN/dS distribution is constrained to be at fluxes below 6.4x10^{-11}
cm^{-2}s^{-1} at 95% confidence level. The high-latitude gamma-ray sky between
1 GeV and 10 GeV is shown to be composed of ~25% point sources, ~69.3% diffuse
Galactic foreground emission, and ~6% isotropic diffuse background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07870</id><created>2015-12-24</created><updated>2016-06-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tuz</keyname><forenames>Vladimir R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Polaritons dispersion in a composite ferrite-semiconductor structure
  near gyrotropic-nihility state</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>21 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Magnetism and Magnetic Materials 419 (2016) 559-565</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jmmm.2016.06.070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of polaritons in a ferrite-semiconductor structure which is
influenced by an external static magnetic field, the gyrotropic-nihility can be
identified from the dispersion equation related to bulk polaritons as a
particular extreme state, at which the longitudinal component of the
corresponding constitutive tensor and bulk constant simultaneously acquire
zero. Near the frequency of the gyrotropic-nihility state, the conditions of
branches merging of bulk polaritons, as well as an anomalous dispersion of bulk
and surface polaritons are found and discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08225</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08225</id><created>2015-12-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Jabbour</keyname><forenames>Michael G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garc&#xed;a-Patr&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Ra&#xfa;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cerf</keyname><forenames>Nicolas J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Majorization preservation of Gaussian bosonic channels</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>New Journal of Physics, Vol. 18, 073047, July 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073047</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that phase-insensitive Gaussian bosonic channels are
majorization-preserving over the set of passive states of the harmonic
oscillator. This means that comparable passive states under majorization are
transformed into equally comparable passive states. The proof relies on a new
preorder relation called Fock-majorization, which coincides with regular
majorization for passive states but also induces a mean photon number order,
thereby connecting the concepts of energy and disorder of a quantum state. As
an application, the consequences of majorization preservation are investigated
in the context of the broadcast communication capacity of bosonic Gaussian
channels. Most of our results being independent of the bosonic nature of the
system under investigation, they could be generalized to other quantum systems
and Hamiltonians, providing a general tool that could prove useful in quantum
information theory and quantum thermodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00045</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00045</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2016-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lao</keyname><forenames>Hai-Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>Hua-Rong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fu-Hu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lacey</keyname><forenames>Roy A.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Evidence of Mass Dependent Differential Kinetic Freeze-out Scenario
  Observed in Pb-Pb Collisions at 2.76 TeV</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ex hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures. The European Physical Journal A, accepted</comments><journal-ref>The European Physical Journal A 52, 203 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16203-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transverse momentum spectra of different particles produced in mid-rapidity
interval in lead-lead (Pb-Pb) collisions with different centrality intervals,
measured by the ALICE Collaboration at center-of-mass energy per nucleon pair
$\sqrt{s_{NN}}=2.76$ TeV, are conformably and approximately described by the
Tsallis distribution. The dependences of parameters (effective temperature,
entropy index, and normalization factor) on event centrality and particle rest
mass are obtained. The source temperature at the kinetic freeze-out is obtained
to be the intercept in the linear relation between effective temperature and
particle rest mass, while the particle transverse flow velocity is
approximately extracted to be the slope in the linear relation between mean
transverse momentum and particle rest mass. It is shown that the source
temperature increases with increase of particle rest mass, which exhibits an
evidence of mass dependent differential kinetic freeze-out scenario or multiple
kinetic freeze-out scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.02125</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.02125</id><created>2016-01-09</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ammon</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leiber</keyname><forenames>Julian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macedo</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase diagram of 4D field theories with chiral anomaly from holography</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>42 pages, 16 figures. Match published version</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 1603 (2016) 164</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP03(2016)164</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Within gauge/gravity duality, we study the class of four dimensional CFTs
with chiral anomaly described by Einstein-Maxwell-Chern-Simons theory in five
dimensions. In particular we determine the phase diagram at finite temperature,
chemical potential and magnetic field. At high temperatures the solution is
given by an electrically and magnetically charged AdS Reissner-Nordstroem black
brane. For sufficiently large Chern-Simons coupling and at sufficiently low
temperatures and small magnetic fields, we find a new phase with helical order,
breaking translational invariance spontaneously. For the Chern-Simons couplings
studied, the phase transition is second order with mean field exponents. Since
the entropy density vanishes in the limit of zero temperature we are confident
that this is the true ground state which is the holographic version of a chiral
magnetic spiral.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06592</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06592</id><created>2016-01-25</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cris&#xf3;stomo</keyname><forenames>Juan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gomez</keyname><forenames>Fernando</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mella</keyname><forenames>Patricio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quinzacara</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salgado</keyname><forenames>Patricio</forenames></author></authors><title>Static solutions in Einstein-Chern-Simons gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>23 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 06(2016) 049</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/06/049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study static solutions with more general symmetries than the
spherical symmetry of the five-dimensional Einstein-Chern-Simons gravity. In
this context, we study the coupling of the extra bosonic field $% h^{a}$ with
ordinary matter which is quantified by the introduction of an energy-momentum
tensor field associated with $h^{a}$. It is found that exist (i) a negative
tangential pressure zone around low-mass distributions ($\mu &lt;\mu_{1}$) when
the coupling constant $\alpha $ is greater than zero; (ii) a maximum in the
tangential pressure, which can be observed in the outer region of a field
distribution that satisfies $\mu &lt;\mu_{2}$; (iii) solutions that behave like
those obtained from models with negative cosmological constant. In such a
situation, the field $h^{a}$ plays the role of a cosmological constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07236</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07236</id><created>2016-01-26</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cassatella-Contra</keyname><forenames>Giovanni A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Manuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Matrix biorthogonal polynomials in the unit circle: Riemann-Hilbert
  problem and matrix discrete Painleve II system</title><categories>math.CA math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><msc-class>14J70, 15A23, 33C45, 37K10, 37L60, 42C05, 46L55</msc-class><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  Matrix Szego biorthogonal polynomials for quasi-definite matrices of measures
are studied. For matrices of Holder weights a Riemann-Hilbert problem is
uniquely solved in terms of the matrix Szego polynomials and its Cauchy
transforms. The Riemann-Hilbert problem is given as an appropriate framework
for the discussion of the Szego matrix and the associated Szego recursion
relations for the matrix orthogonal polynomials and its Cauchy transforms.
Pearson type differential systems characterizing the matrix of weights are
studied. These are linear systems of ordinary differential equations which are
required to be monodromy free. Linear ordinary differential equations for the
matrix Szego polynomials and its Cauchy transforms are derived. It is shown how
these Pearson systems lead to nonlinear difference equations for the Verblunsky
matrices and two examples, of Fuchsian and non-Fuchsian type, are considered.
For both cases a new matrix version of the discrete Painlev\'e II equation for
the Verblunsky matrices is found. Reductions of these matrix discrete Painleve
II systems presenting locality are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.07697</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.07697</id><created>2016-01-28</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sergi</keyname><forenames>Danilo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grossi</keyname><forenames>Loris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leidi</keyname><forenames>Tiziano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ortona</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of capillary infiltration into packing structures by the
  Lattice-Boltzmann method for the optimization of ceramic materials</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Eng. Appl. Comput. Fluid Mech. 10, 487 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/19942060.2016.1189361</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we want to simulate with the Lattice-Boltzmann method in 2D the
capillary infiltration into porous structures obtained from the packing of
particles. The experimental problem motivating our work is the densification of
carbon preforms by reactive melt infiltration. The aim is to determine
optimization principles for the manufacturing of high-performance ceramics.
Simulations are performed for packings with varying structural properties. Our
analysis suggests that the observed slow infiltrations can be ascribed to
interface dynamics. Pinning represents the primary factor retarding fluid
penetration. The mechanism responsible for this phenomenon is analyzed in
detail. When surface growth is allowed, it is found that the phenomenon of
pinning becomes stronger. Systems trying to reproduce typical experimental
conditions are also investigated. It turns out that the standard for accurate
simulations is challenging. The primary obstacle to overcome for enhanced
accuracy seems to be the over-occurrence of pinning.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00135</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00135</id><created>2016-01-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Davidovikj</keyname><forenames>Dejan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Slim</keyname><forenames>Jesse J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bueno</keyname><forenames>Santiago J. Cartamil -</forenames></author><author><keyname>van der Zant</keyname><forenames>Herre S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steeneken</keyname><forenames>Peter G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venstra</keyname><forenames>Warner J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Visualizing the motion of graphene nanodrums</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Nano Lett. 2016 16 (4) 2768-2773</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.nanolett.6b00477</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Membranes of suspended two-dimensional materials show a large variability in
mechanical properties, in part due to static and dynamic wrinkles. As a
consequence, experiments typically show a multitude of nanomechanical resonance
peaks, which makes an unambiguous identification of the vibrational modes
difficult. Here, we probe the motion of graphene nanodrum resonators with
spatial resolution using a phase-sensitive interferometer. By simultaneously
visualizing the local phase and amplitude of the driven motion, we show that
unexplained spectral features represent split degenerate modes. When taking
these into account, the resonance frequencies up to the eighth vibrational mode
agree with theory. The corresponding displacement profiles however, are
remarkably different from theory, as small imperfections increasingly deform
the nodal lines for the higher modes. The Brownian motion, which is used to
calibrate the local displacement, exhibits a similar mode pattern. The
experiments clarify the complicated dynamic behaviour of suspended
two-dimensional materials, which is crucial for reproducible fabrication and
applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01118</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01118</id><created>2016-02-02</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nagel</keyname><forenames>Hannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janke</keyname><forenames>Wolfhard</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of condensate formation in stochastic transport with
  pair-factorized steady states: Nucleation and coarsening time scales</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 052112 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.052112</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Driven diffusive systems such as the zero-range process (ZRP) and the
pair-factorized steady states (PFSS) stochastic transport process are versatile
tools that lend themselves to the study of transport phenomena on a generic
level. While their mathematical structure is simple enough to allow significant
analytical treatment, they offer a variety of interesting phenomena. With
appropriate dynamics, the ZRP and PFSS models feature a condensation transition
where for a supercritical density the translational symmetry breaks
spontaneously and excess particles form a single-site or spatially extended
condensate, respectively. In this paper we numerically study the typical time
scales of the two stages of this condensation process: Nucleation and
coarsening. Nucleation is the first stage of condensation where the bulk system
relaxes to its stationary distribution and droplet nuclei form in the system.
These droplets then gradually grow or evaporate in the coarsening regime to
finally coalesce in a single condensate when the system finally relaxes to the
stationary state.
  We use the ZRP condensation model to discuss the choice of the estimation
method for the nucleation time scale and present scaling exponents for the ZRP
and PFSS condensation models with respect to the choice of the typical droplet
mass. We then proceed to present scaling exponents in the coarsening regime of
the ZRP for partial-asymmetric dynamics and the PFSS model for symmetric and
asymmetric dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03864</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03864</id><created>2016-02-11</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rohleder</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author></authors><title>Eigenvalue estimates for the Laplacian on a metric tree</title><categories>math.SP math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>revised version; accepted for publication in Proc. Amer. Math. Soc</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We provide explicit upper bounds for the eigenvalues of the Laplacian on a
finite metric tree subject to standard vertex conditions. The results include
estimates depending on the average length of the edges or the diameter. In
particular, we establish a sharp upper bound for the spectral gap, i.e. the
smallest positive eigenvalue, and show that equilateral star graphs are the
unique maximizers of the spectral gap among all trees of a given average
length.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04711</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04711</id><created>2016-02-15</created><updated>2016-07-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cilibrizzi</keyname><forenames>Pasquale</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigurdsson</keyname><forenames>Helgi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liew</keyname><forenames>Tim C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohadi</keyname><forenames>Hamid</forenames></author><author><keyname>Askitopoulos</keyname><forenames>Alexis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodbeck</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelykh</keyname><forenames>Ivan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruostekoski</keyname><forenames>Janne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagoudakis</keyname><forenames>Pavlos</forenames></author></authors><title>Half-Skyrmion Spin Textures In Polariton Microcavities</title><categories>physics.optics cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 pages, 9 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045315</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the polarization dynamics of a spatially expanding polariton
condensate under nonresonant linearly polarized optical excitation. The
spatially and temporally resolved polariton emission reveals the formation of
non-trivial spin textures in the form of a quadruplet polarization pattern both
in the linear and circular Stokes parameters, and an octuplet in the diagonal
Stokes parameter. The continuous rotation of the polariton pseudospin vector
through the condensate due to TE-TM splitting exhibits an ordered pattern of
half-skyrmions associated with a half-integer topological number. A theoretical
model based on a driven-dissipative Gross-Pitaevskii equation coupled with an
exciton reservoir describes the dynamics of the nontrivial spin textures
through the optical spin-Hall effect.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07979</id><created>2016-02-18</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gogberashvili</keyname><forenames>Merab</forenames></author></authors><title>Octonionic geometry and conformal transformations</title><categories>physics.gen-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>The journal version</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Geom. Meth. Mod. Phys. 13 (2016) 1650092</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0219887816500924</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe space-time using split octonions over the reals and use their
group of automorphisms, the non-compact form of Cartan's exceptional Lie group
G2, as the main geometrical group of the model. Connections of the G2-rotations
of octonionic 8D space with the conformal transformations in 4D Minkowski
space-time are studied. It is shown that the dimensional constant needed in
these analysis naturally gives the observed value of the cosmological constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.00504</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.00504</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Ribeiro</keyname><forenames>G. A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kl&#xfc;mper</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlation functions of the integrable spin-s chain</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP nlin.SI</categories><comments>35 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 254001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/25/254001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the correlation functions of su(2) invariant spin-s chains in the
thermodynamic limit. We derive non-linear integral equations for an auxiliary
correlation function $\omega$ for any spin s and finite temperature T. For the
spin-3/2 chain for arbitrary temperature and zero magnetic field we obtain
algebraic expressions for the reduced density matrix of two-sites. In the zero
temperature limit, the density matrix elements are evaluated analytically and
appear to be given in terms of Riemann's zeta function values of even and odd
arguments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02233</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02233</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vieira</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezerra</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Confluent Heun functions and the physics of black holes: resonant
  frequencies, Hawking radiation and scattering of scalar waves</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>18 pages. This paper was unified and published with arXiv:1603.02240</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 373 (2016) 28-42</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2016.06.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the confluent Heun functions to study the resonant frequencies
(quasispectrum), the Hawking radiation and the scattering process of scalar
waves, in a class of spacetimes, namely, the ones generated by a
Kerr-Newman-Kasuya spacetime (dyon black hole) and a Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m
black hole surrounded by a magnetic field (Ernst spacetime). In both
spacetimes, the solutions for the angular and radial parts of the corresponding
Klein-Gordon equations are obtained exactly, for massive and massless fields,
respectively. The special cases of Kerr and Schwarzschild black holes are
analyzed and the solutions obtained, as well as in the case of a Schwarzschild
black hole surrounded by a magnetic field. In all these special situations, the
resonant frequencies, Hawking radiation and scattering are studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02240</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02240</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vieira</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bezerra</keyname><forenames>V. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum effects in Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m black hole surrounded by
  magnetic field: the scalar wave case</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This paper has been withdrawn by the author because was unified and
  published with arXiv:1603.02233</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply the confluent Heun functions to study the resonant frequencies
(quasispectrum), the Hawking radiation and the scattering process of scalar
waves, in a class of spacetimes, namely, the ones generated by a
Kerr-Newman-Kasuya spacetime (dyon black hole) and a Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m
black hole surrounded by a magnetic field (Ernst spacetime). In both
spacetimes, the solutions for the angular and radial parts of the corresponding
Klein-Gordon equations are obtained exactly, for massive and massless fields,
respectively. The special cases of Kerr and Schwarzschild black holes are
analyzed and the solutions obtained, as well as in the case of a Schwarzschild
black hole surrounded by a magnetic field. In all these special situations, the
resonant frequencies, Hawking radiation and scattering are studied.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04866</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04866</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shivvers</keyname><forenames>Isaac</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>WeiKang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mauerhan</keyname><forenames>Jon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kleiser</keyname><forenames>Io K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Dyk</keyname><forenames>Schuyler D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silverman</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graham</keyname><forenames>Melissa L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kelly</keyname><forenames>Patrick L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filippenko</keyname><forenames>Alexei V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Sahana</forenames></author></authors><title>SN 2015U: A Rapidly Evolving and Luminous Type Ibn Supernova</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>20 pages, 15 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS, 461, 3057 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1528</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Supernova (SN) 2015U (also known as PSN J07285387+3349106) was discovered in
NGC 2388 on 2015 Feb. 11. A rapidly evolving and luminous event, it showed
effectively hydrogen-free spectra dominated by relatively narrow helium P-Cygni
spectral features and it was classified as a SN Ibn. In this paper we present
photometric, spectroscopic, and spectropolarimetric observations of SN 2015U,
including a Keck/DEIMOS spectrum (resolution $\approx$ 5000) which fully
resolves the optical emission and absorption features. We find that SN 2015U is
best understood via models of shock breakout from extended and dense
circumstellar material (CSM), likely created by a history of mass loss from the
progenitor with an extreme outburst within $\sim$1-2 yr of core collapse (but
we do not detect any outburst in our archival imaging of NGC 2388). We argue
that the high luminosity of SN 2015U was powered not through $^{56}$Ni decay
but via the deposition of kinetic energy into the ejecta/CSM shock interface.
Though our analysis is hampered by strong host-galaxy dust obscuration (which
likely exhibits multiple components), our dataset makes SN 2015U one of the
best-studied Type Ibn supernovae and provides a bridge of understanding to
other rapidly fading transients, both luminous and relatively faint.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05320</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05320</id><created>2016-03-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Winiarski</keyname><forenames>Micha&#x142; J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiendlocha</keyname><forenames>Bart&#x142;omiej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sternik</keyname><forenames>Ma&#x142;gorzata</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wi&#x15b;niewski</keyname><forenames>Piotr</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Brien</keyname><forenames>James R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaczorowski</keyname><forenames>Dariusz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klimczuk</keyname><forenames>Tomasz</forenames></author></authors><title>Rattling enhanced superconductivity in MV$_2$Al$_{20}$ (M = Sc, Lu, Y)
  intermetallic cage compounds</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>34 pages (+ supplemental material), 15 figures (+ 4 in suppl. mat.);
  Accepted for publication in Physical Review B</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 134507 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.134507</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Polycrystalline samples of four intermetallic compounds: MV$_2$Al$_{20}$ (M =
Sc, Y, La, and Lu) were synthesized using an arc-melting technique. The crystal
structures were analyzed by means of powder x-ray diffraction and Rietveld
analysis, and the physical properties were studied by means of heat capacity,
electrical resistivity and magnetic susceptibility measurements down to 0.4 K.
For ScV$_2$Al$_{20}$, LuV$_2$Al$_{20}$, and YV$_2$Al$_{20}$, superconductivity
was observed with critical temperatures T$_c$ = 1.00 K, 0.57 K, and 0.60 K,
respectively. Superconductivity for the Lu compound is reported for the first
time. Theoretical calculations of the electronic and phonon structures were
conducted in order to analyze the superconductivity and dynamics in
ScV$_2$Al$_{20}$, YV$_2$Al$_{20}$, and LuV$_2$Al$_{20}$ and to explain the lack
of a superconducting transition in LaV$_2$Al$_{20}$ down to 0.4 K. The results
of the experimental and theoretical studies show that all the compounds are
weakly-coupled type II BCS superconductors, and reveal the importance of the
M-atom anharmonic &quot;rattling&quot; modes for the superconductivity in these
materials, which seem to enhance T$_c$, especially for ScV$_2$Al$_{20}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06438</id><created>2016-03-21</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Abdurakhimov</keyname><forenames>L. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamashiro</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badrutdinov</keyname><forenames>A. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konstantinov</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong coupling of the cyclotron motion of surface electrons on liquid
  helium to a microwave cavity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el quant-ph</categories><comments>main text (5 pages, 3 figures) and supplemental material (3 pages, 2
  figures), accepted to PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 056803 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.056803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The strong coupling regime is observed in a system of two-dimensional
electrons whose cyclotron motion is coupled to an electro-magnetic mode in a
Fabry-Perot cavity resonator. The Rabi splitting of eigenfrequencies of coupled
motion is observed both in the cavity reflection spectrum and ac current of
electrons, the latter probed by measuring their bolometric photoresponse.
Despite the fact that similar observations of the Rabi splitting in
many-particle systems have been described as a quantum-mechanical effect, we
show that the observed splitting can be explained completely by a model based
on the classical electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07963</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07963</id><created>2016-03-25</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Xin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shafak</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalaydzhyan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muecke</keyname><forenames>O. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaertner</keyname><forenames>F. X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Attosecond Precision Multi-km Laser-Microwave Network</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><comments>42 pages, 13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Synchronous laser-microwave networks delivering attosecond timing precision
are highly desirable in many advanced applications, such as geodesy,
very-long-baseline interferometry, high-precision navigation and
multi-telescope arrays. In particular, rapidly expanding photon science
facilities like X-ray free-electron lasers and intense laser beamlines require
system-wide attosecond-level synchronization of dozens of optical and microwave
signals up to kilometer distances. Once equipped with such precision, these
facilities will initiate radically new science by shedding light on molecular
and atomic processes happening on the attosecond timescale, such as
intramolecular charge transfer, Auger processes and their impact on X-ray
imaging. Here, we present for the first time a complete synchronous
laser-microwave network with attosecond precision, which is achieved through
new metrological devices and careful balancing of fiber nonlinearities and
fundamental noise contributions. We demonstrate timing stabilization of a
4.7-km fiber network and remote optical-optical synchronization across a 3.5-km
fiber link with an overall timing jitter of 580 and 680 attoseconds RMS,
respectively, for over 40 hours. Ultimately we realize a complete
laser-microwave network with 950-attosecond timing jitter for 18 hours. This
work can enable next-generation attosecond photon-science facilities to
revolutionize many research fields from structural biology to material science
and chemistry to fundamental physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09493</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kovacs</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>Center of Integrated Sensor Systems, Danube University Krems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Oezelt</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames><affiliation>Center of Integrated Sensor Systems, Danube University Krems</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schabes</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames><affiliation>Spin Transfer Technologies, Fremont, CA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Schrefl</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames><affiliation>Center of Integrated Sensor Systems, Danube University Krems</affiliation></author></authors><title>Numerical optimization of writer and media for bit patterned magnetic
  recording</title><categories>physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4954888</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we present a micromagnetic study of the performance potential of
bit-patterned (BP) magnetic recording media via joint optimization of the
design of the media and of the magnetic write heads. Because the design space
is large and complex, we developed a novel computational framework suitable for
parallel implementation on compute clusters. Our technique combines advanced
global optimization algorithms and finite-element micromagnetic solvers.
Targeting data bit densities of $4\mathrm{Tb}/\mathrm{in}^2$, we optimize
designs for centered, staggered, and shingled BP writing. The magnetization
dynamics of the switching of the exchange-coupled composite BP islands of the
media is treated micromagnetically. Our simulation framework takes into account
not only the dynamics of on-track errors but also of the thermally induced
adjacent-track erasure. With co-optimized write heads, the results show
superior performance of shingled BP magnetic recording where we identify two
particular designs achieving write bit-error rates of $1.5\mathrm{x}10^{-8}$
and $8.4\mathrm{x}10^{-8}$, respectively. A detailed description of the key
design features of these designs is provided and contrasted with centered and
staggered BP designs which yielded write bit error rates of only
$2.8\mathrm{x}10^{-3}$ (centered design) and $1.7\mathrm{x}10^{-2}$ (staggered
design) even under optimized conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00265</id><created>2016-04-01</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>H. Chau</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vu</keyname><forenames>Thanh</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-separability and steerability of two-qubit states from the geometry
  of steering outcomes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures; improved figures and terminology</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012114 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When two qubits A and B are in an appropriate state, Alice can remotely steer
Bob's system B into different ensembles by making different measurements on A.
This famous phenomenon is known as quantum steering, or Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen
steering. Importantly, quantum steering establishes the correspondence not only
between a measurement on A (made by Alice) and an ensemble of B (owned by Bob)
but also between each of Alice's measurement outcomes and an unnormalized
conditional state of Bob's system. The unnormalized conditional states of B
corresponding to all possible measurement outcomes of Alice are called Alice's
steering outcomes. We show that, surprisingly, the $4$-dimensional geometry of
Alice's steering outcomes completely determines both the non-separability of
the two-qubit state and its steerability from her side. Consequently, the
problem of classifying two-qubit states into non-separable and steerable
classes is equivalent to geometrically classifying certain $4$-dimensional
skewed double-cones.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01459</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01459</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Shou-Shu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Starykh</keyname><forenames>Oleg A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>D. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balents</keyname><forenames>Leon</forenames></author></authors><title>Emergent quasi-one-dimensionality in a kagom\'e magnet: A simple route
  to complexity</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>16 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 035154 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.035154</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ground state phase diagram of the quantum spin-$1/2$ Heisenberg
model on the kagom\'{e} lattice with first- ($J_1 &lt; 0$), second- ($J_2 &lt; 0$),
and third-neighbor interactions ($J_d &gt; 0$) by means of analytical low-energy
field theory and numerical density-matrix renormalization group (DMRG) studies.
The results offer a consistent picture of the $J_d$-dominant regime in terms of
three sets of spin chains weakly coupled by the ferromagnetic inter-chain
interactions $J_{1,2}$. When either $J_1$ or $J_2$ is dominant, the model is
found to support one of two cuboctohedral phases, cuboc1 and cuboc2. These
cuboc states host non-coplanar long-ranged magnetic order and possess finite
scalar spin chirality. However, in the compensated regime $J_1 \simeq J_2$, a
valence bond crystal phase emerges between the two cuboc phases. We find
excellent agreement between an analytical theory based on coupled spin chains
and unbiased DMRG calculations, including at a very detailed level of
comparison of the structure of the valence bond crystal state. To our
knowledge, this is the first such comprehensive understanding of a highly
frustrated two-dimensional (2d) quantum antiferromagnet. We find no evidence of
either the one-dimensional (1d) gapless spin liquid or the chiral spin liquids,
which were previously suggested by parton mean field theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01804</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01804</id><created>2016-04-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Kexin</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Sailing</forenames></author></authors><title>Truly trapped rainbow by utilizing nonreciprocal waveguides</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>main manuscript: 14 pages, 6 figures. supplementary information: 3
  pages, 2 figures, 2 movies</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 30206 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The concept of a &quot;trapped rainbow&quot; has generated considerable interest for
optical data storage and processing. It aims to trap different frequency
components of the wave packet at different positions permanently. However, all
the previously proposed structures cannot truly achieve this effect, due to the
difficulties in suppressing the reflection caused by strong intermodal coupling
and distinguishing different frequency components simultaneously. In this
article, we found a physical mechanism to achieve a truly &quot;trapped rainbow&quot;
storage of electromagnetic wave. We utilize nonreciprocal waveguides under a
tapered magnetic field to achieve this and such a trapping effect is stable
even under fabrication disorders. We also observe hot spots and relatively long
duration time of the trapped wave around critical positions through frequency
domain and time domain simulations. The physical mechanism we found has a
variety of potential applications ranging from wave harvesting and storage to
nonlinearity enhancement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01997</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01997</id><created>2016-04-07</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sotnikov</keyname><forenames>Andrii</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunes</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Field-induced exciton condensation in LaCoO3</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 30510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent observation of magnetic field induced transition in
LaCoO3 we study the effect of external field in systems close to instabilities
towards spin-state ordering and exciton condensation. We show that, while in
both cases the transition can be induced by an external field, temperature
dependencies of the critical field have opposite slopes. Based on this result
we argue that the experimental observations select the exciton condensation
scenario. We show that such condensation is possible due to high mobility of
the intermediate spin excitations. The estimated width of the corresponding
dispersion is large enough to overrule the order of atomic multiplets and to
make the intermediate spin excitation propagating with a specific wave vector
the lowest excitation of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02261</id><created>2016-04-08</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ansorg</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Macedo</keyname><forenames>Rodrigo Panosso</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral decomposition of black-hole perturbations on hyperboloidal
  slices</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Match published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 124016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.124016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a spectral decomposition of solutions to
relativistic wave equations described on horizon penetrating hyperboloidal
slices within a given Schwarzschild-black-hole background. The wave equa- tion
in question is Laplace-transformed which leads to a spatial differential
equation with a complex parameter. For initial data which are analytic with
respect to a compactified spatial coordinate, this equation is treated with the
help of the Mathematica-package in terms of a sophisticated Taylor series
analysis. Thereby, all ingredients of the desired spectral decomposition arise
explicitly to arbitrarily prescribed accuracy, including quasi normal modes,
quasi normal mode amplitudes as well as the jump of the Laplace-transform along
the branch cut. Finally, all contributions are put together to obtain via the
inverse Laplace transformation the spectral de- composition in question. The
paper explains extensively this procedure and includes detailed discussions of
relevant aspects, such as the definition of quasi normal modes and the question
regarding the contribution of infinity frequencies modes to the early time
response of the black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02556</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02556</id><created>2016-04-09</created><updated>2016-06-23</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chakravarty</keyname><forenames>Girish Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Gaveshna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambiase</keyname><forenames>Gaetano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohanty</keyname><forenames>Subhendra</forenames></author></authors><title>Plateau Inflation in SUGRA-MSSM</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures. Replaced with the journal version. Accepted in
  Phys. Lett. B</comments><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explored a Higgs inflationary scenario in the SUGRA embedding of the MSSM
in Einstein frame where the inflaton is contained in the $SU(2)$ Higgs doublet.
We include all higher order non-renormalizable terms to the MSSM superpotential
and an appropriate K\&quot;ahler potential which can provide slow-roll inflaton
potential in the $D-$flat direction. In this model, a plateau-like inflation
potential can be obtained if the imaginary part of the neutral Higgs acts as
the inflaton. The inflationary predictions of this model are consistent with
the latest CMB observations. The model represents a successful Higgs inflation
scenario in the context of Supergravity and it is compatible with Minimal
Supersymmetric extension of the Standard Model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06085</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06085</id><created>2016-04-20</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Starobinsky</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sushkov</keyname><forenames>Sergey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Volkov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The screening Horndeski cosmologies</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>matches the published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1606 (2016) no.06, 007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/06/007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a systematic analysis of homogeneous and isotropic cosmologies in
a particular Horndeski model with Galileon shift symmetry, containing also a
$\Lambda$-term and a matter. The model, sometimes called Fab Five, admits a
rich spectrum of solutions. Some of them describe the standard late time
cosmological dynamic dominated by the $\Lambda$-term and matter, while at the
early times the universe expands with a constant Hubble rate determined by the
value of the scalar kinetic coupling. For other solutions the $\Lambda$-term
and matter are screened at all times but there are nevertheless the early and
late accelerating phases. The model also admits bounces, as well as peculiar
solutions describing &quot;the emergence of time&quot;. Most of these solutions contain
ghosts in the scalar and tensor sectors. However, a careful analysis reveals
three different branches of ghost-free solutions, all showing a late time
acceleration phase. We analyze the dynamical stability of these solutions and
find that all of them are stable in the future, since all their perturbations
stay bounded at late times. However, they all turn out to be unstable in the
past, as their perturbations grow violently when one approaches the initial
spacetime singularity. We therefore conclude that the model has no viable
solutions describing the whole of the cosmological history, although it may
describe the current acceleration phase. We also check that the flat space
solution is ghost-free in the model, but it may acquire ghost in more general
versions of the Horndeski theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.06208</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.06208</id><created>2016-04-21</created><updated>2016-06-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Maimaiti</keyname><forenames>Aili</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holzmann</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truong</keyname><forenames>Viet Giang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ritsch</keyname><forenames>Helmut</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chormaic</keyname><forenames>Sile Nic</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear force dependence on optically bound micro-particle arrays in
  the eva-nescent fields of fundamental and higher order microfibre modes</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 30131 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30131</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Particles trapped in the evanescent field of an ultrathin optical fibre
inter-act over very long distances via multiple scattering of the fibre-guided
fields. In ultrathin fibres that support higher order modes, these
interac-tions are stronger and exhibit qualitatively new behaviour due to the
cou-pling of different fibre modes, which have different propagation
wave-vectors, by the particles. Here, we study one dimensional longitudinal
opti-cal binding interactions of chains of 3 {\mu}m polystyrene spheres under
the influence of the evanescent fields of a two-mode microfibre. The
observa-tion of long-range interactions, self-ordering and speed variation of
parti-cle chains reveals strong optical binding effects between the particles
that can be modelled well by a tritter scattering-matrix approach. The optical
forces, optical binding interactions and the velocity of bounded particle
chains are calculated using this method. Results show good agreement with
finite element numerical simulations. Experimental data and theoreti-cal
analysis show that higher order modes in a microfibre offer a promis-ing method
to not only obtain stable, multiple particle trapping or faster particle
propulsion speeds, but that they also allow for better control over each
individual trapped object in particle ensembles near the microfibre surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07414</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07414</id><created>2016-04-25</created><updated>2016-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pejcha</keyname><forenames>Ondrej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>Brian D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomida</keyname><forenames>Kengo</forenames></author></authors><title>Binary Stellar Mergers with Marginally-Bound Ejecta: Excretion Disks,
  Inflated Envelopes, Outflows, and their Luminous Transients</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>14 pages, 13 figures, 1 table. Accepted to MNRAS. Movie version of
  Figure 1 is available at http://www.astro.princeton.edu/~pejcha/ltwo/</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS (2016), 461, 2527</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1481</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study mass loss from the outer Lagrange point (L2) in binary stellar
mergers and their luminous transients by means of radiative hydrodynamical
simulations. Previously, we showed that for binary mass ratios 0.06 &lt; q &lt; 0.8,
synchronous L2 mass loss results in a radiatively inefficient, dust-forming
unbound equatorial outflow. A similar outflow exists irrespective of q if the
ratio of the sound speed to the orbital speed at the injection point is
sufficiently large, \epsilon = c_T/v_orb &gt; 0.15. By contrast, for cold L2
mass-loss (\epsilon &lt; 0.15) from binaries with q &lt; 0.06 or q &gt; 0.8, the
equatorial outflow instead remains marginally-bound and falls back to the
binary over tens to hundreds of binary orbits, where it experiences additional
tidal torqueing and shocking. As the bound gas becomes virialized with the
binary, the luminosity of the system increases slowly at approximately constant
photosphere radius, causing the temperature to rise. Subsequent evolution
depends on the efficiency of radiative cooling. If the bound atmosphere is able
to cool efficiently, as quantified by radiative diffusion time being shorter
than the advection time (t_diff/t_adv &lt; 1), then the virialized gas collapses
to an excretion disk, while for t_diff/t_adv &gt; 1 an isotropic wind is formed.
Between these two extremes, an inflated envelope transports the heat generated
near the binary to the surface by meridional flows. In all cases, the radiated
luminosity reaches a fraction ~0.01 to 0.1 of Mdot v_orb^2/2, where Mdot is the
mass outflow rate. We discuss the implications of our results for transients in
the luminosity gap between classical novae and supernovae, such as V1309 Sco
and V838 Mon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02831</id><created>2016-05-09</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ermann</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergini</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shepelyansky</keyname><forenames>Dima L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics and thermalization of Bose-Einstein condensate in Sinai
  oscillator trap</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas nlin.CD</categories><comments>11 pages, 14 figures. Final version. Accepted forpublication at Phys.
  Rev. A. Additional information available at
  http://www.quantware.ups-tlse.fr/QWLIB/sinaioscillator/</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013618 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013618</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study numerically the evolution of Bose-Einstein condensate in the Sinai
oscillator trap described by the Gross-Pitaevskii equation in two dimensions.
In the absence of interactions this trap mimics the properties of Sinai
billiards where the classical dynamics is chaotic and the quantum evolution is
described by generic properties of quantum chaos and random matrix theory. We
show that, above a certain border, the nonlinear interactions between atoms
lead to the emergence of dynamical thermalization which generates the
statistical Bose-Einstein distribution over eigenmodes of the system without
interactions. Below the thermalization border the evolution remains
quasi-integrable. Such a Sinai oscillator trap, formed by the oscillator
potential and a repulsive disk located in the vicinity of the center, had been
already realized in rst experiments with the Bose-Einstein condensate formation
by Ketterle group in 1995 and we argue that it can form a convenient test bed
for experimental investigations of dynamical of thermalization. Possible links
and implications for Kolmogorov turbulence in absence of noise are also
discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.05133</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.05133</id><created>2016-05-17</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Caselle</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costagliola</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnoli</keyname><forenames>Nicodemo</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformal perturbation of off-critical correlators in the 3D Ising
  universality class</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, Expanded the discussion of Conformal Perturbation
  Theory</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 026005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.026005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thanks to the impressive progress of conformal bootstrap methods we have now
very precise estimates of both scaling dimensions and OPE coefficients for
several 3D universality classes. We show how to use this information to obtain
similarly precise estimates for off-critical correlators using conformal
perturbation. We discuss in particular the $&lt; \sigma (r) \sigma (0) &gt;$, $&lt;
\epsilon (r) \epsilon (0) &gt;$ and $&lt; \sigma (r) \epsilon (0) &gt;$ two point
functions in the high and low temperature regimes of the 3D Ising model and
evaluate the leading and next to leading terms in the $s = t r^{\Delta_{t}}$
expansion, where $t$ is the reduced temperature. Our results for $&lt; \sigma (r)
\sigma (0) &gt;$ agree both with Monte Carlo simulations and with a set of
experimental estimates of the critical scattering function.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06720</id><created>2016-05-21</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ramm</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>B. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Endl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hearnshaw</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wittenmyer</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gunn</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bergmann</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilmartin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brogt</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The conjectured S-type retrograde planet in nu Octantis: more evidence
  including four years of iodine-cell radial velocities</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>15 pages, 12 figures, 8 tables</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report 1212 radial-velocity (RV) measurements obtained in the years
2009-2013 using an iodine cell for the spectroscopic binary nu Octantis
(K1III/IV). This system (a_bin~2.6 au, P~1050 days) is conjectured to have a
Jovian planet with a semi-major axis half that of the binary host. The extreme
geometry only permits long-term stability if the planet is in a retrograde
orbit. Whilst the reality of the planet (P~415 days) remains uncertain, other
scenarios (stellar variability or apsidal motion caused by a yet unobserved
third star) continue to appear substantially less credible based on CCF
bisectors, line-depth ratios and many other independent details. If this
evidence is validated but the planet is disproved, the claims of other planets
using RVs will be seriously challenged.
  We also describe a significant revision to the previously published RVs and
the full set of 1437 RVs now encompasses nearly 13 years. The sensitive orbital
dynamics allow us to constrain the three-dimensional architecture with a broad
prior probability distribution on the mutual inclination, which with posterior
samples obtained from an N-body Markov chain Monte Carlo is found to be 158.4
+/- 1.2 deg. None of these samples are dynamically stable beyond 1 Myr.
However, a grid search around the best-fitting solution finds a region that has
many models stable for 10 Myr, and includes one model within 1-sigma that is
stable for at least 100 Myr. The planet's exceptional nature demands robust
independent verification and makes the theoretical understanding of its
formation a worthy challenge.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08745</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2016-05-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Brieva</keyname><forenames>Abel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gredel</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jaeger</keyname><forenames>Cornelia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huisken</keyname><forenames>Friedrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henning</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>C60 as a probe for astrophysical environments</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in The Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>Astrophysical Journal, 2016. 826, 122</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/2/122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The C60 molecule has been recently detected in a wide range of astrophysical
environments through its four active intramolecular vibrational modes (T1u)
near 18.9, 17.4, 8.5, and 7.0 microns. The strengths of the mid-infrared
emission bands have been used to infer astrophysical conditions in the
fullerene-rich regions. Widely varying values of the relative intrinsic
strengths (RIS) of these four bands are reported in laboratory and theoretical
papers, which impedes the derivation of the excitation mechanism of C60 in the
astrophysical sources. The spectroscopic analysis of the C60 samples produced
with our method delivers highly reproducible RIS values of 100, 25 +- 1, 26 +-
1, and 40 +- 4. A comparison of the inferred C60 emission band strengths with
the astrophysical data shows that the observed strengths cannot be explained in
terms of fluorescent or thermal emission alone. The large range in the observed
17.4/18.9 emission ratios indicates that either the emission bands contain
significant contributions from emitters other than C60, or that the population
distribution among the C60 vibrational modes is affected by physical processes
other than thermal or UV excitation, such as chemo-luminescence from nascent
C60 or possibly, Poincare fluorescence resulting from an inverse internal
energy conversion. We have carefully analyzed the effect of the weakly-active
fundamental modes and second order modes in the mid-infrared spectrum of C60
and propose that neutral C60 is the carrier of the unidentified emission band
at 6.49 microns which has been observed in fullerene-rich environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09229</id><created>2016-05-26</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stuckey</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDevitt</keyname><forenames>Timothy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sten</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silberstein</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author></authors><title>End of a Dark Age?</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>This version was accepted for publication in the International
  Journal of Modern Physics D; revised version of an essay that won Honorable
  Mention in the Gravity Research Foundation 2016 Awards for Essays on
  Gravitation. 10 pages, 3 figures. arXiv admin note: text overlap with
  arXiv:1509.09288</comments><journal-ref>International Journal of Modern Physics D 25(12), 1644004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271816440041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We argue that dark matter and dark energy phenomena associated with galactic
rotation curves, X-ray cluster mass profiles, and type Ia supernova data can be
accounted for via small corrections to idealized general relativistic spacetime
geometries due to disordered locality. Accordingly, we fit THINGS rotation
curve data rivaling modified Newtonian dynamics, ROSAT/ASCA X-ray cluster mass
profile data rivaling metric-skew-tensor gravity, and SCP Union2.1 SN Ia data
rivaling $\Lambda$CDM without non-baryonic dark matter or a cosmological
constant. In the case of dark matter, we geometrically modify proper mass
interior to the Schwarzschild solution. In the case of dark energy, we modify
proper distance in Einstein-deSitter cosmology. Therefore, the phenomena of
dark matter and dark energy may be chimeras created by an errant belief that
spacetime is a differentiable manifold rather than a disordered graph.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.09738</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.09738</id><created>2016-05-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Grefenstette</keyname><forenames>Brian W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Glesener</keyname><forenames>Lindsay</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krucker</keyname><forenames>S&#xe4;m</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Hugh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hannah</keyname><forenames>Iain G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>David M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>Julia K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Stephen M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>Kristin K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marsh</keyname><forenames>Andrew J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caspi</keyname><forenames>Amir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shih</keyname><forenames>Albert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuhar</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boggs</keyname><forenames>Steven E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christensen</keyname><forenames>Finn E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craig</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forster</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hailey</keyname><forenames>Charles J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>Fiona A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyasaka</keyname><forenames>Hiromasa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stern</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>William W.</forenames></author></authors><title>The First Focused Hard X-ray Images of the Sun with NuSTAR</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>11 pages, accepted to ApJ</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Vol. 826, Issue 1, 20 (11pp); 2016 July
  20</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/20</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from the the first campaign of dedicated solar
observations undertaken by the \textit{Nuclear Spectroscopic Telescope ARray}
({\em NuSTAR}) hard X-ray telescope. Designed as an astrophysics mission, {\em
NuSTAR} nonetheless has the capability of directly imaging the Sun at hard
X-ray energies ($&gt;$3~keV) with an increase in sensitivity of at least two
magnitude compared to current non-focusing telescopes. In this paper we
describe the scientific areas where \textit{NuSTAR} will make major
improvements on existing solar measurements. We report on the techniques used
to observe the Sun with \textit{NuSTAR}, their limitations and complications,
and the procedures developed to optimize solar data quality derived from our
experience with the initial solar observations. These first observations are
briefly described, including the measurement of the Fe K-shell lines in a
decaying X-class flare, hard X-ray emission from high in the solar corona, and
full-disk hard X-ray images of the Sun.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01635</id><created>2016-06-06</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pervishko</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kibis</keyname><forenames>O. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelykh</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of magnetic field on intersubband polaritons in a quantum well:
  Strong to weak coupling conversion</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Opt. Lett. 41, 3595 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.003595</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate theoretically the effect of a magnetic field on intersubband
polaritons in an asymmetric quantum well placed inside an optical resonator. It
is demonstrated that the field-induced diamagnetic shift of electron subbands
in the well increases the broadening of optical lines corresponding to
intersubband electron transitions. As a consequence, the magnetic field can
switch the polariton system from the regime of strong light-matter coupling to
the regime of weak one. This effect paves a way to the effective control of
polaritonic devices with a magnetic field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02946</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02946</id><created>2016-06-09</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Torrielli</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Lectures on Classical Integrability</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>34 pages, 2 figures; pdfLaTeX. Published version</comments><report-no>DMUS-MP-16/04</report-no><journal-ref>J.Phys. A 49 (2016) no.32, 323001</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We review some essential aspects of classically integrable systems. The
detailed outline of the lectures consists of: 1. Introduction and motivation,
with historical remarks; 2. Liouville theorem and action-angle variables, with
examples (harmonic oscillator, Kepler problem); 3. Algebraic tools: Lax pairs,
monodromy and transfer matrices, classical r-matrices and exchange relations,
non-ultralocal Poisson brackets, with examples (non-linear Schroedinger model,
principal chiral field); 4. Features of classical r-matrices: Belavin-Drinfeld
theorems, analyticity properties, and lift of the classical structures to
quantum groups; 5. Classical inverse scattering method to solve integrable
differential equations: soliton solutions, spectral properties and the
Gel'fand-Levitan-Marchenko equation, with examples (KdV equation, Sine-Gordon
model). Prepared for the Durham Young Researchers Integrability School,
organised by the GATIS network. This is part of a collection of lecture notes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05164</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05164</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Barucca</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bardoscia</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caccioli</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Errico</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Visentin</keyname><forenames>Gabriele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Battiston</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caldarelli</keyname><forenames>Guido</forenames></author></authors><title>Network Valuation in Financial Systems</title><categories>q-fin.RM physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>26 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce a network valuation model (hereafter NEVA) for the ex-ante
valuation of claims among financial institutions connected in a network of
liabilities. Similar to previous work, the new framework allows to endogenously
determine the recovery rate on all claims upon the default of some
institutions. In addition, it also allows to account for ex-ante uncertainty on
the asset values, in particular the one arising when the valuation is carried
out at some time before the maturity of the claims. The framework encompasses
as special cases both the ex-post approaches of Eisenberg and Noe and its
previous extensions, as well as the ex-ante approaches, in the sense that each
of these models can be recovered exactly for special values of the parameters.
We characterize the existence and uniqueness of the solutions of the valuation
problem under general conditions on how the value of each claim depends on the
equity of the counterparty. Further, we define an algorithm to carry out the
network valuation and we provide sufficient conditions for convergence to the
maximal solution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05334</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05334</id><created>2016-06-16</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tennie</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedral</keyname><forenames>Vlatko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schilling</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Pinning of fermionic occupation numbers: Higher spatial dimensions and
  spin</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012120 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012120</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The role of the generalized Pauli constraints (GPCs) in higher spatial
dimensions and by incorporating spin degrees of freedom is systematically
explored for a system of interacting fermions confined by a harmonic trap.
Physical relevance of the GPCs is confirmed by analytical means for the ground
state in the regime of weak couplings by finding its vector of natural
occupation numbers close to the boundary of the allowed region. Such
quasipinning is found to become weaker in the intermediate and strong coupling
regime. The study of crossovers between different spatial dimensions by
detuning the harmonic trap frequencies suggests that quasipinning is
essentially an effect for systems with reduced spatial dimensionality. In
addition, we find that quasipinning becomes stronger by increasing the degree
of spin-polarization. Consequently, the number of states available around the
Fermi level plays a key role for the occurrence of quasipinning. This suggests
that quasipinning emerges from the conflict between energy minimization and
fermionic exchange symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08107</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08107</id><created>2016-06-26</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Tomohiro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ogasawara</keyname><forenames>Kota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>Umpei</forenames></author></authors><title>Consistent analytic approach to the efficiency of collisional Penrose
  process</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, minor correction, accepted for publication in Physical
  Review D</comments><report-no>RUP-16-20</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 024038 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a consistent analytic approach to the efficiency of collisional
Penrose process in the vicinity of a maximally rotating Kerr black hole. We
focus on a collision with arbitrarily high center-of-mass energy, which occurs
if either of the colliding particles has its angular momentum fine-tuned to the
critical value to enter the horizon. We show that if the fine-tuned particle is
ingoing on the collision, the upper limit of the efficiency is
$(2+\sqrt{3})(2-\sqrt{2})\simeq 2.186$, while if the fine-tuned particle is
bounced back before the collision, the upper limit is $(2+\sqrt{3})^{2}\simeq
13.93$. Despite earlier claims, the former can be attained for inverse Compton
scattering if the fine-tuned particle is massive and starts at rest at
infinity, while the latter can be attained for various particle reactions, such
as inverse Compton scattering and pair annihilation, if the fine-tuned particle
is either massless or highly relativistic at infinity. We discuss the
difference between the present and earlier analyses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.00465</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.00465</id><created>2016-07-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Yunlong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Naihuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li-Jost</keyname><forenames>Xianqing</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhanced Information Exclusion Relations</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 30440 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30440</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In Hall's reformulation of the uncertainty principle, the entropic
uncertainty relation occupies a core position and provides the first nontrivial
bound for the information exclusion principle. Based upon recent developments
on the uncertainty relation, we present new bounds for the information
exclusion relation using majorization theory and combinatoric techniques, which
reveal further characteristic properties of the overlap matrix between the
measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02940</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hein</keyname><forenames>Hans-Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author></authors><title>Calabi-Yau manifolds with isolated conical singularities</title><categories>math.DG math-ph math.AG math.MP</categories><comments>41 pages, added a short appendix on special Lagrangian vanishing
  cycles</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Let $X$ be a complex projective variety with only canonical singularities and
with trivial canonical bundle. Let $L$ be an ample line bundle on $X$. Assume
that the pair $(X,L)$ is the flat limit of a family of smooth polarized
Calabi-Yau manifolds. Assume that for each singular point $x \in X$ there exist
a Kahler-Einstein Fano manifold $Z$ and a positive integer $q$ dividing $K_Z$
such that $-\frac{1}{q}K_Z$ is very ample and such that the germ $(X,x)$ is
locally analytically isomorphic to a neighborhood of the vertex of the
blow-down of the zero section of $\frac{1}{q}K_{Z}$. We prove that up to
biholomorphism, the unique weak Ricci-flat Kahler metric representing $2\pi
c_1(L)$ on $X$ is asymptotic at a polynomial rate near $x$ to the natural
Ricci-flat Kahler cone metric on $\frac{1}{q}K_Z$ constructed using the Calabi
ansatz. In particular, our result applies if $(X, \mathcal{O}(1))$ is a nodal
quintic threefold in $\mathbb{P}^4$. This provides the first known examples of
compact Ricci-flat manifolds with non-orbifold isolated conical singularities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02979</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02979</id><created>2016-07-11</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Avelino</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barreiro</keyname><forenames>Tiago</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carvalho</keyname><forenames>C. Sofia</forenames></author><author><keyname>da Silva</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lobo</keyname><forenames>Francisco S. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Moruno</keyname><forenames>Prado</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mimoso</keyname><forenames>Jose Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nunes</keyname><forenames>Nelson J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubiera-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saez-Gomez</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sousa</keyname><forenames>Lara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tereno</keyname><forenames>Ismael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trindade</keyname><forenames>Arlindo</forenames></author></authors><title>Unveiling the Dynamics of the Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>94 pages, 14 figures. Review paper accepted for publication in a
  Special Issue of Symmetry. &quot;Symmetry: Feature Papers 2016&quot;. V2: Matches
  published version, now 79 pages (new format)</comments><journal-ref>Symmetry 2016, 8(8), 70</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/sym8080070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the dynamics and evolution of the Universe at early and late
times, focusing on both dark energy and extended gravity models and their
astrophysical and cosmological consequences. Modified theories of gravity not
only provide an alternative explanation for the recent expansion history of the
universe, but they also offer a paradigm fundamentally distinct from the
simplest dark energy models of cosmic acceleration. In this review, we perform
a detailed theoretical and phenomenological analysis of different modified
gravity models and investigate their consistency. We also consider the
cosmological implications of well motivated physical models of the early
universe with a particular emphasis on inflation and topological defects.
Astrophysical and cosmological tests over a wide range of scales, from the
solar system to the observable horizon, severely restrict the allowed models of
the Universe. Here, we review several observational probes -- including
gravitational lensing, galaxy clusters, cosmic microwave background temperature
and polarization, supernova and baryon acoustic oscillations measurements --
and their relevance in constraining our cosmological description of the
Universe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05882</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05882</id><created>2016-07-20</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schubert</keyname><forenames>Klaus R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tests of CPT symmetry in B0-B0bar mixing and in B0 to c cbar K0 decays</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using the time dependences for the decays Y(4S) to B0B0bar to (ell^+- X)(c
cbar K_S,L), we determine the three CPT-sensitive parameters Re (z) and Im (z)
in B0-B0bar mixing and |Abar/A| in B0 to c cbar K0 decays. We find Im(z) =
0.010 +- 0.030 +- 0013, Re(z) = -0:065 +- 0.028 +- 0.014, and |Abar/A| = 0.999
+- 0.023 +- 0.017, in agreement with CPT symmetry. The Re(z) result provides a
limit on one component of Lorentz-symmetry violation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07393</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07393</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2016-07-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cicerone</keyname><forenames>Marcus T</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tyagi</keyname><forenames>Madhusudan</forenames></author></authors><title>Johari-Goldstein Relaxation Events Are Metabasin Transitions</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that by representing quasi-elastic and inelastic neutron scattering
from propylene carbonate (PC) with an explicitly heterogeneous model, we
recover two distinct dynamic signatures in addition to diffusive motion. The
intermediate scattering function provides access to the time-dependence of
these two dynamic processes, and they appear to correspond to transitions
between inherent states and between metabasins on a potential energy landscape.
By fitting the full q-dependence of inelastic scattering, we confirm that that
the Johari-Goldstein ($\beta_{JG}$) relaxation in PC is indistinguishable from
metabasin transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07531</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07531</id><created>2016-07-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Lijuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jingxiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Chenglong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Pinzhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Quanhao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Why is a flare-rich active region CME-poor?</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/2/119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solar active regions (ARs) are the major sources of two kinds of the most
violent solar eruptions, namely flares and coronal mass ejections (CMEs). The
largest AR in the past 24 years, NOAA AR 12192, crossed the visible disk from
2014 October 17 to 30, unusually produced more than one hundred flares,
including 32 M-class and 6 X-class ones, but only one small CME. Flares and
CMEs are believed to be two phenomena in the same eruptive process. Why is such
a flare-rich AR so CME-poor? We compared this AR with other four ARs; two were
productive in both and two were inert. The investigation of the photospheric
parameters based on the SDO/HMI vector magnetogram reveals that the flare-rich
AR 12192, as the other two productive ARs, has larger magnetic flux, current
and free magnetic energy than the two inert ARs, but contrast to the two
productive ARs, it has no strong, concentrated current helicity along both
sides of the flaring neutral line, indicating the absence of a mature magnetic
structure consisting of highly sheared or twisted field lines. Furthermore, the
decay index above the AR 12192 is relatively low, showing strong constraint.
These results suggest that productive ARs are always large and have enough
current and free energy to power flares, but whether or not a flare is
accompanied by a CME is seemingly related to (1) if there is mature sheared or
twisted core field serving as the seed of the CME, (2) if the constraint of the
overlying arcades is weak enough.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07533</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07533</id><created>2016-07-25</created><updated>2016-07-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Quinzacara</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salgado</keyname><forenames>Patricio</forenames></author></authors><title>Stellar equilibrium in Einstein-Chern-Simons gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2013) 73:2479</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-013-2479-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a spherically symmetric internal solution within the context of
Einstein-Chern-Simons gravity and derive a generalized five-dimensional
Tolman-Oppenheimer-Volkoff (TOV) equation. It is shown that the generalized TOV
equation leads, in a certain limit, to the standard five-dimensional TOV
equation
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07873</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07873</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Haghighat</keyname><forenames>Babak</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Wenbin</forenames></author></authors><title>M-strings in thermodynamic limit: Seiberg-Witten geometry</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We initiate the study of M-strings in the thermodynamic limit. In this limit
the BPS partition function of M5 branes localizes on configurations with a
large number of strings which leads to a reformulation of the partition
function in terms of a matrix model. We solve this matrix model and obtain its
spectral curve which can be interpreted as the Seiberg-Witten curve associated
to the compactified M5 brane theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07887</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07887</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Sakkaris</keyname><forenames>Perry</forenames></author></authors><title>QuDot Nets: Quantum Computers and Bayesian Networks</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 26 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new implementation of quantum computation that treats quantum
computers as a special type of Bayesian Network called a QuDot Net. QuDot Nets
allow for the efficient representation of some qubit systems. Single qubit
quantum gates can be implemented as edge transformations on QuDot Nets. The X,
H, R(k), M and SWAP gates are discussed in detail and results show linear
scaling as the number of qubits are increased. We show that measurement and
semi-quantum control gates can be efficiently implemented using QuDot Nets and
present results from a QuDot Net implementation of the terminal Quantum Fourier
Transform. We show how QuDot Nets can implement coherent control gates using
multi-digraphs by labelling parallel edges. Lastly, we discuss implications to
quantum foundations if a classical implementation of quantum computation is
realized.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07889</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07889</id><created>2016-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Shayak</keyname><forenames>B</forenames></author></authors><title>A Method for stability analysis of magnetic bearings : Basic stability
  criteria</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><comments>Selected to presented at ISMB 15</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work I outline a general procedure for dynamic modeling and stability
analysis of a magnetic bearing, which is a rotating shaft confined inside a
chamber through electromagnetic forces alone. I consider the simplest type of
self-propelled bearing, namely a permanent magnet synchronous motor and an
induction motor rotor freely suspended inside the corresponding stator, and
having no eccentricity-fedback control algorithm. Writing Euler's equations for
the rotor mechanics and Maxwell's equations for the electromagnetic field leads
to a systematic technique for analysing the dynamics of the complete system.
Physical arguments indicate that that two essential components for rotor
confinement are a spatial gradient in the stator magnetic field and a torque
angle lying in the second quadrant. These predictions are confirmed through the
linear stability analysis. The direct practical utility of the results is
mitigated by the presence of a repeated eigenvalue in the linearized equations.
Despite this limitation, the analysis presented can act as a good starting
point for more accurate treatments of other magnetic bearing configurations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07894</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07894</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Zink</keyname><forenames>Jonathon K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christian</keyname><forenames>Damian</forenames></author></authors><title>The search for IR excess in low signal to noise sources</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present sources selected from their Wide-field Infrared Survey Explorer
(WISE) colors that merit future observations to image for disks and possible
exoplanet companions. Introducing a weighted detection method, we eliminated
the enormous number of specious excess seen in low signal to noise objects by
requiring greater excess for fainter stars. This is achieved by sorting through
the 747 million sources of the ALLWISE database. In examining these dim stars,
it can be shown that a non-Gaussian distribution best describes the spread
around the main-sequence polynomial fit function. Using a gamma Probability
Density Function (PDF), we can best mimic the main sequence distribution and
exclude natural fluctuations in IR excess. With this new methodology we
re-discover 25 IR excesses and present 14 new candidates. One source
(J053010.20-010140.9), suggests a 8.40 $\pm$ 0.73 AU disk, a likely candidate
for possible direct imagining of planets that are likely fully formed. Although
all of these sources are well within the current flux ratio limit of
$\sim$10$^{-6}$ (Wyatt 2008), J223423.85+403515.8 shows the highest bolometric
flux ratio ($f_d$=0.0694) between disk and host star, providing a very good
candidate for direct imaging of the circumstellar disk itself. In re-examining
the Kepler candidate catalog (original study preformed by Kennedy and Wyatt
2012), we found one new candidate that indicates disk like characteristics (TYC
3143-322-1).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07901</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07901</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Jiyeon</forenames></author></authors><title>Vector boson (W,Z) Studies with CMS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures, DIS2016 proceedings</comments><report-no>CMS CR-2016/124</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on recent measurements of W and Z boson production at CMS. These
include measurements of inclusive and differential W and Z boson production
cross sections at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 and 13 TeV, measurements of the angular
coefficients of Z boson production, forward-backward asymmetry of
Z/$\gamma^{*}$ events, and W charge asymmetry at $\sqrt{s}$ = 8 TeV. These
measurements can be used to improve PDFs and refine QCD calculations of weak
boson production processes. In addition, a W-like mass measurement using Z
boson events has been performed to probe the experimental uncertainties
expected for a W mass measurement at $\sqrt{s}$ = 7 TeV.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07902</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>DeLorenzo</keyname><forenames>L. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>K. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-high Q Acoustic Resonance in Superfluid 4He</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the measurement of the acoustic quality factor of a gram-scale,
kilo-hertz frequency superfluid resonator, detected through the parametric
coupling to a superconducting niobium microwave cavity. For temperature between
400mK and 50mK, we observe a $T^{-4}$ temperature dependence of the quality
factor, consistent with a 3-phonon dissipation mechanism. We observe Q factors
up to $1.4\cdot10^8$, consistent with the dissipation due to dilute $^3$He
impurities, and expect that significant further improvements are possible.
These experiments are relevant to exploring quantum behavior and decoherence of
massive macroscopic objects, the laboratory detection of continuous wave
gravitational waves from pulsars, and the probing of possible limits to
physical length scales.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07905</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Deming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling of a Single Multimode Fiber Imaging System</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed theoretical analysis on image transmission via a single
multimode fiber (MMF). A single MMF imaging model is developed to study the
light wave propagation from the light source to the camera, by using free-space
Fourier optics theory and mode-coupling theory. A mathematical expression is
obtained for the complete single MMF imaging system, which is further validated
by image-transmission simulations. Our model is believed to be the first
theoretical model to describe the complete MMF imaging system based on the
transmission of individual modes. Therefore, this model is robust and capable
of analyzing MMF image transmission under specific mode-coupling conditions. We
use our model to study bending-induced image blur in single-MMF image
transmission, and the result has found a good agreement with that of existing
experimental studies. These should provide important insights into future MMF
imaging system developments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07913</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07913</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>Ruipu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Weiwei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Lixin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author></authors><title>n-Lie bialgebras</title><categories>math.RA math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The $n$-Lie bialgebras are studied. In Section 2, the $n$-Lie coalgebra with
rank $r$ is defined, and the structure of it is discussed. In Section 3, the
$n$-Lie bialgebra is introduced. A triple $(L, \mu, \Delta)$ is an $n$-Lie
bialgebra if and only if $\Delta$ is a conformal $1$-cocycle on the $n$-Lie
algebra $L$ associated to $L$-modules $(L^{\otimes n}, \rho_s^{\mu})$, $1\leq
s\leq n$, and the structure of $n$-Lie bialgebras is investigated by the
structural constants. In Section 4, two-dimensional extension of finite
dimensional $n$-Lie bialgebras are studied. For an $m$ dimensional $n$-Lie
bialgebra $(L, \mu, \Delta)$, and an $ad_{\mu}$-invariant symmetric bilinear
form on $L$, the $m+2$ dimensional $(n+1)$-Lie bialgebra is constructed. In the
last section, the bialgebra structure on the finite dimensional simple $n$-Lie
algebra $A_n$ is discussed. It is proved that only bialgebra structures on the
simple $n$-Lie algebra $A_n$ are rank zero, and rank two.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07922</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07922</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>Lauren Melissa Flor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coziol</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schr&#xf6;eder</keyname><forenames>Klauss-Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caretta</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;sar A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jack</keyname><forenames>Dennis</forenames></author></authors><title>Relation between Brown Dwarfs and Exoplanets</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Poster #149 from proceeding of The 19th Cambridge Workshop on Cool
  Stars, Stellar Systems, and the Sun; 06-10 June 2016, Uppsala, Sweden</comments><doi>10.5281/zenodo.58717</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most debated subjects in Astronomy since the discovery of
exoplanets is how can we distinguish the most massive of such objects from
very-low mass stars like Brown Dwarfs (BDs)? We have been looking for evidences
of a difference in physical characteristics that could be related to different
formation processes. Using a new diagnostic diagram that compares the baryonic
gravitational potential (BGP) with the distances from their host stars, we have
classified a sample of 355 well-studied exoplanets according to their possible
structures. We have then compared the exoplanets to a sample of 87 confirmed
BDs, identifying a range in BGP that could be common to both objects. By
analyzing the mass-radius relations (MRR) of the exoplanets and BDs in those
different BGP ranges, we were able to distinguish different characteristic
behaviors. By comparing with models in the literature, our results suggest that
BDs and massive exoplanets might have similar structures dominated by liquid
metallic hydrogen (LMH).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07932</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07932</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Safronova</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly Enhanced Effects of Lorentz-Symmetry Violation in Yb$^+$ and
  Highly Charged Ions</title><categories>hep-ph physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Lorentz-symmetry test with Ca$^+$ ions demonstrated the potential of using
quantum information inspired technology for tests of fundamental physics. A
systematic study of atomic-system sensitivities to Lorentz violation identified
the ytterbium ion as an ideal system with high sensitivity as well as excellent
experimental controllability. A test of Lorentz-violating physics in the
electron-photon sector with Yb$^+$ ions has the potential to reach levels of
10$^{-23}$, five orders of magnitude more sensitive than the current best
bounds. Similar sensitivities may be also reached with highly charged ions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07936</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07936</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Li-Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Xiu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Rong-Can</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Hong-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Adiabatic Generation of N-quNit Singlet States with Cavity QED</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages,5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A theoretical scheme is presented for the adiabatic generation of N-quNit
singlet states with $N\geqslant3$, which may be more feasible than previous
ones in a cavity. In this proposal, the system may be robust both parameter
fluctuations and dissipation along a dark state. In addition, quantum
information is only stored in atomic ground states and there is no energy
exchanged between atoms and photons in a cavity so as to reduce the influence
of atomic spontaneous emission and cavity decays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07937</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07937</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Yong-Pan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Tie-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Cong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mi</keyname><forenames>Si-Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Daquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Chuan</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective mass sensing using optomechanically induced transparency in
  microresonator system</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Detecting and weighing the individual nanoparticles is an important approach
to study the behavior and properties of single particles. Here we illustrate an
effective mass sensing scheme using optomechanical resonator system. Based on
the optomechanically induced transparency phenomenon, a Stokes field reference
approach is used to sense the mass of the particle on the microresonator. The
field intensity of the transmission field will be changed by the effect of the
particle which avoids the limits of decay induced spectral width in the
resonance shift detection. Exploiting the perturbation method, we theoretically
evaluated the dynamical behavior of the system, and achieved the femtogram
level mass sensing without the need for high cavity Q-value, and strong
coupling strength in the optomechanically system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07940</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07940</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Long</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Yongxiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Zhiming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Yulu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Quan</forenames></author></authors><title>Intermittency measurement in two dimensional bacterial turbulence</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 7 figures. This paper is published on Physical Review E,
  93, 062226, 2016</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E, 93, 062226, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.062226</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, an experimental velocity database of a bacterial collective
motion , e.g., \textit{B. subtilis}, in turbulent phase with volume filling
fraction $84\%$ provided by Professor Goldstein at the Cambridge University UK,
was analyzed to emphasize the scaling behavior of this active turbulence
system. This was accomplished by performing a Hilbert-based methodology
analysis to retrieve the scaling property without the $\beta-$limitation. A
dual-power-law behavior separated by the viscosity scale $\ell_{\nu}$ was
observed for the $q$th-order Hilbert moment $\mathcal{L}_q(k)$. This
dual-power-law belongs to an inverse-cascade since the scaling range is above
the injection scale $R$, e.g., the bacterial body length. The measured scaling
exponents $\zeta(q)$ of both the small-scale \red{(resp. $k&gt;k_{\nu}$) and
large-scale (resp. $k&lt;k_{\nu}$)} motions are convex, showing the
multifractality. A lognormal formula was put forward to characterize the
multifractal intensity. The measured intermittency parameters are $\mu_S=0.26$
and $\mu_L=0.17$ respectively for the small- and large-scale motions. It
implies that the former cascade is more intermittent than the latter one, which
is also confirmed by the corresponding singularity spectrum $f(\alpha)$ vs
$\alpha$. Comparison with the conventional two-dimensional Ekman-Navier-Stokes
equation, a continuum model indicates that the origin of the multifractality
could be a result of some additional nonlinear interaction terms, which
deservers a more careful investigation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07943</id><created>2016-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knezevic</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonequilibrium phonon effects in midinfrared quantum cascade lasers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Applied Physics 116, 123105 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4896400</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effects of nonequilibrium phonon dynamics on the operation
of a GaAs-based midinfrared quantum cascade laser over a range of temperatures
(77--300 K) via a coupled ensemble Monte Carlo simulation of electron and
optical-phonon systems. Nonequilibrium phonon effects are shown to be important
below 200 K. At low temperatures, nonequilibrium phonons enhance injection
selectivity and efficiency by drastically increasing the rate of interstage
electron scattering from the lowest injector state to the next-stage upper
lasing level via optical-phonon absorption. As a result, the current density
and modal gain at a given field are higher and the threshold current density
lower and considerably closer to experiment than results obtained with thermal
phonons. By amplifying phonon absorption, nonequilibrium phonons also hinder
electron energy relaxation and lead to elevated electronic temperatures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07954</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07954</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sajedian</keyname><forenames>Iman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Inki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zakery</keyname><forenames>Abdolnasser</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rho</keyname><forenames>Junsuk</forenames></author></authors><title>A highly efficient method for second and third harmonic generation from
  magnetic metamaterials</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Second and third harmonic signals have been usually generated by using
nonlinear crystals, but that method suffers from the low efficiency in small
thicknesses. Metamaterials can be used to generate harmonic signals in small
thicknesses. Here, we introduce a new method for amplifying second and third
harmonic generation from magnetic metamaterials. We show that by using a
grating structure under the metamaterial, the grating and the metamaterial form
a resonator, and amplify the resonant behavior of the metamaterial. Therefore,
we can generate second and third harmonic signals with high efficiency from
this metamaterial-based nonlinear media.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07972</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07972</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>Andr&#xe9;s</forenames></author><author><keyname>Diaz</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>John</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tarazona</keyname><forenames>Carlos G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Phenomenological aspects from vacuum stability and metastability in
  models with soft breaking of a \texorpdfstring{$U\left( 1\right)$}{lg} global
  symmetry</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 37 Figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the vacuum behavior of an extended Higgs sector with two doublets in
a scenario with a softly broken \texorpdfstring{$U(1)$}{lg} global symmetry.
The soft-violation term is introduced to avoid massless-axion particles arising
when the global symmetry becomes spontaneously broken. This model has
metastable states through the possible presence of multiple non-degenerate
minima, which is unwanted from the phenomenological point of view if the
metastable state is not long-lived enough. The analysis of this fact leads to
find possible exclusion limits over parameter space of quartic couplings.
Results improve the individual behavior of initial conditions for
renormalization group equations; also determining unstable zones for the
effective Higgs potential at one loop level. Besides vacuum stability analyses,
the influence of absence of charge violation minima is considered as a limiting
case excluding zones in the parameter space. Extremal cases for the model as
well as criticality phenomena are discussed with the aid of relation among
Higgs masses or splittings among them. From vacuum behavior and LHC results,
phenomenological aspects in the searching of charged and heavier Higgs bosons
are considered to evaluate the scalar alignment regimen of the two Higgs
doublet model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07973</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07973</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Ghigo</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames><affiliation>IJLRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiao-Fei</forenames><affiliation>IJLRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Armentano</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames><affiliation>IJLRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Lagr&#xe9;e</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Yves</forenames><affiliation>IJLRA</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Fullana</keyname><forenames>Jose-Maria</forenames><affiliation>IJLRA</affiliation></author></authors><title>Linear and nonlinear viscoelastic arterial wall models: application on
  animals</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.med-ph</categories><comments>in Journal of Biomechanical Engineering, American Society of
  Mechanical Engineers, 2016</comments><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work deals with the viscoelasticity of the arterial wall and its
influence on the pulse waves. We describe the viscoelasticity by a non-linear
Kelvin-Voigt model in which the coefficients are fitted using experimental time
series of pressure and radius measured on a sheep's arterial network. We
obtained a good agreement between the results of the nonlinear Kelvin-Voigt
model and the experimental measurements. We found that the viscoelastic
relaxation time-defined by the ratio between the viscoelastic coefficient and
the Young's modulus-is nearly constant throughout the network. Therefore, as it
is well known that smaller arteries are stiffer, the viscoelastic coefficient
rises when approaching the peripheral sites to compensate the rise of the
Young's modulus, resulting in a higher damping effect. We incorporated the
fitted viscoelastic coefficients in a nonlinear 1D fluid model to compute the
pulse waves in the network. The damping effect of viscoelasticity on the high
frequency waves is clear especially at the peripheral sites.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07977</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07977</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bizyaev</keyname><forenames>Ivan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamaev</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Hess-Appelrot system and its nonholonomic analogs</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper is concerned with the nonholonomic Suslov problem and its
generalization proposed by Chaplygin. The issue of the existence of an
invariant measure with singular density (having singularities at some points of
phase space) is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07982</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07982</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Bizyaev</keyname><forenames>Ivan A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borisov</keyname><forenames>Alexey V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mamaev</keyname><forenames>Ivan S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalizations of the Kovalevskaya case and quaternions</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper provides a detailed description of various reduction schemes in
rigid body dynamics. Analysis of one of such nontrivial reductions makes it
possible to order the cases already found and to obtain new generalizations of
the Kovalevskaya case to e(3). We note that the above reduction allows one to
obtain in a natural way some singular additive terms which were proposed
earlier by D.N. Goryachev.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07990</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07990</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>Christopher E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giustino</keyname><forenames>Feliciano</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified theory of electron-phonon renormalization and phonon-assisted
  optical absorption</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This is an author-created, un-copyedited version of an article
  published in J. Phys.: Condens. Matter. IOP Publishing Ltd is not responsible
  for any errors or omissions in this version of the manuscript or any version
  derived from it. The Version of Record is available online at
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0953-8984/26/36/365503</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 26, 365503 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/26/36/365503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theory of electronic excitation energies and optical absorption
spectra which incorporates energy-level renormalization and phonon-assisted
optical absorption within a unified framework. Using time-independent
perturbation theory we show how the standard approaches for studying vibronic
effects in molecules and those for addressing electron-phonon interactions in
solids correspond to slightly different choices for the non-interacting
Hamiltonian. Our present approach naturally leads to the Allen-Heine theory of
temperature-dependent energy levels, the Franck-Condon principle, the
Herzberg-Teller effect and to phonon-assisted optical absorption in indirect
band gap materials. In addition, our theory predicts sub-gap phonon-assisted
optical absorption in direct gap materials, as well as an exponential edge
which we tentatively assign to the Urbach tail. We also consider a
semiclassical approach to the calculation of optical absorption spectra which
simultaneously captures energy-level renormalization and phonon-assisted
transitions and is especially suited to first-principles electronic structure
calculations. We demonstrate this approach by calculating the phonon-assisted
optical absorption spectrum of bulk silicon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07992</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07992</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>Christopher E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giustino</keyname><forenames>Feliciano</forenames></author></authors><title>Structure of a Water Monolayer on the Anatase TiO$_2$(101) Surface</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 9 figures. Published in Phys. Rev. Appl. by the American
  Physical Society (2014)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Applied 2, 014001 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevApplied.2.014001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Titanium dioxide (TiO$_2$) plays a central role in the study of artificial
photosynthesis, owing to its ability to perform photocatalytic water splitting.
Despite over four decades of intense research efforts in this area, there is
still some debate over the nature of the first water monolayer on the
technologically-relevant anatase TiO$_2$ (101) surface. In this work we use
first-principles calculations to reverse-engineer the experimental
high-resolution X-ray photoelectron spectra measured for this surface in [Walle
et al., J. Phys. Chem. C 115, 9545 (2011)], and find evidence supporting the
existence of a mix of dissociated and molecular water in the first monolayer.
Using both semilocal and hybrid functional calculations we revise the current
understanding of the adsorption energetics by showing that the energetic cost
of water dissociation is reduced via the formation of a hydrogen-bonded
hydroxyl-water complex. We also show that such a complex can provide an
explanation of an unusual superstructure observed in high-resolution scanning
tunneling microscopy experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07993</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Patrick</keyname><forenames>Christopher E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giustino</keyname><forenames>Feliciano</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantitative analysis of valence photoemission spectra and quasiparticle
  excitations at chromophore-semiconductor interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 figures. Article published by in Phys. Rev. Lett. by the American
  Physical Society (2012)</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 109, 116801 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.109.116801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigating quasiparticle excitations of molecules on surfaces through
photoemission spectroscopy forms a major part of nanotechnology research.
Resolving spectral features at these interfaces requires a comprehensive theory
of electron removal and addition processes in molecules and solids which
captures the complex interplay of image charges, thermal effects and
configurational disorder. We here develop such a theory and calculate the
quasiparticle energy-level alignment and the valence photoemission spectrum for
the prototype biomimetic solar cell interface between anatase TiO2 and the N3
chromophore. By directly matching our calculated photoemission spectrum to
experimental data we clarify the atomistic origin of the chromophore peak at
low binding energy. This case study sets a new standard in the interpretation
of photoemission spectroscopy at complex chromophore/semiconductor interfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.07998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.07998</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mol</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benjamin</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briggs</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author></authors><title>Interference-based molecular transistors</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Molecular transistors have the potential for switching with lower gate
voltages than conventional field-effect transistors. We have calculated the
performance of a single-molecule device in which there is interference between
electron transport through the highest occupied molecular orbital and the
lowest unoccupied molecular orbital of a single molecule. Quantum interference
results in a subthreshold slope that is independent of temperature. For
realistic parameters the change in gate potential required for a change in
source-drain current of two decades is 20 mV, which is a factor of six smaller
than the theoretical limit for a metal-oxide-semiconductor field-effect
transistor.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08002</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08002</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Qi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Xiongfeng</forenames></author></authors><title>Efficient measurement-device-independent detection of multipartite
  entanglement structure</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 1 figure, comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012343 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012343</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Witnessing entanglement is crucial in quantum information processing. With
properly preparing ancillary states, it has been shown previously that genuine
entanglement can be witnessed without trusting measurement devices. In this
work, we generalize the scenario and show that generic multipartite
entanglement structures, including entanglement of subsystems and entanglement
depth, can be witnessed via measurement-device-independent means. As the
original measurement-device-independent entanglement witness scheme exploits
only one out of four Bell measurement outcomes for each party, a direct
generalization to multipartite quantum states will inevitably cause
inefficiency in entanglement detection after taking account of statistical
fluctuations. To resolve this problem, we also present a way to utilize all the
measurement outcomes. The scheme is efficient for multipartite entanglement
detection and can be realized with state-of-the-art technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08004</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08004</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Abe</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andreopoulos</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Antonova</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ariga</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Autiero</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ban</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barbi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barker</keyname><forenames>G. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barr</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartet-Friburg</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Batkiewicz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berardi</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berkman</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhadra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bienstock</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blondel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bolognesi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordoni</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brailsford</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bravar</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bronner</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Avanzini</keyname><forenames>M. Buizza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calland</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cartwright</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Castillo</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Catanesi</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cervera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cherdack</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chikuma</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christodoulou</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clifton</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coleman</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Collazuol</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coplowe</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cremonesi</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dabrowska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Rosa</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dealtry</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denner</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennis</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Densham</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dewhurst</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Lodovico</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Luise</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolan</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drapier</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duffy</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumarchez</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dziewiecki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Emery-Schrenk</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ereditato</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feusels</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Finch</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorentini</keyname><forenames>G. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friend</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fujii</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fukuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furmanski</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galymov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garcia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giganti</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gizzarelli</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grant</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadley</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haegel</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haigh</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hansen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hartz</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hasegawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hastings</keyname><forenames>N. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayashino</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hayato</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helmer</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hierholzer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillairet</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiraki</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hiramoto</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hirota</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hogan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holeczek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosomi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ichikawa</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Imber</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Insler</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Intonti</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwai</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iwamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Izmaylov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jamieson</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johnson</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jo</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonsson</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jung</keyname><forenames>C. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabirnezhad</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaboth</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kajita</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kakuno</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kameda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karlen</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karpikov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katori</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kearns</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khabibullin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khotjantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>King</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kisiel</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knight</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knox</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kobayashi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koch</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koga</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Konaka</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kondo</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopylov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kormos</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Korzenev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koshio</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kropp</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudenko</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurjata</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kutter</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lagoda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamont</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamoureux</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larkin</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lasorak</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laveder</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lawe</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lindner</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liptak</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Litchfield</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Longhin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lopez</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ludovici</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magaletti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mahn</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malek</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manly</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marino</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martins</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martynenko</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maruyama</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matveev</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mavrokoridis</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>W. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzucato</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCarthy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCauley</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McFarland</keyname><forenames>K. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McGrew</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mefodiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metelko</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mezzetto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mijakowski</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Minamino</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mineev</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mine</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Missert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miura</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriyama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Th. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myslik</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakadaira</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakahata</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakamura</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakanishi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakaya</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayoshi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nantais</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nielsen</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nirkko</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishikawa</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Novella</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nowak</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>O'Keeffe</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ohta</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okumura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Okusawa</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oryszczak</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oser</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovsyannikova</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owen</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyama</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palladino</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palomino</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paolone</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>N. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavin</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Payne</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkin</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petrov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickard</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pickering</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guerra</keyname><forenames>E. S. Pinzon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pistillo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Posiadala-Zezula</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poutissou</keyname><forenames>J. -M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poutissou</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Przewlocki</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Quilain</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radermacher</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radicioni</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ratoff</keyname><forenames>P. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ravonel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rayner</keyname><forenames>M. A. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redij</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reinherz-Aronis</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Riccio</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rojas</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rondio</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roth</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubbia</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rychter</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sacco</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sakashita</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe1;nchez</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scantamburlo</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholberg</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwehr</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Seiya</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiguchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sekiya</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sgalaberna</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shah</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaikhiev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaker</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shaw</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shiozawa</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shirahige</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Short</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smy</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobczyk</keyname><forenames>J. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sobel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Southwell</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinmann</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stewart</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stowell</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suvorov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>S. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tacik</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tada</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeda</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takeuchi</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>H. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tanaka</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terhorst</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terri</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thakore</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thompson</keyname><forenames>L. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobayama</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toki</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomura</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Touramanis</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsukamoto</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tzanov</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uchida</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vagins</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallari</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasseur</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wachala</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walter</keyname><forenames>C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wark</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warzycha</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wascko</keyname><forenames>M. O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendell</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkes</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilking</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilkinson</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>J. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamada</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yamamoto</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yanagisawa</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yano</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yershov</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yokoyama</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zalewska</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zalipska</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zambelli</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zaremba</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziembicki</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zimmerman</keyname><forenames>E. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zito</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x17b;muda</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Sensitivity of the T2K accelerator-based neutrino experiment with an
  Extended run to $20\times10^{21}$ POT</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>18 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent measurements at the T2K experiment indicate that CP violation in
neutrino mixing may be observed in the future by long-baseline neutrino
oscillation experiments. We explore the physics program of an extension to the
currently approved T2K running of $7.8\times 10^{21}$ protons-on-target to
$20\times 10^{21}$ protons-on-target,aiming at initial observation of CP
violation with 3$\,\sigma$ or higher significance for the case of maximum CP
violation. With accelerator and beam line upgrades, as well as analysis
improvements, this program would occur before the next generation of
long-baseline neutrino oscillation experiments that are expected to start
operation in 2026.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08010</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08010</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Chay</keyname><forenames>Junegone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ha</keyname><forenames>Taewook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Inchol</forenames></author></authors><title>Infrared finiteness in the factorization of the dijet cross section in
  hadron-hadron collision near threshold</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>32 pages, 7 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The factorization theorem for the dijet cross section is considered in
hadron-hadron collisions near threshold with a cone-type jet algorithm. We
focus on the infrared finiteness of the factorized parts by carefully
distinguishing the ultraviolet and infrared divergences in dimensional
regularization. The soft function, subject to a jet algorithm, shows a
complicated divergence structure. It is shown that the soft function becomes
infrared finite only after the emission in the beam directions is included.
Among many partonic processes, we take $q\overline{q} \rightarrow gg$ as a
specific example to consider the dijet cross section, and verify explicitly
that each factorized part is infrared finite. We also compute the anomalous
dimensions of the factorized components to next-to-leading logarithmic
accuracy. The hard and the soft functions have nontrivial color structure,
while the jet and the collinear distribution functions are diagonal in color
space. The dependence of the soft anomalous dimension on the jet algorithm is
color diagonal and is cancelled by that of the jet functions. The sum of the
remaining anomalous dimensions also cancels, thus the dijet cross section is
independent of the renormalization scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08015</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Woodhouse</keyname><forenames>Francis G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forrow</keyname><forenames>Aden</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fawcett</keyname><forenames>Joanna B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dunkel</keyname><forenames>J&#xf6;rn</forenames></author></authors><title>Stochastic cycle selection in active flow networks</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures; SI text available at article on pnas.org</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. U.S.A. 113 (29), 8200-8205 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1603351113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Active biological flow networks pervade nature and span a wide range of
scales, from arterial blood vessels and bronchial mucus transport in humans to
bacterial flow through porous media or plasmodial shuttle streaming in slime
molds. Despite their ubiquity, little is known about the self-organization
principles that govern flow statistics in such non-equilibrium networks. Here
we connect concepts from lattice field theory, graph theory, and transition
rate theory to understand how topology controls dynamics in a generic model for
actively driven flow on a network. Our combined theoretical and numerical
analysis identifies symmetry-based rules that make it possible to classify and
predict the selection statistics of complex flow cycles from the network
topology. The conceptual framework developed here is applicable to a broad
class of non-biological far-from-equilibrium networks, including actively
controlled information flows, and establishes a new correspondence between
active flow networks and generalized ice-type models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08029</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08029</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Dauparas</keyname><forenames>Justas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lauga</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author></authors><title>Flagellar flows around bacterial swarms</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Flagellated bacteria on nutrient-rich substrates can differentiate into a
swarming state and move in dense swarms across surfaces. A recent experiment
measured the flow in the fluid around an Escherichia coli swarm (Wu, Hosu and
Berg, 2011 Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 108 4147). A systematic chiral flow was
observed in the clockwise direction (when viewed from above) ahead of the swarm
with flow speeds of about $10~\mu$m/s, about 3 times greater than the radial
velocity at the edge of the swarm. The working hypothesis is that this flow is
due to the action of cells stalled at the edge of a colony that extend their
flagellar filaments outwards, moving fluid over the virgin agar. In this work
we quantitatively test his hypothesis. We first build an analytical model of
the flow induced by a single flagellum in a thin film and then use the model,
and its extension to multiple flagella, to compare with experimental
measurements. The results we obtain are in agreement with the flagellar
hypothesis. The model provides further quantitative insight into the flagella
orientations and their spatial distributions as well as the tangential speed
profile. In particular, the model suggests that flagella are on average
pointing radially out of the swarm and are not wrapped tangentially.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08034</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08034</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakrabarti</keyname><forenames>Soumya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Narayan</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational collapse in f(R) gravity for a spherically symmetric
  spacetime admitting a homothetic Killing vector</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>11 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2016) 131: 144</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2016-16144-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The gravitational collapse of a spherical distribution, in a class of f(R)
theories of gravity, where f(R) is power function of R, is discussed. The
spacetime is assumed to admit a homothetic Killing vector. In the collapsing
modes, some of the situations indeed hit a singularity, but they are all
covered with an apparent horizon. Some peculiar cases are observed where the
collapsing body settles to a constant radius at a given value of the radial
coordinate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08043</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Haowei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Bo-Qiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Light speed variation from gamma ray burst GRB 160509A</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>5 latex pages, 2 figures, final version for publication</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B 760 (2016) 602-604</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is postulated in Einstein's relativity that the speed of light in vacuum
is a constant for all observers. However, the effect of quantum gravity could
bring an energy dependence of light speed. Even a tiny speed variation, when
amplified by the cosmological distance, may be revealed by the observed time
lags between photons with different energies from astrophysical sources. From
the newly detected long gamma ray burst GRB~160509A, we find evidence to
support the prediction for a linear form modification of light speed in
cosmological space.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08056</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08056</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Brun</keyname><forenames>S&#xf8;ren J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pereira</keyname><forenames>Vitor M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pedersen</keyname><forenames>Thomas G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Boron and nitrogen doping in graphene antidot lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 245420 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.245420</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bottom-up fabrication of graphene antidot lattices (GALs) has previously
yielded atomically precise structures with sub-nanometer periodicity. Focusing
on this type of experimentally realized GAL, we perform density functional
theory calculations on the pristine structure as well as GALs with edge carbon
atoms substituted with boron or nitrogen. We show that p- and n-type doping
levels emerge with activation energies that depend on the level of
hydrogenation at the impurity. Furthermore, a tight-binding parameterization
together with a Green's function method are used to describe more dilute
doping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08062</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08062</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Rolls</keyname><forenames>Edward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Togashi</keyname><forenames>Yuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Erban</keyname><forenames>Radek</forenames></author></authors><title>Varying the resolution of the Rouse model on temporal and spatial
  scales: application to multiscale modelling of DNA dynamics</title><categories>physics.bio-ph physics.comp-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>Submitted to Multiscale Modeling and Simulation</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A multi-resolution bead-spring model for polymer dynamics is developed as a
generalization of the Rouse model. A polymer chain is described using beads of
variable sizes connected by springs with variable spring constants. A numerical
scheme which can use different timesteps to advance the positions of different
beads is presented and analyzed. The position of a particular bead is only
updated at integer multiples of the timesteps associated with its connecting
springs. This approach extends the Rouse model to a multiscale model on both
spatial and temporal scales, allowing simulations of localized regions of a
polymer chain with high spatial and temporal resolution, while using a coarser
modelling approach to describe the rest of the polymer chain. A method for
changing the model resolution on-the-fly is developed using the
Metropolis-Hastings algorithm. It is shown that this approach maintains key
statistics of the end-to-end distance and diffusion of the polymer filament and
makes computational savings when applied to a model for the binding of a
protein to the DNA filament.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08063</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08063</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discontinuous transition in an equilibrium percolation model with
  suppression</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Discontinuous transition is observed in the equilibrium cluster properties of
a percolation model with suppressed cluster growth as the growth parameter g0
is tuned to the critical threshold at sufficiently low initial seed
concentration rho in contrast to the previously reported results on non-
equilibrium growth models. In the present model, the growth process follows all
the criteria of the original percolation model except continuously updated
occupation probability of the lattice sites that suppresses the growth of a
cluster according to its size. As rho varied from higher values to smaller
values, a line of continuous transition points encounters a coexistence region
of spanning and non- spanning large clusters. At sufficiently small values of
rho (less equal 0.05), the growth parameter g0 exceeds the usual percolation
threshold and generates compact spanning clusters leading to discontinuous
transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08088</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Karsai</keyname><forenames>Szilvia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barnaf&#xf6;ldi</keyname><forenames>Gergely G&#xe1;bor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forg&#xe1;cs-Dajka</keyname><forenames>Emese</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xf3;sfay</keyname><forenames>P&#xe9;ter</forenames></author></authors><title>Correspondence of Many-flavor Limit and Kaluza-Klein Degrees of Freedom
  in the Description of Compact Stars</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 color figures, 1 table, Contribution to the CPOD 2016,
  Wroclaw, Poland</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the correspondence between non-interacting multi-hadron fermion
star equation of state in the many-flavor limit and the degrees of freedom of a
Kaluza\,--\,Klein compact star. Many flavors can be interpreted in this
framework as one extra compacti\-fied spatial dimension with various,
more-and-more massive hadron state excitations. The effect of increasing the
degrees of freedom was investigated on the equation of state and in connection
with the mass-radius relation, $M(R)$. The maximum mass of the star,
$M_{\mathrm{max}}$ were also calculated as a function of the maximum number of
excited states, $n$ and the size of the compactified extra dimension,
$R_{\mathrm{c}}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08108</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08108</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Kaptein</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Emden</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iannuzzi</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Investigation of the concept of beauty via a lock-in feedback experiment</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lock-in feedback circuits are routinely used in physics laboratories all
around the world to extract small signals out of a noisy environment. In a
recent paper (M. Kaptein, R. van Emden, and D. Iannuzzi, paper under review),
we have shown that one can adapt the algorithm exploited in those circuits to
gain insight in behavioral economics. In this paper, we extend this concept to
a very subjective socio-philosophical concept: the concept of beauty. We run an
experiment on 7414 volunteers, asking them to express their opinion on the
physical features of an avatar. Each participant was prompted with an image
whose features were adjusted sequentially via a lock-in feedback algorithm
driven by the opinion expressed by the previous participants. Our results show
that the method allows one to identify the most attractive features of the
avatar.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08111</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08111</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Scaramuzza</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasson</keyname><forenames>Jay D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Laser Gyroscopes, Gravity, and the SME</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this contribution to the CPT'16 proceedings, we illustrate the potential
use of ring-laser systems in searching for Lorentz violation in the framework
of the Standard-Model Extension. We present expressions for the
Lorentz-violating contribution to the ring-laser signal for a sample system and
make sensitivity estimates for the GINGER project.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08114</id><created>2016-07-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Sivaram</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Classical space-time as Rydberg states of underlying quantum geometries</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>7 pages, written for the Gravity Foundation 2016 Essays on
  Gravitation</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Classical macroscopic space-time is pictured in terms of Rydberg states of an
underlying discritzed `atomic' quantum geometry at Planck scales. While quantum
geometry on such scales involves several very short lived transitions changing
curvature and topologies, the Rydberg states have very long lifetimes, going as
a high power of the quantum number n. This means space-time on macroscopic
scales are almost infinitely stable. The large degeneracy in the Rydberg
levels, with high n, can also account for a large black hole entropy, as well
as long lifetime of massive black holes to quantum decays. We have a possible
promising paradigm to link quantum geometry at Planck scales, to classical
space-time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08124</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08124</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Carinci</keyname><forenames>Gioia</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Masi</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giardin&#xe0;</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Presutti</keyname><forenames>Errico</forenames></author></authors><title>Free boundary problems in PDEs and particle systems</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><comments>101 pages, 1 figure in SpringerBriefs in Mathematical Physics (2016),
  http://www.springer.com/jp/book/9783319333694</comments><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-33370-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this volume a theory for models of transport in the presence of a free
boundary is developed. Macroscopic laws of transport are described by PDEs.
When the system is open, there are several mechanisms to couple the system with
the external forces. Here a class of systems where the interaction with the
exterior takes place in correspondence of a free boundary is considered. Both
continuous and discrete models sharing the same structure are analyzed. In Part
I a free boundary problem related to the Stefan Problem is worked out in all
details. For this model a new notion of relaxed solution is proposed for which
global existence and uniqueness is proven. It is also shown that this is the
hydrodynamic limit of the empirical mass density of the associated particle
system. In Part II several other models are discussed. The expectation is that
the results proved for the basic model extend to these other cases. All the
models discussed in this volume have an interest in problems arising in several
research fields such as heat conduction, queuing theory, propagation of fire,
interface dynamics, population dynamics, evolution of biological systems with
selection mechanisms.In general researchers interested in the relations between
PDEs and stochastic processes can find in this volume an extension of this
correspondence to modern mathematical physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08151</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08151</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Myrzakul</keyname><forenames>Akbota</forenames></author><author><keyname>Myrzakulov</keyname><forenames>Ratbay</forenames></author></authors><title>Darboux transformations and exact soliton solutions of integrable
  coupled spin systems related with the Manakov system</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>9 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a Darboux transformation of a general $su(3)$-valued spin system
called the $\Gamma$-spin system. Using this Darboux transformation we derive a
recursive formula for the soliton solutions of this spin system. Then using
these results we present explicit expressions for the 1-soliton solution of the
coupled $su(2)$-valued spin systems, namely, of the coupled M-LIII equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08155</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08155</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Alves</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bastos</keyname><forenames>Catarina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertolami</keyname><forenames>Orfeu</forenames></author></authors><title>Entangled States and the Gravitational Quantum Well</title><categories>gr-qc quant-ph</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 table, 6 figues</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the continuous variable entanglement of a system of two particles
under the influence of Earth's gravitational field. We determine a phase-space
description of this bipartite system by calculating its Wigner function and
verify its entanglement by applying a generalization of the PPT criterion for
non-Gaussian states. We also examine the influence of gravity on an idealized
entanglement protocol to be shared between stations at different potentials
based on the correlation of states of the gravitational quantum well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08162</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Cook</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ragozzine</keyname><forenames>Darin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Granvik</keyname><forenames>Mikael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stephens</keyname><forenames>Denise C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Realistic Detectability of Close Interstellar Comets</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>Published in Astrophysical Journal, 18 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 825, 1 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/1/51</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the planet formation process, billions of comets are created and
ejected into interstellar space. The detection and characterization of such
interstellar comets (also known as extra-solar planetesimals or extra-solar
comets) would give us in situ information about the efficiency and properties
of planet formation throughout the galaxy. However, no interstellar comets have
ever been detected, despite the fact that their hyperbolic orbits would make
them readily identifiable as unrelated to the solar system. Moro-Mart\'in et
al. 2009 have made a detailed and reasonable estimate of the properties of the
interstellar comet population. We extend their estimates of detectability with
a numerical model that allows us to consider &quot;close&quot; interstellar comets, e.g.,
those that come within the orbit of Jupiter. We include several constraints on
a &quot;detectable&quot; object that allow for realistic estimates of the frequency of
detections expected from the Large Synoptic Survey Telescope (LSST) and other
surveys. The influence of several of the assumed model parameters on the
frequency of detections is explored in detail. Based on the expectation from
Moro-Mart\'in et al. 2009, we expect that LSST will detect 0.001-10
interstellar comets during its nominal 10-year lifetime, with most of the
uncertainty from the unknown number density of small (nuclei of $\sim$0.1-1 km)
interstellar comets. Using simulated LSST-like astrometric data, we study the
problem of orbit determination for these bodies, finding that LSST could
identify their orbits as hyperbolic and determine an ephemeris sufficiently
accurate for follow-up in about 4-7 days. We give the hyperbolic orbital
parameters of the most detectable interstellar comets. Taking the results into
consideration, we give recommendations to future searches for interstellar
comets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08168</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08168</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Dupuis</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fehr</keyname><forenames>Serge</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lamontagne</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvail</keyname><forenames>Louis</forenames></author></authors><title>Adaptive Versus Non-Adaptive Strategies in the Quantum Setting with
  Applications</title><categories>quant-ph cs.CR</categories><comments>28 pages, 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove a general relation between adaptive and non-adaptive strategies in
the quantum setting, i.e., between strategies where the adversary can or cannot
adaptively base its action on some auxiliary quantum side information. Our
relation holds in a very general setting, and is applicable as long as we can
control the bit-size of the side information, or, more generally, its
&quot;information content&quot;. Since adaptivity is notoriously difficult to handle in
the analysis of (quantum) cryptographic protocols, this gives us a very
powerful tool: as long as we have enough control over the side information, it
is sufficient to restrict ourselves to non-adaptive attacks.
  We demonstrate the usefulness of this methodology with two examples. The
first is a quantum bit commitment scheme based on 1-bit cut-and-choose. Since
bit commitment implies oblivious transfer (in the quantum setting), and
oblivious transfer is universal for two-party computation, this implies the
universality of 1-bit cut-and-choose, and thus solves the main open problem of
[FKSZZ13]. The second example is a quantum bit commitment scheme proposed in
1993 by Brassard et al. It was originally suggested as an unconditionally
secure scheme, back when this was thought to be possible. We partly restore the
scheme by proving it secure in (a variant of) the bounded quantum storage
model.
  In both examples, the fact that the adversary holds quantum side information
obstructs a direct analysis of the scheme, and we circumvent it by analyzing a
non-adaptive version, which can be done by means of known techniques, and
applying our main result.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08171</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Tsung-Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>Wen-Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Model of Dual Superconductor for Quark Confinement</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures</comments><report-no>CYCU-HEP-16-07</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that a hairy black hole solution can provide a holographically dual
description of quark confinement. There exists a one-parameter sensible metric
which receives the backreaction of matter contents in the holographic action,
where the scalar and gauge field are responsible for the condensation of
chromomagnetic monopoles. This model features a preconfining phase triggered by
second-order monopole condensation and a first-order confinement/deconfinement
phase transition. To confirm the confinement, the quark-antiquark potential is
calculated by probing a QCD string in both phases. At last, contribution from
Kaluza-Klein monopoles in the confining phase is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08177</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilhelm</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aqeel</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Palstra</keyname><forenames>T. T. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lefering</keyname><forenames>A. J. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Br&#xfc;ck</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pappas</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic relaxation phenomena in Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$ and phase diagram</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 12 figures, accepted for publication in Physical Review B
  (2016)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an investigation of the magnetic field-temperature phase diagram
of Cu$_2$OSeO$_3$ based on DC magnetisation and AC susceptibility measurements
covering a broad frequency range of four orders of magnitude, from very low
frequencies reaching 0.1 Hz up to 1 kHz. The experiments were performed in the
vicinity of $T_C=58.2$ K and around the skyrmion lattice A-phase. At the
borders between the different phases the characteristic relaxation times reach
several milliseconds and the relaxation is non-exponential. Consequently the
borders between the different phases depend on the specific criteria and
frequency used and an unambiguous determination is not possible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08180</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08180</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Fazio</keyname><forenames>Gianluca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferrighi</keyname><forenames>Lara</forenames></author><author><keyname>Di Valentin</keyname><forenames>Cristiana</forenames></author></authors><title>Boron-Doped Graphene As Active Electrocatalyst For Oxygen Reduction
  Reaction At A Fuel-Cell Cathode</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Catalysis 2014, 318, 203-210</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcat.2014.07.024</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Boron-doped graphene was reported to be the best non-metal doped graphene
electrocatalyst for the oxygen reduction reaction (ORR) working at an onset
potential of 0.035 V [JACS 136 (2014) 4394]. In the present DFT study,
intermediates and transition structures along the possible reaction pathways
are determined. Both Langmuir-Hinschelwood and Eley-Rideal mechanisms are
discussed. Molecular oxygen binds the positively charged B atom and forms an
open shell end-on dioxygen intermediate. The associative path is favoured with
respect to the dissociative one. The free energy diagrams along the
four-reduction steps are investigated with the methodology by N{\o}rskov and
co. [JPC B 108 (2004) 17886] in both acidic and alkaline conditions. The pH
effect on the stability of the intermediates of reduction is analyzed in terms
of the Pourbaix diagram. At pH = 14 we compute an onset potential value for the
electrochemical ORR of U = 0.05 V, which compares very well with the
experimental value in alkaline conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08203</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Yanyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonzalez</keyname><forenames>Marta C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective benefits in traffic during mega events via the use of
  information technologies</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Information technologies today can inform each of us about the best
alternatives for shortest paths from origins to destinations, but they do not
contain incentives or alternatives that manage the information efficiently to
get collective benefits. To obtain such benefits, we need to have not only good
estimates of how the traffic is formed but also to have target strategies to
reduce enough vehicles from the best possible roads in a feasible way. The
opportunity is that during large events the traffic inconveniences in large
cities are unusually high, yet temporary, and the entire population may be more
willing to adopt collective recommendations for social good. In this paper, we
integrate for the first time big data resources to quantify the impact of
events and propose target strategies for collective good at urban scale. In the
context of the Olympic Games in Rio de Janeiro, we first predict the expected
increase in traffic. To that end, we integrate data from: mobile phones,
Airbnb, Waze, and transit information, with game schedules and information of
venues. Next, we evaluate the impact of the Olympic Games to the travel of
commuters, and propose different route choice scenarios during the peak hours.
Moreover, we gather information on the trips that contribute the most to the
global congestion and that could be redirected from vehicles to transit.
Interestingly, we show that (i) following new route alternatives during the
event with individual shortest path can save more collective travel time than
keeping the routine routes, uncovering the positive value of information
technologies during events; (ii) with only a small proportion of people
selected from specific areas switching from driving to public transport, the
collective travel time can be reduced to a great extent. Results are presented
on-line for the evaluation of the public and policy makers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08205</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Tierney</keyname><forenames>Tim M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Clark</keyname><forenames>Christopher A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carmichael</keyname><forenames>David W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Is Bonferroni correction more sensitive than Random Field Theory for
  most fMRI studies?</title><categories>stat.AP physics.med-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random Field Theory has been used in the fMRI literature to address the
multiple comparisons problem. The method provides an analytical solution for
the computation of precise p-values when its assumptions are met. When its
assumptions are not met the thresholds generated by Random Field Theory can be
more conservative than Bonferroni corrections, which are arguably too stringent
for use in fMRI. As this has been well documented theoretically it is
surprising that a majority of current studies (~80%) would not meet the
assumptions of Random Field Theory and therefore would have reduced
sensitivity. Specifically most data is not smooth enough to meet the good
lattice assumption. Current studies smooth data on average by twice the voxel
size which is rarely sufficient to meet the good lattice assumption. The amount
of smoothing required for Random Field Theory to produce accurate p-values
increases with image resolution and decreases with degrees of freedom. There is
no rule of thumb that is valid for all study designs but for typical data (3mm
resolution, and greater than 20 subjects) residual smoothness with FWHM = 4
times voxel size should produce valid results. However, it should be stressed
that for higher spatial resolution and lower degrees of freedom the critical
smoothness required will increase sharply. This implies that researchers should
carefully choose appropriate smoothing kernels. This can be facilitated by the
simulations we provide that identify the critical smoothness at which the
application of RFT becomes appropriate. For some applications such as
presurgical mapping or, imaging of small structures, probing the
laminar/columnar structure of the cortex these smoothness requirements may be
too great to preserve spatial structure. As such, this study suggests
developments are needed in Random Field Theory to fully exploit the resolution
of modern neuroimaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.08224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-28</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.08224</id><created>2016-07-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Collins</keyname><forenames>Harry</forenames></author></authors><title>Interactional Expertise and Embodiment</title><categories>physics.hist-ph physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>31 pages, 2 Tables</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  In Part 1 of this paper, I introduce the idea of interactional expertise
while in Part 2, I focus on its implications for philosophical theories of the
importance of the body in forming our conceptual world. I argue that the way
philosophers have dealt with the body turns attention away from the most
important questions and that we cannot answer these questions without making
the notion of socialisation, and therefore interactional expertise, a central
concept in our thinking. This makes language at least as important, and often
more important than bodily practice in our understanding of the world. The
notion of a disembodied socialised agent leads in the direction of interesting
questions while the notion of an embodied but unsocialised human actor is
unimaginable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
