<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:42:04Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-25" from="2016-07-25" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1006.4541</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1006.4541</id><created>2010-06-23</created><updated>2010-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author></authors><title>Dilation of arbitrary symmetric quantum dynamical semigroups on
  $B(\clh)$</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><msc-class>81S25 (46L55 46L60 46N50 60J25)</msc-class><journal-ref>Infin. Dimens. Anal. Quantum Probab. Relat. Top. 15 (2012), no. 3</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove the existence of Hudson Parthasarathy dilation of a quantum
dynamical semigroup on $B(\clh),$ which is symmetric with respect to the
canonical normal trace on it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1101.1200</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1101.1200</id><created>2011-01-06</created><updated>2011-02-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Biswarup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goswami</keyname><forenames>Debashish</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Brownian Motion on noncommutative manifolds: construction,
  deformation and exit times</title><categories>math.OA math-ph math.FA math.MP</categories><report-no>QBM01</report-no><journal-ref>Comm. Math. Phys. 309 (2012) no. 1 193-228</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-011-1368-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We begin with a review and analytical construction of quantum Gaussian
process (and quantum Brownian motions) in the sense of [25],[10] and others,
and then formulate and study in details (with a number of interesting examples)
a definition of quantum Brownian motions on those noncommutative manifolds (a
la Connes) which are quantum homogeneous spaces of their quantum isometry
groups in the sense of [11]. We prove that bi-invariant quantum Brownian motion
can be 'deformed' in a suitable sense. Moreover, we propose a noncommutative
analogue of the well-known asymptotics of the exit time of classical Brownian
motion. We explicitly analyze such asymptotics for a specific example on
noncommutative two-torus A{\theta}, which seems to behave like a
one-dimensional manifold, perhaps reminiscent of the fact that A{\theta} is a
noncommutative model of the (locally one-dimensional) 'leaf-space' of the
Kronecker foliation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1204.2858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1204.2858</id><created>2012-04-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Souza</keyname><forenames>Reinaldo de Melo e</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kort-Kamp</keyname><forenames>W. J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sigaud</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farina</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Image method in the calculation of the van der Waals force between an
  atom and a conducting surface</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>This is a pedagogical and introductory paper on van der Waals forces
  between an atom and a conducting surface</comments><doi>10.1119/1.4798548</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Initially, we make a detailed historical survey of van der Waals forces,
collecting the main references on the subject. Then, we review a method
recently proposed by Eberlein and Zietal to compute the dispersion van der
Waals interaction between a neutral but polarizable atom and a perfectly
conducting surface of arbitrary shape. This method has the advantage of
relating the quantum problem to a corresponding classical one in electrostatics
so that all one needs is to compute an appropriate Green function. We show how
the image method of electrostatics can be conveniently used together with the
Eberlein and Zietal mehtod (when the problem admits an image solution). We then
illustrate this method in a couple of simple but important cases, including the
atom-sphere system. Particularly, in our last example, we present an original
result, namely, the van der Waals force between an atom and a boss hat made of
a grounded conducting material.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1306.2757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1306.2757</id><created>2013-06-12</created><updated>2014-11-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ian</keyname><forenames>Hou</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-lattice chains and multipartite entanglement in a cavity</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Europhys. Lett. 114, 50005 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Unlike atoms in a lattice, the spacings between neighboring qubits in a
superconducting quantum circuit are mesoscopic and non-uniform. The strength of
interaction between this quasi-lattice chain of qubits and a resonator mode in
circuit transmission lines is inhomogeneous and geometrically dependent on the
circuit layout. We propose a projection-deformation method to give analytically
the eigenstates of the quasi-particle excitation that arise in the
quasi-lattice. We further show that, during the quasi-particle excitation, the
distribution of multi-photon resonances between the resonator photon and the
quasi-lattice is determined by the degree the quasi-lattice is deformed from a
normal lattice. The multi-photon resonances lead to simultaneous generation of
GHZ-type and W-type of multipartite entanglement states of the qubits, which is
enhanced by the inhomogeneous interaction. Comparing the concurrence and the
3-tangle generated, we find that the totally non-separable GHZ entanglement is
specifically increased, up to two orders of magnitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.2542</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.2542</id><created>2013-12-09</created><updated>2014-05-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kyriakopoulos</keyname><forenames>Nikos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koukouloyannis</keyname><forenames>Vassilis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skokos</keyname><forenames>Charalampos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kevrekidis</keyname><forenames>Panayotis</forenames></author></authors><title>Chaotic behavior of three interacting vortices in a confined
  Bose-Einstein condensate</title><categories>nlin.CD</categories><comments>15 pages, 11 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4882169</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experimental works, we investigate a system of vortex
dynamics in an atomic Bose-Einstein condensate (BEC), consisting of three
vortices, two of which have the same charge. These vortices are modeled as a
system of point particles which possesses a Hamiltonian structure. This tripole
system constitutes a prototypical model of vortices in BECs exhibiting chaos.
By using the angular momentum integral of motion we reduce the study of the
system to the investigation of a two degree of freedom Hamiltonian model and
acquire quantitative results about its chaotic behavior. Our investigation tool
is the construction of scan maps by using the Smaller ALignment Index (SALI) as
a chaos indicator. Applying this approach to a large number of initial
conditions we manage to accurately and efficiently measure the extent of chaos
in the model and its dependence on physically important parameters like the
energy and the angular momentum of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1402.2880</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1402.2880</id><created>2014-02-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Scemama</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Renon</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rapacioli</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author></authors><title>A Sparse SCF algorithm and its parallel implementation: Application to
  DFTB</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cs.DC physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Theory Comput., 2014, 10 (6), 2344-2354</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/ct500115v</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an algorithm and its parallel implementation for solving a self
consistent problem as encountered in Hartree Fock or Density Functional Theory.
The algorithm takes advantage of the sparsity of matrices through the use of
local molecular orbitals. The implementation allows to exploit efficiently
modern symmetric multiprocessing (SMP) computer architectures. As a first
application, the algorithm is used within the density functional based tight
binding method, for which most of the computational time is spent in the linear
algebra routines (diagonalization of the Fock/Kohn-Sham matrix). We show that
with this algorithm (i) single point calculations on very large systems
(millions of atoms) can be performed on large SMP machines (ii) calculations
involving intermediate size systems (1~000--100~000 atoms) are also strongly
accelerated and can run efficiently on standard servers (iii) the error on the
total energy due to the use of a cut-off in the molecular orbital coefficients
can be controlled such that it remains smaller than the SCF convergence
criterion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1405.4082</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1405.4082</id><created>2014-05-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Caffarel</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giner</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scemama</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ram&#xed;rez-Sol&#xed;s</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin density distribution in open-shell transition metal systems: A
  comparative post-Hartree-Fock, Density Functional Theory and quantum Monte
  Carlo study of the CuCl2 molecule</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 12 Figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Theory Comput., 2014, 10 (12), 5286-5296</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/ct5004252</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparative study of the spatial distribution of the spin
density (SD) of the ground state of CuCl2 using Density Functional Theory
(DFT), quantum Monte Carlo (QMC), and post-Hartree-Fock wavefunction theory
(WFT). A number of studies have shown that an accurate description of the
electronic structure of the lowest-lying states of this molecule is
particularly challenging due to the interplay between the strong dynamical
correlation effects in the 3d shell of the copper atom and the delocalization
of the 3d hole over the chlorine atoms. It is shown here that qualitatively
different results for SD are obtained from these various quantum-chemical
approaches. At the DFT level, the spin density distribution is directly related
to the amount of Hartree-Fock exchange introduced in hybrid functionals. At the
QMC level, Fixed-node Diffusion Monte Carlo (FN-DMC) results for SD are
strongly dependent on the nodal structure of the trial wavefunction employed
(here, Hartree-Fock or Kohn-Sham with a particular amount of HF exchange) : in
the case of this open-shell system, the 3N -dimensional nodes are mainly
determined by the 3-dimensional nodes of the singly occupied molecular orbital.
Regarding wavefunction approaches, HF and CASSCF lead to strongly localized
spin density on the copper atom, in sharp contrast with DFT. To get a more
reliable description and shed some light on the connections between the various
theoretical descriptions, Full CI-type (FCI) calculations are performed. To
make them feasible for this case a perturbatively selected CI approach
generating multi-determinantal expansions of reasonable size and a small
tractable basis set are employed. Although semi-quantitative, these near-FCI
calculations allow to clarify how the spin density distribution evolves upon
inclusion of dynamic correlation effects. A plausible scenario about the nature
of the SD is proposed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3672</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3672</id><created>2014-08-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Giner</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scemama</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caffarel</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Fixed-Node Diffusion Monte Carlo potential energy curve of the fluorine
  molecule F2 using selected configuration interaction trial wavefunctions</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>16 pages, 15 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 142, 044115 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4905528</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The potential energy curve of the F$_2$ molecule is calculated with
Fixed-Node Diffusion Monte Carlo (FN-DMC) using Configuration Interaction
(CI)-type trial wavefunctions. To keep the number of determinants reasonable
(the first and second derivatives of the trial wavefunction need to be
calculated at each step of FN-DMC), the CI expansion is restricted to those
determinants that contribute the most to the total energy. The selection of the
determinants is made using the so-called CIPSI approach (Configuration
Interaction using a Perturbative Selection made Iteratively). Quite remarkably,
the nodes of CIPSI wavefunctions are found to be systematically improved when
increasing the number of selected determinants. To reduce the non-parallelism
error of the potential energy curve a scheme based on the use of a
$R$-dependent number of determinants is introduced. Numerical results show that
improved FN-DMC energy curves for the F$_2$ molecule are obtained when
employing CIPSI trial wavefunctions. Using the Dunning's cc-pVDZ basis set the
FN-DMC energy curve is of a quality similar to that obtained with FCI/cc-pVQZ.
A key advantage of using selected CI in FN-DMC is the possibility of improving
nodes in a systematic and automatic way without resorting to a preliminary
multi-parameter stochastic optimization of the trial wavefunction performed at
the Variational Monte Carlo level as usually done in FN-DMC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.3754</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.3754</id><created>2014-08-16</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marcolli</keyname><forenames>Matilde</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Rota-Baxter algebras, singular hypersurfaces, and renormalization on
  Kausz compactifications</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>35 pages, LaTeX</comments><msc-class>32S25, 81T15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider Rota-Baxter algebras of meromorphic forms with poles along a
(singular) hypersurface in a smooth projective variety and the associated
Birkhoff factorization for algebra homomorphisms from a commutative Hopf
algebra. In the case of a normal crossings divisor, the Rota-Baxter structure
simplifies considerably and the factorization becomes a simple pole
subtraction. We apply this formalism to the unrenormalized momentum space
Feynman amplitudes, viewed as (divergent) integrals in the complement of the
determinant hypersurface. We lift the integral to the Kausz compactification of
the general linear group, whose boundary divisor is normal crossings. We show
that the Kausz compactification is a Tate motive and that the boundary divisor
and the divisor that contains the boundary of the chain of integration are
mixed Tate configurations. The regularization of the integrals that we obtain
differs from the usual renormalization of physical Feynman amplitudes, and in
particular it may give mixed Tate periods in some cases that have non-mixed
Tate contributions when computed with other renormalization methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.3671</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.3671</id><created>2014-09-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Scemama</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Applencourt</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giner</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caffarel</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Accurate nonrelativistic ground-state energies of 3d transition metal
  atoms</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 tables</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 141, 244110 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4903985</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present accurate nonrelativistic ground-state energies of the transition
metal atoms of the 3d series calculated with Fixed-Node Diffusion Monte Carlo
(FN-DMC). Selected multi-determinantal expansions obtained with the CIPSI
method (Configuration Interaction using a Perturbative Selection made
Iteratively) and including the most prominent determinants of the full CI
expansion are used as trial wavefunctions. Using a maximum of a few tens of
thousands determinants, fixed-node errors on total DMC energies are found to be
greatly reduced for some atoms with respect to those obtained with Hartree-Fock
nodes. The FN-DMC/(CIPSI nodes) ground-state energies presented here are, to
the best of our knowledge, the most accurate values reported so far. Thanks to
the variational property of FN-DMC total energies, the results also provide
lower bounds for the absolute value of all-electron correlation energies,
$|E_c|$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.01148</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.01148</id><created>2015-01-06</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ewings</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perring</keyname><forenames>T. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sikora</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abernathy</keyname><forenames>D. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomioka</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tokura</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin excitations used to probe the nature of the exchange coupling in
  the magnetically ordered ground state of Pr$_{0.5}$Ca$_{0.5}$MnO$_{3}$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014405 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014405</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have used time-of-flight inelastic neutron scattering to measure the spin
wave spectrum of the canonical half-doped manganite
Pr$_{0.5}$Ca$_{0.5}$MnO$_{3}$, in its magnetic and orbitally ordered phase. The
data, which cover multiple Brillouin zones and the entire energy range of the
excitations, are compared with several different models that are all consistent
with the CE-type magnetic order, but arise through different exchange coupling
schemes. The Goodenough model, i.e. an ordered state comprising strong nearest
neighbor ferromagnetic interactions along zig-zag chains with antiferromagnetic
inter-chain coupling, provides the best description of the data, provided that
further neighbor interactions along the chains are included. We are able to
rule out a coupling scheme involving formation of strongly bound ferromagnetic
dimers, i.e. Zener polarons, on the basis of gross features of the observed
spin wave spectrum. A model with weaker dimerization reproduces the observed
dispersion but can be ruled out on the basis of discrepancies between the
calculated and observed structure factors at certain positions in reciprocal
space. Adding further neighbor interactions results in almost no dimerization,
i.e. recovery of the Goodenough model. These results are consistent with
theoretical analysis of the degenerate double exchange model for half-doping,
and provide a recipe for how to interpret future measurements away from
half-doping, where degenerate double exchange models predict more complex
ground states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.00836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.00836</id><created>2015-03-03</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Shin-Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambert</keyname><forenames>Neill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Che-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miranowicz</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yueh-Nan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nori</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantifying Non-Markovianity with Temporal Steering</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 2 figures, plus supplementary information. Updated title to
  match the published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 116, 020503 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.116.020503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Einstein-Podolsky-Rosen (EPR) steering is a type of quantum correlation which
allows one to remotely prepare, or steer, the state of a distant quantum
system. While EPR steering can be thought of as a purely spatial correlation
there does exist a temporal analogue, in the form of single-system temporal
steering. However, a precise quantification of such temporal steering has been
lacking. Here we show that it can be measured, via semidefinite programming,
with a temporal steerable weight, in direct analogy to the recently proposed
EPR steerable weight. We find a useful property of the temporal steerable
weight in that it is a non-increasing function under completely-positive
trace-preserving maps and can be used to define a sufficient and practical
measure of strong non-Markovianity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05129</id><created>2015-04-20</created><updated>2015-05-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Forgacs</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukacs</keyname><forenames>Arpad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaposnik</keyname><forenames>Fidel A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Abelian Vortices with a Twist</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev. D91 (2015) no.12, 125001</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.91.125001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Non-Abelian flux-tube (string) solutions carrying global currents are found
in the bosonic sector of 4-dimensional N=2 super-symmetric gauge theories. The
specific model considered here posseses U(2)local x SU(2)global symmetry, with
two scalar doublets in the fundamental representation of SU(2). We construct
string solutions that are stationary and translationally symmetric along the x3
direction, and they are characterized by a matrix phase between the two
doublets, referred to as &quot;twist&quot;. Consequently, twisted strings have nonzero
(global) charge, momentum, and in some cases even angular momentum per unit
length. The planar cross section of a twisted string corresponds to a
rotationally symmetric, charged non-Abelian vortex, satisfying 1st order
Bogomolny-type equations and 2nd order Gauss-constraints. Interestingly,
depending on the nature of the matrix phase, some of these solutions even break
rotational symmetry in R3. Although twisted vortices have higher energy than
the untwisted ones, they are expected to be linearly stable since one can
maintain their charge (or twist) fixed with respect to small perturbations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.08113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.08113</id><created>2015-04-30</created><updated>2016-06-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Higashikawa</keyname><forenames>Sho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ueda</keyname><forenames>Masahito</forenames></author></authors><title>$\mu$-Symmetry breaking: an algebraic approach to finding mean fields of
  quantum many-body systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>23 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013613 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013613</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the most fundamental problems in quantum many-body systems is the
identification of a mean field in spontaneous symmetry breaking which is
usually made in a heuristic manner. We propose a systematic method of finding a
mean field based on the Lie algebra and the dynamical symmetry by introducing a
class of symmetry broken phases which we call $\mu$-symmetry breaking. We show
that for $\mu$-symmetry breaking the quadratic part of an effective Lagrangian
of Nambu-Goldstone modes can be block-diagonalized and that homotopy groups of
topological excitations can be calculated systematically.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.00778</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.00778</id><created>2015-05-04</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Khatri</keyname><forenames>Rishi</forenames></author></authors><title>An alternative validation strategy for the Planck cluster catalog and
  $y$-distortion maps</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>A&amp;A 592, A48 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526479</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an all sky map of the $y$-type distortion calculated from the full
mission Planck HFI (High Frequency Instrument) data using the recently proposed
approach to component separation based on parametric model fitting and model
selection. This simple model selection approach allows us to distinguish
between carbon monoxide (CO) line emission and $y$-type distortion, something
that is not possible using the internal linear combination based methods. We
create a mask to cover the regions of significant CO emission relying on the
information in the $\chi^2$ map obtained when fitting for the $y$-distortion
and CO emission to the lowest four HFI channels. We revisit the second Planck
cluster catalog and try to quantify the quality of the cluster candidates in an
approach that is similar in spirit to Aghanim et al. (2014). We find that at
least $93\%$ of the clusters in the cosmology sample are free of CO
contamination. We also find that $59\%$ of unconfirmed candidates may have
significant contamination from molecular clouds. We agree with Planck
collaboration (2015) for the worst offenders. We suggest an alternative
validation strategy of measuring and subtracting the CO emission from the
Planck cluster candidates using radio telescopes thus improving the reliability
of the catalog. Our CO mask and annotations to the Planck cluster catalog
identifying cluster candidates with possible CO contamination are made publicly
available.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1505.01863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1505.01863</id><created>2015-05-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Motazedifard</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naderi</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roknizadeh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>An analogue model for controllable Casimir radiation in a nonlinear
  cavity with amplitude-modulated pumping: Generation and quantum statistical
  properties</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages and 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Opt. Soc. Am. B 32, 1555(2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/JOSAB.32.001555</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present and investigate an analogue model for a controllable photon
geberation via the dynamical Casimir effect (DCE) in a cavity containing a
degenerate optical amplifier (OPA) which is pumed by an amplitude-modulated
field. The time modulation of the pump field in the model OPA system is
equivalent to a periodic modulation of the cavity length, which is responsible
for the generation of the Casimir radiation. By taking into account the rapidly
oscillating terms of the modulation frequency, the effects of the corresponding
counter-rotating terms (CRTs) on the analogue Casimir radiation emerge clearly.
We find that the mean number of generated photons and their quantum statistical
properties exhibit oscillatory behaviors, which are controllable through the
modulation frequency as an external control parameter.We also recognize a new
phenomenon, the so-called &quot;Anti-DCE,&quot; in which pair photons can be coherently
annihilated due to the time-modulated pumping. We show that the Casimir
radiation exhibits quadrature squeezing, photon bunching and super-Poissonian
statistics which are controllable by modulation frequency. We also calculate
the power spectrum of the intracavity light field. We find that the appearance
of the side bands in the spectrum is due to the presence of the CRTs.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01532</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01532</id><created>2015-06-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Xiangying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Jiping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ni</keyname><forenames>Yushan</forenames></author></authors><title>Intelligent thermal cloak-concentrators</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 109, 031907 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4959251</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  How to macroscopically control the flow of heat at will is up to now a
challenge, which, however, is very important for human life since heat flow is
a ubiquitous phenomenon in nature. Inspired by intelligent electronic
components or intelligent materials, here we demonstrate, analytically and
numerically, a unique class of intelligent bifunctional thermal metamaterials
called thermal cloak-concentrators, which can automatically change from a cloak
(concentrator) to a concentrator (cloak) when the applied temperature field
decreases (increases). For future experimental realization, the behavior is
also confirmed by assembling homogeneous isotropic materials according to the
effective medium theory. The underlying mechanism originates from the effect of
nonlinearity in thermal conduction. This work not only makes it possible to
achieve a switchable Seebeck effect, but also offers guidance both for
macroscopic manipulation of heat flow at will and for the design of similar
intelligent multifunctional metamaterials in optics, electromagnetics,
acoustics, or elastodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.04775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.04775</id><created>2015-07-16</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smaldino</keyname><forenames>Paul E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Janssen</keyname><forenames>Marco A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hillis</keyname><forenames>Vicken</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bednar</keyname><forenames>Jenna</forenames></author></authors><title>Adoption as a Social Marker: Innovation Diffusion with Outgroup Aversion</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>26 pages, 10 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Social identities are among the key factors driving behavior in complex
societies. Signals of social identity are known to influence individual
behaviors in the adoption of innovations. Yet the population-level consequences
of identity signaling on the diffusion of innovations are largely unknown. Here
we use both analytical and agent-based modeling to consider the spread of a
beneficial innovation in a structured population in which there exist two
groups who are averse to being mistaken for each other. We investigate the
dynamics of adoption and consider the role of structural factors such as
demographic skew and communication scale on population-level outcomes. We find
that outgroup aversion can lead to adoption being delayed or suppressed in one
group, and that population-wide underadoption is common. Comparing the two
models, we find that differential adoption can arise due to structural
constraints on information flow even in the absence of intrinsic between-group
differences in adoption rates. Further, we find that patterns of polarization
in adoption at both local and global scales depend on the details of
demographic organization and the scale of communication. This research has
particular relevance to widely beneficial but identity-relevant products and
behaviors, such as green technologies, where overall levels of adoption
determine the positive benefits that accrue to society at large.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.02281</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.02281</id><created>2015-08-03</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rahaman</keyname><forenames>Farook</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maharaj</keyname><forenames>Sunil D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sardar</keyname><forenames>Iftikar Hossain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Koushik</forenames></author></authors><title>Conformally symmetric relativistic star</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Mod.Phys.Lett.A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate whether compact stars having Tolman-like interior geometry
admit conformal symmetry. Taking anisotropic pressure along the two principal
directions within the compact object, we obtain physically relevant quantities
such as transverse and radial pressure, density and redshift function. We study
the equation of state for the matter distribution inside the star. From the
relation between pressure and density function of the constituent matter, we
explore the nature and properties of the interior matter. The red shift
function, compactness parameter are found to be physically reasonable. The
matter inside the star satisfies the null, weak and strong energy conditions.
Finally, we compare the masses and radii predicted from the model with
corresponding values in some observed stars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.00704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.00704</id><created>2015-09-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Bera</keyname><forenames>Anindita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rakshit</keyname><forenames>Debraj</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewenstein</keyname><forenames>Maciej</forenames></author><author><keyname>De</keyname><forenames>Aditi Sen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Ujjwal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wehr</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Order-from-disorder and critical scalings of spontaneous magnetization
  in random-field quantum spin systems</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.stat-mech quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014421 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014421</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the effect of a unidirectional quenched random field on the
anisotropic quantum spin-1/2 $XY$ model, which magnetizes spontaneously in the
absence of the random field. We adopt mean-field approach to show that
spontaneous magnetization persists even in the presence of this random field
but the magnitude of magnetization gets suppressed due to disorder, and the
system magnetizes in the directions parallel and transverse to the random
field. Our results are obtained by analytical calculations within perturbative
framework and by numerical simulations. Interestingly, we show that it is
possible to enhance a component of the magnetization in presence of the
disorder field provided we apply an additional constant field in the $XY$
plane. Moreover, we derive generalized expressions for the critical temperature
and the scalings of the magnetization near the critical point for the $XY$ spin
system with arbitrary fixed quantum spin angular momentum.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.05394</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.05394</id><created>2015-09-17</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sharkey</keyname><forenames>James P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foo</keyname><forenames>Darryl C. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kabla</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baumberg</keyname><forenames>Jeremy J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bowman</keyname><forenames>Richard W.</forenames></author></authors><title>A one-piece 3D printed flexure translation stage for open-source
  microscopy</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>7 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Review of Scientific Instruments, 87, 025104 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4941068</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Open source hardware has the potential to revolutionise the way we build
scientific instruments; with the advent of readily-available 3D printers,
mechanical designs can now be shared, improved and replicated faster and more
easily than ever before. However, printed parts are typically plastic and often
perform poorly compared to traditionally machined mechanisms. We have overcome
many of the limitations of 3D printed mechanisms by exploiting the compliance
of the plastic to produce a monolithic 3D printed flexure translation stage,
capable of sub-micron-scale motion over a range of $8\times8\times4\,$mm. This
requires minimal post-print clean-up, and can be automated with
readily-available stepper motors. The resulting plastic composite structure is
very stiff and exhibits remarkably low drift, moving less than $20\,\mu$m over
the course of a week, without temperature stabilisation. This enables us to
construct a miniature microscope with excellent mechanical stability, perfect
for timelapse measurements in situ in an incubator or fume hood. The ease of
manufacture lends itself to use in containment facilities where disposability
is advantageous, and to experiments requiring many microscopes in parallel.
High performance mechanisms based on printed flexures need not be limited to
microscopy, and we anticipate their use in other devices both within the
laboratory and beyond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08846</id><created>2015-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Siminos</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skupin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>S&#xe4;vert</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cole</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mangles</keyname><forenames>S. P. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaluza</keyname><forenames>M. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling ultrafast shadowgraphy in laser-plasma interaction experiments</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Plasma Phys. Control. Fusion 58, 065004 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0741-3335/58/6/065004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrafast shadowgraphy is a new experimental technique that uses few cycle
laser pulses to image density gradients in a rapidly evolving plasma. It
enables structures that move at speeds close to the speed of light, such as
laser driven wakes, to be visualized. Here we study the process of
shadowgraphic image formation during the propagation of a few cycle probe pulse
transversely through a laser-driven wake using three-dimensional
particle-in-cell simulations. In order to construct synthetic shadowgrams a
near-field snapshot of the ultrashort probe pulse is analyzed by means of
Fourier optics, taking into account the effect of a typical imaging setup. By
comparing synthetic and experimental shadowgrams we show that the generation of
synthetic data is crucial for the correct interpretation of experiments.
Moreover, we study the dependence of synthetic shadowgrams on various
parameters such as the imaging system aperture, the position of the object
plane and the probe pulse delay, duration and wavelength. Finally, we show that
time-dependent information from the interaction can be recovered from a single
shot by using a broadband, chirped probe pulse and subsequent spectral
filtering.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01987</id><created>2015-10-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Aschwanden</keyname><forenames>Markus J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thresholded Power Law Size Distributions of Instabilities in
  Astrophysics</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>42 pages, 16 Figures, accepted for publication in The Astrophysical
  Journal (2015 Oct 7)</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, 814:19 (25pp), 2015 November 20</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/814/1/19</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Power law-like size distributions are ubiquitous in astrophysical
instabilities. There are at least four natural effects that cause deviations
from ideal power law size distributions, which we model here in a generalized
way: (1) a physical threshold of an instability; (2) incomplete sampling of the
smallest events below a threshold $x_0$; (3) contamination by an
event-unrelated background $x_b$; and (4) truncation effects at the largest
events due to a finite system size. These effects can be modeled in simplest
terms with a &quot;thresholded power law&quot; distribution function (also called
generalized Pareto [type II] or Lomax distribution), $N(x) dx \propto
(x+x_0)^{-a} dx$, where $x_0 &gt; 0$ is positive for a threshold effect, while
$x_0 &lt; 0$ is negative for background contamination. We analytically derive the
functional shape of this thresholded power law distribution function from an
exponential-growth evolution model, which produces avalanches only when a
disturbance exceeds a critical threshold $x_0$. We apply the thresholded power
law distribution function to terrestrial, solar (HXRBS, BATSE, RHESSI), and
stellar flare (Kepler) data sets. We find that the thresholded power law model
provides an adequate fit to most of the observed data. Major advantages of this
model are the automated choice of the power law fitting range, diagnostics of
background contamination, physical inastability thresholds, instrumental
detection thresholds, and finite system size limits. When testing
self-organized criticality models, which predict ideal power laws, we suggest
to include these natural truncation effects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.00757</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.00757</id><created>2015-11-02</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jansen</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schuster</keyname><forenames>M. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Signoracci</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hagen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navr&#xe1;til</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Open $sd$-shell nuclei from first principles</title><categories>nucl-th nucl-ex</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94, 011301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.011301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the ab initio coupled-cluster effective interaction (CCEI) method
to deformed open-shell nuclei with protons and neutrons in the valence space,
and compute binding energies and excited states of isotopes of neon and
magnesium. We employ a nucleon-nucleon and three-nucleon interaction from
chiral effective field theory evolved to a lower cutoff via a similarity
renormalization group transformation. We find good agreement with experiment
for binding energies and spectra, while charge radii of neon isotopes are
underestimated. For the deformed nuclei $^{20}$Ne and $^{24}$Mg we reproduce
rotational bands and electric quadrupole transitions within uncertainties
estimated from an effective field theory for deformed nuclei, thereby
demonstrating that collective phenomena in $sd$-shell nuclei emerge from
complex ab initio calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01482</id><created>2015-11-04</created><updated>2016-01-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arvanitakis</keyname><forenames>Alex S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher spins from Nambu-Chern-Simons theory</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>27 pages, 2 appendices; v2: Reference added, fixed minor typo in
  arxiv abstract</comments><report-no>DAMTP-2015-66</report-no><journal-ref>Commun. Math. Phys. (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00220-016-2712-x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a new theory of higher spin gravity in three spacetime dimensions.
This is defined by what we will call a Nambu-Chern-Simons (NCS) action; this is
to a Nambu 3-algebra as an ordinary Chern-Simons (CS) action is to a Lie
(2-)algebra. The novelty is that the gauge group of this theory is simple; this
stands in contrast to previously understood interacting 3D higher spin theories
in the frame-like formalism. We also consider the $N=8$ supersymmetric
NCS-matter model (BLG theory), where the NCS action originated: Its fully
supersymmetric M2 brane configurations are interpreted as Hopf fibrations, the
homotopy type of the (infinite) gauge group is calculated and its instantons
are classified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.03755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.03755</id><created>2015-11-11</created><updated>2016-03-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bambi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardenas-Avendano</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olmo</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubiera-Garcia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Wormholes and nonsingular space-times in Palatini $f(R)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-58</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 93, 064016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.93.064016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We reconsider the problem of $f(R)$ theories of gravity coupled to
Born-Infeld theory of electrodynamics formulated in a Palatini approach, where
metric and connection are independent fields. By studying electrovacuum
configurations in a static and spherically symmetric space-time, we find
solutions which reduce to their Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;om counterparts at large
distances but undergo important non-perturbative modifications close to the
center. Our new analysis reveals that the point-like singularity is replaced by
a finite-size wormhole structure, which provides a geodesically complete and
thus nonsingular space-time, despite the existence of curvature divergences at
the wormhole throat. Implications of these results, in particular for the
cosmic censorship conjecture, are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.04971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.04971</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hatefi</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author></authors><title>On RR Couplings and Bulk Singularity Structures of Non-BPS Branes</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, no figure, Latex file, v3: clarifications added. Published
  version in PLB</comments><report-no>QMUL-PH-15-25,TUW-15-26</report-no><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B760 (2016) 509-519</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We compute the five point world sheet scattering amplitude of a symmetric
closed string Ramond-Ramond , a transverse scalar field, a world volume gauge
field and a real tachyon in both world volume and transverse directions of
brane in type IIA and IIB superstring theory. We provide the complete analysis
of $&lt;C^{-1} \phi^0 A^0 T ^{-1}&gt;$ S-matrix and show that both $u'=u+\frac{1}{4}$
and $t$ channel bulk singularity structures can also be examined by this
S-matrix. Various remarks about new restricted Bianchi identities on world
volume for the other pictures have also been made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.08372</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.08372</id><created>2015-11-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Thiele</keyname><forenames>Illia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Skupin</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nuter</keyname><forenames>Rachel</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling arbitrarily shaped and tightly focused laser pulses in
  electromagnetic codes</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>J. Comp. Phys. 321, 1110 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jcp.2016.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Investigation of laser matter interaction with electromagnetic codes requires
to implement sources for the electromagnetic fields. A way to do so is to
prescribe the fields at the numerical box boundaries in order to achieve the
desired fields inside the numerical box. Here we show that the often used
paraxial approximation can lead to unexpected field profiles with strong impact
on the laser matter interaction results. We propose an efficient numerical
algorithm to compute the required laser boundary conditions consistent with the
Maxwell's equations for arbitrarily shaped, tightly focused laser pulses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.01189</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.01189</id><created>2015-12-03</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Halpern</keyname><forenames>Nicole Yunger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faist</keyname><forenames>Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oppenheim</keyname><forenames>Jonathan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Winter</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author></authors><title>Microcanonical and resource-theoretic derivations of the thermal state
  of a quantum system with noncommuting charges</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Published version. 7 pages (2 figures) + appendices. The leading
  author's surname is &quot;Yunger Halpern.&quot;</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12051 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12051</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The grand canonical ensemble lies at the core of quantum and classical
statistical mechanics. A small system thermalizes to this ensemble while
exchanging heat and particles with a bath. A quantum system may exchange
quantities represented by operators that fail to commute. Whether such a system
thermalizes and what form the thermal state has are questions about truly
quantum thermodynamics. Here we investigate this thermal state from three
perspectives. First, we introduce an approximate microcanonical ensemble. If
this ensemble characterizes the system-and-bath composite, tracing out the bath
yields the system's thermal state. This state is expected to be the equilibrium
point, we argue, of typical dynamics. Finally, we define a resource-theory
model for thermodynamic exchanges of noncommuting observables. Complete
passivity---the inability to extract work from equilibrium states---implies the
thermal state's form, too. Our work opens new avenues into equilibrium in the
presence of quantum noncommutation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.02704</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.02704</id><created>2015-12-08</created><updated>2016-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Durkin</keyname><forenames>Malcolm</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondragon-Shem</keyname><forenames>Ian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eley</keyname><forenames>Serena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hughes</keyname><forenames>Taylor L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mason</keyname><forenames>Nadya</forenames></author></authors><title>History-dependent dissipative vortex dynamics in superconducting arrays</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 024510 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.024510</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We perform current(I)-voltage(V) measurements on low resistance
superconductor-normal-superconductor arrays in finite magnetic fields, focusing
on the dilute vortex population regime. We observe significant deviations from
predicted behavior, notably the absence of a differential resistance peak near
the vortex de-pinning current, and a broad linear I-V region with an
extrapolated I intercept equal to the de-pinning current. Comparing these
results to an overdamped molecular vortex model, we find that this behavior can
be explained by the presence of a history dependent dissipative force. This
approach has not been considered previously, yet is crucial for obtaining a
correct description of the vortex dynamics in superconducting arrays.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07653</id><created>2015-12-23</created><updated>2016-04-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Engelhardt</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Benito</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Platero</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandes</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological instabilities in ac-driven bosonic systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>5 pages and supplementary information, 3 figures, comments are
  welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 045302 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.045302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Under non-equilibrium conditions, bosonic modes can become dynamically
unstable with an exponentially growing occupation. On the other hand,
topological band structures give rise to symmetry protected midgap states. In
this letter, we investigate the interplay of instability and topology. Thereby,
we establish a general relation between topology and instability under
ac-driving. We apply our findings to create dynamical instabilities which are
strongly localized at the boundaries of a finite-size system. As these
localized instabilities are protected by symmetry, they can be considered as
topological instabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08511</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2015-12-29</updated><authors><author><keyname>Florinsky</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Filippov</keyname><forenames>S. V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Development of virtual morphometric globes using Blender</title><categories>physics.geo-ph astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>14 pages, 7 figures (references corrected)</comments><acm-class>J.2; I.3.7</acm-class><journal-ref>Keldysh Institute Preprints, 2016, No. 37, 18 p</journal-ref><doi>10.20948/prepr-2016-37</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Virtual globes - programs implementing interactive three-dimensional (3D)
models of planets - are increasingly used in geosciences. Global morphometric
models can be useful for tectonic and planetary studies. We describe the
development of the first testing version of the system of virtual morphometric
globes for the Earth, Mars, and the Moon. As the initial data, we used three
15'-gridded global digital elevation models (DEMs) extracted from SRTM30_PLUS,
the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter, and the Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter gridded
archives. For three planetary bodies, we derived global digital models and maps
of several morphometric attributes (i.e., horizontal curvature, vertical
curvature, minimal curvature, maximal curvature, and catchment area). To
develop the system, we used Blender, the open-source software for 3D modeling
and visualization. First, a 3D sphere model was generated. Second, the global
morphometric maps as textures were imposed to the sphere surface. Finally, the
real-time 3D graphics Blender engine was used to implement globe rotation and
zooming. The testing of the developed system demonstrated its good performance.
Morphometric globes clearly represent peculiarities of planetary topography,
according to the physical and mathematical sense of a particular morphometric
variable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09100</id><created>2015-12-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Charbonneau</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corwin</keyname><forenames>Eric I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Parisi</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poncet</keyname><forenames>Alexis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zamponi</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author></authors><title>Universal non-Debye scaling in the density of states of amorphous solids</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 045503 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.045503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  At the jamming transition, amorphous packings are known to display anomalous
vibrational modes with a density of states (DOS) that remains constant at low
frequency. The scaling of the DOS at higher densities remains, however,
unclear. One might expect to find simple Debye scaling, but recent results from
effective medium theory and the exact solution of mean-field models both
predict an anomalous, non-Debye scaling. Being mean-field solutions, however,
these solutions are only strictly applicable to the limit of infinite spatial
dimension, and it is unclear what value they have for finite-dimensional
systems. Here, we study packings of soft spheres in dimensions 3 through 7 and
find, far from jamming, a universal non-Debye scaling of the DOS that is
consistent with the mean-field predictions. We also consider how the soft mode
participation ratio converges to the mean-field prediction as dimension
increases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00156</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00156</id><created>2016-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Olmo</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubiera-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author></authors><title>Geons as wormholes of modified gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages; Contribution to the proceedings of &quot;The Fourtheenth Marcel
  Grossmann Meeting on General Relativity&quot;, University of Rome &quot;La Sapienza&quot;,
  Rome, July 12-18, 2015, based on an invited talk delivered at the AT3
  parallel session</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-57</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Wormholes may arise as solutions of extensions of General Relativity without
violation of the energy conditions. Working in a Palatini approach we consider
classical geometries supporting such wormholes. It is shown that the resulting
space-times represent explicit realizations of the concept of geon introduced
by Wheeler, interpreted as self-consistent bodies generated by an
electromagnetic field without sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.00161</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.00161</id><created>2016-01-02</created><authors><author><keyname>Olmo</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubiera-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Puente</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Wormholes as a cure for black hole singularities</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages, contribution to the proceedings of &quot;The Fourtheenth Marcel
  Grossmann Meeting on General Relativity&quot;, University of Rome &quot;La Sapienza&quot;,
  Rome, July 12-18, 2015, based on an invited talk delivered at the AT3
  parallel session</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-56</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using exactly solvable models, it is shown that black hole singularities in
different electrically charged configurations can be cured. Our solutions
describe black hole space-times with a wormhole giving structure to the
otherwise point-like singularity. We show that geodesic completeness is
satisfied despite the existence of curvature divergences at the wormhole
throat. In some cases, physical observers can go through the wormhole and in
other cases the throat lies at an infinite affine distance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.06075</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.06075</id><created>2016-01-22</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Omodei</keyname><forenames>Elisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Domenico</keyname><forenames>Manlio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arenas</keyname><forenames>Alex</forenames></author></authors><title>Evaluating the impact of interdisciplinary research: a multilayer
  network approach</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.DL</categories><doi>10.1017/nws.2016.15</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nowadays, scientific challenges usually require approaches that cross
traditional boundaries between academic disciplines, driving many researchers
towards interdisciplinarity. Despite its obvious importance, there is a lack of
studies on how to quantify the influence of interdisciplinarity on the research
impact, posing uncertainty in a proper evaluation for hiring and funding
purposes. Here we propose a method based on the analysis of bipartite
interconnected multilayer networks of citations and disciplines, to assess
scholars, institutions and countries interdisciplinary importance. Using data
about physics publications and US patents, we show that our method allows to
reward, using a quantitative approach, scholars and institutions that have
carried out interdisciplinary work and have had an impact in different
scientific areas. The proposed method could be used by funding agencies,
universities and scientific policy decision makers for hiring and funding
purposes, and to complement existing methods to rank universities and
countries.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00635</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00635</id><created>2016-02-01</created><authors><author><keyname>Aschwanden</keyname><forenames>Markus J.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Vertical Current Approximation Nonlinear Force-Free Field Code -
  Description, Performance Tests, and Measurements of Magnetic Energies
  Dissipated in Solar Flares</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>23 Figures, 50 pages</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Supplement Series, 224:25 (32pp), 2016
  June</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0067-0049/224/2/25</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we provide an updated description of the Vertical Current
Approximation Nonlinear Force-Free Field (VCA-NLFFF) code, which is designed to
measure the evolution of the potential, nonpotential, free energies, and the
dissipated magnetic energies during solar flares. This code provides a
complementary and alternative method to existing traditional NLFFF codes. The
chief advantages of the VCA-NLFFF code over traditional NLFFF codes are the
circumvention of the unrealistic assumption of a force-free photosphere in the
magnetic field extrapolation method, the capability to minimize the
misalignment angles between observed coronal loops (or chromospheric fibril
structures) and theoretical model field lines, as well as computational speed.
In performance tests of the VCA-NLFFF code, by comparing with the NLFFF code of
Wiegelmann (2004), we find agreement in the potential, nonpotential, and free
energy within a factor of about 1.3, but the Wiegelmann code yields in the
average a factor of 2 lower flare energies. The VCA-NLFFF code is found to
detect decreases in flare energies in most X, M, and C-class flares. The
successful detection of energy decreases during a variety of flares with the
VCA-NLFFF code indicates that current-driven twisting and untwisting of the
magnetic field is an adequate model to quantify the storage of magnetic
energies in active regions and their dissipation during flares. - The VCA-NLFFF
code is also publicly available in the Solar SoftWare (SSW).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01798</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01798</id><created>2016-02-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Olmo</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rubiera-Garcia</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Puente</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of curvature divergences on physical observers in a wormhole
  space-time with horizons</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>14 pages; Accepted for publication on Class. Quant. Grav</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-55</report-no><journal-ref>Class.Quant.Grav 33 (2016) no.11, 115007</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0264-9381/33/11/115007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The impact of curvature divergences on physical observers in a black hole
space-time which, nonetheless, is geodesically complete is investigated. This
space-time is an exact solution of certain extensions of General Relativity
coupled to Maxwell's electrodynamics and, roughly speaking, consists on two
Reissner-Nordstr\&quot;{o}m (or Schwarzschild or Minkowski) geometries connected by
a spherical wormhole near the center. We find that, despite the existence of
infinite tidal forces, causal contact is never lost among the elements making
up the observer. This suggests that curvature divergences may not be as
pathological as traditionally thought.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02119</id><created>2016-02-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Aschwanden</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reardon</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jess</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Tracing the Chromospheric and Coronal Magnetic Field with AIA, IRIS,
  IBIS, and ROSA Data</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>29 pages, 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal 826:61 (18 pp), 2016 July 20</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/61</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The aim of this study is to explore the suitability of chromospheric images
for magnetic modeling of active regions. We use high-resolution images (0.1&quot;)
from the Interferometric Bidimensional Spectrometer (IBIS) in the Ca II 8542 A
line, the Rapid Oscillations in the Solar Atmosphere (ROSA) instrument in the
H-alpha 6563 A line, the Interface Region Imaging Spectrograph (IRIS) in the
2796 A line, and compare non-potential magnetic field models obtained from
those chromospheric images with those obtained from images of the Atmospheric
Imaging Assembly (AIA) in coronal (171 A, etc.) and in chromospheric (304 A)
wavelengths. Curvi-linear structures are automatically traced in those images
with the OCCULT-2 code, to which we forward-fitted magnetic field lines
computed with the Vertical-Current Approximation Non-Linear Force Free Field
(VCA-NLFFF) code. We find that the chromospheric images: (1) reveal crisp
curvi-linear structures (fibrils, loop segments, spicules) that are extremely
well-suited for constraining magnetic modeling; (2) that these curvi-linear
structures are field-aligned with the best-fit solution by a median
misalignment angle of ~4-7 deg; (3) the free energy computed from coronal data
may underestimate that obtained from cromospheric data by a factor of ~ 2-4,
(4) the height range of chromospheric features is confined to h ~ 4000$ km,
while coronal features are detected up to h ~ 35,000$ km; and (5) the
plasma-beta parameter is beta ~ 10^(-5)-10^(-1) for all traced features. We
conclude that chromospheric images reveal important magnetic structures that
are complementary to coronal images and need to be included in comprehensive
magnetic field models, a quest that is not accomodated in standard NLFFF codes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03377</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03377</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bialas</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bzdak</keyname><forenames>Adam</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-particle correlations in transverse momenta from statistical
  clusters</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex nucl-ex</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett. B760 (2016) 438-441</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We evaluate $n$-particle ($n=2,3,4,5$) transverse momentum correlations for
pions and kaons following from the decay of statistical clusters. These
correlation functions could provide strong constraints on a possible existence
of thermal clusters in the process of particle production.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06297</id><created>2016-02-19</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guidi</keyname><forenames>Giovanni</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scannapieco</keyname><forenames>Cecilia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walcher</keyname><forenames>C. Jakob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallazzi</keyname><forenames>Anna</forenames></author></authors><title>Physical properties of galaxies: toward a consistent comparison between
  hydrodynamical simulations and SDSS</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>19 pages, 18 figures, accepted for publication by MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1790</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the effects of applying observational techniques to derive the
properties of simulated galaxies, with the aim of making an unbiased comparison
between observations and simulations. For our study, we used fifteen galaxies
simulated in a cosmological context using three different feedback and chemical
enrichment models, and compared their z=0 properties with data from the Sloan
Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). We show that the physical properties obtained
directly from the simulations without post-processing can be very different to
those obtained mimicking observational techniques. In order to provide
simulators a way to reliably compare their galaxies with SDSS data, for each
physical property that we studied - colours, magnitudes, gas and stellar
metallicities, mean stellar ages and star formation rates - we give scaling
relations that can be easily applied to the values extracted from the
simulations. These scalings have in general a high correlation, except for the
galaxy mean stellar ages and gas oxygen metallicities. Our simulated galaxies
are photometrically similar to galaxies in the blue cloud/green valley, but in
general they appear older, passive and with lower metal content compared to
most of the spirals in SDSS. As a careful assessment of the
agreement/disagreement with observations is the primary test of the baryonic
physics implemented in hydrodynamical codes, our study shows that considering
the observational biases in the derivation of the galaxies' properties is of
fundamental importance to decide on the failure/success of a galaxy formation
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07923</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Fukuyama</keyname><forenames>Takeshi</forenames></author></authors><title>General Spin Precession and Betatron Oscillation in Storage Ring</title><categories>physics.acc-ph hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, two figures</comments><journal-ref>Modern Physics Letters A (MPLA), vol.31, 1650135 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0217732316501352</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give the geralized expression of spin precession of extended bunch
particles having both anomalous magnetic and electric dipole moments in storage
ring. The transversal betatron oscillation formula of the bunch is also given.
The latter is the generalization of the Farley's pitch correction
\cite{Farley}, including radial oscillation as well as vertical one. Some
useful formulae for muon storage ring are discussed in appendix.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08305</id><created>2016-02-26</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Qaiumzadeh</keyname><forenames>Alireza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Titov</keyname><forenames>Mikhail</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of light-induced effective magnetic field in Rashba ferromagnets</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014425 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent experiments on all-optical magnetization reversal in
conductive ferromagnetic thin films we use nonequilibrium formalism to
calculate the effective magnetic field induced in a Rashba ferromagnet by a
short laser pulse. The main contribution to the effect originates in the direct
optical transitions between spin-split subbands. The resulting effective
magnetic field is inversely proportional to the impurity scattering rate and
can reach the amplitude of a few Tesla in the systems like Co/Pt bilayers. We
showthat the total light-induced effective magnetic field in ferromagnetic
systems is the sum of two contributions: a helicity dependent term, which is an
even function of magnetization, and a helicity independent term, which is an
odd function of magnetization. The primary role of the spin-orbit interaction
is to widen the frequency range for direct optical transitions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.01604</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.01604</id><created>2016-03-04</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cardella</keyname><forenames>Davide</forenames></author><author><keyname>Celli</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonella</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Manipulating waves by distilling frequencies: a tunable shunt-enabled
  rainbow trap</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>D.C. and P.C. both contributed majorly to the realization of this
  work</comments><journal-ref>Smart Mater. Struct. 25, 085017 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0964-1726/25/8/085017</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we propose and test a strategy for tunable, broadband wave
attenuation in electromechanical waveguides with shunted piezoelectric
inclusions. Our strategy is built upon the vast pre-existing literature on
vibration attenuation and bandgap generation in structures featuring periodic
arrays of piezo patches, but distinguishes itself for several key features.
First, we demystify the idea that periodicity is a requirement for wave
attenuation and bandgap formation. We further embrace the idea of &quot;organized
disorder&quot; by tuning the circuits as to resonate at distinct neighboring
frequencies. In doing so, we create a tunable &quot;rainbow trap&quot; [Tsakmakidis et
al. Nature 450, 397-401 (2007)] capable of attenuating waves with broadband
characteristics, by &quot;distilling&quot; (sequentially) seven frequencies from a
traveling wavepacket. Finally, we devote considerable attention to the
implications in terms of packet distortion of the spectral manipulation
introduced by shunting. This work is also meant to serve as a didactic tool for
those approaching the field of shunted piezoelectrics, and attempts to provide
a different perspective, with abundant details, on how to successfully design
an experimental setup involving resistive-inductive shunts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.03093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.03093</id><created>2016-03-09</created><updated>2016-07-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bradlyn</keyname><forenames>Barry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cano</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhijun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vergniory</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cava</keyname><forenames>R. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernevig</keyname><forenames>B. Andrei</forenames></author></authors><title>Beyond Dirac and Weyl fermions: Unconventional quasiparticles in
  conventional crystals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>v1: main text 9pgs. 29pg supplementary material. Submitted on
  2/18/2016 v2: 2 new authors and 19 new materials added. Discussion of 4-band
  spin-3/2 fermions added, with emphasis on overlap with other materials of
  interest. Discussion of Zeeman splitting and other experimental implications
  added. v3: Accepted version. Minor typos fixed, title changed (formerly &quot;New
  fermions&quot;). Now 10+41pgs</comments><journal-ref>Science 10.1126/science.aaf5037 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1126/science.aaf5037</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In quantum field theory, we learn that fermions come in three varieties:
Majorana, Weyl, and Dirac. Here we show that in solid state systems this
classification is incomplete and find several additional types of crystal
symmetry-protected free fermionic excitations . We exhaustively classify linear
and quadratic 3-, 6- and 8- band crossings stabilized by space group symmetries
in solid state systems with spin-orbit coupling and time-reversal symmetry.
Several distinct types of fermions arise, differentiated by their degeneracies
at and along high symmetry points, lines, and surfaces. Some notable
consequences of these fermions are the presence of Fermi arcs in non-Weyl
systems and the existence of Dirac lines. Ab-initio calculations identify a
number of materials that realize these exotic fermions close to the Fermi
level.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04748</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04748</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nicholl</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Berger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smartt</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Margutti</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamble</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alexander</keyname><forenames>K. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>T. -W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inserra</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Arcavi</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blanchard</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cartier</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chambers</keyname><forenames>K. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Childress</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chornock</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cowperthwaite</keyname><forenames>P. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drout</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flewelling</keyname><forenames>H. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fraser</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gal-Yam</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Galbany</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harmanen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holoien</keyname><forenames>T. W. -S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosseinzadeh</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Howell</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jerkstrand</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kankare</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kochanek</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Z. -Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lunnan</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Magnier</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maguire</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McCully</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDonald</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Metzger</keyname><forenames>B. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Milisavljevic</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynolds</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saario</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shappee</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valenti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Villar</keyname><forenames>V. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Waters</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Young</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>SN 2015bn: a detailed multi-wavelength view of a nearby superluminous
  supernova</title><categories>astro-ph.SR astro-ph.CO astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Slightly updated to match published version</comments><journal-ref>2016, ApJ 826, 39</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/39</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present observations of SN 2015bn (= PS15ae = CSS141223-113342+004332 =
MLS150211-113342+004333), a Type I superluminous supernova (SLSN) at redshift
$z=0.1136$. As well as being one of the closest SLSNe I yet discovered, it is
intrinsically brighter ($M_U\approx-23.1$) and in a fainter galaxy
($M_B\approx-16.0$) than other SLSNe at $z\sim0.1$. We used this opportunity to
collect the most extensive dataset for any SLSN I to date, including
densely-sampled spectroscopy and photometry, from the UV to the NIR, spanning
$-$50 to +250 days from optical maximum. SN 2015bn fades slowly, but exhibits
surprising undulations in the light curve on a timescale of 30-50 days,
especially in the UV. The spectrum shows extraordinarily slow evolution except
for a rapid transformation between +7 and +20-30 days. No narrow emission lines
from slow-moving material are observed at any phase. We derive physical
properties including the bolometric luminosity, and find slow velocity
evolution and non-monotonic temperature and radial evolution. A deep radio
limit rules out a healthy off-axis gamma-ray burst, and places constraints on
the pre-explosion mass loss. The data can be consistently explained by a
$\gtrsim10\,{\rm M}_\odot$ stripped progenitor exploding with $\sim
10^{51}\,$erg kinetic energy, forming a magnetar with a spin-down timescale of
$\sim20$ days (thus avoiding a gamma-ray burst) that reheats the ejecta and
drives ionization fronts. The most likely alternative scenario -- interaction
with $\sim20\,{\rm M}_\odot$ of dense, inhomogeneous circumstellar material --
can be tested with continuing radio follow-up.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09243</id><created>2016-03-30</created><updated>2016-05-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hsu</keyname><forenames>Jen-Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Peng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lewandowski</keyname><forenames>Charles W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>D'Urso</keyname><forenames>Brian</forenames></author></authors><title>Cooling the Motion of Diamond Nanocrystals in a Magneto-Gravitational
  Trap in High Vacuum</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures, and 2 pages of supplementary information. One
  Reference was added. Typographical errors are corrected. Figure file format
  was changed for compactness</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 30125 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30125</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Levitated diamond nanocrystals with nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centres in high
vacuum have been proposed as a unique system for experiments in fundamental
quantum mechanics, including the generation of large quantum superposition
states and tests of quantum gravity. This system promises extreme isolation
from its environment while providing quantum control and sensing through the NV
centre spin. While optical trapping has been the most explored method of
levitation, recent results indicate that excessive optical heating of the
nanodiamonds under vacuum may make the method impractical with currently
available materials. Here, we study an alternative magneto-gravitational trap
for diamagnetic particles, such as diamond nanocrystals, with stable levitation
from atmospheric pressure to high vacuum. Magnetic field gradients from
permanent magnets confine the particle in two dimensions, while confinement in
the third dimension is gravitational. We demonstrate that feedback cooling of
the centre-of-mass motion of a trapped nanodiamond cluster results in cooling
of one degree of freedom to less than 1 K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.09399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.09399</id><created>2016-03-30</created><updated>2016-06-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Motazedifard</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bemani</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Naderi</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roknizadeh</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitali</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Force sensing based on coherent quantum noise cancellation in a hybrid
  optomechanical cavity with squeezed-vacuum injection</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13Pages, 5 Figures and 2 Appendix</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 ( 2016) 073040</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073040</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose and analyse a feasible experimental scheme for a quantum force
sensor based on the elimination of back-action noise through coherent quantum
noise cancellation (CQNC) in a hybrid atom-cavity optomechanical setup assisted
with squeezed vacuum injection. The force detector, which allows for a
continuous, broad-band detection of weak forces well below the standard quantum
limit (SQL), is formed by a single optical cavity simultaneously coupled to a
mechanical oscillator and to an ensemble of ultracold atoms. The latter acts as
a negative-mass oscillator so that atomic noise cancels exactly the back-action
noise from the mechanical oscillator due to destructive quantum interference.
Squeezed vacuum injection enforces this cancellation and allows to reach
sub-SQL sensitivity in a very wide frequency band, and at much lower input
laser powers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.04500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.04500</id><created>2016-04-15</created><updated>2016-06-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Azarhoosh</keyname><forenames>Pooya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frost</keyname><forenames>Jarvist M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McKechnie</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walsh</keyname><forenames>Aron</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Schilfgaarde</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Relativistic origin of slow electron-hole recombination in hybrid halide
  perovskite solar cells</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>19 pages, 2 figures. V3 updates text and SI</comments><journal-ref>APL Materials 4, 091501 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4955028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The hybrid perovskite CH3NH3PbI3 (MAPI) exhibits long minority-carrier
lifetimes and diffusion lengths. We show that slow recombination originates
from a spin-split indirect-gap. Large internal electric fields act on
spin-orbit-coupled band extrema, shifting band-edges to inequivalent
wavevectors, making the fundamental gap indirect. From a description of
photoluminescence within the quasiparticle self-consistent GW (QSGW)
approximation for MAPI, CdTe and GaAs, we predict carrier lifetime as a
function of light intensity and temperature. At operating conditions we find
radiative recombination in MAPI is reduced by a factor of more than 350
compared to direct gap behavior. The indirect gap is retained with dynamic
disorder.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07122</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07122</id><created>2016-04-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>Cai-Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Shude</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author></authors><title>The role of major gas-rich mergers on the evolution of galaxies from the
  blue cloud to the red sequence</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>32 pages, 8 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/826/1/30</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With the aim of exploring the fast evolutionary path from the blue cloud of
star-forming galaxies to the red sequence of quiescent galaxies in the local
universe, we select a local advanced merging infrared luminous and
ultraluminous galaxy (adv-merger (U)LIRGs) sample and perform careful dust
extinction corrections to investigate their positions in the SFR-$M_{\ast}$,
u-r and NUV-r color-mass diagrams. The sample consists of 89 (U)LIRGs at the
late merger stage, obtained from cross-correlating the IRAS Point Source
Catalog Redshift Survey and 1 Jy ULIRGs samples with the Sloan Digital Sky
Survey DR7 database. Our results show that $74\%\pm 5\%$ of adv-merger (U)LIRGs
are localized above the $1\, \sigma$ line of the local star-forming galaxy main
sequence. We also find that all adv-merger (U)LIRGs are more massive than and
as blue as the blue cloud galaxies after corrections of Galactic and internal
dust extinctions, with $95\%\pm 2\%$ and $81\%\pm 4\%$ of them outside the blue
cloud on the u-r and NUV-r color-mass diagrams, respectively. These results,
combined with the short timescale for exhausting the molecular gas reservoir in
adv-merger (U)LIRGs ($3\times 10^{7}$ to $3\times 10^{8}$ years), imply that
the adv-merger (U)LIRGs are likely at the starting point of the fast
evolutionary track previously proposed by several groups. While the number
density of adv-merger (U)LIRGs is only $\sim 0.1\%$ of the blue cloud
star-forming galaxies in the local universe, this evolutionary track may play a
more important role at high redshift.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01193</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2016-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lan</keyname><forenames>Shanquan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongbao</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Quantum Turbulence in Finite Temperature Bose-Einstein
  Condensates</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>16 pages, 9 figures, 1 table References added and clarifications made</comments><journal-ref>JHEP07(2016)092</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)092</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the various indications that holographic superfluid is BCS like
at the standard quantization but BEC like at the alternative quantization, we
have implemented the alternative quantization in the dynamical holographic
superfluid for the first time. With this accomplishment, we further initiate
the detailed investigation of quantum turbulence in finite temperature BEC by a
long time stable numerical simulation of bulk dynamics, which includes the two
body decay of vortex number caused by vortex pair annihilation, the onset of
superfluid turbulence signaled by Kolmogorov scaling law, and a direct energy
cascade demonstrated by injecting energy to the turbulent superfluid. All of
these results share the same patterns as the holographic superfluid at the
standard quantization, thus suggest that these should be universal features for
quantum turbulence at temperatures order of the critical temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03018</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03018</id><created>2016-05-10</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Finlayson</keyname><forenames>Samuel D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartlett</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-additivity of pair interactions in charged colloids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Final version</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 145, 034905 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4959122</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is general wisdom that the pair potential of charged colloids in a liquid
may be closely approximated by a Yukawa interaction, as predicted by the
classical Derjaguin-Landau-Verwey-Overbeek (DLVO) theory. We experimentally
determine the effective forces in a binary mixture of like-charged particles,
of species 1 and 2, with blinking optical tweezers. The measured forces are
consistent with a Yukawa pair potential but the (12) cross-interaction is not
equal to the geometric mean of the (11) and (22) like-interactions, as expected
from DLVO. The deviation is a function of the electrostatic screening length
and the size ratio, with the cross-interaction measured being consistently
weaker than DLVO predictions. The corresponding non-additivity parameter is
negative and grows in magnitude with increased size asymmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03878</id><created>2016-05-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Lodewyck</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bilicki</keyname><forenames>S&#x142;awomir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bookjans</keyname><forenames>Eva</forenames></author><author><keyname>Robyr</keyname><forenames>Jean-Luc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Chunyan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vallet</keyname><forenames>Gr&#xe9;goire</forenames></author><author><keyname>Targat</keyname><forenames>Rodolphe Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nicolodi</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coq</keyname><forenames>Yann Le</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;na</keyname><forenames>Jocelyne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abgrall</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenbusch</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bize</keyname><forenames>S&#xe9;bastien</forenames></author></authors><title>Optical to microwave clock frequency ratios with a nearly continuous
  strontium optical lattice clock</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>Metrologia 53, 1123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0026-1394/53/4/1123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Optical lattice clocks are at the forefront of frequency metrology. Both the
instability and systematic uncertainty of these clocks have been reported to be
two orders of magnitude smaller than the best microwave clocks. For this
reason, a redefinition of the SI second based on optical clocks seems possible
in the near future. However, the operation of optical lattice clocks has not
yet reached the reliability that microwave clocks have achieved so far. In this
paper, we report on the operation of a strontium optical lattice clock that
spans several weeks, with more than 80% uptime. We make use of this long
integration time to demonstrate a reproducible measurement of frequency ratios
between the strontium clock transition and microwave Cs primary and Rb
secondary frequency standards.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04015</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04015</id><created>2016-05-12</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fukui</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsugai</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>A spin pump characterized by entanglement Chern numbers</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. Soc. Jpn. 85, 083703 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.7566/JPSJ.85.083703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a spin pump on a two-leg ladder chain of the Rice--Mele model. To
characterize the spin pump, we propose the Chern number for the many-body
ground state of the entanglement Hamiltonian, which is referred to as the
entanglement Chern number. We show that this model has two phases distinguished
by the entanglement Chern numbers. These two phases can be experimentally
verified in cold atoms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04425</id><created>2016-05-14</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizing maximally singular phase-space distributions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013814 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013814</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Phase-space distributions are widely applied in quantum optics to access the
nonclassical features of radiations fields. In particular, the inability to
interpret the Glauber-Sudarshan distribution in terms of a classical
probability density is the fundamental benchmark for quantum light. However,
this phase-space distribution cannot be directly reconstructed for arbitrary
states, because of its singular behavior. In this work, we perform a
characterization of the Glauber-Sudarshan representation in terms of
distribution theory. We address important features of such distributions: (i)
the maximal degree of their singularities is studied, (ii) the ambiguity of
representation is shown, and (iii) their dual space for nonclassicality tests
is specified. In this view, we reconsider the methods for regularizing the
Glauber-Sudarshan distribution for verifying its nonclassicality. This
treatment is supported with comprehensive examples and counterexamples.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04550</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04550</id><created>2016-05-15</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larmier</keyname><forenames>Coline</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dumonteil</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malvagi</keyname><forenames>Fausto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mazzolo</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoia</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-size effects and percolation properties of Poisson geometries</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>15 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 012130 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.012130</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Random tessellations of the space represent a class of prototype models of
heterogeneous media, which are central in several applications in physics,
engineering and life sciences. In this work, we investigate the statistical
properties of $d$-dimensional isotropic Poisson geometries by resorting to
Monte Carlo simulation, with special emphasis on the case $d=3$. We first
analyse the behaviour of the key features of these stochastic geometries as a
function of the dimension $d$ and the linear size $L$ of the domain. Then, we
consider the case of Poisson binary mixtures, where the polyhedra are assigned
two `labels' with complementary probabilities. For this latter class of random
geometries, we numerically characterize the percolation threshold, the strength
of the percolating cluster and the average cluster size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.06975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.06975</id><created>2016-05-23</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Sperling</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogel</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Agarwal</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Operational definition of quantum correlations of light</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013833 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013833</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum features of correlated optical modes define a major aspect of the
nonclassicality in quantized radiation fields. However, the phase-sensitive
detection of a two-mode light field is restricted to interferometric setups and
local intensity measurements. Even the full reconstruction of the quantum state
of a single radiation mode relies on such detection layouts and the preparation
of a well-defined reference light field. In this work, we establish the notion
of the essential quantum correlations of two-mode light fields. It refers to
those quantum correlations which are measurable by a given device, i.e., the
accessible part of a nonclassical Glauber-Sudarshan phase-space distribution,
which does not depend on a global phase. Assuming a simple four-port
interferometer and photon-number-resolving detectors, we derive the
reconstruction method and nonclassicality criteria based on the
Laplace-transformed moment-generating function of the essential
quasiprobability. With this technique, we demonstrate that the essential
quantum correlations of a polarization tomography scheme are observable even if
the detectors are imperfect and cannot truly resolve the photon statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07605</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07605</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>&#xc5;str&#xf6;m</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonomi</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calliari</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calvini</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Checchia</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donzella</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faraci</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forsberg</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonella</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klinger</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#xd6;dqvist</keyname><forenames>L. Sundqvist</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagano</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramous</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urbani</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vanini</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zenoni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zumerle</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision measurements of Linear Scattering Density using Muon
  Tomography</title><categories>physics.ins-det</categories><comments>16 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Instrumentation, Volume 11, July 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1748-0221/11/07/P07010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that muon tomography can be used to precisely measure the
properties of various materials. The materials which have been considered have
been extracted from an experimental blast furnace, including carbon (coke) and
iron oxides, for which measurements of the linear scattering density relative
to the mass density have been performed with an absolute precision of 10%. We
report the procedures that are used in order to obtain such precision, and a
discussion is presented to address the expected performance of the technique
when applied to heavier materials. The results we obtain do not depend on the
specific type of material considered and therefore they can be extended to any
application.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08681</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08681</id><created>2016-05-27</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kannike</keyname><forenames>Kristjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelaggi</keyname><forenames>Giulio Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salvio</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strumia</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author></authors><title>The Higgs of the Higgs and the diphoton channel</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 4 figures; one figure added and title and other wording
  changed (version accepted by JHEP)</comments><report-no>CERN-PH-TH-2016-128, IFUP-TH/2016</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1607 (2016) 101</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  LHC results do not confirm conventional natural solutions to the Higgs mass
hierarchy problem, motivating alternative interpretations where a
hierarchically small weak scale is generated from a dimension-less quantum
dynamics. We propose weakly and strongly-coupled models where the field that
breaks classical scale invariance giving mass to itself and to the Higgs is
identified with a possible new resonance within the LHC reach. As an example,
we identify such resonance with the 750 GeV diphoton excess recently reported
by ATLAS and CMS. Such models can be extrapolated up to the Planck scale,
provide Dark Matter candidates and eliminate the SM vacuum instability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.02251</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.02251</id><created>2016-05-30</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fischer</keyname><forenames>Ulrich C.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Photon Spin and the Electrodynamic Origin of the charge of the
  Electron</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure, 1 table added, correction in eq 1,2; new
  numbering of equations, corrected derivation of electromagnetic properties of
  photon, modified derivation of electromagnetic origin of the charge of the
  electron, modified outline of quantum topology</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We recently performed experiments on the transfer of photon spin to electron
orbital angular momentum. For an interpretation of the experimental results we
used a classical electrodynamic model of the photon as a propagating
electromagnetic solitary wave which is developed in detail here. A linearly
polarized monochromatic photon is considered as a propagating solitary
electromagnetic wave of finite energy hf which carries an angular momentum
h/2pi with the frequency f and Plancks constant h. This model has, apart from
being a tool for an interpretation of our experimental results, far reaching
consequences of fundamental relevance and guides us to an outline to a unified
quantum theory of electromagnetism and gravitation including an explanation of
the electrodynamic origin of the quantized charge of an electron.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03526</id><created>2016-06-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>E. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cowie</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Songaila</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barger</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenwasser</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wold</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author></authors><title>An Ultraluminous Lyman Alpha Emitter with a Blue Wing at z=6.6</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, 1 table, accepted for publication in ApJ Letters</comments><journal-ref>2016 Astrophys.J. 825, L7</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/825/1/L7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the detection of the most luminous high-redshift Lyman Alpha
Emitting galaxy (LAE) yet seen, with log L(Ly alpha) = 43.9 ergs/s. The galaxy
-- COSMOS Lyman alpha 1, or COLA1 -- was detected in a search for
ultra-luminous LAEs with Hyper Suprime-Cam on the Subaru telescope. It was
confirmed to lie at z = 6.593 based on a Lyman alpha line detection obtained
from followup spectroscopy with the DEIMOS spectrograph on Keck2. COLA1 is the
first very high-redshift LAE to show a multi-component Lyman alpha line profile
with a blue wing, which suggests that it could lie in a highly ionized region
of the intergalactic medium and could have significant infall. If this
interpretation is correct, then ultra-luminous LAEs like COLA1 offer a unique
opportunity to determine the properties of the HII regions around these
galaxies which will help in understanding the ionization of the z ~ 7
intergalactic medium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08169</id><created>2016-06-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Sivankutty</keyname><forenames>Siddharth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsvirkun</keyname><forenames>Viktor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bouwmans</keyname><forenames>G&#xe9;raud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kogan</keyname><forenames>Dani</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oron</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andresen</keyname><forenames>Esben Ravn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rigneault</keyname><forenames>Herv&#xe9;</forenames></author></authors><title>Extended field-of-view in a lensless endoscope using an aperiodic
  multicore fiber</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Submitted to Optics Letters</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.41.003531</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate lensless endoscopy using coherent beam combining and aperiodic
multicore fibers (MCF). We show that diffracted orders, inherent to MCF with
periodically arranged cores, dramatically reduce the field of view (FoV) and
that randomness in MCF core positions can increase the FoV up to the
diffraction limit set by a single fiber core, while maintaining MCF
experimental feasibility. We demonstrate experimentally pixelation-free
lensless endoscopy imaging over a 120 micron FoV with an aperiodic MCF designed
with widely spaced cores. We show that this system is suitable to perform beam
scanning imaging by simply applying a tilt to the proximal wavefront.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.08566</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.08566</id><created>2016-06-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Gupta</keyname><forenames>Satyendra Nath</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pal</keyname><forenames>Anand</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muthu</keyname><forenames>D. V. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>P. S. Anil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sood</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Metallic monoclinic phase in VO$_2$ induced by electrochemical gating:
  in-situ Raman study</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>EPL, 115 (2016) 17001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/115/17001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report in-situ Raman scattering studies of electrochemically top gated
VO$_2$ thin film to address metal-insulator transition (MIT) under gating. The
room temperature monoclinic insulating phase goes to metallic state at a gate
voltage of 2.6 V. However, the number of Raman modes do not change with
electrolyte gating showing that the metallic phase is still monoclinic. The
high frequency Raman mode A$_g$(7) near 616 cm$^{-1}$ ascribed to V-O vibration
of bond length 2.06 \AA~ in VO$_6$ octahedra hardens with increasing gate
voltage and the B$_g$(3) mode near 654 cm$^{-1}$ softens. This shows that the
distortion of the VO$_6$ octahedra in the monoclinic phase decreases with
gating. The time dependent Raman data at fixed gate voltages of 1 V (for 50
minute, showing enhancement of conductivity by a factor of 50) and 2 V (for 130
minute, showing further increase in conductivity by a factor of 5) show similar
changes in high frequency Raman modes A$_g$(7) and B$_g$(3) as observed in
gating. This slow change in conductance together with Raman frequency changes
show that the governing mechanism for metalization is more likely to the
diffusion controlled oxygen vacancy formation due to the applied electric
field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09475</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09475</id><created>2016-06-30</created><authors><author><keyname>Snijders</keyname><forenames>Paul C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>&#x15e;en</keyname><forenames>Cengiz</forenames></author><author><keyname>McConnell</keyname><forenames>Michael P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ying-Zhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>May</keyname><forenames>Andrew F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herklotz</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Anthony T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ward</keyname><forenames>T. Zac</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamic defect correlations dominate activated electronic transport in
  SrTiO3</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6:30141 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep30141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Strontium titanate (SrTiO3, STO) is a critically important material for the
study of emergent electronic phases in complex oxides, as well as for the
development of applications based on their heterostructures. Despite the large
body of knowledge on STO, there are still many uncertainties regarding the role
of defects in the properties of STO, including their influence on
ferroelectricity in bulk STO and ferromagnetism in STO-based heterostructures.
We present a detailed analysis of the decay of persistent photoconductivity in
STO single crystals with defect concentrations that are relatively low but
significantly affect their electronic properties. The results show that
photo-activated electron transport cannot be described by a superposition of
the properties due to independent point defects as current models suggest but
is, instead, governed by defect complexes that interact through dynamic
correlations. These results emphasize the importance of defect correlations for
activated electronic transport properties of semiconducting and insulating
perovskite oxides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01405</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01405</id><created>2016-07-05</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gayen</keyname><forenames>Sirshendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aggarwal</keyname><forenames>Leena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheet</keyname><forenames>Goutam</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Tip induced unconventional superconductivity on Weyl
  semimetal TaAs&quot; [arXiv:1607.00513]</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>v2 corrected a claim of simultaneity in arXiv and v3 gives reference
  to a paper showing correct ballistic regime data on TaAs</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recently, Wang $et$ $al.$ have reported the observation of &quot;unconventional
superconductivity&quot; in the Weyl semimetal TaAs [arXiv:1607.00513]. The authors
have written &quot;\textit{A conductance plateau and sharp double dips are observed
in the point contact spectra, indicating p-wave like unconventional
superconductivity. Furthermore, the zero bias conductance peak in low
temperature regime is detected, suggesting potentially the existence of
Majorana zero modes. The experimentally observed tunneling spectra can be
interpreted with a novel mirror-symmetry protected topological superconductor
induced in TaAs, which can exhibit zero bias and double finite bias peaks, and
double conductance dips in the measurements}.&quot; In this comment we show that for
a superconducting point contact, the features like a zero-bias conductance
peak, a plateau and single or multiple conductance dips might arise due to
simple contact-heating related effects. Such features are routinely observed in
point contacts involving a wide variety of superconductors when the experiments
are not performed in the right regime of mesoscopic transport. We also show
that the data presented by Wang $et$ $al.$ in a single transport regime of
point contact do not confirm tip induced superconductivity (TISC). Even if it
is assumed that Wang $et$ $al.$ achieved TISC on TaAs, all the spectra that
they have reported show striking similarities with the type of spectra expected
in thermal regime of transport. Such data cannot be used for extracting any
spectroscopic information and based on such data any discussion on &quot;p-wave&quot;
superconductivity or the emergence of Majorana modes should be considered
invalid. This version (v2) also includes a brief discussion on the response of
Wang $et$ $al.$ to the first version (v1) of this comment. Correct ballistic
regime data on TaAs point contacts can be found in arXiv:1607.05131 (2016).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01620</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01620</id><created>2016-07-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Sandev</keyname><forenames>Trifce</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iomin</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xe9;ndez</keyname><forenames>Vicen&#xe7;</forenames></author></authors><title>L\'evy processes on a generalized fractal comb</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and Theoretical 49 (2016)
  355001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/35/355001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Comb geometry, constituted of a backbone and fingers, is one of the most
simple paradigm of a two dimensional structure, where anomalous diffusion can
be realized in the framework of Markov processes. However, the intrinsic
properties of the structure can destroy this Markovian transport. These effects
can be described by the memory and spatial kernels. In particular, the fractal
structure of the fingers, which is controlled by the spatial kernel in both the
real and the Fourier spaces, leads to the L\'evy processes (L\'evy flights) and
superdiffusion. This generalization of the fractional diffusion is described by
the Riesz space fractional derivative. In the framework of this generalized
fractal comb model, L\'evy processes are considered, and exact solutions for
the probability distribution functions are obtained in terms of the Fox
$H$-function for a variety of the memory kernels, and the rate of the
superdiffusive spreading is studied by calculating the fractional moments. For
a special form of the memory kernels, we also observed a competition between
long rests and long jumps. Finally, we considered the fractional structure of
the fingers controlled by a Weierstrass function, which leads to the power-law
kernel in the Fourier space. It is a special case, when the second moment
exists for superdiffusion in this competition between long rests and long
jumps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02540</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02540</id><created>2016-07-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Leach</keyname><forenames>K. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garrett</keyname><forenames>P. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ball</keyname><forenames>G. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bender</keyname><forenames>P. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bildstein</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brown</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burbadge</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faestermann</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hadinia</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Holt</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laffoley</keyname><forenames>A. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jamieson</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jigmeddorj</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Radich</keyname><forenames>A. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rand</keyname><forenames>E. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stroberg</keyname><forenames>S. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Svensson</keyname><forenames>C. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Towner</keyname><forenames>I. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wirth</keyname><forenames>H. -F.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Search for $0^+$ States in $^{50}$Cr: Implications for the
  Superallowed $\beta$-decay of $^{50}$Mn</title><categories>nucl-ex nucl-th</categories><comments>Accepted for Publication in Physical Review C as a Rapid
  Communication</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Rev.C94:011304,2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.011304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A $^{52}$Cr$(p,t)$$^{50}$Cr two-neutron pickup reaction was performed using
the Q3D magnetic spectrograph at the Maier-Leibnitz-Laboratorium in Garching,
Germany. Excited states in $^{50}$Cr were observed up to an excitation energy
of 5.3 MeV. Despite significantly increased sensitivity and resolution over
previous work, no evidence of the previously assigned first excited $0^+$ state
was found. As a result, the $0^+_2$ state is reassigned at an excitation energy
of $E_x=3895.0(5)$ keV in $^{50}$Cr. This reassignment directly impacts direct
searches for a non-analogue Fermi $\beta^+$ decay branch in $^{50}$Mn. These
results also show better systematic agreement with the theoretical predictions
for the $0^+$ state spectrum in $^{50}$Cr using the same formalism as the
isospin-symmetry-breaking correction calculations for superallowed nuclei. The
experimental data are also compared to $ab$-$initio$ shell-model predictions
using the IM-SRG formalism based on $NN$ and $3N$ forces from chiral-EFT in the
$pf$-shell for the first time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05745</id><created>2016-07-19</created><updated>2016-07-22</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hanson</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-High Energy Astrophysical Neutrino Detection, and the Search for
  Lorentz Invariance Violations</title><categories>astro-ph.HE hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A growing class of ultra-high energy neutrino (UHE-nu) observatories based on
the Askaryan effect and Antarctic ice is able to search for Lorentz invariance
violation (LIV). The ARA, ARIANNA, ANITA and EVA collaborations have the power
to constrain the Standard Model Extension (SME) by measuring the flux and
energy distribution of neutrinos created through the GZK process. The future
expansion of ARA, at the South Pole, pushes the discovery potential further.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06469</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06469</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Campione</keyname><forenames>Salvatore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Basilio</keyname><forenames>Lorena I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warne</keyname><forenames>Larry K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Langston</keyname><forenames>William L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luk</keyname><forenames>Ting S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wendt</keyname><forenames>Joel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reno</keyname><forenames>John L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keeler</keyname><forenames>Gordon A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brener</keyname><forenames>Igal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinclair</keyname><forenames>Michael B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Broken symmetry dielectric resonators for high quality-factor Fano
  metasurfaces</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a new approach to dielectric metasurface design that relies on a
single resonator per unit cell and produces robust, high quality-factor Fano
resonances. Our approach utilizes symmetry breaking of highly symmetric
resonator geoemetries, such as cubes, to induce couplings between the otherwise
orthogonal resonator modes. In particular, we design perturbations that couple
&quot;bright&quot; dipole modes to &quot;dark&quot; dipole modes whose radiative decay is
suppressed by local field effects in the array. Our approach is widely scalable
from the near-infrared to radio frequencies. We first unravel the Fano
resonance behavior through numerical simulations of a germanium resonator-based
metasurface that achieved a quality-factor of ~1300 at ~10.8 um. Then, we
present two experimental demonstrations operating in the near-infrared (~1 um):
a silicon-based implementation that achieved a quality-factor of ~350; and a
gallium arsenide-based structure that achieves a quality-factor of ~600 - the
highest near-infrared quality-factor experimentally demonstrated to date with
this kind of metasurfaces. Importantly, large electromagnetic field
enhancements appear within the resonators at the Fano resonant frequencies. We
envision that combining high-quality factor, high field enhancement resonances
with nonlinear and active/gain materials such as gallium arsenide will lead to
new classes of active optical devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06472</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06472</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xiawei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loeb</keyname><forenames>Abraham</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasar-driven outflows account for the missing extragalactic gamma-ray
  background</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Published in Nature Physics</comments><doi>10.1038/nphys3837</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of the extragalactic $\gamma$-ray background permeating throughout
the Universe remains a mystery forty years after its discovery. The
extrapolated population of blazars can account for only half of the background
radiation at the energy range of ~ 0.1-10 GeV. Here we show that quasar-driven
outflows generate relativistic protons that produce the missing component of
the extragalactic $\gamma$-ray background and naturally match its spectral
fingerprint, with a generic break above ~ 1 GeV. The associated $\gamma$-ray
sources are too faint to be detected individually, explaining why they had not
been identified so far. However, future radio observations may image their
shock fronts directly. Our best fit to the Fermi-LAT observations of
extragalactic $\gamma$-ray background spectrum provides constraints on the
outflow parameters that agree with observations of these outflows and
theoretical predictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06479</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06479</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Fattahi</keyname><forenames>Azadeh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Navarro</keyname><forenames>Julio F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sawala</keyname><forenames>Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenk</keyname><forenames>Carlos S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sales</keyname><forenames>Laura V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oman</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaller</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>The cold dark matter content of Galactic dwarf spheroidals: no cores, no
  failures, no problem</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>13 pages + 3 pages Appendix, 10 Figures, Submitted to MNRAS</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the dark matter content of satellite galaxies in Lambda-CDM
cosmological hydrodynamical simulations of the Local Group from the APOSTLE
project. We find excellent agreement between simulation results and estimates
for the 9 brightest Galactic dwarf spheroidals (dSphs) derived from their
stellar velocity dispersions and half-light radii. Tidal stripping plays an
important role by gradually removing dark matter from the outside in, affecting
in particular fainter satellites and systems of larger-than-average size for
their luminosity. Our models suggest that tides have significantly reduced the
dark matter content of Can Ven I, Sextans, Carina, and Fornax, a prediction
that may be tested by comparing them with field galaxies of matching luminosity
and size. Uncertainties in observational estimates of the dark matter content
of individual dwarfs have been underestimated in the past, at times
substantially. We use our improved estimates to revisit the `too-big-to-fail'
problem highlighted in earlier N-body work. We reinforce and extend our
previous conclusion that the APOSTLE simulations show no sign of this problem.
The resolution does not require `cores' in the dark mass profiles, but, rather,
relies on revising assumptions and uncertainties in the interpretation of
observational data and accounting for `baryon effects' in the theoretical
modelling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06480</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Breed</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venter</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harding</keyname><forenames>A. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Very-high energy emission from pulsars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, conference proceedings of SAIP 2015</comments><journal-ref>Proceedings of the 60th Annual Conference of the South African
  Institute of Physics (2015), ed. by M. Chithambo and A. Venter, pp. 278 -
  283, ISBN: 978-0-620-70714-5, http://events.saip.org.za</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The vast majority of pulsars detected by the Fermi Large Area Telescope (LAT)
display exponentially cutoff spectra with cutoffs falling in a narrow band
around a few GeV. Early spectral modelling predicted spectral cutoffs at
energies of up to 100 GeV, assuming curvature radiation. It was therefore not
expected that pulsars would be visible in the very-high energy (VHE) regime
(&gt;100 GeV). The VERITAS announcement of the detection of pulsed emission from
the Crab pulsar at energies up to 400 GeV (and now up to 1.5 TeV as detected by
MAGIC) therefore raised important questions about our understanding of the
electrodynamics and local environment of pulsars. H.E.S.S. has now detected
pulsed emission from the Vela pulsar down to tens of GeV, making this the
second pulsar detected by a ground-based Cherenkov telescope. Deep upper limits
have also been obtained by VERITAS and MAGIC for the Geminga pulsar. We will
review the latest developments in VHE pulsar science, including an overview of
the latest observations, refinements, and extensions to radiation models and
magnetic field structures, and the implementation of new radiation mechanisms.
This will assist us in understanding the VHE emission detected from the Crab
pulsar, and predicting the level of VHE emission expected from other pulsars,
which is very important for the upcoming CTA.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06482</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Percy</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deibert</keyname><forenames>Emily</forenames></author></authors><title>Studies of the Long Secondary Periods in Pulsating Red Giants</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Submitted to JAAVSO</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have used systematic, sustained visual observations from the AAVSO
International Database, and the AAVSO time-series analysis package VSTAR to
study the unexplained &quot;long secondary periods&quot; (LSPs) in 27 pulsating red
giants. In our sample, the LSPs range from 479 to 2967 days, and are on average
8.1 +/- 1.3 times the pulsation period. There is no evidence for more than one
LSP in each star. In stars with both the fundamental and first overtone radial
period present, the LSP is more often about 10 times the latter. The visual
amplitudes of the LSPs are typically 0.1 magnitude and do not correlate with
the LSP. The phase curves tend to be sinusoidal, but at least two are sawtooth.
The LSPs are stable, within their errors, over the timespan of our data, which
is typically 25,000 days. The amplitudes, however, vary by up to a factor of
two or more on a timescale of roughly 20-30 LSPs. There is no obvious
difference between the behavior of the carbon (C) stars and the normal oxygen
(M) stars. Previous multicolor photoelectric observations showed that the LSP
color variations are similar to those of the pulsation period, and of the LSPs
in the Magellanic Clouds, and not like those of eclipsing stars. We note that
the LSPs are similar to the estimated rotation periods of the stars, though the
latter have large uncertainties. This suggests that the LSP phenomenon may be a
form of modulated rotational variability.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06486</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06486</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Yesiltas</keyname><forenames>Ozlem</forenames></author></authors><title>Position Dependent Mass Approach and Quantization for a Torus Lagrangian</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have shown that a Lagrangian for a torus surface can yield second order
nonlinear differential equations using the Euler-Lagrange formulation. It is
seen that these second order nonlinear differential equations can be
transformed into the nonlinear quadratic and Mathews-Lakshmanan equations using
the position dependent mass approach developed by Mustafa for the classical
systems. Then, we have applied the quantization procedure to the nonlinear
quadratic and Mathews-Lakshmanan equations and found their exact solutions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06487</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06487</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Dumusque</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author></authors><title>Radial Velocity Fitting Challenge. I. Simulating the data set including
  realistic stellar radial-velocity signals</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>23 pages, 16 figures, accepted for publication in Astronomy and
  Astrophysics</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201628672</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stellar signals are the main limitation for precise radial-velocity (RV)
measurements. These signals arise from the photosphere of the stars. The m/s
perturbation created by these signals prevents the detection and mass
characterization of small-mass planetary candidates such as Earth-twins.
Several methods have been proposed to mitigate stellar signals in RV
measurements. However, without precisely knowing the stellar and planetary
signals in real observations, it is extremely difficult to test the efficiency
of these methods.
  The goal of the RV fitting challenge is to generate simulated RV data
including stellar and planetary signals and to perform a blind test within the
community to test the efficiency of the different methods proposed to recover
planetary signals despite stellar signals.
  In this first paper, we describe the simulation used to model the
measurements of the RV fitting challenge. Each simulated planetary system
includes the signals from instrumental noise, stellar oscillations,
granulation, supergranulation, stellar activity, and observed and simulated
planetary systems. In addition to RV variations, this simulation also models
the effects of instrumental noise and stellar signals on activity observables
obtained by HARPS-type high-resolution spectrographs, that is, the calcium
activity index log(R'hk) and the bisector span and full width at half maximum
of the cross-correlation function.
  We publish the 15 systems used for the RV fitting challenge including the
details about the planetary systems that were injected into each of them (data
available at CDS and here: https://rv-challenge.wikispaces.com.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06492</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Hoai-Minh</forenames></author></authors><title>Cloaking an arbitrary object via anomalous localized resonance: the
  cloak is independent of the object</title><categories>math-ph math.AP math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we present various schemes of cloaking an arbitrary objects
via anomalous localized resonance and provide their analysis in two and three
dimensions. This is a way to cloak an object using negative index materials in
which the cloaking device is independent of the object. As a result, we show
that in two dimensional quasistatic regime an annular plasmonic structure $-I$
cloaks small but finite size objects near by. We also discuss its connections
with superlensing and cloaking using complementary media. In particular, we
confirm the possibility that a lens can act like a cloak and conversely. This
possibility was raised about a decade ago in the literature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06500</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Ashoke</forenames></author></authors><title>One Loop Mass Renormalization of Unstable Particles in Superstring
  Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>LaTeX; 38 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Most of the massive states in superstring theory are expected to undergo mass
renormalization at one loop order. Typically these corrections should contain
imaginary parts, indicating that the states are unstable against decay into
lighter particles. However in such cases, direct computation of the
renormalized mass using superstring perturbation theory yields divergent
result. Previous approaches to this problem involve various analytic
continuation techniques, or deforming the integral over the moduli space of the
torus with two punctures into the complexified moduli space near the boundary.
In this paper we use insights from string field theory to describe a different
approach that gives manifestly finite result for the mass shift satisfying
unitarity relations. The procedure is applicable to all states of
(compactified) type II and heterotic string theories. We illustrate this by
computing the one loop correction to the mass of the first massive state on the
leading Regge trajectory in SO(32) heterotic string theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06501</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06501</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Malcomson</keyname><forenames>Matthew</forenames></author></authors><title>Momentum Evolution Numerics of an Impurity in a Quantum Quench</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>PhD Thesis, 96 pages, 39 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A discussion on the momentum evolution of an impurity interacting via a
finite delta potential repulsion with a non-interacting fermionic background
gas is presented. It has recently been shown that the momentum evolution of
this system displays two interesting features, namely a non-zero thermalised
value and a long-lived quantum mechanical oscillation around this plateau named
&quot;quantum flutter&quot; [Mathy, Zvonarev, Demler, Nat. Phys. 2012]. We discuss
revivals in the momentum of the impurity, which have been seen before but not
yet thoroughly investigated. Subsequently it is shown the quantum flutter and
revivals are caused by disjoint sets of eigenstate transitions, and this fact
is used to interpret some of their aspects. This attribution of momentum
features to different eigenstate subsets allows quantitative reproduction of
these features with much less computational expense than has so far been
possible. Finally some results on the distribution of the momentum of
eigenstates and their relation to the momentum of the impurity once the system
has been thermalised are presented along with a discussion on the time averaged
infinite time value of the momentum and its comparison to different eigenstate
subsets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06522</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Locatelli</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pierno</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Baldovin</keyname><forenames>Fulvio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Orlandini</keyname><forenames>Enzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Yizhou</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pagliara</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Single-file escape of colloidal particles from microfluidic channels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 038001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.038001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Single-file diffusion is a ubiquitous physical process exploited by living
and synthetic systems to exchange molecules with their environment. It is
paramount quantifying the escape time needed for single files of particles to
exit from constraining synthetic channels and biological pores. This quantity
depends on complex cooperative effects, whose predominance can only be
established through a strict comparison between theory and experiments. By
using colloidal particles, optical manipulation, microfluidics, digital
microscopy and theoretical analysis we uncover the self-similar character of
the escape process and provide closed-formula evaluations of the escape time.
We find that the escape time scales inversely with the diffusion coefficient of
the last particle to leave the channel. Importantly, we find that at the
investigated {\bf microscale}, bias forces as tiny as $10^{-15}\;{\rm N}$
determine the magnitude of the escape time by drastically reducing
interparticle collisions. Our findings provide crucial guidelines to optimize
the design of micro- and nano-devices for a variety of applications including
drug delivery, particle filtering and transport in geometrical constrictions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06548</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Xu-Guang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Jie</forenames></author></authors><title>The Symmetry of Current of the Coherent State From the View of O(3)
  sigma-model</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Acta Physica Polonica A Vol122, 2012 31-37</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we apply the reduced density trajectory, phi-mapping
topological current theory and Ginzberg-Landau model to study the current of
the coherent state. We give the new expression of the current of the coherent
state. Based on this expression, the symmetry of the coherence is studied. We
find that the current of the coherent state corresponds to the supercurrent of
two-condensate system. The partial wave functions of the coherence carry new
charges and their interaction is mediated by new U(1) gauge potential.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06552</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06552</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Kobakhidze</keyname><forenames>Archil</forenames></author></authors><title>Heavy axion in asymptotically safe QCD</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>4 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Assuming QCD exhibits an interacting fixed-point behaviour in the ultraviolet
regime, I argue that the axion can be substantially heavier than in the
conventional case of asymptotically free QCD due to the enhanced contribution
of small size instantons to its mass.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06559</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06559</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishihara</keyname><forenames>Hiroki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harada</keyname><forenames>Masayasu</forenames></author></authors><title>Relations among pionic decays of spin-1 mesons from an SU(4)$\times$U(1)
  emergent symmetry in QCD</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>17 pages, 3 figures, 8 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by recent results by lattice analysis, we assume that the spin-1
mesons of $\left( \rho, \omega, a_1, \rho', \omega', b_1, f_1, h_1\right)$ make
a representation of $\mathbf{16}$ of U(4) emergent symmetry in two-flavor QCD
when the chiral symmetry is not broken. We study the decay properties of the
spin-1 mesons by using a chiral model with an SU(4)$\times$U(1) hidden local
symmetry. We first show that, since the SU(4) symmetry is spontaneously broken
together with the chiral symmetry, each coupling of the interaction among one
pion and two spin-1 mesons is proportional to the mass difference of the
relevant spin-1 mesons similarly to the Goldberger-Treiman relation. In
addition, some of one-pion couplings are related with each other by the SU(4)
symmetry. We further show that there is a relation among the mass of $\rho'$
meson, the $\rho'\pi\pi$ coupling and the $\rho'$-photon mixing strength as
well as the Kawarabayashi-Suzuki-Riazuddin-Fayyazuddin relation for the $\rho$
meson. From the relations, we give numerical predictions such as ratios of the
spin-1 meson decay widths, which are compared with future experiments for
testing the existence of the U(4) emergent symmetry.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06570</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06570</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Patra</keyname><forenames>Atanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakrobarty</keyname><forenames>Monodeep</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Anushree</forenames></author></authors><title>Mapping of Electronic Band Gap along the Axis of Single InAs/InSbxAs1-x
  Heterostructured Nanowire</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the graded electronic band gap along the axis of individual
heterostructured WZ-ZB InAs/InSb0.12As0.88 nanowires. Resonance Raman imaging
has been exploited to map the axial variation in the second excitation gap
energy (E1) at the high symmetry point (L point) of the Brillouin zone. We
relate the origin of the observed evolution of the gap energy to the fine
tuning of the alloy composition from the tip towards the interface of the
nanowire. The electronic band structures of InAs, InSb and InSbxAs1-x alloy
systems at x=0.125, 0.25, 0.50, 0.75 and 0.875, using all electron density
functional theory code Wien2k, are reported. The measured band gap along the
axis of the InAs/InSb0.12As0.88 nanowire is correlated with the calculated gap
energy at the A point and the L point of the Brillouin zone for InAs and
InSb0.125As0.875, respectively. We draw a one-to-one correspondence between the
variation of the E1 gap and the fundamental E0 gap in the calculated electronic
band structure and propose the graded fundamental gap energy across the axis of
the nanowire.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06575</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06575</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>S. -F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>W. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kung</keyname><forenames>H. -H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>H. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>P. -C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blumberg</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective excitations of dynamic Fermi surface deformations in
  BaFe$_2$(As$_{0.5}$P$_{0.5}$)$_2$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use electronic Raman scattering to study the low-energy excitations in
BaFe$_2$(As$_{0.5}$P$_{0.5}$)$_2$ ($T_c \approx 16$ K) samples. In addition to
a superconducting pair breaking peak (2$\Delta=6.7$ meV) in the A$_{1g}$
channel with a linear tail towards zero energy, suggesting a nodal gap
structure, we detect spectral features associated to Pomeranchuk oscillations
in the A$_{1g}$, B$_{1g}$ and B$_{2g}$ channels. We argue that the small Fermi
energy of the system is an essential condition for these Pomeranchuk
oscillations to be underdamped. The Pomeranchuk oscillations have the same
frequencies in the B$_{1g}$ and B$_{2g}$ channels, which we explain by the
mixing of these symmetries resulting from the removal of the $\sigma_v$ and
$\sigma_v$ symmetry planes due to a large As/P disorder. Interestingly, we show
that the temperature at which the peaks corresponding to the Pomeranchuk
oscillations get underdamped is consistent with the non-Fermi liquid to Femi
liquid crossover determined by transport, suggesting that the Pomeranchuk
instability plays an important role in the low-energy physics of the Fe-based
superconductors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06585</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06585</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Jakobczyk</keyname><forenames>Lech</forenames></author></authors><title>Maximal mutual correlation: an algebraic measure of correlations in
  bipartite quantum systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We introduce an algebraic measure of correlations in bipartite quantum
systems. The proposed quantity, called maximal mutual correlation, provides the
information how much a given state differs from the product state of its
marginals. In contrast to the entanglement or quantum discord, maximal mutual
correlation can be non - zero for some classically correlated quantum states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06595</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06595</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Naldoni</keyname><forenames>Alberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guler</keyname><forenames>Urcan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhuoxian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marelli</keyname><forenames>Marcello</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malara</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meng</keyname><forenames>Xiangeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kildishev</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boltasseva</keyname><forenames>Alexandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shalaev</keyname><forenames>Vladimir M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Enhancing Hot Carrier Collection for Solar Water Splitting with
  Plasmonic Titanium Nitride</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>31 pages (Manuscript+Supporting Information), 4 figures, 13
  supplementary figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The use of hot electrons generated from the decay of surface plasmons is a
new paradigm to increase the conversion yield in solar energy technologies.
Titanium nitride (TiN) is an emerging plasmonic ceramic that offers
compatibility with CMOS technology, corrosion resistance, as well as mechanical
strength and durability thus outperforming noble metals (i.e., Au, Ag) in terms
of cost, mechanical, chemical and thermal stability. Here, we show that
plasmonic TiN nanoparticles produce 25% higher photocurrent enhancement than Au
nanoparticles decorated on TiO2 nanowires for photoelectrochemical water
splitting. Our results highlight that TiN offers superior performance in hot
carrier generation due to enhanced absorption efficiency, increased electron
mean free path, and the ability to form an Ohmic junction with TiO2, thus
enabling an extremely efficient electron collection not achievable with
plasmonic Au nanoparticles. Our findings show that transition metal nitrides
enable practical plasmonic devices with enhanced performance for solar energy
conversion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06601</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Sigismondi</keyname><forenames>Costantino</forenames></author></authors><title>Lo Gnomone Clementino Astronomia Meridiana in Basilica</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.EP physics.hist-ph</categories><comments>78 pages, with color images and photo. Text in Italian</comments><journal-ref>Published in GERBERTVS 7 ISSN 2038-3675 (2014) pp. 3-80</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Clementine Gnomon realized in 1702 by the astronomer Francesco Bianchini
(1661-1729) upon the will of Pope Clement XI (1700-1721) in the Basilica of
Santa Maria degli Angeli in Rome is fully reviewed about its scientific
functions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06616</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06616</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Krutitsky</keyname><forenames>Konstantin V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Osterloh</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xfc;tzhold</keyname><forenames>Ralf</forenames></author></authors><title>Avalanche of entanglement and correlations at quantum phase transitions</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ground-state entanglement in the quantum Ising model with
nearest neighbor ferromagnetic coupling $J$ and find a sequential increase of
entanglement depth with growing $J$. This entanglement avalanche starts with
two-point entanglement, as measured by the concurrence, and continues via the
three-tangle and four-tangle, until finally, deep in the ferromagnetic phase
for $J=\infty$, arriving at pure $\ell$-partite (GHZ type) entanglement of all
$\ell$ spins. Comparison with the two, three, and four-point correlations
reveals a similar sequence and shows strong ties to the above entanglement
measures for small $J$. However, we also find a partial inversion of the
hierarchy, where the four-point correlation exceeds the three- and two-point
correlations, well before the critical point is reached. Qualitatively similar
behavior is also found for the Bose-Hubbard model, suggesting that this is a
general feature of a quantum phase transition. This should have far reaching
consequences for approximations starting from a mean-field limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06630</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06630</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Iacob</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author></authors><title>Remarks on the geometric quantization of a class of harmonic oscillator
  type potentials</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The conditions that must be fulfilled by a certain physical system to apply
geometric quantization prescription on it are investigated. These terms are
sought as mathematical requirements, which can be traced in an analysis of
integrable systems, from the perspective of both potential function and
Hamiltonian vector field. The answer is found in momentum map critical points.
Basically, a certain disposal of points that allow a momentum map $C^*$
isomorphism, of observables, with harmonic oscillator momentum map enforce
geometric quantization rules. Following the general theory, two newly presented
examples, which exhibits these properties, are quantified through geometric
quantization prescription. The Lennard-Jones' type potential is one of the
examples, it is known as describing molecules in interaction. We end with a
third example that shows the local isomorphism of potentials do not induce
$C^*$ isomorphism of observables.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06633</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06633</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ca&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Acu&#xf1;a</keyname><forenames>Evelyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cari&#xf1;e</keyname><forenames>Jaime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Barra</keyname><forenames>Johanna F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez</keyname><forenames>Esteban S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xavier</keyname><forenames>Guilherme B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>Gustavo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cabello</keyname><forenames>Ad&#xe1;n</forenames></author></authors><title>Experimental demonstration of the connection between quantum
  contextuality and graph theory</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012337 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012337</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a method that exploits a connection between quantum contextuality
and graph theory to reveal any form of quantum contextuality in high-precision
experiments. We use this technique to identify a graph which corresponds to an
extreme form of quantum contextuality unnoticed before and test it using
high-dimensional quantum states encoded in the linear transverse momentum of
single photons. Our results open the door to the experimental exploration of
quantum contextuality in all its forms, including those needed for quantum
computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06650</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06650</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Bambusi</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Reducibility of 1-d Schr\&quot;odinger equation with time quasiperiodic
  unbounded perturbations, II</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>37K55, 35J10</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the Schr\&quot;odinger equation on $\R$ with a potential behaving as
$x^{2l}$ at infinity, $l\in[1,+\infty)$ and with a small time quasiperiodic
perturbation. We prove that, if the perturbation belongs to a class of
unbounded symbols including smooth potentials and magnetic type terms with
controlled growth at infinity, then the system is reducible.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06663</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06663</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Hendi</keyname><forenames>Seyed Hossein</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahiyan</keyname><forenames>Shahram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panah</keyname><forenames>Behzad Eslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Faizal</keyname><forenames>Mir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Momennia</keyname><forenames>Mehrab</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical behavior of charged black holes in Gauss-Bonnet gravity`s
  rainbow</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 8 figures, published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94 (2016) no.2, 024028</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Following an earlier study regarding Gauss-Bonnet-Maxwell black holes in the
presence of gravity's rainbow [S. H. Hendi and M. Faizal, Phys. Rev. D 92,
044027 (2015)], in this paper, we will consider all constants as energy
dependent ones. The geometrical and thermodynamical properties of this
generalization are studied and the validation of the first law of
thermodynamics is examined. Next, through the use of proportionality between
cosmological constant and thermodynamical pressure, van der Waals-like behavior
of these black holes in extended phase space is investigated. An interesting
critical behavior for sets of rainbow functions in this case is reported. Also,
the critical behavior of uncharged and charged solutions is analyzed and it is
shown that the generalization to a charged case puts an energy dependent
restriction on values of different parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06670</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06670</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Olmo</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonsingular black holes in Palatini extensions of General Relativity</title><categories>hep-th gr-qc</categories><comments>37 pages, 3 figures. Lecture notes published as a chapter in the book
  &quot;Theoretical Frontiers in Black Holes and Cosmology&quot;, Springer Proceedings in
  Physics, Eds. R. Kallosh and E. Orazi, (2016)</comments><report-no>IFIC/16-53</report-no><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-31352-8_5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An introduction to extended theories of gravity formulated in metric-affine
(or Palatini) spaces is presented. Focusing on spherically symmetric
configurations with electric fields, we will see that in these theories the
central singularity present in General Relativity is generically replaced by a
wormhole structure. The resulting space-time becomes geodesically complete and,
therefore, can be regarded as non-singular. We illustrate these properties
considering two different models, namely, a quadratic $f(R)$ theory and a
Born-Infeld like gravity theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06673</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Sendetskyi</keyname><forenames>Oles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anghinolfi</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scagnoli</keyname><forenames>Valerio</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;ller</keyname><forenames>Gunnar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leo</keyname><forenames>Na&#xeb;mi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alberca</keyname><forenames>Aurora</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kohlbrecher</keyname><forenames>Joachim</forenames></author><author><keyname>L&#xfc;ning</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Staub</keyname><forenames>Urs</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heyderman</keyname><forenames>Laura Jane</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic diffuse scattering in artificial kagome spin ice</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures;
  http://journals.aps.org/prb/abstract/10.1103/PhysRevB.93.224413</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review B 93, 224413 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.224413</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The study of magnetic correlations in dipolar-coupled nanomagnet systems with
synchrotron x-ray scattering provides a means to uncover emergent phenomena and
exotic phases, in particular in systems with thermally active magnetic moments.
From the diffuse signal of soft x-ray resonant magnetic scattering, we have
measured magnetic correlations in a highly dynamic artificial kagome spin ice
with sub-70-nm Permalloy nanomagnets. On comparing experimental scattering
patterns with Monte Carlo simulations based on a needle-dipole model, we
conclude that kagome ice I phase correlations exist in our experimental system
even in the presence of moment fluctuations, which is analogous to bulk spin
ice and spin liquid behavior. In addition, we describe the emergence of
quasi-pinch-points in the magnetic diffuse scattering in the kagome ice I
phase. These quasi-pinch-points bear similarities to the fully developed pinch
points with singularities of a magnetic Coulomb phase, and continually evolve
into the latter on lowering the temperature. The possibility to measure
magnetic diffuse scattering with soft x rays opens the way to study magnetic
correlations in a variety of nanomagnetic systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06675</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Haworth</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruijsenaars</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames></author></authors><title>Hilbert space theory for relativistic dynamics with reflection. Special
  cases</title><categories>math-ph math.CA math.MP math.QA nlin.SI quant-ph</categories><comments>64 pages, to appear in Journal of Integrable Systems</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present and study a novel class of one-dimensional Hilbert space
eigenfunction transforms that diagonalize analytic difference operators
encoding the (reduced) two-particle relativistic hyperbolic Calogero-Moser
dynamics. The scattering is described by reflection and transmission amplitudes
$t$ and $r$ with function-theoretic features that are quite different from
nonrelativistic amplitudes. The axiomatic Hilbert space analysis in the
appendices is inspired by and applied to the attractive two-particle
relativistic Calogero-Moser dynamics for a sequence of special couplings.
Together with the scattering function $u$ of the repulsive case, this leads to
a triple of amplitudes $u, t, r$ satisfying the Yang-Baxter equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06683</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06683</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Morante</keyname><forenames>Koldo</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Bellomio</keyname><forenames>Augusto</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Gil-Cart&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>David</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Redondo-Morata</keyname><forenames>Lorena</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sot</keyname><forenames>Jes&#xfa;s</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Scheuring</keyname><forenames>Simon</forenames><affiliation>Bio-AFM-Lab</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Valle</keyname><forenames>Mikel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gonz&#xe1;lez-Ma&#xf1;as</keyname><forenames>Juan Manuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tsumoto</keyname><forenames>Kouhei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caaveiro</keyname><forenames>Jose M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Identification of a membrane-bound prepore species clarifies the lytic
  mechanism of actinoporins</title><categories>physics.bio-ph</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><journal-ref>Journal of Biological Chemistry, American Society for Biochemistry
  and Molecular Biology, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1074/jbc.M116.734053</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pore-forming toxins (PFT) are cytolytic proteins belonging to the molecular
warfare apparatus of living organisms. The assembly of the functional
transmembrane pore requires several intermediate steps ranging from a
water-soluble monomeric species to the multimeric ensemble inserted in the cell
membrane. The non-lytic oligomeric intermediate known as prepore plays an
essential role in the mechanism of insertion of the class of $\beta$-PFT.
However, in the class of $\alpha$-PFT like the actinoporins produced by sea
anemones, evidence of membrane-bound prepores is still lacking. We have
employed single-particle cryo-electron microscopy (cryo-EM) and atomic force
microscopy (AFM) to identify, for the first time, a prepore species of the
actinoporin fragaceatoxin C (FraC) bound to lipid vesicles. The size of the
prepore coincides that of the functional pore, except for the transmembrane
region, which is absent in the prepore. Biochemical assays indicated that, in
the prepore species, the N-terminus is not inserted in the bilayer but exposed
to the aqueous solution. Our study reveals the structure of the prepore complex
in actinoporins, and highlights the role of structural intermediates for the
formation of cytolytic pores by an $\alpha$-PFT.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06690</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06690</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Ralph</keyname><forenames>D. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Spin-Orbit Logic with Magnetoelectric Nodes: A Scalable
  Charge Mediated Nonvolatile Spintronic Logic&quot; (arXiv:1512.05428)</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Researchers from Intel Corporation recently proposed &quot;Magneto-Electric Spin
Orbit (MESO)&quot; logic as a new strategy for beyond-CMOS electronics [1]. The
Intel researchers project that this concept has the potential to reduce the
switching energy per bit &quot;to near thermodynamic limits for GHz logic (100 kT
switching at 100 ps delay)&quot;, i.e., to near 0.4 aJ. Here I point out that the
switching energy stated in ref. [1] is incorrect, because the paper neglects a
large energy cost associated with Ohmic dissipation that is unavoidable within
the MESO scheme. Using optimistic parameters, the true minimum switching energy
per bit within the MESO approach is at least 150 fJ, or more than 300,000 times
greater than the value stated in ref. [1]. Given this large energy cost, the
MESO concept is not a viable strategy for beyond-CMOS logic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06721</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06721</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Guazzini</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sara&#xe7;</keyname><forenames>Ay&#xe7;a</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donati</keyname><forenames>Camillo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nardi</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vilone</keyname><forenames>Daniele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Meringolo</keyname><forenames>Patrizia</forenames></author></authors><title>Participation and Privacy perception in virtual environments: the role
  of sense of community, culture and sex between Italian and Turkish</title><categories>cs.CY cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to Complexity</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Advancements in information and communication technologies have enhanced our
possibilities to communicate worldwide, eliminating borders and making it
possible to interact with people coming from other cultures like never happened
before. Such powerful tools have brought us to reconsider our concept of
privacy and social involvement in order to make them fit into this wider
environment. It is possible to claim that the ICT revolution is changing our
world and is having a core role as a mediating factor for social movements
(e.g., Arab spring) and political decisions (e.g., Brexit), shaping the world
in a faster and shared brand new way. It is then interesting to explore how the
perception of this brand new environment (in terms of social engagement,
privacy perception and sense of belonging to a community) differs even in
similar cultures separated by recent historical reasons, as for example in
Italian and Turkish cultures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06725</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06725</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Sarma</keyname><forenames>Gopal P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Reductionism and the Universal Calculus</title><categories>physics.hist-ph math.HO</categories><comments>11 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the seminal essay, &quot;On the unreasonable effectiveness of mathematics in
the physical sciences,&quot; physicist Eugene Wigner poses a fundamental
philosophical question concerning the relationship between a physical system
and our capacity to model its behavior with the symbolic language of
mathematics. In this essay, I examine an ambitious 16th and 17th-century
intellectual agenda from the perspective of Wigner's question, namely, what
historian Paolo Rossi calls &quot;the quest to create a universal language.&quot; While
many elite thinkers pursued related ideas, the most inspiring and forceful was
Gottfried Leibniz's effort to create a &quot;universal calculus,&quot; a pictorial
language which would transparently represent the entirety of human knowledge,
as well as an associated symbolic calculus with which to model the behavior of
physical systems and derive new truths. I suggest that a deeper understanding
of why the efforts of Leibniz and others failed could shed light on Wigner's
original question. I argue that the notion of reductionism is crucial to
characterizing the failure of Leibniz's agenda, but that a decisive argument
for the why the promises of this effort did not materialize is still lacking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06740</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06740</id><created>2016-05-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lizardo</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Dong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Yuxiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Striegel</keyname><forenames>Aaron D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hachen</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chawla</keyname><forenames>Nitesh V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Gender Differences in Communication Behaviors, Spatial Proximity
  Patterns, and Mobility Habits</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The existence of gender differences in the structure and composition of
social networks is a well established finding in the social and behavioral
sciences, but researchers continue to debate whether structural, dispositional,
or life course factors are the primary driver of these differences. In this
paper we extend work on gender differences in social networks to patterns of
interaction, propinquity, and connectivity captured via a social sensing
platform comprised of an ensemble of individuals' phone calls, text messaging,
face-to-face interactions, and traces of their mobility activities. We attempt
to isolate dispositional from other factors by focusing on a relatively
homogeneous population on a relatively closed setting at the same stage in the
life course. Analysis across three different networks along with mobility data
reveals systematic gender differences in terms of communicative,
distributional, mobility, and spatial proximity tendencies. Most importantly,
some patterns observed in the communication network (e.g. stronger same-gender
preference for women) are found to be reversed in the spatial proximity
context, with men displaying a greater tendency to spend time in a narrower
(and thus more predictable) range of spaces with same-gender peers than women.
These findings provide robust and novel evidence for the powerful effect of
gender in structuring behavior across a wide range of communication and
mobility behaviors, validating and extending recent work pointing to
differences of socio-cultural and evolutionary origin in the styles of
sociability and interaction characteristic of men and women.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06745</id><created>2016-07-21</created><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Indentation of Coatings at micro/nano scale: Crack formation and
  deflection</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nanoindentation is an effective way of finding mechanical properties at
nanoscale. They are especially useful for thin films where elimination of the
substrate effect is required. The mechanism is based upon depth sensing
indentation based on Oliver and Pharr modeling. Nanoindentation was used to
evaluate the nanomechanical and fractographic properties of hard coatings
deposited by magnetron sputtering. Radial and lateral cracks accompanied by
delamination of the coatings were observed during the indentation tests. A
novel phenomenon of stress induced crystallization was observed in case of the
CNx films which resulted in crack deflection. Indentations at micro scale using
Vickers Indenter were also done and the cracking phenomena were analyzed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06753</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06753</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Marconi</keyname><forenames>Mathias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Javaloyes</keyname><forenames>Julien</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raineri</keyname><forenames>Fabrice</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levenson</keyname><forenames>Ariel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yacomotti</keyname><forenames>Alejandro M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Stimulated scattering in strongly coupled nanolasers induced by Rabi
  oscillations</title><categories>physics.optics quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, first version submitted to OSA</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Two coupled-cavity systems, or &quot;photonic dimers&quot;, are efficient test-beds for
both fundamental optics -the realization of quantum correlated states,
Josephson physics, and so forth-, and applications such as optical flip-flop
memories. In this work we report on the first observation of nonlinear mode
interaction in a photonic dimer formed by two semiconductor photonic crystal
coupled nanolasers. For this, we investigate energy transfer between hybrid
modes, which manifests as a switching from the blue-detuned (bonding) to the
red-detuned (anti-bonding) modes. An mean-field model allows us to explain this
phenomenon as stimulated scattering due to carrier population oscillations in
the cavities at the Rabi frequency. Such asymmetrical mode interaction is
universal in semiconductor laser photonic molecules, and unveils the origin of
cross-correlation dips in the statistics of mode fluctuations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06776</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06776</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Peil</keyname><forenames>Steven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hanssen</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swanson</keyname><forenames>Thomas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Taylor</keyname><forenames>Jennifer</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ekstrom</keyname><forenames>Christopher R.</forenames></author></authors><title>The USNO rubidium fountains</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>8th Symposium on Frequency Standards and Metrology 2015</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 723 (2016) 012004</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/723/1/012004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Four rubidium fountains at the U.S. Naval Observatory (USNO) have been in
operation for 4.5 years. Each fountain has demonstrated periods of stability
marked by Total or Theo deviation below 10^-16. Occasional frequency changes,
on order of 1.5 times per year per fountain, introduce deviations from
white-frequency noise behavior. Averaged together, the four fountains form an
ensemble with a white-frequency noise level of 10^-13 and excellent long-term
stability as compared to the primary frequency standards contributing to TAI.
Progress on using the clocks at USNO for improving limits on coupling of
fundamental constants to gravity by measuring the universality of the
gravitational redshift for different types of clocks is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06786</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06786</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author></authors><title>Prospects for Testing Lorentz and CPT Invariance in the Top-Quark Sector</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><report-no>IUHET 613</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present how to further the search for Lorentz and CPT violation in the
top-quark sector after the first measurement in this sector by D0. We compute
the Lorentz-violating matrix element for top pair production via gluon fusion,
which allows a similar but more precise measurement at the LHC. For CPT
violation, we analyze single-top production, derive the modified matrix
elements, and predict possible signals.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06788</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06788</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Werndl</keyname><forenames>Charlotte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frigg</keyname><forenames>Roman</forenames></author></authors><title>Boltzmannian Equilibrium in Stochastic Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>forthcoming in: Michela Massimi and Jan-Willem Romeijn (eds):
  Proceedings of the EPSA15 Conference. Springer</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Equilibrium is a central concept of statistical mechanics. In previous work
we introduced the notions of a Boltzmannian alpha-epsilon-equilibrium and a
Boltzmannian gamma-varepsilon-equilibrium (Werndl and Frigg 2015a, 2015b). This
was done in a deterministic context. We now consider systems with a stochastic
micro-dynamics and transfer these notions from the deterministic to the
stochastic context. We then prove stochastic equivalents of the Dominance
Theorem and the Prevalence Theorem. This establishes that also in stochastic
systems equilibrium macro-regions are large in requisite sense.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06789</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06789</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Pilania</keyname><forenames>Ghanshyam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whittle</keyname><forenames>Karl R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Chao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grimes</keyname><forenames>Robin W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stanek</keyname><forenames>Christopher R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sickafus</keyname><forenames>Kurt E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uberuaga</keyname><forenames>Blas Pedro</forenames></author></authors><title>Using machine learning to identify factors that govern amorphization of
  irradiated pyrochlores</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Structure-property relationships is a key materials science concept that
enables the design of new materials. In the case of materials for application
in radiation environments, correlating radiation tolerance with fundamental
structural features of a material enables materials discovery. Here, we use a
machine learning model to examine the factors that govern amorphization
resistance in the complex oxide pyrochlore ($A_2B_2$O$_7$). We examine the
fidelity of predictions based on cation radii and electronegativities, the
oxygen positional parameter, and the energetics of disordering and amorphizing
the material. No one factor alone adequately predicts amorphization resistance.
We find that, when multiple families of pyrochlores (with different B cations)
are considered, radii and electronegativities provide the best prediction but
when the machine learning model is restricted to only the $B$=Ti pyrochlores,
the energetics of disordering and amorphization are optimal. This work provides
new insight into the factors that govern the amorphization susceptibility and
highlights the ability of machine learning approaches to generate that insight.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06791</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06791</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Capel</keyname><forenames>Pierre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nollet</keyname><forenames>Yvan</forenames></author></authors><title>From the Coulomb breakup of halo nuclei to neutron radiative capture</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.SR nucl-ex</categories><comments>8 pages, 7 figures, contribution to the proceedings of the 54th
  International Winter Meeting on Nuclear Physics (25-29 January 2016, Bormio,
  Italy)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Coulomb breakup is used to infer radiative-capture cross sections at
astrophysical energies. We test theoretically the accuracy of this indirect
technique in the particular case of 15C, for which both the Coulomb breakup to
^{14}C+n and the radiative capture 14C(n,{\gamma})15C have been measured. We
analyse the dependance of Coulomb-breakup calculations on the projectile
description in both its initial bound state and its continuum. Our calculations
depend not only on the Asymptotic Normalisation Coefficient (ANC) of the 15C
ground state, but also on the 14C-n continuum. This questions the method
proposed by Summers and Nunes [Phys. Rev. C 78, 011601 (2008), ibid. 78, 069908
(2008)], which assumes that an ANC can be directly extracted from the
comparison of calculations to breakup data. Fortunately, the sensitivity to the
continuum description can be absorbed in a normalisation constant obtained by a
simple {\chi}2 fit of our calculations to the measurements. By restricting this
fit to low 14C-n energy in the continuum, we can achieve a better agreement
between the radiative-capture cross sections inferred from the Coulomb-breakup
method and the exact ones. This result revives the Coulomb-breakup technique to
infer neutron radiative-capture capture to loosely-bound states, which would be
very useful for r- and s-process modelling in explosive stellar environments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06800</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06800</id><created>2016-07-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Malek</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kree</keyname><forenames>Reiner</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Transitions in a Dragged Growing Polymer Chain</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the Rouse model of polymer dynamics to situations of non-stationary
chain growth. For a dragged polymer chain of length $N(t) = t^\alpha$, we find
two transitions in conformational dynamics. At $\alpha= 1/2$, the propagation
of tension and the average shape of the chain change qualitatively, while at
$\alpha = 1 $ the average center-of-mass motion stops. These transitions are
due to a simple physical mechanism: a race duel between tension propagation and
polymer growth. Therefore they should also appear for growing semi-flexible or
stiff polymers. The generalized Rouse model inherits much of the versatility of
the original Rouse model: it can be efficiently simulated and it is amenable to
analytical treatment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:cond-mat/0606439</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-25</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>cond-mat/0606439</id><created>2006-06-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Scemama</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leli&#xe8;vre</keyname><forenames>Tony</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoltz</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canc&#xe8;s</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caffarel</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>An efficient sampling algorithm for Variational Monte Carlo</title><categories>cond-mat.other</categories><comments>23 pages</comments><journal-ref>J. Chem. Phys. 125, 114105 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.2354490</doi><abstract>  We propose a new algorithm for sampling the $N$-body density $|\Psi({\bf
R})|^2/\int_{\mathbb{R}^{3N}} |\Psi|^2$ in the Variational Monte Carlo (VMC)
framework. This algorithm is based upon a modified Ricci-Ciccotti
discretization of the Langevin dynamics in the phase space $({\bf R},{\bf P})$
improved by a Metropolis acceptation/rejection step. We show through some
representative numerical examples (Lithium, Fluorine and Copper atoms, and
phenol molecule), that this algorithm is superior to the standard sampling
algorithm based on the biased random walk (importance sampling).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
