<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:41:14Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-21" from="2016-07-21" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.2093</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.2093</id><created>2013-12-07</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Hall Effect in Chemically Disordered L10-Mn1.5Ga</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Physical Review B 89 (22), 220406, 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.89.220406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The anomalous Hall effect (AHE) in perpendicularly magnetized L10-Mn1.5Ga
single-crystalline films is investigated as a function of degree of long-range
chemical ordering and temperature. Our results provide firm evidence that
phonons has negligibly smaller effect on skew scattering contributions to AHE
resistivity than defects, the overlook of which in conventional scaling laws
results in significant discrepancies and exponent n beyond 2 when fitting the
data. We find that the broken of long-range chemical ordering strongly affects
both intrinsic and extrinsic contributions of AHE conductivity, e.g., it
greatly suppresses intrinsic contributions by influencing the topology of the
band structures. Our results are of great importance for both physical
understanding and technological engineering of the AHE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.4653</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.4653</id><created>2013-12-17</created><updated>2014-12-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hood</keyname><forenames>Kaitlyn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Sungyon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roper</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author></authors><title>Inertial migration of a rigid sphere in three-dimensional Poiseuille
  flow</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>submitted to Journal of Fluid Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, 2015, 765, 452-479</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2014.739</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inertial lift forces are exploited within inertial microfluidic devices to
position, segregate, and sort particles or droplets. However the forces and
their focusing positions can currently only be predicted by numerical
simulations, making rational device design very difficult. Here we develop
theory for the forces on particles in microchannel geometries. We use numerical
experiments to dissect the dominant balances within the Navier-Stokes equations
and derive an asymptotic model to predict the lateral force on the particle as
a function of particle size. Our asymptotic model is valid for a wide array of
particle sizes and Reynolds numbers, and allows us to predict how focusing
position depends on particle size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1403.1204</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1403.1204</id><created>2014-03-05</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takook</keyname><forenames>Mohammad Vahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Field Theory in de Sitter Universe: Ambient Space Formalism</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>75 pages, typos corrected, paper improved, V5 some errors corrected</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum field theory in the $4$-dimensional de Sitter space-time is
constructed in the ambient space formalism in a rigorous mathematical
framework. This work is based on the group representation theory and the
analyticity of the complexified pseudo-Riemannian manifolds. The unitary
irreducible representations of de Sitter group and their corresponding Hilbert
spaces are reformulated in the ambient space formalism. Defining the creation
and annihilation operators, quantum field operators and their corresponding
analytic two-point functions for various spin fields have been constructed. The
various spin massless fields can be constructed in terms of the massless
conformally coupled scalar field in this formalism. Then the quantum massless
minimally coupled scalar field operator, for the first time, is also
constructed on Bunch-Davies vacuum state which preserve the analyticity. We
show that the massless fields with $s \geq 3$ cannot propagate in de Sitter
ambient space formalism. The massless gauge invariant field equations for $s=1,
\frac{3}{2}, 2$ are studied. The gauge spin-$\frac{3}{2}$ fields satisfy the
Grassmannian algebra, and hence provoke one to couple them with the gauge
spin-$2$ field and the super-algebra is naturally appeared.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1410.3228</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1410.3228</id><created>2014-10-13</created><updated>2016-01-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wabnitz</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Min</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author></authors><title>Coherence loss of partially mode-locked fiber laser</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><doi>10.1038/srep24995</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Stochastically driven nonlinear processes limit the number of amplified modes
in a natural system due to competitive mode interaction, which is accompanied
by loss of coherence when increasing the complexity of system. Specifically, we
find that modulation instability, which exhibits great fluctuations when it is
spontaneously grown from noise in conservative systems, may possess a high
degree of coherence in dissipative laser system with gain. Nonlinear mode
interactions can be competitive or cooperative: adjusting the intracavity
polarization state controls the process of loss of coherence. Single-shot
spectra reveal that fiber laser redistributes its energy from center wavelength
mode to sidebands through parametric instabilities, and subsequently
longitudinal modes are populated via cascaded four-wave-mixing. Parametric
frequency conversion populates longitudinal modes with a random distribution of
position, intensity and polarization, resulting in partially (rather than
highly) coherent pulses. These dynamics unveil a new route towards complex
pattern formation in nonlinear laser systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1411.7737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1411.7737</id><created>2014-11-27</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kohama</keyname><forenames>Akihisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iida</keyname><forenames>Kei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oyamatsu</keyname><forenames>Kazuhiro</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy and mass-number dependence of hadron-nucleus total reaction cross
  sections</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures; supplement is available at RNC Preprint archive
  system (http://ribf-result.riken.jp/), black sphere cross section formula
  corrected. To be appeared in J. Phys. Soc. Japan</comments><report-no>RIKEN-NC-NP-143</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We systematically analyze nuclear reaction data that are sensitive to nuclear
size, namely, proton-nucleus total reaction cross sections and differential
elastic cross sections, using a phenomenological black-sphere approximation of
nuclei that we are developing. In this framework, the radius of the black
sphere is found to be a useful length scale that simultaneously accounts for
the observed proton-nucleus total reaction cross section and first diffraction
peak in the proton elastic differential cross section. This framework is
expected to be applicable to any kind of projectile that is strongly attenuated
in the nucleus. On the basis of a cross-section formula constructed within this
framework, we find that a less familiar $A^{1/6}$ dependence plays a crucial
role in describing the energy dependence of proton-nucleus total reaction cross
sections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.07871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.07871</id><created>2015-02-27</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Roy</keyname><forenames>Sthitadhi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roychowdhury</keyname><forenames>Krishanu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Sourin</forenames></author></authors><title>Pseudospin-valve effect on transport in junctions of three-dimensional
  topological insulator surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>11 pages, 5 figures, 1 table, version published in New Journal of
  Physics</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18, 073038 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073038</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the surface states of pristine 3D topological insulators (TIs)
are analogs of ferromagnetic half metals due to complete polarization of an
emergent momentum independent pseudospin (SU(2)) degree of freedom on the
surface. To put this claim on firm footing, we present results for TI surfaces
perpendicular to the crystal growth axis, which clearly show that the tunneling
conductance between two such TI surfaces of the same TI material is dominated
by this half metallic behavior leading to physics reminiscent of a spin-valve.
Further using the generalized tunnel magnetoresistance derived in this work we
also study the tunneling current between arbitrary TI surfaces. We also perform
a comprehensive study of the effect of all possible surface potentials allowed
by time reversal symmetry on this spin-valve effect and show that it is robust
against most of such potentials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07536</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07536</id><created>2015-03-25</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zlochower</keyname><forenames>Yosef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lousto</keyname><forenames>Carlos O.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the remnant mass, spin, and recoil from unequal-mass,
  precessing black-hole binaries: The Intermediate Mass Ratio Regime</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.GA astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>New version includes correction for errors in the published version
  (see Erratum Phys. Rev. D 94, 029901 (2016))</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 92, 024022 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.92.024022</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the modeling of the properties of the remnant black hole resulting
the merger of a black-hole binary as a function of the parameters of the
binary. We provide a set of empirical formulas for the final mass, spin and
recoil velocity of the final black hole as a function of the mass ratio and
individual spins of the progenitor. In order to determine the fitting
coefficients for these formulas, we perform a set of 128 new numerical
evolutions of precessing, unequal-mass black-hole binaries, and fit to the
resulting remnant mass, spin, and recoil. In order to reduce the complexity of
the analysis, we chose configurations that have one of the black holes
spinning, with dimensionless spin alpha=0.8, at different angles with respect
to the orbital angular momentum, and the other non-spinning. In addition to
evolving families of binaries with different spin-inclination angles, we also
evolved binaries with mass ratios as small as q=1/6. We use the resulting
empirical formulas to predict the probabilities of black hole mergers leading
to a given recoil velocity, total radiated gravitational energy, and final
black hole spin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.03684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.03684</id><created>2015-04-14</created><updated>2015-04-30</updated><authors><author><keyname>Knispel</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyne</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stappers</keyname><forenames>B. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Freire</keyname><forenames>P. C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lazarus</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Allen</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aulbert</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bock</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdanov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brazier</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Camilo</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cardoso</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cordes</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crawford</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deneva</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eggenstein</keyname><forenames>H. -B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fehrmann</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferdman</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hessels</keyname><forenames>J. W. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jenet</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karako-Argaman</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaspi</keyname><forenames>V. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Leeuwen</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lorimer</keyname><forenames>D. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lynch</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Machenschalk</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madsen</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>McLaughlin</keyname><forenames>M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patel</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ransom</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siemens</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spitler</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stairs</keyname><forenames>I. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stovall</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Swiggum</keyname><forenames>J. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Venkataraman</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wharton</keyname><forenames>R. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>W. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Einstein@Home Discovery of a PALFA Millisecond Pulsar in an Eccentric
  Binary Orbit</title><categories>astro-ph.HE gr-qc</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures, 2 tables; accepted for publication in The
  Astrophysical Journal</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal, Volume 806, Issue 1, article id. 140, 9
  pp. (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0004-637X/806/1/140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report the discovery of the millisecond pulsar (MSP) PSR J1950+2414
($P=4.3$ ms) in a binary system with an eccentric ($e=0.08$) 22-day orbit in
Pulsar ALFA survey observations with the Arecibo telescope. Its companion star
has a median mass of 0.3 $M_\odot$ and is most likely a white dwarf. Fully
recycled MSPs like this one are thought to be old neutron stars spun-up by mass
transfer from a companion star. This process should circularize the orbit, as
is observed for the vast majority of binary MSPs, which predominantly have
orbital eccentricities $e &lt; 0.001$. However, four recently discovered binary
MSPs have orbits with $0.027 &lt; e &lt; 0.44$; PSR J1950+2414 is the fifth such
system to be discovered. The upper limits for its intrinsic spin period
derivative and inferred surface magnetic field strength are comparable to those
of the general MSP population. The large eccentricities are incompatible with
the predictions of the standard recycling scenario: something unusual happened
during their evolution. Proposed scenarios are a) initial evolution of the
pulsar in a triple system which became dynamically unstable, b) origin in an
exchange encounter in an environment with high stellar density, c) rotationally
delayed accretion-induced collapse of a super-Chandrasekhar white dwarf, and d)
dynamical interaction of the binary with a circumbinary disk. We compare the
properties of all five known eccentric MSPs with the predictions of these
formation channels. Future measurements of the masses and proper motion might
allow us to firmly exclude some of the proposed formation scenarios.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.05113</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.05113</id><created>2015-04-20</created><updated>2015-08-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nikolaev</keyname><forenames>A. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kato expansion in quantum canonical perturbation theory</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>18 pages. Version 2: Additional discussion of the computational
  algorithms</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 062102 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953639</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work establishes a connection between canonical perturbation series in
quantum mechanics and a Kato expansion for the resolvent of the Liouville
superoperator. Our approach leads to an explicit expression for a generator of
a block-diagonalizing Dyson's ordered exponential in arbitrary perturbation
order. Unitary intertwining of perturbed and unperturbed averaging
superprojectors allows for a description of ambiguities in the generator and
block-diagonalized Hamiltonian.
  We compare the efficiency of the corresponding computational algorithm with
the efficiencies of the Van Vleck and Magnus methods for high perturbative
orders.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1508.07235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1508.07235</id><created>2015-08-28</created><updated>2016-07-08</updated><authors><author><keyname>Correggi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dimonte</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Third Critical Speed for Rotating Bose-Einstein Condensates</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.quant-gas math.MP</categories><comments>pdfLaTeX, 39 pages, minor changes, to appear in J. Math. Phys</comments><journal-ref>J. Math. Phys. 57, 071901 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4954805</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a two-dimensional rotating Bose-Einstein condensate confined by an
anharmonic trap in the framework of the Gross-Pitaevksii theory. We consider a
rapid rotation regime close to the transition to a giant vortex state. It was
proven in [M. Correggi {\it et al}, {\it J. Math. Phys. \textbf{53}(2012)] that
such a transition occurs when the angular velocity is of order $ \varepsilon
^{-4}$, with $ \varepsilon ^{-2} $ denoting the coefficient of the nonlinear
term in the Gross-Pitaevskii functional and $ \varepsilon \ll 1 $ (Thomas-Fermi
regime). In this paper we identify a finite value $ \Omega_{\mathrm{c}} $ such
that, if $ \Omega = \Omega_0/\varepsilon ^4 $ with $ \Omega_0 &gt;
\Omega_{\mathrm{c}} $, the condensate is in the giant vortex phase. Under the
same condition we prove a refined energy asymptotics and an estimate of the
winding number of any Gross-Pitaevskii minimizer.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02003</id><created>2015-09-07</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Soltwisch</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haase</keyname><forenames>Anton</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wernecke</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Probst</keyname><forenames>Juergen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoengen</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burger</keyname><forenames>Sven</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krumrey</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scholze</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author></authors><title>Correlated Diffuse X-ray Scattering from Periodically Nano-Structured
  Surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 035419 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.035419</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Laterally periodic nanostructures were investigated with grazing incidence
small angle X-ray scattering. To support an improved reconstruction of
nanostructured surface geometries, we investigated the origin of the
contributions to the diffuse scattering pattern which is correlated to the
surface roughness. Resonant diffuse scattering leads to a palm-like structure
of intensity sheets. Dynamic scattering generates the so-called Yoneda band
caused by a resonant scatter enhancement at the critical angle of total
reflection and higher-order Yoneda bands originating from a subsequent
diffraction of the Yoneda enhanced scattering at the grating. Our explanations
are supported by modelling using a solver for the time-harmonic Maxwell's
equations based on the finite-element method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.02868</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.02868</id><created>2015-09-09</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;sar A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casta&#xf1;er</keyname><forenames>Elisa E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The amenity space and the evolution of neighborhoods</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>no comments</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neighborhoods populated by amenities--such as restaurants, cafes, and
libraries--are considered to be a key property of desirable cities. Yet,
despite the global enthusiasm for amenity-rich neighborhoods, little is known
about the empirical laws governing the colocation of amenities at the
neighborhood scale. Here, we contribute to our understanding of the naturally
occurring neighborhood-scale agglomerations of amenities observed in cities by
using a dataset summarizing the precise location of millions of amenities. We
use this dataset to build the network of co-location of amenities, or Amenity
Space, by first introducing a clustering algorithm to identify neighborhoods,
and then using the identified neighborhoods to map the probability that two
amenities will be co-located in one of them. Finally, we use the Amenity Space
to build a recommender system that identifies the amenities that are missing in
a neighborhood given its current pattern of specialization. This opens the door
for the construction of amenity recommendation algorithms that can be used to
evaluate neighborhoods and inform their improvement and development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.04298</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.04298</id><created>2015-09-14</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Banchi</keyname><forenames>Leonardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pancotti</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bose</keyname><forenames>Sougato</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum gate learning in engineered qubit networks: Toffoli gate with
  always-on interactions</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.dis-nn nlin.CG</categories><comments>8 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>npj Quantum Information 2: 16019 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/npjqi.2016.19</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We put forward a strategy to encode a quantum operation into the unmodulated
dynamics of a quantum network without the need of external control pulses,
measurements or active feedback. Our optimization scheme, inspired by
supervised machine learning, consists in engineering the pairwise couplings
between the network qubits so that the target quantum operation is encoded in
the natural reduced dynamics of a network section. The efficacy of the proposed
scheme is demonstrated by the finding of uncontrolled four-qubit networks that
implement either the Toffoli gate, the Fredkin gate, or remote logic
operations. The proposed Toffoli gate is stable against imperfections, has a
high-fidelity for fault tolerant quantum computation, and is fast, being based
on the non-equilibrium dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1509.08431</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1509.08431</id><created>2015-09-28</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kogoj</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vidmar</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mierzejewski</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trugman</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonca</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermalization after photoexcitation from the perspective of optical
  spectroscopy</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.other cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.supr-con</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 014304 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.014304</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We analyze the thermalization of a photoexcited charge carrier coupled to a
single branch of quantum phonons within the Holstein model. To this end, we
calculate the far-from-equilibrium time evolution of a pure many-body state and
compare it with predictions of the thermal Gibbs ensemble. We show that at
strong enough carrier excitation, the nonequilibrium system evolves towards a
thermal steady state. Our analysis is based on two classes of observables.
First, the occupations of fermionic momenta, which are the eigenvalues of the
one-particle density matrix, match in the steady state the values in the
corresponding Gibbs ensemble. This indicates thermalization of static fermionic
correlations on the entire lattice. Second, the dynamic current-current
correlations, including the time-resolved optical conductivity, also take the
form of their thermal counterparts. Remarkably, both static and dynamic
fermionic correlations thermalize with identical temperatures. Our results
suggest that the subsequent relaxation processes, observed in time-resolved
ultrafast spectroscopy, may be efficiently described by applying quasithermal
approaches, e.g., multi-temperature models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.02617</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.02617</id><created>2015-10-09</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Larsen</keyname><forenames>Patricia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Challinor</keyname><forenames>Anthony</forenames></author></authors><title>Intrinsic alignment contamination to CMB lensing-galaxy weak lensing
  correlations from tidal torquing</title><categories>astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>Updated calculation to include all LPT terms to consistent order. 10
  pages, 5 figures. Accepted for publication in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1645</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Correlations of galaxy ellipticities with large-scale structure, due to
galactic tidal interactions, provide a potentially significant contaminant to
measurements of cosmic shear. However, these intrinsic alignments are still
poorly understood for galaxies at the redshifts typically used in cosmic shear
analyses. For spiral galaxies, it is thought that tidal torquing is significant
in determining alignments resulting in zero correlation between the intrinsic
ellipticity and the gravitational potential in linear theory. Here, we
calculate the leading-order correction to this result in the tidal-torque model
from non-linear evolution, using second-order perturbation theory, and relate
this to the contamination from intrinsic alignments to the recently-measured
cross-correlation between galaxy ellipticities and the CMB lensing potential.
On the scales relevant for CMB lensing observations, the squeezed limit of the
gravitational bispectrum dominates the correlation. Physically, the large-scale
mode that sources CMB lensing modulates the small-scale power and hence the
intrinsic ellipticity, due to non-linear evolution. We find that the angular
cross-correlation from tidal torquing has a very similar scale dependence as in
the linear alignment model, believed to be appropriate for elliptical galaxies.
The amplitude of the cross-correlation is predicted to depend strongly on the
formation redshift, being smaller for galaxies that formed at higher redshift
when the bispectrum of the gravitational potential was smaller. Finally, we
make simple forecasts for constraints on intrinsic alignments from the
correlation of forthcoming cosmic shear measurements with current CMB lensing
measurements. We note that cosmic variance can be significantly reduced in
measurements of the difference in the intrinsic alignments for elliptical and
spiral galaxies if these can be separated (e.g., using colour).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.06715</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.06715</id><created>2015-10-22</created><updated>2016-05-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hoang</keyname><forenames>Thai M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahn</keyname><forenames>Jonghoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bang</keyname><forenames>Jaehoon</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tongcang</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron spin control of optically levitated nanodiamonds in vacuum</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12250 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12250</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron spins of diamond nitrogen-vacancy (NV) centers are important quantum
resources for nanoscale sensing and quantum information. Combining NV spins
with levitated optomechanical resonators will provide a hybrid quantum system
for novel applications. Here we optically levitate a nanodiamond and
demonstrate electron spin control of its built-in NV centers in low vacuum. We
observe that the strength of electron spin resonance (ESR) is enhanced when the
air pressure is reduced. To better understand this system, we investigate the
effects of trap power and measure the absolute internal temperature of
levitated nanodiamonds with ESR after calibration of the strain effect. We also
observe that oxygen and helium gases have different effects on both the
photoluminescence and the ESR contrast of nanodiamond NV centers, indicating
potential applications of NV centers in oxygen gas sensing. Our results pave
the way towards a levitated spin-optomechanical system for studying macroscopic
quantum mechanics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.08652</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.08652</id><created>2015-10-29</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Benedetti</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buscemi</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bordone</keyname><forenames>Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paris</keyname><forenames>Matteo G. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-Markovian continuous-time quantum walks on lattices with dynamical
  noise</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 042313 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.042313</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We address the dynamics of continuous-time quantum walks on one-dimensional
disordered lattices inducing dynamical noise in the system. Noise is described
as time-dependent fluctuations of the tunneling amplitudes between adjacent
sites, and attention is focused on non-Gaussian telegraph noise, going beyond
the usual assumption of fast Gaussian noise. We observe the emergence of two
different dynamical behaviors for the walker, corresponding to two opposite
noise regimes: slow noise (i.e. strong coupling with the environment) confines
the walker into few lattice nodes, while fast noise (weak coupling) induces a
transition between quantum and classical diffusion over the lattice. A phase
transition between the two dynamical regimes may be observed by tuning the
ratio between the autocorrelation time of the noise and the coupling between
the walker and the external environment generating the noise. We also address
the non-Markovianity of the quantum map by assessing its memory effects, as
well as evaluating the information backflow to the system. Our results suggest
that the non-Markovian character of the evolution is linked to the dynamical
behavior in the slow noise regime, and that fast noise induces a Markovian
dynamics for the walker.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.02485</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.02485</id><created>2015-11-08</created><updated>2016-07-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Qisi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Yao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Bingying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiaowen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeuchi</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Christianson</keyname><forenames>A. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Walker</keyname><forenames>H. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adroja</keyname><forenames>D. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abdel-Hafiez</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Xiaojia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chareev</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>A. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic ground state of FeSe</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>Supplementary information included; accepted by Nature Communications</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12182 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12182</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Elucidating the nature of the magnetism of a high-temperature superconductor
is crucial for establishing its pairing mechanism. The parent compounds of the
cuprate and iron-pnictide superconductors exhibit N\'eel and stripe magnetic
order, respectively. However, FeSe, the structurally simplest iron-based
superconductor, shows nematic order (Ts = 90 K), but not magnetic order in the
parent phase, and its magnetic ground state is intensely debated. Here, we
report inelastic neutron-scattering experiments that reveal both stripe and
N\'eel spin fluctuations over a wide energy range at 110 K. On entering the
nematic phase, a substantial amount of spectral weight is transferred from the
N\'eel to the stripe spin fluctuations. Moreover, the total fluctuating
magnetic moment of FeSe is ~ 60% larger than that in the iron pnictide
BaFe2As2. Our results suggest that FeSe is a novel S = 1 nematic
quantum-disordered paramagnet interpolating between the N\'eel and stripe
magnetic instabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05244</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05244</id><created>2015-11-16</created><authors><author><keyname>Suganuma</keyname><forenames>Hideo</forenames><affiliation>Kyoto U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sakumichi</keyname><forenames>Naoyuki</forenames><affiliation>Ochanomizu U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>The three-quark potential and perfect Abelian dominance in SU(3) lattice
  QCD</title><categories>hep-lat</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>PoS LATTICE2015 (2016) 323</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the static three-quark (3Q) potential for more than 300 different
patterns of 3Q systems with high statistics, i.e., 1000-2000 gauge
configurations, in SU(3) lattice QCD at the quenched level. For all the
distances, the 3Q potential is found to be well described by the Y-ansatz,
i.e., one-gluon-exchange (OGE) Coulomb plus Y-type linear potential. Also, we
investigate Abelian projection of quark confinement in the context of the dual
superconductor picture proposed by Yoichiro~Nambu~{\it et al.} in SU(3) lattice
QCD. Remarkably, quark confinement forces in both Q$\bar{\rm Q}$ and 3Q systems
can be described only with Abelian variables in the maximally Abelian gauge,
i.e., $\sigma_{\rm Q \bar Q} \simeq \sigma_{\rm Q \bar Q}^{\rm Abel} \simeq
\sigma_{\rm 3Q} \simeq \sigma_{\rm 3Q}^{\rm Abel}$, which we call ``perfect
Abelian dominance'' of quark confinement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00295</id><created>2015-12-01</created><updated>2016-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>W. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Background Evaluation for the Neutron Sources in the Daya Bay Experiment</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nucl. Instrum. Methods A, 833 (2016), 27-32</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.nima.2016.07.007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an evaluation of the background induced by $^{241}$Am-$^{13}$C
neutron calibration sources in the Daya Bay reactor neutrino experiment. As a
significant background for electron-antineutrino detection at 0.26$\pm$0.12 per
detector per day on average, it has been estimated by a Monte Carlo simulation
that was benchmarked by a special calibration data set. This dedicated data set
also provided the energy spectrum of the background.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.03768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.03768</id><created>2015-12-11</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hebecker</keyname><forenames>Arthur</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rompineve</keyname><forenames>Fabrizio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Westphal</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author></authors><title>Axion Monodromy and the Weak Gravity Conjecture</title><categories>hep-th astro-ph.CO hep-ph</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 figures; v2: references added, typos corrected; v3:
  published version + minor clarifications on self dual flux in Sec. 3.2</comments><report-no>DESY-15-242</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP04(2016)157</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Axions with broken discrete shift symmetry (axion monodromy) have recently
played a central role both in the discussion of inflation and the `relaxion'
approach to the hierarchy problem. We suggest a very minimalist way to
constrain such models by the weak gravity conjecture for domain walls: While
the electric side of the conjecture is always satisfied if the
cosine-oscillations of the axion potential are sufficiently small, the magnetic
side imposes a cutoff, $\Lambda^3 \sim m f M_{pl}$, independent of the height
of these `wiggles'. We compare our approach with the recent related proposal by
Ibanez, Montero, Uranga and Valenzuela. We also discuss the non-trivial
question which version, if any, of the weak gravity conjecture for domain walls
should hold. In particular, we show that string compactifications with branes
of different dimensions wrapped on different cycles lead to a `geometric weak
gravity conjecture' relating volumes of cycles, norms of corresponding forms
and the volume of the compact space. Imposing this `geometric conjecture',
e.g.~on the basis of the more widely accepted weak gravity conjecture for
particles, provides at least some support for the (electric and magnetic)
conjecture for domain walls.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04598</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04598</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2015-12-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rivera</keyname><forenames>Nicholas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaminer</keyname><forenames>Ido</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhen</keyname><forenames>Bo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Joannopoulos</keyname><forenames>John D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soljacic</keyname><forenames>Marin</forenames></author></authors><title>2D Plasmonics for Enabling Novel Light-Matter Interactions</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>Supplementary Materials not included (first page edited)</comments><journal-ref>Science 353.6296 (2016): 263-269</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The physics of light-matter interactions is strongly constrained by both the
small value of the fine-structure constant and the small size of the atom.
Overcoming these limitations is a long-standing challenge. Recent theoretical
and experimental breakthroughs have shown that two dimensional systems, such as
graphene, can support strongly confined light in the form of plasmons. These 2D
systems have a unique ability to squeeze the wavelength of light by over two
orders of magnitude. Such high confinement requires a revisitation of the main
assumptions of light-matter interactions. In this letter, we provide a general
theory of light-matter interactions in 2D systems which support plasmons. This
theory reveals that conventionally forbidden light-matter interactions, such
as: high-order multipolar transitions, two-plasmon spontaneous emission, and
spin-flip transitions can occur on very short time-scales - comparable to those
of conventionally fast transitions. Our findings enable new platforms for
spectroscopy, sensing, broadband light generation, and a potential test-ground
for non-perturbative quantum electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05322</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05322</id><created>2015-12-16</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Blesneag</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Buchbinder</keyname><forenames>Evgeny I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Candelas</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lukas</keyname><forenames>Andre</forenames></author></authors><title>Holomorphic Yukawa Couplings in Heterotic String Theory</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>53 pages, Latex; typos corrected</comments><journal-ref>JHEP 01 (2016) 152</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2016)152</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop techniques, based on differential geometry, to compute holomorphic
Yukawa couplings for heterotic line bundle models on Calabi-Yau manifolds
defined as complete intersections in projective spaces. It is shown explicitly
how these techniques relate to algebraic methods for computing holomorphic
Yukawa couplings. We apply our methods to various examples and evaluate the
holomorphic Yukawa couplings explicitly as functions of the complex structure
moduli. It is shown that the rank of the Yukawa matrix can decrease at specific
loci in complex structure moduli space. In particular, we compute the up Yukawa
coupling and the singlet-Higgs-lepton trilinear coupling in the heterotic
standard model described in arXiv:1404.2767
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05447</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05447</id><created>2015-12-16</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bradler</keyname><forenames>Kamil</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mirhosseini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fickler</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Broadbent</keyname><forenames>Anne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyd</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Finite-key security analysis for multilevel quantum key distribution</title><categories>quant-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v4: close to the published version</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 18 (2016) 073030</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a detailed security analysis of a d-dimensional quantum key
distribution protocol based on two and three mutually unbiased bases (MUBs)
both in an asymptotic and finite key length scenario. The finite secret key
rates are calculated as a function of the length of the sifted key by (i)
generalizing the uncertainly relation-based insight from BB84 to any d-level
2-MUB QKD protocol and (ii) by adopting recent advances in the second-order
asymptotics for finite block length quantum coding (for both d-level 2- and
3-MUB QKD protocols). Since the finite and asymptotic secret key rates increase
with d and the number of MUBs (together with the tolerable threshold) such QKD
schemes could in principle offer an important advantage over BB84. We discuss
the possibility of an experimental realization of the 3-MUB QKD protocol with
the orbital angular momentum degrees of freedom of photons.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05555</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05555</id><created>2015-12-17</created><updated>2016-07-10</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Zhu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Yungui</forenames></author></authors><title>PPN parameters in gravitational theory with nonminimally derivative
  coupling</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>minor corrections, 1 table added, Int. J. Mod. Phys. D in press</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys. D 26 (2017) 1750005</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817500055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The nonminimal coupling of the kinetic term to Einstein's tensor helps the
implementation of inflationary models due to the gravitationally enhanced
friction. We calculate the parametrized post-Newtonian (PPN) parameters for the
scalar--tensor theory of gravity with nonminimally derivative coupling. We find
that under experimental constraint from the orbits of millisecond pulsars in
our galaxy, the theory deviates from Einstein's general relativity in the order
of $10^{-20}$, and the effect of the nonminimal coupling is negligible if we
take the scalar field as dynamical dark energy. With the assumed conditions
that the background scalar field is spatially homogeneous and evolves only on
cosmological timescales and the contribution to stress--energy in the solar
system from the background scalar field is subdominant, the scalar field is
required to be massless.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.06525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.06525</id><created>2015-12-21</created><updated>2016-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>van Milligen</keyname><forenames>B. Ph.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Estrada</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Carreras</keyname><forenames>B. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ascas&#xed;bar</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hidalgo</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pastor</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fontdecaba</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balb&#xed;n</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Team</keyname><forenames>the TJ-II</forenames></author></authors><title>The causal impact of magnetic fluctuations in slow and fast L-H
  transitions at TJ-II</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>38 pages, 15 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4958807</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work focuses on the relationship between L-H (or L-I) transitions and
MHD activity in the low magnetic shear TJ-II stellarator. It is shown that the
presence of a low order rational surface in the plasma edge (gradient) region
lowers the threshold density for H-mode access. MHD activity is systematically
suppressed near the confinement transition.
  We apply a causality detection technique (based on the Transfer Entropy) to
study the relation between magnetic oscillations and locally measured plasma
rotation velocity (related to Zonal Flows). For this purpose, we study a large
number of discharges in two magnetic configurations, corresponding to 'fast'
and 'slow' transitions. With the 'slow' transitions, the developing Zonal Flow
prior to the transition is associated with the gradual reduction of magnetic
oscillations. The transition itself is marked by a strong spike of 'information
transfer' from magnetic to velocity oscillations, suggesting that the magnetic
drive may play a role in setting up the final sheared flow responsible for the
H-mode transport barrier. Similar observations were made for the 'fast'
transitions. Thus, it is shown that magnetic oscillations associated with
rational surfaces play an important and active role in confinement transitions,
so that electromagnetic effects should be included in any complete transition
model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07235</id><created>2015-12-22</created><updated>2016-06-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Govenius</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lake</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;tt&#xf6;nen</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of zeptojoule microwave pulses using electrothermal feedback
  in proximity-induced Josephson junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 030802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.030802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We experimentally investigate and utilize electrothermal feedback in a
microwave nanobolometer based on a normal-metal
($\mbox{Au}_{x}\mbox{Pd}_{1-x}$) nanowire with proximity-induced
superconductivity. The feedback couples the temperature and the electrical
degrees of freedom in the nanowire, which both absorbs the incoming microwave
radiation, and transduces the temperature change into a radio-frequency
electrical signal. We tune the feedback in situ and access both positive and
negative feedback regimes with rich nonlinear dynamics. In particular, strong
positive feedback leads to the emergence of two metastable electron temperature
states in the millikelvin range. We use these states for efficient threshold
detection of coherent 8.4 GHz microwave pulses containing approximately 200
photons on average, corresponding to $1.1 \mbox{ zJ} \approx 7.0 \mbox{ meV}$
of energy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.07836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.07836</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhattacharya</keyname><forenames>Kolahal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Banerjee</keyname><forenames>Sudeshna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mondal</keyname><forenames>Naba K</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical computation of process noise matrix in Kalman filter for
  fitting curved tracks in magnetic field within dense, thick scatterers</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>Total 27 pages, 14 figures, 2 tables</comments><journal-ref>European Physical Journal C, Volume: 76, Issue: 382, 07 July 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4243-1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the context of track fitting problems by a Kalman filter, the appropriate
functional forms of the elements of the random process noise matrix are derived
for tracking through thick layers of dense materials and magnetic field. This
work complements the form of the process noise matrix obtained by Mankel[1].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09374</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09374</id><created>2015-12-29</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arroja</keyname><forenames>Frederico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartolo</keyname><forenames>Nicola</forenames></author><author><keyname>Karmakar</keyname><forenames>Purnendu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matarrese</keyname><forenames>Sabino</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological perturbations in mimetic Horndeski gravity</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>v1: 17 pages. v2: minor changes, typos corrected and references
  added. Published version. v3: equations of Appendix D corrected. No changes
  in the conclusions. Supersedes published version</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 04 (2016) 042</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/04/042</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study linear scalar perturbations around a flat FLRW background in mimetic
Horndeski gravity. In the absence of matter, we show that the Newtonian
potential satisfies a second-order differential equation with no spatial
derivatives. This implies that the sound speed for scalar perturbations is
exactly zero on this background. We also show that in mimetic $G^3$ theories
the sound speed is equally zero. We obtain the equation of motion for the
comoving curvature perturbation (first order differential equation) and solve
it to find that the comoving curvature perturbation is constant on all scales
in mimetic Horndeski gravity. We find solutions for the Newtonian potential
evolution equation in two simple models. Finally we show that the sound speed
is zero on all backgrounds and therefore the system does not have any wave-like
scalar degrees of freedom.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.03143</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.03143</id><created>2016-01-13</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Soroushfar</keyname><forenames>Saheb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saffari</keyname><forenames>Reza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahami</keyname><forenames>Ehsan</forenames></author></authors><title>Geodesic equations in the static and rotating dilaton black holes:
  Analytical solutions and applications</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>29 figures, 4 tables, 35 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 024010 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.024010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we consider the timelike and null geodesics around the static
[GMGHS (Gibbons, Maeda, Garfinkle, Horowitz and Strominger), magnetically
charged GMGHS, electrically charged GMGHS] and the rotating (Kerr-Sen
dilaton-axion) dilaton black holes. The geodesic equations are solved in terms
of Weierstrass elliptic functions. To classify the trajectories around the
black holes, we use the analytical solution and effective potential techniques
and then characterize the different types of the resulting orbits in terms of
the conserved energy and angular momentum. Also, using the obtained results we
study astrophysical applications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.00673</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.00673</id><created>2016-02-01</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mart&#xed;nez-Rodr&#xed;guez</keyname><forenames>H&#xe9;ctor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piro</keyname><forenames>Anthony L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwab</keyname><forenames>Josiah</forenames></author><author><keyname>Badenes</keyname><forenames>Carles</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutronization During Carbon Simmering In Type Ia Supernova Progenitors</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 16 figures, 6 tables, accepted for publication in the ApJ</comments><doi>10.3847/0004-637X/825/1/57</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When a Type Ia supernova (SN Ia) progenitor first ignites carbon in its core,
it undergoes ${\sim} \,10^{3}-10^{4} \,$yr of convective burning prior to the
onset of thermonuclear runaway. This carbon simmering phase is important for
setting the thermal profile and composition of the white dwarf. Using the
\texttt{MESA} stellar evolution code, we follow this convective burning and
examine the production of neutron-rich isotopes. The neutron content of the SN
fuel has important consequences for the ensuing nucleosynthesis, and, in
particular, for the production of secondary Fe-peak nuclei like Mn and stable
Ni. These elements have been observed in the X-ray spectra of SN remnants like
Tycho, Kepler, and 3C 397, and their yields can provide valuable insights into
the physics of SNe Ia and the properties of their progenitors. We find that
weak reactions during simmering can at most generate a neutron excess of
${\approx} \, 3 \times 10^{-4}$. This is ${\approx} \, 8 \times 10^{-4}$ lower
than that found in previous studies that do not take the full density and
temperature profile of the simmering region into account. Our results imply
that the progenitor metallicity is the main contributor to the neutron excess
in SN Ia fuel for $Z \gtrsim 1/3 \, Z_{\odot}$. Alternatively, at lower
metallicities, this neutron excess provides a floor that should be present in
any centrally-ignited SN~Ia scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.01714</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.01714</id><created>2016-02-04</created><updated>2016-06-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Konstantinou-Rizos</keyname><forenames>Sotiris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mikhailov</keyname><forenames>Alexander V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anticommutative extension of the Adler map</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>Revised version: Small paragraph added to the introduction, and some
  other minor changes</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 30LT03 (7pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/30/30LT03</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct a noncommutative (Grassmann) extension of the well known Adler
Yang-Baxter map. It satisfies the Yang-Baxter equation, it is reversible and
birational. Our extension preserves all the properties of the original map
except the involutivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02024</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02024</id><created>2016-02-05</created><updated>2016-06-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Nakano</keyname><forenames>Kosuke</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hongo</keyname><forenames>Kenta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maezono</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author></authors><title>Phonon dispersions and Fermi surfaces nesting explaining the variety of
  charge ordering in titanium-oxypnictides superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>Scientific Reports accepted</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 29661, (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29661</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There has been a puzzle between experiments and theoretical predictions on
the charge ordering of layered titanium-oxypnictides superconductors.
Unconventional mechanisms to explain this discrepancy have been argued so far,
even affecting the understanding of superconductivity on the compound. We
provide a new theoretical prediction, by which the discrepancy itself is
resolved without any complicated unconventional explanation. Phonon dispersions
and changes of nesting vectors in Fermi surfaces are clarified to lead to the
variety of superlattice structures even for the common crystal structures when
without CDW, including orthorhombic $2 \times 2 \times 1$ one for
BaTi$_2$As$_2$O, which has not yet been explained successfully so far, being
different from tetragonal $\sqrt{2} \times \sqrt{2} \times 1$ for
BaTi$_2$Sb$_2$O and BaTi$_2$Bi$_2$O. The electronic structure analysis can
naturally explain experimental observations about CDW including most latest
ones without any cramped unconventional mechanisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04526</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04526</id><created>2016-02-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Fenker</keyname><forenames>Benjamin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behr</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Melconian</keyname><forenames>Dan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anderson</keyname><forenames>Rhys M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Anholm</keyname><forenames>Melissa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ashery</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Behling</keyname><forenames>Richard S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cohen</keyname><forenames>Iuliana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Craiciu</keyname><forenames>Ioana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Donohue</keyname><forenames>John M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farfan</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friesen</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorelov</keyname><forenames>Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>McNeil</keyname><forenames>James</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mehlman</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Norton</keyname><forenames>Heather</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olchanski</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smale</keyname><forenames>Scott</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theriault</keyname><forenames>O</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vantyghem</keyname><forenames>Adrian N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Warner</keyname><forenames>Claire L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Precision measurement of the nuclear polarization in laser-cooled,
  optically pumped $^{37}\mathrm{K}$</title><categories>physics.atom-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>32 pages, 11 figures, submitted to New Journal of Physics</comments><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/18/7/073028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a measurement of the nuclear polarization of laser-cooled,
optically-pumped $^{37}\mathrm{K}$ atoms which will allow us to precisely
measure angular correlation parameters in the beta-decay of the same atoms.
These results will be used to test the $V-A$ framework of the weak interaction
at high precision. At the TRIUMF Neutral Atom Trap (TRINAT), a magneto-optical
trap (MOT) confines and cools neutral $^{37}\mathrm{K}$ atoms and optical
pumping spin-polarizes them. We monitor the nuclear polarization of the same
atoms that are decaying in situ by photoionizing a small fraction of the
partially polarized atoms and then use the standard optical Bloch equations to
model their population distribution. We obtain an average nuclear polarization
of $P = 0.9913\pm0.0008$, which is significantly more precise than previous
measurements with this technique. Since our current measurement of the
beta-asymmetry has $0.2\%$ statistical uncertainty, the polarization
measurement reported here will not limit its overall uncertainty. This result
also demonstrates the capability to measure the polarization to $&lt;0.1\%$,
allowing for a measurement of angular correlation parameters to this level of
precision, which would be competitive in searches for new physics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.06772</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.06772</id><created>2016-02-22</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Owerre</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>A first theoretical realization of honeycomb topological magnon
  insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>12 pages with 6 figures. Published version</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Condens. Matter 28 (2016) 386001</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0953-8984/28/38/386001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It has been recently shown that in the Heisenberg (anti)ferromagnet on the
honeycomb lattice, the magnons (spin wave quasipacticles) realize a massless
two-dimensional (2D) Dirac-like Hamiltonian. It was shown that the Dirac magnon
Hamiltonian preserves time-reversal symmetry defined with the sublattice pseudo
spins and the Dirac points are robust against magnon-magnon interactions. The
Dirac points also occur at nonzero energy. In this paper, we propose a simple
realization of nontrivial topology (magnon edge states) in this system. We show
that the Dirac points are gapped when the inversion symmetry of the lattice is
broken by introducing a next-nearest neighbour Dzyaloshinskii-Moriya (DM)
interaction. Thus, the system realizes magnon edge states similar to Haldane
model for quantum anomalous Hall effect in electronic systems. However, in
contrast to electronic spin current where dissipation can be very large due to
Ohmic heating, noninteracting topological magnons can propagate for long time
without dissipation as magnons are uncharged particles. We observe the same
magnon edge states for the XY model on the honeycomb lattice. Remarkably, in
this case the model maps to interacting hardcore bosons on the honeycomb
lattice. Quantum magnetic systems with nontrivial magnon edge states are called
topological magnon insulators. They have been studied theoretically on the
kagome lattice and recently observed experimentally on the kagome magnet
Cu(1-3, bdc) with three magnon bulk bands. Our results for the honeycomb
lattice suggests an experimental procedure to search for honeycomb topological
magnon insulators within a class of 2D quantum magnets and ultracold atoms
trapped in honeycomb optical lattices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08046</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08046</id><created>2016-02-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosenberg</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chiesa</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shiwei</forenames></author></authors><title>Rashba spin-orbit coupling, strong interactions, and the BCS-BEC
  crossover in the ground state of the two-dimensional Fermi Gas</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 040401 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.040401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent experimental realization of spin-orbit coupled Fermi gases
provides a unique opportunity to study the interplay between strong interaction
and SOC in a tunable, disorder-free system. We present here precision ab initio
numerical results on the two-dimensional, unpolarized, uniform Fermi gas with
attractive interactions and Rashba SOC. Using auxiliary-field quantum Monte
Carlo and incorporating recent algorithmic advances, we carry out exact
calculations on sufficiently large system sizes to provide accurate results
systematically as a function of experimental parameters. We obtain the equation
of state, the momentum distributions, the pseudo-spin correlations and the
pairing wave functions. Our results help illuminate the rich pairing structure
induced by SOC, and provide benchmarks for theory and guidance to future
experimental efforts.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02511</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02511</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Dornmair</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schroeder</keyname><forenames>C. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Floettmann</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marchetti</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maier</keyname><forenames>A. R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasma-driven ultrashort bunch diagnostic</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><doi>10.1103/PhysRevAccelBeams.19.062801</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ultrashort electron bunches are crucial for an increasing number of
applications, however, diagnosing their longitudinal phase space remains a
challenge. We propose a new method that harnesses the strong electric fields
present in a laser driven plasma wakefield. By transversely displacing driver
laser and witness bunch, a streaking field is applied to the bunch. This field
maps the time information to a transverse momentum change and, consequently, to
a change of transverse position. We illustrate our method with simulations
where we achieve a time resolution in the attosecond range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.05385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.05385</id><created>2016-03-17</created><updated>2016-06-03</updated><authors><author><keyname>Alam</keyname><forenames>Md. Mehboob</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knecht</keyname><forenames>Stefan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fromager</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Ghost interaction correction in ensemble density-functional theory for
  excited states with and without range separation</title><categories>physics.chem-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012511 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012511</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Ensemble density-functional theory (eDFT) suffers from the so-called &quot;ghost
interaction&quot; error when approximate exchange-correlation functionals are used.
In this work, we present a rigorous ghost interaction correction (GIC) scheme
in the context of range-separated eDFT. The method relies on an exact
decomposition of the ensemble short-range exchange-correlation energy into a
multideterminantal exact exchange term, which involves the long-range
interacting ensemble density matrix instead of the Kohn--Sham (KS) one, and a
complementary density-functional correlation energy. A generalized adiabatic
connection formula is derived for the latter. In order to perform practical
calculations, the complementary correlation functional has been simply modeled
by its ground-state local density approximation (LDA) while long-range
interacting ground- and excited-state wavefunctions have been obtained
self-consistently by combining a long-range configuration interaction
calculation with a short-range LDA potential. We show that GIC reduces the
curvature of approximate range-separated ensemble energies drastically while
providing considerably more accurate excitation energies, even for
charge-transfer and double excitations. Interestingly, the method performs well
also in the context of standard KS-eDFT, which is recovered when the
range-separation parameter is set to zero.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06246</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06246</id><created>2016-03-20</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jevicki</keyname><forenames>Antal</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suzuki</keyname><forenames>Kenta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoon</keyname><forenames>Junggi</forenames></author></authors><title>Bi-Local Holography in the SYK Model</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 6 figures; v2: minor corrections, typos corrected and
  references added; v3: typos corrected and references added; v4: improved
  discussion of AdS bulk interpretation; v5: improved discussion of zero mode
  and reference added; v6: improved discussion of zero mode, references added,
  version to appear in JHEP; v7: reference added</comments><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)007</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss large $N$ rules of the Sachdev-Ye-Kitaev model and the bi-local
representation of holography of this theory. This is done by establishing $1/N$
Feynman rules in terms of bi-local propagators and vertices, which can be
evaluated following the recent procedure of Polchinski and Rosenhaus. These
rules can be interpreted as Witten type diagrams of the dual AdS theory, which
we are able to define at IR fixed point and off.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07601</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07601</id><created>2016-03-24</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Fuminobu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Ryo</forenames></author></authors><title>Renormalization Group Improved Higgs Inflation with a Running Kinetic
  Term</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-ex</categories><comments>14 pages, 1 figure, published version</comments><report-no>TU-1019, IPMU16-0038</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B760 (2016) 329-334</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a Higgs inflation model with a running kinetic term, taking account
of the renormalization group evolution of relevant coupling constants.
Specifically we study two types of the running kinetic Higgs inflation, where
the inflaton potential is given by the quadratic or linear term potential in a
frame where the Higgs field is canonically normalized. We solve the
renormalization group equations at two-loop level and calculate the scalar
spectral index and the tensor-to-scalar ratio. We find that, even if the
renormalization group effects are included, the quadratic inflation is ruled
out by the CMB observations, while the linear one is still allowed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00088</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00088</id><created>2016-03-31</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Panzarino</keyname><forenames>Jason F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupert</keyname><forenames>Timothy J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Plasticity-induced restructuring of a nanocrystalline grain boundary
  network</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>13 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The grain boundary-mediated mechanisms that control plastic deformation of
nanocrystalline metals should cause evolution of the grain boundary network,
since they directly alter misorientation relationships between crystals.
Unfortunately, current experimental techniques are unable to track such
evolution, due to limits on both spatial and temporal resolution. In this work,
molecular dynamics simulations are used to study grain boundary restructuring
in nanocrystalline Al during both monotonic tension and cyclic loading. This
task is enabled by the creation of new analysis tools for atomistic datasets
that allow for a complete characterization and tracking of microstructural
descriptors of the grain boundary network. Quantitative measurements of grain
boundary character distribution, triple junction type, grain boundary plane
normal, and other interfacial network characteristics are extracted and
analyzed. The results presented here show that nanocrystalline plasticity leads
to an increase in special boundary fraction and disruption of two-dimensional
boundary connectivity, with the most dramatic evolution occurring in the
smallest grain sizes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00184</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00184</id><created>2016-04-01</created><updated>2016-04-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hosoi</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuura</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishida</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mizukami</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Watashige</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kasahara</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsuda</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shibauchi</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nematic quantum critical point without magnetism in FeSe1-xSx
  superconductors</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures. Some discussions are added</comments><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA 113, 8139-8143 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1605806113</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The importance of antiferromagnetic fluctuations are widely acknowledged in
most unconventional superconductors. In addition, cuprates and iron pnictides
often exhibit unidirectional (nematic) electronic correlations, including
stripe and orbital orders, whose fluctuations may also play a key role for
electron pairing. However, these nematic correlations are intertwined with
antiferromagnetic or charge orders, preventing us to identify the essential
role of nematic fluctuations. This calls for new materials having only
nematicity without competing or coexisting orders. Here we report systematic
elastoresistance measurements in FeSe$_{1-x}$S$_{x}$ superconductors, which,
unlike other iron-based families, exhibit an electronic nematic order without
accompanying antiferromagnetic order. We find that the nematic transition
temperature decreases with sulphur content $x$, whereas the nematic
fluctuations are strongly enhanced. Near $x\approx0.17$, the nematic
susceptibility diverges towards absolute zero, revealing a nematic quantum
critical point. This highlights FeSe$_{1-x}$S$_{x}$ as a unique nonmagnetic
system suitable for studying the impact of nematicity on superconductivity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01975</id><created>2016-04-05</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Y. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maguire</keyname><forenames>G. Q.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author><author><keyname>Noz</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Do Small-mass Neutrinos participate in Gauge Transformations?</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>15 pages</comments><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics Volume 2016, Article ID 1847620</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/1847620</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Neutrino oscillation experiments presently suggest that neutrinos have a
small but finite mass. If neutrinos are to have mass, there should be a Lorentz
frame in which they can be brought to rest. This paper discusses how Wigner's
little groups can be used to distinguish between massive and massless
particles. We derive a representation of the SL(2,c) group which separates out
the two sets of spinors contained therein. One set is gauge dependent. The
other set is gauge-invariant and represents polarized neutrinos. We show that a
similar calculation can be done for the Dirac equation. In the
large-momentum/zero-mass limit, the Dirac spinors can be separated into large
and small components. The large components are gauge invariant, while the small
components are not. These small components represent spin-$\frac{1}{2}$
non-zero mass particles. If we renormalize the large components, these gauge
invariant spinors again represent the polarization of neutrinos. Massive
neutrinos cannot be invariant under gauge transformations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02069</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02069</id><created>2016-04-07</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hashino</keyname><forenames>Katsuya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kakizaki</keyname><forenames>Mitsuru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kanemura</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Matsui</keyname><forenames>Toshinori</forenames></author></authors><title>Synergy between measurements of the gravitational wave and the triple
  Higgs coupling in probing first order phase transition</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>29 pages, 18 figures, version published in Physical Review D</comments><report-no>UT-HET 112</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 015005 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.015005</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Probing the Higgs potential and new physics behind the electroweak symmetry
breaking is one of the most important issues of particle physics. In
particular, nature of electroweak phase transition is essential for
understanding physics at the early Universe, such that the strongly first order
phase transition is required for a successful scenario of electroweak
baryogenesis. The strongly first order phase transition is expected to be
tested by precisely measuring the triple Higgs boson coupling at future
colliders like the International Linear Collider. It can also be explored via
the spectrum of stochastic gravitational waves to be measured at future
space-based interferometers such as eLISA and DECIGO. We discuss
complementarity of both the methods in testing the strongly first order phase
transition of the electroweak symmetry in models with additional isospin
singlet scalar fields with and without classical scale invariance. We find that
they are synergetic in identifying specific models of electroweak symmetry
breaking in more details.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03043</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03043</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pastore</keyname><forenames>Raffaele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coniglio</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Candia</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fierro</keyname><forenames>Annalisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciamarra</keyname><forenames>Massimo Pica</forenames></author></authors><title>Cage-jump motion reveals universal dynamics and non-universal structural
  features in glass forming liquids</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>Published in the J. Stat. Mech. Special Issue &quot;The Role of Structure
  in Glassy and Jammed Systems&quot;</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 054050 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/05/054050</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The sluggish and heterogeneous dynamics of glass forming liquids is
frequently associated to the transient coexistence of two phases of particles,
respectively with an high and low mobility. In the absence of a dynamical order
parameter that acquires a transient bimodal shape, these phases are commonly
identified empirically, which makes difficult investigating their relation with
the structural properties of the system. Here we show that the distribution of
single particle diffusivities can be accessed within a Continuous Time Random
Walk description of the intermittent motion, and that this distribution
acquires a transient bimodal shape in the deeply supercooled regime, thus
allowing for a clear identification of the two coexisting phase. In a simple
two-dimensional glass forming model, the dynamic phase coexistence is
accompanied by a striking structural counterpart: the distribution of the
crystalline-like order parameter becomes also bimodal on cooling, with
increasing overlap between ordered and immobile particles. This simple
structural signature is absent in other models, such as the three-dimesional
Kob-Andersen Lennard-Jones mixture, where more sophisticated order parameters
might be relevant. In this perspective, the identification of the two dynamical
coexisting phases opens the way to deeper investigations of structure-dynamics
correlations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03577</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03577</id><created>2016-04-12</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Araujo</keyname><forenames>Jonas B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casana</keyname><forenames>Rodolfo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferreira</keyname><forenames>Manoel M.</forenames><suffix>Jr</suffix></author></authors><title>General CPT-even dimension-five nonminimal couplings between fermions
  and photons yielding EDM and MDM</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B, Vol. 760, p. 302-308 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.070</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, we examine a new class of CPT-even nonminimal interactions,
between fermions and photons, deprived of higher order derivatives, that yields
electric dipole moment (EDM) and magnetic dipole moment (MDM) in the context of
the Dirac equation. The couplings are dimension-five CPT-even and
Lorentz-violating nonminimal structures, composed of a rank-2 tensor,
$T_{\mu\nu}$, the electromagnetic tensor, and gamma matrices, being addressed
in its axial and non-axial Hermitian versions, and also comprising general
possibilities. We then use the electron's anomalous magnetic dipole moment and
electron electric dipole moment measurements to reach upper bounds of $1$ part
in $10^{20}$ and $10^{25}$ (eV )$^{-1}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.03983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.03983</id><created>2016-04-13</created><updated>2016-04-27</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moriya</keyname><forenames>Takashi J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tauris</keyname><forenames>Thomas M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining the ellipticity of strongly magnetized neutron stars
  powering superluminous supernovae</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure, 1 table, accepted by Monthly Notices of the Royal
  Astronomical Society Letters</comments><journal-ref>Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society: Letters, Volume
  460, Issue 1, p.L55-L58 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Superluminous supernovae (SLSNe) have been suggested to be powered by
strongly magnetized, rapidly rotating neutron stars which are often called
magnetars. In this process, rotational energy of the magnetar is radiated via
magnetic dipole radiation and heats the supernova ejecta. However, if magnetars
are highly distorted in their geometric shape, rotational energy is mainly lost
as gravitational wave radiation and thus such magnetars cannot power SLSNe. By
simply comparing electromagnetic and gravitational wave emission timescales, we
constrain upper limits to the ellipticity of magnetars by assuming that they
power the observed SLSNe. We find that their ellipticity typically needs to be
less than about a few 1e-3. This indicates that the toroidal magnetic field
strengths in these magnetars are typically less than a few 1e16 G so that their
distortions remain small. Because light-curve modelling of SLSNe shows that
their dipole magnetic field strengths are of the order of 1e14 G, the ratio of
poloidal to toroidal magnetic field strengths is found to be larger than ~ 0.01
in magnetars powering SLSNe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08509</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08509</id><created>2016-04-28</created><updated>2016-07-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reich</keyname><forenames>K. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shklovskii</keyname><forenames>B. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous conductivity, Hall factor, magnetoresistance, and thermopower
  of accumulation layer in $\text{SrTiO}_3$</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045310 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045310</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the low temperature conductivity of the electron accumulation layer
induced by the very strong electric field at the surface of $\text{SrTiO}_3$
sample. Due to the strongly nonlinear lattice dielectric response, the
three-dimensional density of electrons $n(x)$ in such a layer decays with the
distance from the surface $x$ very slowly as $n(x) \propto 1/x^{12/7}$. We show
that when the mobility is limited by the surface scattering the contribution of
such a tail to the conductivity diverges at large $x$ because of growing time
electrons need to reach the surface. We explore truncation of this divergence
by the finite sample width, by the bulk scattering rate, or by the crossover to
the bulk linear dielectric response with the dielectric constant $\kappa$. As a
result we arrive at the anomalously large mobility, which depends not only on
the rate of the surface scattering, but also on the physics of truncation.
Similar anomalous behavior is found for the Hall factor, the magnetoresistance,
and the thermopower.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01326</id><created>2016-05-04</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ferrer-i-Cancho</keyname><forenames>Ramon</forenames></author></authors><title>Compression and the origins of Zipf's law for word frequencies</title><categories>cs.CL physics.data-an physics.soc-ph q-bio.NC</categories><comments>arguments have been improved; in press in Complexity (Wiley)</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we sketch a new derivation of Zipf's law for word frequencies based on
optimal coding. The structure of the derivation is reminiscent of Mandelbrot's
random typing model but it has multiple advantages over random typing: (1) it
starts from realistic cognitive pressures (2) it does not require fine tuning
of parameters and (3) it sheds light on the origins of other statistical laws
of language and thus can lead to a compact theory of linguistic laws. Our
findings suggest that the recurrence of Zipf's law in human languages could
originate from pressure for easy and fast communication.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01728</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01728</id><created>2016-05-05</created><updated>2016-07-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Shi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cautun</keyname><forenames>Marius</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenk</keyname><forenames>Carlos S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Liang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Crain</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaller</keyname><forenames>Matthieu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schaye</keyname><forenames>Joop</forenames></author><author><keyname>Theuns</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author></authors><title>Alignments between galaxies, satellite systems and haloes</title><categories>astro-ph.GA astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>12 pages, 13 figures, 1 table. Updated to match published version</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1247</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The spatial distribution of the satellite populations of the Milky Way and
Andromeda are puzzling in that they are nearly perpendicular to the disks of
their central galaxies. To understand the origin of such configurations we
study the alignment of the central galaxy, satellite system and dark matter
halo in the largest of the &quot;Evolution and Assembly of GaLaxies and their
Environments&quot; (EAGLE) simulation. We find that centrals and their satellite
systems tend to be well aligned with their haloes, with a median misalignment
angle of $33^{\circ}$ in both cases. While the centrals are better aligned with
the inner $10$ kpc halo, the satellite systems are better aligned with the
entire halo indicating that satellites preferentially trace the outer halo. The
central - satellite alignment is weak (median misalignment angle of
$52^{\circ}$) and we find that around $20\%$ of systems have a misalignment
angle larger than $78^{\circ}$, which is the value for the Milky Way. The
central - satellite alignment is a consequence of the tendency of both
components to align with the dark matter halo. As a consequence, when the
central is parallel to the satellite system, it also tends to be parallel to
the halo. In contrast, if the central is perpendicular to the satellite system,
as in the case of the Milky Way and Andromeda, then the central - halo
alignment is much weaker. Dispersion-dominated (spheroidal) centrals have a
stronger alignment with both their halo and their satellites than
rotation-dominated (disk) centrals. We also found that the halo, the central
galaxy and the satellite system tend to be aligned with the surrounding
large-scale distribution of matter, with the halo being the better aligned of
the three.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.02182</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.02182</id><created>2016-05-07</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aseev</keyname><forenames>P. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nagaev</keyname><forenames>K. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Shot noise in the edge states of 2D topological insulators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045425 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045425</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the resistance and shot noise in the edge states of a 2D
topological insulator that result from the exchange of electrons between these
states and conducting puddles in the bulk of the insulator. The two limiting
cases where the energy relaxation is either absent or very strong are
considered. A finite time of spin relaxation in the puddles is introduced
phenomenologically. Depending on this time and on the strength of coupling
between the edge states and the puddles, the Fano factor $F=S_I/2eI$ ranges
from 0 to 1/3, which is in an agreement with the available experimental data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03632</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03632</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Leon</keyname><forenames>Gabriel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bengochea</keyname><forenames>Gabriel R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Landau</keyname><forenames>Susana J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-matter bounce and inflation in the light of the CSL model</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.CO quant-ph</categories><comments>27 pages, including 6 figures, 2 tables and one Appendix. Final
  version. Accepted in EPJC</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76 (2016) 407</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4245-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Continuous Spontaneous Localization (CSL) model has been proposed as a
possible solution to the quantum measurement problem by modifying the
Schr\&quot;{o}dinger equation. In this work, we apply the CSL model to two
cosmological models of the early Universe: the matter bounce scenario and slow
roll inflation. In particular, we focus on the generation of the classical
primordial inhomogeneities and anisotropies that arise from the dynamical
evolution, provided by the CSL mechanism, of the quantum state associated to
the quantum fields. In each case, we obtained a prediction for the shape and
the parameters characterizing the primordial spectra (scalar and tensor), i.e.
the amplitude, the spectral index and the tensor-to-scalar ratio. We found that
there exist CSL parameter values, allowed by other non-cosmological
experiments, for which our predictions for the angular power spectrum of the
CMB temperature anisotropy are consistent with the best fit canonical model to
the latest data released by the Planck Collaboration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07562</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07562</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-06-24</updated><authors><author><keyname>Borrero-Echeverry</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrison</keyname><forenames>Benjamin C. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Aqueous ammonium thiocyanate solutions as refractive index-matching
  fluids with low density and viscosity</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures. Corrected missing minus signs in Table 1</comments><journal-ref>Exp. Fluids 57, 123 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s00348-016-2207-8</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that aqueous solutions of ammonium thiocyanate (NH4SCN) can be used
to match the index of refraction of several transparent materials commonly used
in experiments, while maintaining low viscosity and density compared to other
common refractive index-matching liquids. We present empirical models for
estimating the index of refraction, density, and kinematic viscosity of these
solutions as a function of temperature and concentration. Finally, we summarize
the chemical compatibility of ammonium thiocyanate with materials commonly used
in apparatus.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.07720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.07720</id><created>2016-05-24</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ghiglieri</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Laine</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Neutrino dynamics below the electroweak crossover</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>42 pages. v2: references and clarifications added</comments><journal-ref>JCAP 1607 (2016) 015</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/07/015</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We estimate the thermal masses and damping rates of active (m &lt; eV) and
sterile (M ~ GeV) neutrinos with thermal momenta k ~ 3T at temperatures below
the electroweak crossover (5 GeV &lt; T &lt; 160 GeV). These quantities fix the
equilibration or &quot;washout&quot; rates of Standard Model lepton number densities.
Sterile neutrinos interact via direct scatterings mediated by Yukawa couplings,
and via their overlap with active neutrinos. Including all leading-order
reactions we find that the washout rate generally exceeds the Hubble rate for 5
GeV &lt; T &lt; 30 GeV. Therefore it is challenging to generate a large lepton
asymmetry facilitating dark matter computations operating at T &lt; 5 GeV, whereas
the generation of a baryon asymmetry at T &gt; 130 GeV remains an option. Our
differential rates are tabulated in a form suitable for studies of specific
scenarios with given neutrino Yukawa matrices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08975</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08975</id><created>2016-05-29</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Soroushfar</keyname><forenames>Saheb</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saffari</keyname><forenames>Reza</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grunau</keyname><forenames>Saskia</forenames></author></authors><title>Geodesic motion in the spacetime of a static charged black hole in
  $f(R)$ gravity</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>This paper has been merged with arXiv:1605.08976, 18 pages, 2 tables
  , 8 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the present paper we study the geodesic motion of test particles and light
rays in the spacetime of a static charged black hole in $f(R)$ gravity. The
complete set of analytic solutions of the geodesic equations in the spacetime
of this black hole are presented. The geodesic equations are solved in terms of
Weierstrass elliptic $\wp$ function and derivatives of Kleinian $\sigma$
function. With the help of parametric diagrams and effective potentials we
analyze the geodesic motion and give a list of all possible orbit types. The
different types of the resulting orbits are characterized in terms of the
conserved energy, angular momentum, charge and cosmological constant.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00065</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00065</id><created>2016-05-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Kundu</keyname><forenames>Joyjit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pascal</keyname><forenames>Tod</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prendergast</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Whitelam</keyname><forenames>Stephen</forenames></author></authors><title>Selective gas capture via kinetic trapping</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>12 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1039/C6CP03940E</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Conventional approaches to the capture of CO_2 by metal-organic frameworks
focus on equilibrium conditions, and frameworks that contain little CO_2 in
equilibrium are often rejected as carbon-capture materials. Here we use a
statistical mechanical model, parameterized by quantum mechanical data, to
suggest that metal-organic frameworks can be used to separate CO_2 from a
typical flue gas mixture when used under {\em nonequilibrium} conditions. The
origin of this selectivity is an emergent gas-separation mechanism that results
from the acquisition by different gas types of different mobilities within a
crowded framework. The resulting distribution of gas types within the framework
is in general spatially and dynamically heterogeneous. Our results suggest that
relaxing the requirement of equilibrium can substantially increase the
parameter space of conditions and materials for which selective gas capture can
be effected.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.01127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.01127</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Plotnikov</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rouillard</keyname><forenames>A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davies</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bothmer</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eastwood</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gallagher</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harrison</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kilpua</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;stl</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perry</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodriguez</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lavraud</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>G&#xe9;not</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pinto</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Diaz</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-Term Tracking of Corotating Density Structures using Heliospheric
  Imaging</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>27 pages, 12 figures, published in Solar Physics</comments><doi>10.1007/s11207-016-0935-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The systematic monitoring of the solar wind in high-cadence and
high-resolution heliospheric images taken by the Solar-Terrestrial Relation
Observatory (STEREO) spacecraft permits the study of the spatial and temporal
evolution of variable solar wind flows from the Sun out to 1~AU, and beyond. As
part of the EU Framework 7 (FP7) Heliospheric Cataloguing, Analysis and
Techniques Service (HELCATS) project, we have generated a catalogue listing the
properties of 190 corotating structures well-observed in images taken by the
Heliospheric Imager instruments on-board STEREO-A. We present here one of very
few long-term analyses of solar wind structures advected by the background
solar wind. This analysis confirms that most of the corotating density
structures detected by the heliospheric imagers comprises a series of density
inhomogeneities advected by the slow solar wind that eventually become
entrained by stream interaction regions. We have derived the spatial-temporal
evolution of each of these corotating density structures by using a
well-established fitting technique. The mean radial propagation speed of the
corotating structures is found to be $311 \pm 31$ km~s$^{-1}$. We predicted the
arrival time of each corotating density structure at different probes. We show
that the speeds of the corotating density structures derived using our fitting
technique track well the long-term variation of the radial speed of the slow
solar wind during solar minimum years (2007--2008). Furthermore, we demonstrate
that these features originate near the coronal neutral line that eventually
becomes the heliospheric current sheet.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.03879</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.03879</id><created>2016-06-13</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Langfeld</keyname><forenames>Kurt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lucini</keyname><forenames>Biagio</forenames></author></authors><title>Form the density-of-states method to finite density quantum field theory</title><categories>hep-lat hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>12 pages, 14 figures, based upon talks presented at Excited QCD 2016,
  6-12 March 2016, Costa da Caparica, Portugal; typos corrected in this final
  version</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the last 40 years, Monte Carlo calculations based upon Importance
Sampling have matured into the most widely employed method for determinig first
principle results in QCD. Nevertheless, Importance Sampling leads to
spectacular failures in situations in which certain rare configurations play a
non-secondary role as it is the case for Yang-Mills theories near a first order
phase transition or quantum field theories at finite matter density when
studied with the re-weighting method. The density-of-states method in its LLR
formulation has the potential to solve such overlap or sign problems by means
of an exponential error suppression. We here introduce the LLR approach and its
generalisation to complex action systems. Applications include U(1), SU(2) and
SU(3) gauge theories as well as the Z3 spin model at finite densities and
heavy-dense QCD.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.05257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.05257</id><created>2016-06-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Reinhardt</keyname><forenames>Aleks</forenames></author><author><keyname>Frenkel</keyname><forenames>Daan</forenames></author></authors><title>DNA brick self-assembly with an off-lattice potential</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.chem-ph</categories><journal-ref>Soft Matter 12, 6253-6260 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6SM01031H</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report Monte Carlo simulations of a simple off-lattice patchy-particle
model for DNA `bricks'. We relate the parameters that characterise this model
with the binding free energy of pairs of single-stranded DNA molecules. We
verify that an off-lattice potential parameterised in this way reproduces much
of the behaviour seen with a simpler lattice model we introduced previously,
although the relaxation of the geometric constraints leads to a more
error-prone self-assembly pathway. We investigate the self-assembly process as
a function of the strength of the non-specific interactions. We show that our
off-lattice model for DNA bricks results in robust self-assembly into a variety
of target structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.02794</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.02794</id><created>2016-07-10</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Pastore</keyname><forenames>Raffaele</forenames></author><author><keyname>de Candia</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fierro</keyname><forenames>Anallisa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciamarra</keyname><forenames>Massimo Pica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Coniglio</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster structure and dynamics in gels and glasses</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>Published in the J. Stat. Mech. Special Issue of &quot;The Role of
  Structure in Glassy and Jammed Systems &quot;</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. 074011 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/074011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamical arrest of gels is the consequence of a well defined structural
phase transition, leading to the formation of a spanning cluster of bonded
particles. The dynamical glass transition, instead, is not accompanied by any
clear structural signature. Nevertheless, both transitions are characterized by
the emergence of dynamical heterogeneities. Reviewing recent results from
numerical simulations, we discuss the behavior of dynamical heterogeneities in
different systems and show that a clear connection with the structure exists in
the case of gels. The emerging picture may be also relevant for the more
elusive case of glasses. We show, as an example, that the relaxation process of
a simple glass-forming model can be related to a reverse percolation transition
and discuss further perspective in this direction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04285</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mancini</keyname><forenames>Mattia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>Raffaella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Graziani</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Valiante</keyname><forenames>Rosa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dayal</keyname><forenames>Pratika</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maio</keyname><forenames>Umberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ciardi</keyname><forenames>Benedetta</forenames></author></authors><title>Interpreting the evolution of galaxy colours from $z = 8$ to $z = 5$</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>accepted in MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1783</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We attempt to interpret existing data on the evolution of the UV luminosity
function and UV colours, $\beta$, of galaxies at $5 \leq z \leq 8$, to improve
our understanding of their dust content and ISM properties. To this aim, we
post-process the results of a cosmological hydrodynamical simulation with a
chemical evolution model, which includes dust formation by supernovae and
intermediate mass stars, dust destruction in supernova shocks, and grain growth
by accretion of gas-phase elements in dense gas. We find that observations
require a steep, Small Magellanic Cloud-like extinction curve and a clumpy dust
distribution, where stellar populations younger than 15 Myr are still embedded
in their dusty natal clouds. Investigating the scatter in the colour
distribution and stellar mass, we find that the observed trends can be
explained by the presence of two populations: younger, less massive galaxies
where dust enrichment is mainly due to stellar sources, and massive, more
chemically evolved ones, where efficient grain growth provides the dominant
contribution to the total dust mass. Computing the IR-excess - UV color
relation we find that all but the dustiest model galaxies follow a relation
shallower than the Meurer et al. (1999) one, usually adopted to correct the
observed UV luminosities of high-$z$ galaxies for the effects of dust
extinction. As a result, their total star formation rates might have been
over-estimated. Our study illustrates the importance to incorporate a proper
treatment of dust in simulations of high-$z$ galaxies, and that massive, dusty,
UV-faint galaxies might have already appeared at $z \lesssim 7$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04655</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04655</id><created>2016-07-15</created><updated>2016-07-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Albert</keyname><forenames>Christopher G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Veronesi</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nijman</keyname><forenames>Eug&#xe8;ne</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rejlek</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Prediction of the vibroacoustic response of a structure-liner-fluid
  system based on a patch transfer function approach and direct experimental
  subsystem characterisation</title><categories>physics.class-ph</categories><journal-ref>Applied Acoustics 112, 14-24 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.apacoust.2016.05.006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The vibro-acoustic response of a structure-liner-fluid system is predicted by
application of a patch impedance coupling methodology. In contrast to existing
numerical approaches, impedance matrices of structure and liner are determined
by a direct experimental approach, avoiding the requirement of material
parameters. Emphasis is placed on poroelastic lining materials. The method
accounts for surface input and transfer terms and for cross and cross-transfer
terms through the specimen. A single test-rig characterisation procedure for
layered poroelastic media is proposed. The specimen is considered as a single
component -- no separation of layers is necessary. Problem specific boundary
conditions for skeleton and fluid, which may cause non-reciprocal cross terms,
are dealt with by the procedure. Methods of measurement for the assessment of
impedance matrices are presented and their accuracy and limitations are
discussed. An air gap correction method for surface impedance measurements is
presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04905</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04905</id><created>2016-07-17</created><updated>2016-07-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jacobsen</keyname><forenames>Gunnar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lid&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>Marisol</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Tianhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popov</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Friberg</keyname><forenames>Ari T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Pre- and Post-compensation of Chromatic Dispersion on
  Equalization Enhanced Phase Noise in Coherent Multilevel Systems</title><categories>cs.IT math.IT physics.optics</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><msc-class>94A12</msc-class><acm-class>C.2.5</acm-class><journal-ref>Journal of Optical Communications, Vol.32(4), 257-261, 2011</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we present a comparative study in order to specify the
influence of equalization enhanced phase noise (EEPN) for pre- and
post-compensation of chromatic dispersion in high capacity and high
constellation systems. This is - to our knowledge - the first detailed study in
this area for pre-compensation systems. Our main results show that the local
oscillator phase noise determines the EEPN influence in post-compensation
implementations whereas the transmitter laser determines the EEPN in
pre-compensation implementations. As a result of significance for the
implementation of practical longer-range systems it is to be emphasized that
the use of chromatic dispersion equalization in the optical domain - e.g. by
the use of dispersion compensation fibers - eliminates the EEPN entirely. Thus,
this seems a good option for such systems operating at high constellations in
the future.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05759</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05759</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>Sue Ann</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhen</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase models and clustering in networks of oscillators with delayed
  coupling</title><categories>math.DS nlin.AO</categories><msc-class>34C15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a general model for a network of oscillators with time delayed,
circulant coupling. We use the theory of weakly coupled oscillators to reduce
the system of delay differential equations to a phase model where the time
delay enters as a phase shift. We use the phase model to study the existence
and stability of cluster solutions. Cluster solutions are phase locked
solutions where the oscillators separate into groups. Oscillators within a
group are synchronized while those in different groups are phase-locked. We
give model independent existence and stability results for symmetric cluster
solutions. We show that the presence of the time delay can lead to the
coexistence of multiple stable clustering solutions. We apply our analytical
results to a network of Morris Lecar neurons and compare these results with
numerical continuation and simulation studies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05760</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05760</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>Yuchen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Lingming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>Hong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Peide D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Performance Enhancement of Black Phosphorus Field-Effect Transistors by
  Chemical Doping</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published in IEEE Electron Device Letters, VOL. 37, NO. 4, APRIL 2016</comments><doi>10.1109/LED.2016.2535905</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this letter, a new approach to chemically dope black phosphorus (BP) is
presented, which significantly enhances the device performance of BP
field-effect transistors for an initial period of 18 h, before degrading to
previously reported levels. By applying
2,3,5,6-tetrafluoro-7,7,8,8-tetracyanoquinodimethane (F4-TCNQ), low ON-state
resistance of 3.2 ohm.mm and high field-effect mobility of 229 cm2/Vs are
achieved with a record high drain current of 532 mA/mm at a moderate channel
length of 1.5 {\mu}m.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05761</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05761</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Zuluaga</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fuentes-Fernandez</keyname><forenames>E. M. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chabal</keyname><forenames>I. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thonhauser</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Cluster Assisted Water Dissociation Mechanism in MOF-74 and Controlling
  it Using Helium</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Materials Chemistry A, 2016, 4, 11524 - 11530</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C6TA02501C</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the water dissociation reaction H$_2$O$\rightarrow$OH+H in the
confined environment of MOF-74 channels can be precisely controlled by the
addition of the noble gas He. Elucidating the entire reaction process with ab
initio methods and infrared (IR) spectroscopy, we prove that the interaction
between water molecules is critical to the formation of water clusters, which
reduce the dissociation barrier by up to 37% and thus influence the reaction
significantly. Our time-resolved IR measurements confirm that the formation of
these clusters can be suppressed by introducing He gas, providing unprecedented
control over water dissociation rates. Since the water dissociation reaction is
the cause of the structural instability of MOF-74 in the presence of water, our
finding of the reaction mechanism lays the groundwork for designing water
stable versions of MOF-74 as well as understanding water related phenomena in
MOFs in general.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05762</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05762</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Bucklein</keyname><forenames>Brian K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moody</keyname><forenames>J. Ward</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hintz</keyname><forenames>Eric G.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Effect of Nearby Voids on Galaxy Number Counts</title><categories>astro-ph.IM astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>23 pages 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The size, shape and degree of emptiness of void interiors sheds light on the
details of galaxy formation. A particularly interesting question is whether
void interiors are completely empty or contain a dwarf population. However the
nearby voids that are most conducive for dwarf searches have large angular
diameters, on the order of a steradian, making it difficult to redshift-map a
statistically significant portion of their volume to the magnitude limit of
dwarf galaxies. As part of addressing this problem, we investigate here the
usefulness of number counts in establishing the best locations to search inside
nearby (d &lt; 300 Mpc) galaxy voids, utilizing Wolf plots of log(n &lt; m) vs. m as
the basic diagnostic. To illustrate expected signatures, we consider the
signature of three void profiles, &quot;cut out&quot;, &quot;built up&quot;, and &quot;universal
profile&quot; carved into Monte-Carlo Schechter function models. We then investigate
the signatures of voids in the Millennium Run dark matter simulation and the
Sloan Digital Sky Survey. We find in all of these the evidence for cut-out and
built-up voids is most discernible when the void diameter is similar to the
distance to its center. However the density distribution of the universal
profile that is characteristic of actual voids is essentially undetectable at
any distance. A useful corollary of this finding is that galaxy counts are a
reliable measure of survey completeness and stellar contamination even when
sampling through significant voids.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05768</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames><affiliation>YNNU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames><affiliation>YNAO</affiliation></author></authors><title>Modelling the multi-wavelength emission of flat spectrum radio quasar 3C
  279</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures, published in MNRAS (2016MNRAS.457.3535Z)</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw078</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We employ a length-dependent conical jet model for the jet structure and
emission properties of flat spectrum radio quasar 3C 279 in the steady state.
In the model, ultra-relativistic leptons are injected at the base of jet and
propagate along the jet structure, non-thermal photons are produced by both
synchrotron emission and inverse Comtpon scattering off synchrotron photons and
external soft photons at each segment of jet. We derive the total energy
spectra contribution through integrating every segment. We apply the model to
the quasi-simultaneous multi-wavelength observed data of two quiescent epoches.
Using the observed radio data of source, we determine the length of jet $L\sim
100$ pc, and magnetic field $B_{0}\sim 0.1-1$ G at the base of jet. Assuming a
steady geometry of the jet structure and suitable physical parameters, we
reproduce the multi-wavelength spectra during two quiescent observed epoches,
respectively. Our results show that the initial $\gamma$-ray emission site
takes place at $\sim 0.5$ pc from black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05771</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05771</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Isea</keyname><forenames>Raul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayo-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author></authors><title>Mathematical analysis of the spreading of a rumor among different
  subgroups of spreaders</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, Open Access</comments><journal-ref>Pure and Applied Mathematics Letters (2015), Vol. 2015, pp 50-54</journal-ref><license>http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper presents a system of differential equations that describes the
spreading of a rumor when it is propagated by different subgroups of spreaders.
The system that is developed is a generalization of the model proposed by Daley
and Kendall. Finally, the system is applied to the exchange rate of the
parallel dollar in Venezuela, where the source data that was used were obtained
from Google Trends.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05785</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05785</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Baskal</keyname><forenames>Sibel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Young S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Noz</keyname><forenames>Marilyn E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Entangled Harmonic Oscillators and Space-time Entanglement</title><categories>quant-ph hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>32 pages with 11 figures</comments><journal-ref>Symmetry 2016, 8(7), 55</journal-ref><doi>10.3390/sym8070055</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mathematical basis for the Gaussian entanglement is discussed in detail,
as well as its implications in the internal space-time structure of
relativistic extended particles. It is shown that the Gaussian entanglement
shares the same set of mathematical formulas with the harmonic oscillator in
the Lorentz-covariant world. It is thus possible to transfer the concept of
entanglement to the Lorentz-covariant picture of the bound state which requires
both space and time separations between two constituent particles. These space
and time variables become entangled as the bound state moves with a
relativistic speed. It is shown also that our inability to measure the
time-separation variable leads to an entanglement entropy together with a rise
in the temperature of the bound state. As was noted by Paul A. M. Dirac in
1963, the system of two oscillators contains the symmetries of O(3,2) de Sitter
group containing two O(3,1) Lorentz groups as its subgroups. Dirac noted also
that the system contains the symmetry of the Sp(4) group which serves as the
basic language for two-mode squeezed states. Since the Sp(4) symmetry contains
both rotations and squeezes, one interesting case is the combination of
rotation and squeeze resulting in a shear. While the current literature is
mostly on the entanglement based on squeeze along the normal coordinates, the
shear transformation is an interesting future possibility. The mathematical
issues on this problem are clarified.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05787</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05787</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yunes</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author></authors><title>Musings on Lorentz Violation Given the Recent Gravitational-Wave
  Observations of Coalescing Binary Black Holes</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent observation of gravitational waves by the LIGO/Virgo collaboration
provides a unique opportunity to probe the extreme gravity of coalescing binary
black holes. In this regime, the gravitational interaction is not only strong,
but the spacetime curvature is large, characteristic velocities are a
non-negligible fraction of the speed of light, and the time scale on which the
curvature and gravity change is small. This contribution discusses some
consequences of these observations on modifications to General Relativity, with
a special emphasis on Lorentz-violating theories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05793</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05793</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Low</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Zhenhua</forenames></author></authors><title>Electron tunneling through a single magnetic barrier in HgTe topological
  insulator</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>4 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron tunneling through a single magnetic barrier in a HgTe topological
insulator has been theoretically investigated. We find that the perpendicular
magnetic field would not lead to spin-flip of the edge states due to the
conservation of the angular moment. By tuning the magnetic field and Fermi
energy, the edge channels can be transited from switch-on states to switch-off
states and the current can be transmitted from unpolarized states to totally
spin polarized states. These features offer us and efficient way to control the
topological edge state transport, and pave a way to construct the
nanoelectronic devices utilizing the topological edge states.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05805</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05805</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Estrecho</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brodbeck</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamp</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>H&#xf6;fling</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Truscott</keyname><forenames>A. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ostrovskaya</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Visualising Berry phase and diabolical points in a quantum
  exciton-polariton billiard</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Diabolical points (degeneracies) can naturally occur in spectra of
two-dimensional quantum systems and classical wave resonators due to simple
symmetries. Geometric Berry phase is associated with these spectral
degeneracies. Here, we demonstrate a diabolical point and the corresponding
Berry phase in the spectrum of hybrid light-matter quasiparticles --
exciton-polaritons in semiconductor microcavities. It is well known that
sufficiently strong optical pumping can drive exciton-polaritons to quantum
degeneracy, whereby they form a macroscopically populated quantum coherent
state similar to a Bose-Einstein condensate. By pumping a microcavity with a
spatially structured light, we create a two-dimensional quantum billiard for
the exciton-polariton condensate and demonstrate a diabolical point in the
spectrum of the billiard eigenstates. The fully reconfigurable geometry of the
potential walls controlled by the optical pump enables a striking experimental
visualisation of the Berry phase associated with the diabolical point. The
Berry phase is observed and measured by direct imaging of the macroscopic
exciton-polariton wavefunctions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05823</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05823</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Caimmi</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-component, rigidly rotating polytropes: improved and extended
  theory</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>69 pages, 2 tables and 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Applied Mathematical Sciences, Vol. 10, 2016, no. 37, 1821 - 1889</journal-ref><doi>10.12988/ams.2016.63121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  With respect to earlier investigations, the theory of multi-component,
concentric, copolar, axisymmetric, rigidly rotating polytropes is improved and
extended, including subsystems with nonzero density on the boundary and
subsystems with intersecting boundaries. The formulation is restricted to two
subsystems for simplicity but, in principle, can be extended to $N$ subsystems.
Equilibrium configurations are independent of the nature of the fluid i.e.
collisional or collisionless, provided the polytropic index lies within the
range, $1/2\le n\le5$, as in one-component systems. The solution of the
equilibrium equations is expanded in power series, which can be continued up to
the boundary and outside via starting points placed at increasingly larger
distance from the centre of mass. A detailed analysis is devoted to special
cases where the solution of the equilibrium equations can be expressed
analytically. Finally a guidance example is shown, involving homogeneous
subsystems with intersecting boundaries, where a substantially flattened
component extends outside a slightly flattened one.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05827</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05827</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Abbas</keyname><forenames>Fysol Ibna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhuiyan</keyname><forenames>G. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>A. Z. Ziauddin</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy of mixing and entropy of mixing for Cu$_{x}$Al$_{1-x}$ liquid
  binary alloys</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages in pdf file, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The free energy of mixing and the entropy of mixing for Cu$_{x}$Al$_{1-x}$
liquid binary alloys have been systematically investigated by using the
electronic theory of metals along with the perturbation approach at a
thermodynamic state $T=1373$ K. The interionic interaction and a reference
liquid are the fundamental components of the theory. The interionic interaction
is described by a local pseudopotential. A liquid of hard spheres (HS) of two
different effective diametres is used to describe the reference system for
alloys. The results of the calculations for energy of mixing agree well with
the available experimental data. Calculation of entropy of mixing is parameter
free and, the agreement with experiment, in this case, is found to be fairly
good.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05829</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05829</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Moghrabi</keyname><forenames>Kassem</forenames></author></authors><title>Next-to-next-to-leading order Skyrme interaction in nuclear matter:
  Nuclear bulk quantities at second order in perturbation theory</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the explicit form of the next-to-next-to-leading order (N$^2$LO)
Skyrme interaction in momentum space by including the fourth-order gradient
potentials to the standard Skyrme interaction. With the N$^2$LO Skyrme
interaction, we evaluate the second-order corrections to the nuclear bulk
quantities of nuclear matter: equation of state (EoS) of isospin symmetric and
pure neutron matter, density-dependent in-medium effective nucleon mass,
isospin-asymmetry energy, pressure and incompressibility. These second-order
contributions are ultraviolet (UV) divergent due to the zero range character of
the interaction and renormalized using the techniques of dimensional
regularization (DR) with the minimal subtraction scheme (MS). We adjust the 18
parameters of the interaction by performing a global fit to the nuclear bulk
quantities. Besides the too strong dependence $k_F^{12}$ of several
second-order corrections, a very good reproduction of a realistic nuclear
matter saturation curve with all the nuclear bulk quantities in the density
region $0.12&lt;\rho&lt;0.20\;$ fm$^{-3}$ is obtained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05833</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05833</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kadam</keyname><forenames>Guru Prakash</forenames></author></authors><title>On the thermodynamically consistent quasiparticle model of quark gluon
  plasma</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We give the alternative formulation of quasiparticle model of quark gluon
plasma with medium dependent dispersion relation. The model is
thermodynamically consistent provided the medium dependent contribution to the
energy density is taken in to account. We establish the connection of our model
with other variants of quasiparticle models which are thermodynamically
consistent. We test the model by comparing the equation of state with the
lattice gauge theory simulations of SU(3) pure gluodynamics .
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05835</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05835</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Rukmini</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raghavendra</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmed</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Priya</keyname><forenames>D. Shanti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Unnisa</keyname><forenames>Syeda Azeem</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical survey and analysis of photometric and spectroscopic data on
  NEAS</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Volume 3, No. 2 (April -- June 2016)</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Studies on Near Earth Asteroids (NEAs) throw light on discoveries,
identification, orbit prediction and civil alert capabilities, including
potential asteroid impact hazards. Due to various new observational programs,
the discovery rate of NEAs has drastically increased over the last few years.
In this paper we present the statistical survey and analysis of fundamental
parameters (derived from Photometric and Spectroscopic observations) of a large
sample of NEAs from various databases like IAU Minor Planet Center, European
Asteroid Research Node (E.A.R.N.), Near Earth Objects - Dynamic Site (NEODyS-
2), M4AST and SMASSMTT portals. We also discuss the characterization of NEAs on
the basis of the correlations between theparametersstudied from different
observationsand theirphysical implicationsin understanding the nature and
physical properties of these objects.
  Keywords: NEOs; Apollo; Amor; Aten; Observations: Photometric, Spectroscopic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05837</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05837</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Rehacek</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Paur</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoklasa</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motka</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hradil</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sanchez-Soto</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispelling Rayleigh's Curse</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Comments most welcome!</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We devise a systematic method to determine the Fisher information required
for resolving two incoherent point sources with a diffraction-limited linear
imaging device. The resulting Cram\'er-Rao bound gives the lowest variance
achievable for an unbiased estimator. When only intensity in the image plane is
recorded, this bound diverges as the separation between the sources tends to
zero, an effect which has been dubbed as Rayleigh's curse. However, this curse
can be lifted using suitable coherent measurements. In particular, we determine
a class of measurements that can be easily implemented as projections on the
orthogonalised derivatives of the point spread function of the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05847</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05847</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kantzas</keyname><forenames>Dimitrios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petropoulou</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mastichiadis</keyname><forenames>Apostolos</forenames></author></authors><title>Early-time signatures of {\gamma}-ray emission from supernovae in dense
  circumstellar media</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present our results on the {\gamma}-ray emission from interaction-powered
supernovae (SNe), a recently discovered SN type that is suggested to be
surrounded by a circumstellar medium (CSM) with densities 10^7-10^12~ cm^-3.
Such high densities favor inelastic collisions between relativistic protons
accelerated in the SN blast wave and CSM protons and the production of
{\gamma}-ray photons through neutral pion decays. Using a numerical code that
includes synchrotron radiation, adiabatic losses due to the expansion of the
source, photon-photon interactions, proton-proton collisions and proton-photon
interactions, we calculate the multi-wavelength non-thermal photon emission
soon after the shock breakout and follow its temporal evolution until 100-1000
days. Focusing on the {\gamma}-ray emission at &gt;100 MeV, we show that this
could be detectable by the Fermi-LAT telescope for nearby (&lt;10 Mpc) SNe with
dense CSM (&gt;10^11 cm^-3).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05853</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05853</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Albi</keyname><forenames>Giacomo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pareschi</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Toscani</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanella</keyname><forenames>Mattia</forenames></author></authors><title>Recent advances in opinion modeling: control and social influence</title><categories>physics.soc-ph math.OC nlin.AO</categories><comments>Chapter of the Birkhauser-Springer book (to appear) by N. Bellomo, P.
  Degond, and E. Tadmor Eds., &quot;Active Particles Volume 1, Theory, Methods, and
  Applications&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We survey some recent developments on the mathematical modeling of opinion
dynamics. After an introduction on opinion modeling through interacting
multi-agent systems described by partial differential equations of kinetic
type, we focus our attention on two major advancements: optimal control of
opinion formation and influence of additional social aspects, like conviction
and number of connections in social networks, which modify the agents' role in
the opinion exchange process.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05855</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05855</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Marcucci</keyname><forenames>Lorenzo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reggiani</keyname><forenames>Carlo</forenames></author></authors><title>Mechanosensing in myosin filament solves a 60 years old conflict in
  skeletal muscle modeling between high power output and slow rise in tension</title><categories>physics.bio-ph q-bio.QM q-bio.SC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Almost 60 years ago Andrew Huxley with his seminal paper \cite{Huxley1957}
laid the foundation of modern muscle modeling, linking chemical events to
mechanical performance. He described mechanics and energetics of muscle
contraction through the cyclical attachment and detachment of myosin motors to
the actin filament with ad hoc assumptions on the dependence of the rate
constants on the strain of the myosin motors. That relatively simple hypothesis
is still present in recent models, even though with several modifications to
adapt the model to the different experimental constraints which became
subsequently available. However, already in that paper, one controversial
aspect of the model became clear. Relatively high attachment and detachment
rates of myosin to the actin filament were needed to simulate the high power
output at intermediate velocity of contraction. However, these rates were
incompatible with the relatively slow rise in tension after activation, despite
the rise should be generated by the same rate functions. This discrepancy has
not been fully solved till today, despite several hypotheses have been
forwarded to reconcile the two aspects. Here, using a conventional muscle
model, we show that the recently revealed mechanosensing mechanism of
recruitment of myosin motors \cite{Linarietal2015} can solve this long standing
problem without any further ad-hoc hypotheses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05871</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kondratiev</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kozitsky</keyname><forenames>Yuri</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of states in a continuum migration model</title><categories>math.DS math-ph math.MP</categories><msc-class>60J80, 92D25, 82C22</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Markov evolution of states of a continuum migration model is studied. The
model describes an infinite system of entities placed in $\mathds{R}^d$ in
which the constituents appear (immigrate) with rate $b(x)$ and disappear, also
due to competition. For this model, we prove the existence of the evolution of
states $\mu_0 \mapsto \mu_t$ such that the moments $\mu_t(N_\Lambda^n)$, $n\in
\mathds{N}$, of the number of entities in compact $\Lambda \subset
\mathds{R}^d$ remain bounded for all $t&gt;0$. Under an additional condition, we
prove that the density of entities and the second correlation function remain
bounded globally in time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05878</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05878</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kadlec</keyname><forenames>Filip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kadlec</keyname><forenames>Christelle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vit</keyname><forenames>Jakub</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borodavka</keyname><forenames>Fedir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kempa</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prokleska</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bursik</keyname><forenames>Josef</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uhrecky</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rols</keyname><forenames>Stephane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chai</keyname><forenames>Yi Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhai</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Young</forenames></author><author><keyname>Drahokoupil</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goian</keyname><forenames>Veronica</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kamba</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author></authors><title>Electromagnon in the Z-type hexaferrite $({\rm Ba}_{x}{\rm
  Sr}_{1-x})_3\rm Co_2Fe_{24}O_{41}$</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>Paper 8 pages + Suppl. Materials 3 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 024419 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.024419</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We studied experimentally the high-temperature magnetoelectric $({\rm
Ba}_{x}{\rm Sr}_{1-x})_3\rm Co_2Fe_{24}O_{41}$ prepared as ceramics (x = 0,
0.2) and a single crystal (x = 0.5) using inelastic neutron scattering, THz
time-domain, Raman and far-infrared spectroscopies. The spectra, measured with
varying temperature and magnetic field, reveal rich information about the
collective spin and lattice excitations. In the ceramics, we observed an
infrared-active magnon which is absent in $E^{\omega}\perp z$ polarized THz
spectra of the crystal, and we assume that it is an electromagnon active in
$E^{\omega} \| z$ polarized spectra. On heating from 7 to 250 K, the frequency
of this electromagnon drops from 36 to 25 cm$^{-1}$ and its damping gradually
increases, so it becomes overdamped at room temperature. Applying external
magnetic field has a similar effect on the damping and frequency of the
electromagnon, and the mode is no more observable in the THz spectra above 2 T,
as the transverse-conical magnetic structure transforms into a collinear one.
Raman spectra reveal another spin excitation with a slightly different
frequency and much higher damping. Upon applying magnetic field higher than 3
T, in the low-frequency part of the THz spectra, a narrow excitation appears
whose frequency linearly increases with magnetic field. We interpret this
feature as the ferromagnetic resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05923</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kopnov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gerber</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>MegaOhm Extraordinary Hall effect in oxidized CoFeB</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Applied Physics Letters 109, 022404 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4958832</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on development of controllably oxidized CoFeB ferromagnetic films
demonstrating the extraordinary Hall effect (EHE) resistivity exceeding 1 Ohmcm
and magnetic field sensitivity up to 10^6 Ohm/T. Such EHE resistivity is four
orders of magnitude higher than previously observed in ferromagnetic materials,
while sensitivity is two orders larger than the best of semiconductors
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05934</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05934</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Chamel</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mutafchieva</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stoyanov</keyname><forenames>Zh. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mihailov</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>R. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Landau quantization and neutron emissions by nuclei in the crust of a
  magnetar</title><categories>astro-ph.HE nucl-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys.: Conf. Ser. 724, 012034 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/724/1/012034</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Magnetars are neutron stars endowed with surface magnetic fields of the order
of $10^{14}-10^{15}$~G, and with presumably much stronger fields in their
interior. As a result of Landau quantization of electron motion, the
neutron-drip transition in the crust of a magnetar is shifted to either higher
or lower densities depending on the magnetic field strength. The impact of
nuclear uncertainties is explored considering the recent series of
Brussels-Montreal microscopic nuclear mass models. All these models are based
on the Hartree-Fock-Bogoliubov method with generalized Skyrme functionals. They
differ in their predictions for the symmetry energy coefficient at saturation,
and for the stiffness of the neutron-matter equation of state. For comparison,
we have also considered the very accurate but more phenomenological model of
Duflo and Zuker. Although the equilibrium composition of the crust of a
magnetar and the onset of neutron emission are found to be model dependent, the
quantum oscillations of the threshold density are essentially universal.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05943</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05943</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Chamel</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraint on the internal structure of a neutron star from Vela pulsar
  glitches</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Proceedings of the conference &quot;The Modern Physics of Compact Stars
  2015&quot; held in Erevan, Armenia, from 30 September 2015 to 3 October 2015. To
  appear in Proceedings of Science</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Pulsars are spinning extremely rapidly with periods as short as about $1.4$
milliseconds and delays of a few milliseconds per year at most, thus providing
the most accurate clocks in the Universe. Nevertheless, sudden spin ups have
been detected in some pulsars like the emblematic Vela pulsar. These abrupt
changes in the pulsar's rotation period have long been thought to be the
manifestation of a neutron superfluid permeating the inner crust of neutron
stars. However, the neutron superfluid has been recently found to be so
strongly coupled to the crust that it does not carry enough angular momentum to
explain the Vela data. We explore the extent to which pulsar-timing
observations can be reconciled with the standard glitch theory considering the
lack of knowledge of the dense-matter equation of state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05945</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05945</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Sulston</keyname><forenames>Kenneth W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Davison</keyname><forenames>Sydney G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytical Treatment of Benzene Transmittivity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The renormalization method has been previously used in conjunction with the
Lippman-Schwinger equation to calculate transmission probabilities for benzene
molecules, within the tight-binding approximation. Those results are extended
here by presenting explicit formulas for the transmission probability
functions, which are subsequently analysed for their anti-resonances,
resonances and other maxima and minima.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05948</id><created>2016-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Yadav</keyname><forenames>Bal Krishna</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Murli Manohar</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological arrow of time in f(R) gravity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>Paper presented at Summer School on Cosmology (6-17 June, 2016) at
  the Abdus Salam Internationl Centre for Theoretical Physics, Trieste, Italy</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The cosmological arrow of time may be linked to the thermodynamic arrow by
second law of thermodynamics. The time asymmetry is also associated with
dissipative fluid as Tolman introduced a viscous fluid to generate an arrow of
time in cyclic cosmology. An arrow of time in cyclic cosmology has been shown
using scalar field.In this work we find out the cosmological arrow of time in
f(R) gravity. Here we use the relation between a new scalar field and $f(R)$.
The dynamics of this new scalar field may emerge the arrow of time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05950</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05950</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Yunyun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cui</keyname><forenames>Fenping</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular dynamics simulation of fabrication of Cu mono-component
  metallic glass by physical vapor deposition on Zr substrate</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, the single-component Cu metallic glass was fabricated by the
physical vapor deposition on the Zr (0001) crystal substrate at 100 K using the
classical molecular dynamic simulation. The same deposition process was
performed on the Cu (1 0 0) and Ni (1 0 0) crystal substrate for comparison,
only the Cu crystal deposited layer with the fcc structure can be obtained.
When depositing the Cu atoms on the Zr substrate at 300 K, the crystal
structure was formed, which indicates that except the suitable substrate, low
temperature is also a key factor for the amorphous structure formation. The Cu
liquid quenching from 2000 K to 100 K were also simulated with the cooling rate
1012 K/s to form the Cu glass film in this work. The Cu metallic glass from the
two different processes (physical vapor deposition and rapid thermal quenching
from liquid) revealed the same radial distribution function and X-ray
diffraction pattern, but the different microstructure from the coordination
number and Voronoi tessellation analysis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05953</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05953</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Karhu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nauta</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vainio</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mets&#xe4;l&#xe4;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoekstra</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Halonen</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double resonant absorption measurement of acetylene symmetric
  vibrational states probed with cavity ring down spectroscopy</title><categories>physics.chem-ph physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><journal-ref>The Journal of Chemical Physics, 144, 244201 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4954159</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A novel mid-infrared/near-infrared double resonant absorption setup for
studying infrared-inactive vibrational states is presented. A strong
vibrational transition in the mid-infrared region is excited using an idler
beam from a singly resonant continuous-wave optical parametric oscillator, to
populate an intermediate vibrational state. High output power of the optical
parametric oscillator and the strength of the mid-infrared transition result in
efficient population transfer to the intermediate state, which allows measuring
secondary transitions from this state with a high signal-to-noise ratio. A
secondary, near-infrared transition from the intermediate state is probed using
cavity ring down spectroscopy, which provides high sensitivity in this
wavelength region. Due to the narrow linewidths of the excitation sources, the
rovibrational lines of the secondary transition are measured with sub-Doppler
resolution. The setup is used to access a previously unreported symmetric
vibrational state of acetylene, $\nu_1+\nu_2+\nu_3+\nu_4^1+\nu_5^{-1}$ in the
normal mode notation. Single-photon transitions to this state from the
vibrational ground state are forbidden. Ten lines of the newly measured state
are observed and fitted with the linear least-squares method to extract the
band parameters. The vibrational term value was measured to be at 9775.0018(45)
$\text{cm}^{-1}$, the rotational parameter $B$ was 1.162222 $\text{cm}^{-1}$,
and the quartic centrifugal distortion parameter $D$ was 3.998(62)$\times
10^{-6} \text{cm}^{-1}$, where the numbers in the parenthesis are one-standard
errors in the least significant digits.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05955</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05955</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Groenen</keyname><forenames>Rik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Zhaoliang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gauquelin</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hoekstra</keyname><forenames>Roel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spanjer</keyname><forenames>Bart</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Gorsel</keyname><forenames>Merle</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borkent</keyname><forenames>Sam</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Minh</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vargas-LLona</keyname><forenames>Laura</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodijk</keyname><forenames>Eddy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Damen</keyname><forenames>Cas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verbeeck</keyname><forenames>Jo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koster</keyname><forenames>Gertjan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rijnders</keyname><forenames>Guus</forenames></author></authors><title>Epitaxial growth of complex oxides on silicon by enhanced surface
  diffusion in large area pulsed laser deposition</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>4 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Homogeneous highly epitaxial LaSrMnO3 (LSMO) thin films have been grown on
Yttria-stabilized-Zirconia (YsZ) / CeO2 buffer layers on technological relevant
4&quot; silicon wafers using a Twente Solid State Technology B.V. (TSST) developed
large area Pulsed Laser Deposition (PLD) setup. We study and show the results
of the effect of an additional SrRuO3 buffer layer on the growth temperature
dependent structural and magnetic properties of LSMO films. With the
introduction of a thin SrRuO3 layer on top of the buffer stack, LSMO films show
ferromagnetic behaviour for growth temperatures as low as 250C. We suggest that
occurrence of epitaxial crystal growth of LSMO at these low growth temperatures
can be understood by an improved surface diffusion, which ensures sufficient
intermixing of surface species for formation of the correct phase. This
intermixing is necessary because the full plume is collected on the 4&quot; wafer
resulting in a compositional varying flux of species on the wafer, in contrast
to small scale experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05959</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05959</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Baldoncini</keyname><forenames>M</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strati</keyname><forenames>V</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wipperfurth</keyname><forenames>S A</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fiorentini</keyname><forenames>G</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mantovani</keyname><forenames>F</forenames></author><author><keyname>McDonough</keyname><forenames>W F</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ricci</keyname><forenames>B</forenames></author></authors><title>Geoneutrinos and reactor antineutrinos at SNO+</title><categories>physics.geo-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>7 pages including 2 figures and 1 table, in XIV International
  Conference on Topics in Astroparticle and Underground Physics (TAUP 2015) IOP
  Publishing , published on Journal of Physics: Conference Series 718 (2016)
  062003</comments><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/718/6/062003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In the heart of the Creighton Mine near Sudbury (Canada), the SNO+ detector
is foreseen to observe almost in equal proportion electron antineutrinos
produced by U and Th in the Earth and by nuclear reactors. SNO+ will be the
first long baseline experiment to measure a reactor signal dominated by CANDU
cores ($\sim$55\% of the total reactor signal), which generally burn natural
uranium. Approximately 18\% of the total geoneutrino signal is generated by the
U and Th present in the rocks of the Huronian Supergroup-Sudbury Basin: the
60\% uncertainty on the signal produced by this lithologic unit plays a crucial
role on the discrimination power on the mantle signal as well as on the
geoneutrino spectral shape reconstruction, which can in principle provide a
direct measurement of the Th/U ratio in the Earth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05960</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05960</id><created>2016-07-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Nishimura</keyname><forenames>Kimihide</forenames></author></authors><title>QCD emergent from spontaneous breakdown of relativity</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spontaneous violation of relativistic invariance of the vacuum can derive
quantum chromodynamics from an U(1) Higgs model including fermions, if the
emergent theory is Lorentz invariant. In this model, the vacuum becomes
anisotropic, and a fermion created on a triplet of spin-one vacua acquires
degeneracy analogous to the color degrees of freedom. The Nambu-Goldstone
bosons originating from the breakdown of rotational symmetry provide the quasi
fermions with SU(3)$\times$U(1) effective interactions, which are interpretable
as mediated by gluons and photons. The confinement of quasi quarks as well as
that of Nambu-Goldstone gluons follow from the Lorentz invariance of the
emergent theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05985</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05985</id><created>2016-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Pengshun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jianbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Shengguo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Wenjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Zhaoyang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shanqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>Chenggang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Test of non-Newtonian gravitational force at micrometer range</title><categories>gr-qc hep-ph</categories><comments>Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz Symmetry,
  Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report an experimental test of non-Newtonian gravitational forces at mi-
crometer range. To experimentally subtract off the Casimir force and the
electrostatic force background, differential force measurements were performed
by sensing the lateral force between a gold sphere and a density modulated
source mass using a soft cantilever. The current sensitivity is limited by the
patch electrostatic force, which is further improved by two dimensional (2D)
force mapping. The preliminary result sets a model independent constraint on
the Yukawa type force at this range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05987</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05987</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Noordmans</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing Lorentz Symmetry using Chiral Perturbation Theory</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>4 pages, Presented at the Seventh Meeting on CPT and Lorentz
  Symmetry, Bloomington, Indiana, June 20-24, 2016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the low-energy effects of a selected set of Lorentz- and
CPT-violating quark and gluon operators by deriving the corresponding chiral
effective lagrangian. Using this effective lagrangian, low-energy hadronic
observables can be calculated. We apply this to magnetometer experiments and
derive the best bounds on some of the Lorentz-violating coefficients. We point
out that progress can be made by studying the nucleon-nucleon potential, and by
considering storage-ring experiments for deuterons and other light nuclei.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.05996</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.05996</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Ohlmann</keyname><forenames>Sebastian T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roepke</keyname><forenames>Friedrich K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pakmor</keyname><forenames>Ruediger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Springel</keyname><forenames>Volker</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mueller</keyname><forenames>Ewald</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic Field Amplification During the Common Envelope Phase</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>5 pages, 2 figures, 1 table. Accepted for publication in MNRAS
  Letters</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw144</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  During the common envelope (CE) phase, a giant star in a binary system
overflows its Roche lobe and unstable mass transfer leads to a spiral-in of the
companion, resulting in a close binary system or in a merger of the stellar
cores. Dynamo processes during the CE phase have been proposed as a mechanism
to generate magnetic fields that are important for forming magnetic white
dwarfs (MWDs) and for shaping planetary nebulae. Here, we present the first
magnetohydrodynamics simulations of the dynamical spiral-in during a CE phase.
We find that magnetic fields are strongly amplified in the accretion stream
around the $1M_\odot$ companion as it spirals into the envelope of a $2M_\odot$
RG. This leads to field strengths of 10 to 100 kG throughout the envelope after
120 d. The magnetic field amplification is consistent with being driven by the
magnetorotational instability. The field strengths reached in our simulation
make the magnetic field interesting for diagnostic purposes, but they are
dynamically irrelevant. They are also too small to explain the formation of the
highest fields found in MWDs, but may be relevant for luminous red novae, and
detecting magnetic fields in these events would support the scenario as
proposed here.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06001</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06001</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Garolera</keyname><forenames>Blai</forenames></author></authors><title>On the gravity dual of the light-front vacuum</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>21 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Building on a previous conjecture, we argue that the holographic dual of the
light-front vacuum state of a superconformal field theory quantized in the
front form of dynamics contains the Kaigorodov spacetime, which is nothing but
a pp-wave propagating in AdS. Evidence in favor of this conjecture is
presented. In particular we verify the matching of global symmetries and
discuss the contribution of the zero mode sector in both sides of the
correspondence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06003</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06003</id><created>2016-07-19</created><authors><author><keyname>Pfeiffer</keyname><forenames>Tom</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wieser</keyname><forenames>Wolfgang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Petermann</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolb</keyname><forenames>Jan-Phillip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eibl</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huber</keyname><forenames>Robert</forenames></author></authors><title>Flexible A-scan rate MHz OCT: Computational downscaling by coherent
  averaging</title><categories>physics.med-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>This work was supported by the German Research Foundation (DFG) (Hu
  1006/6-1) and European Union projects FDML-Raman (FP7 ERC StG, contract no.
  259158) and ENCOMOLE-2i (Horizon 2020, ERC CoG no. 646669). in Proc. SPIE
  9697, Optical Coherence Tomography and Coherence Domain Optical Methods in
  Biomedicine XX, 969703 (March 8, 2016)</comments><doi>10.1117/12.2214788</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In order to realize fast OCT-systems with adjustable line rate, we
investigate averaging of image data from an FDML based MHz-OCT-system. The line
rate can be reduced in software and traded in for increased system sensitivity
and image quality. We compare coherent and incoherent averaging to effectively
scale down the system speed of a 3.2 MHz FDML OCT system to around 100 kHz in
postprocessing. We demonstrate that coherent averaging is possible with MHz
systems without special interferometer designs or digital phase stabilisation.
We show OCT images of a human finger knuckle joint in vivo with very high
quality and deep penetration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06011</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06011</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Julius</keyname></author><author><keyname>Mahale</keyname><forenames>Gopinath</forenames></author><author><keyname>T.</keyname><forenames>Sumana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adityakrishna</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the Modeling of Error Functions as High Dimensional Landscapes for
  Weight Initialization in Learning Networks</title><categories>cs.LG cs.CV physics.data-an stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next generation deep neural networks for classification hosted on embedded
platforms will rely on fast, efficient, and accurate learning algorithms.
Initialization of weights in learning networks has a great impact on the
classification accuracy. In this paper we focus on deriving good initial
weights by modeling the error function of a deep neural network as a
high-dimensional landscape. We observe that due to the inherent complexity in
its algebraic structure, such an error function may conform to general results
of the statistics of large systems. To this end we apply some results from
Random Matrix Theory to analyse these functions. We model the error function in
terms of a Hamiltonian in N-dimensions and derive some theoretical results
about its general behavior. These results are further used to make better
initial guesses of weights for the learning algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06012</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06012</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Brambilla</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Corti</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gatti</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Heralding pure single photons: a comparision between counter-propagating
  and co-propagating twin photons</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the possibility of generating pure heralded single photons
through spontaneous parametric down-conversion comparing the
counter-propagating geometry studied in [1] with more conventional
co-propagating configurations which enhance the purity of the heralded photon
state through the technique of group-velocity matching. We estimate the Schmidt
number associated to the temporal modes as a function of the pump pulse
duration for three particular configurations, showing how the different
phase-matching conditions influences the degree of separability that can be
achieved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06014</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06014</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Yangbo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>Chen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Wenqi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Junfei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suo</keyname><forenames>Dingjie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Popa</keyname><forenames>Bogdan-Ioan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jing</keyname><forenames>Yun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cummer</keyname><forenames>Steven A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Acoustic Holographic Rendering with Two-dimensional Metamaterial-based
  Passive Phased Array</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Acoustic holographic rendering in complete analogy with optical holography
are useful for various applications, ranging from multi-focal lensing,
multiplexed sensing and synthesizing three-dimensional complex sound fields.
Conventional approaches rely on a large number of active transducers and phase
shifting circuits. In this paper we show that by using passive metamaterials as
subwavelength pixels, holographic rendering can be achieved without cumbersome
circuitry and with only a single transducer, thus significantly reducing system
complexity. Such metamaterial-based holograms can serve as versatile platforms
for various advanced acoustic wave manipulation and signal modulation, leading
to new possibilities in acoustic sensing, energy deposition and medical
diagnostic imaging.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06027</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Dubovskii</keyname><forenames>Leonid</forenames></author></authors><title>New Approach to Metal-Insulator Phase Transition Kinetics in Magnetic
  Field</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.other</categories><comments>5 hages</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The metal--insulator phase transition is considered on the basis of
Ginzburg-Landau type equations with two different order parameters. An
inclusion of magnetic field in this picture is an important step for
understanding of behavior of the metal--insulator phase transition kinetics.
The magnetic field leads to various singularities of the surface tension and
results in drastic variations of the phase transition kinetics. The strongest
singularity is due to Landau diamagnetism and determines anomalous features of
MI transition kinetics. This singularity supports the well known experimental
fact that almost all semimetals behave like diamagnetic materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06040</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06040</id><created>2016-07-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Zocca</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwart</keyname><forenames>Bert</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimizing heat loss in DC networks using batteries</title><categories>physics.class-ph math.OC</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electricity transmission networks dissipate a non-negligible fraction of the
power they transport due to the heat loss in the transmission lines. In this
work we explore how the transport of energy can be more efficient by adding to
the network multiple batteries that can coordinate their operations. Such
batteries can both charge using the current excess in the network or discharge
to meet the network current demand. Either way, the presence of batteries in
the network can be leveraged to mitigate the intrinsic uncertainty in the power
generation and demand and, hence, transport the energy more efficiently through
the network. We consider a resistive DC network with stochastic external
current injections or consumptions and show how the expected total heat loss
depends on the network structure and on the batteries operations. Furthermore,
in the case where the external currents are modeled by Ornstein-Uhlenbeck
processes, we derive the dynamical optimal control for the batteries over a
finite time interval.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06050</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06050</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>John A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashidi</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koleini</keyname><forenames>Mohammad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitters</keyname><forenames>Jason L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolkow</keyname><forenames>Robert A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple Silicon Atom Artificial Molecules</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present linear ensembles of dangling bond chains on a hydrogen terminated
Si(100) surface, patterned in the closest spaced arrangement allowed by the
surface lattice. Local density of states maps over a range of voltages
extending spatially over the close-coupled entities reveal a rich energetic and
spatial variation of electronic states. These artificial molecules exhibit
collective electronic states resulting from covalent interaction of the
constituent atoms. A pronounced electrostatic perturbation of dangling bond
chain structure is induced by close placement of a negatively dangling bond.
The electronic changes so induced are entirely removed, paradoxically, by
addition of a second dangling bond.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06059</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06059</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>K&#xfc;gler</keyname><forenames>S. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gianniotis</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling multimodal photometric redshift regression with noisy
  observations</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>7 pages. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:1606.06094</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we are trying to extent the existing photometric redshift
regression models from modeling pure photometric data back to the spectra
themselves. To that end, we developed a PCA that is capable of describing the
input uncertainty (including missing values) in a dimensionality reduction
framework. With this &quot;spectrum generator&quot; at hand, we are capable of treating
the redshift regression problem in a fully Bayesian framework, returning a
posterior distribution over the redshift. This approach allows therefore to
approach the multimodal regression problem in an adequate fashion. In addition,
input uncertainty on the magnitudes can be included quite naturally and lastly,
the proposed algorithm allows in principle to make predictions outside the
training values which makes it a fascinating opportunity for the detection of
high-redshifted quasars.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.06076</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-21</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.06076</id><created>2016-07-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Balbekov</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Dependence of the TMCI threshold on the space charge tune shift</title><categories>physics.acc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Transverse mode coupling instability of a bunch with space charge is
considered in frameworks of the boxcar model. Presented results demonstrate a
monotonous growth of the TMCI threshold at increasing space charge tune shift,
and do not support the supposition that the monotony can be violated at a
higher SC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
