<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-11T22:39:33Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2016-07-15" from="2016-07-15" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1110.2362</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1110.2362</id><created>2011-10-11</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zieli&#x144;ska</keyname><forenames>Joanna A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beduini</keyname><forenames>Federica A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Godbout</keyname><forenames>Nicolas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>Morgan W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultra-Narrow Faraday Rotation Filter at the Rb D1 Line</title><categories>physics.optics physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>3 pages, 2 figures. Manuscript same as v1. FADOF calculator
  (ancillary file) now allows for extension to the D2 line</comments><journal-ref>Optics Letters, Vol. 37, Issue 4, pp. 524-526 (2012)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OL.37.000524</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a theoretical and experimental study of the ultra-narrow bandwidth
Faraday anomalous dispersion optical filter (FADOF) operating at the rubidium
D1 line (795 nm). This atomic line gives better performance than other lines
for the main FADOF figures of merit, e.g. simultaneously 71% transmission, 445
MHz bandwidth and 1.2 GHz equivalent noise bandwidth.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1112.0675</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1112.0675</id><created>2011-12-03</created><authors><author><keyname>Katoch</keyname><forenames>Jyoti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishigami</keyname><forenames>Masa</forenames></author></authors><title>Impact of Calcium on Transport Property of Graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics Condensed Matter, 28, 115301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.ssc.2011.11.003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the impact of calcium adsorbates on the transport property
of graphene. Although calcium renders conductivity linearly dependent on the
carrier density of graphene as predicted, our experimental results diverge from
the existing theoretical calculations. Our data expose the inadequacy of any
existing theory to describe the minimum conductivity of graphene and indicate
that a more complete testing of the impurity scattering calculations will
require improving the experimental capabilities by minimizing the contribution
from the substrate-bound charged impurities and developing an ability to count
the number of adsorbates while measuring transport.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1208.5169</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1208.5169</id><created>2012-08-25</created><updated>2016-07-01</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gavish</keyname><forenames>Nir</forenames></author><author><keyname>Promislow</keyname><forenames>Keith</forenames></author></authors><title>Dependence of the dielectric constant of electrolyte solutions on ionic
  concentration - a microfield approach</title><categories>physics.chem-ph cond-mat.other physics.bio-ph</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in Physical Review E</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review E 94, 012611 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.012611</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a novel microfield approach for studying the dependence of the
orientational polarization of the water in aqueous electrolyte solutions upon
the salt concentration and temperature. The model takes into account the
orientation of the solvent dipoles due to the electric field created by ions,
and the effect of thermal fluctuations. The model predicts a dielectric
functional dependence of the form $\varepsilon(c)=\varepsilon_w-\beta L(3\alpha
c/\beta),\quad\beta=\varepsilon_w-\varepsilon_{\rm ms}$, where $L$ is the
Langevin function, $c$ is the salt concentration, $\varepsilon_w$ is the
dielectric of pure water, $\varepsilon_{\rm ms}$ is the dielectric of the
electrolyte solution at the molten salt limit, and $\alpha$ is the total excess
polarization of the ions. The functional form gives a remarkably accurate
description of the dielectric constant for a variety of salts and a wide range
of concentrations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1301.1836</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1301.1836</id><created>2013-01-09</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Lin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Junde</forenames></author></authors><title>Tomita-Takesaki Modular Theory vs. Quantum Information Theory</title><categories>math-ph math.MP math.OA quant-ph</categories><comments>v1: 29 pages, LaTeX, this review article is not completed and to be
  continued. The first goal of writing this topic is just to understand the
  notion of cyclic and separating vector in von Neumann algebra. The second
  goal is to apply Tomita-Takesaki modular theory in Quantum Information
  Theory. All comments are welcome!. v2: 41 pages, LaTeX, no figure. Expansion
  of previous version. arXiv admin note: text overlap with arXiv:0802.1234,
  arXiv:0906.3980 by other authors</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper, we will try to find out the relationship between separating
and cyclic vectors in the theory of von Neumann algebra and entangled states in
the theory of quantum information. The corresponding physical interpretation is
presented as well.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1312.0831</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1312.0831</id><created>2013-12-03</created><updated>2014-01-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aste</keyname><forenames>Andreas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chung</keyname><forenames>Won Sang</forenames></author></authors><title>How to commute</title><categories>math-ph hep-th math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, Latex, one new chapter and a new contributing author added</comments><journal-ref>Adv.Stud.Theor.Phys. 10 (2016) 125-133</journal-ref><doi>10.12988/astp.2016.512116</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A simple exposition of the rarely discussed fact that a set of free boson
fields describing different, i.e. kinematically different particle types can be
quantized with mutual anticommutation relations is given by the explicit
construction of the Klein transformations changing anticommutation relations
into commutation relations. The q-analog of the presented results is also
treated. The analogous situation for two independent free fermion fields with
mutual commutation or anticommutation relations is briefly investigated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.7009</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.7009</id><created>2014-01-27</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author></authors><title>GHZ transform (I): Bell transform and quantum teleportation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>v1: 11 pages, 3 figures; v2: 19 pages, 3 figures, v3: latex, 33
  pages, 3 figures, v4: latex, 36 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is well-known that maximally entangled states such as the
Greenberger-Horne-Zeilinger (GHZ) states, with the Bell states as the simplest
examples, are widely exploited in quantum information and computation. We study
the application of such maximally entangled states from the viewpoint of the
GHZ transform, which is a unitary basis transformation from the product states
to the GHZ states. The algebraic structure of the GHZ transform is made clear
and representative examples for it are verified as multi-qubit Clifford gates.
In this paper, we focus on the Bell transform as the simplest example of the
GHZ transform and apply it to the reformulation of quantum circuit model of
teleportation and the reformulation of the fault-tolerant construction of
single-qubit gates and two-qubit gates in teleportation-based quantum
computation. We clearly show that there exists a natural algebraic structure
called the teleportation operator in terms of the Bell transform to catch
essential points of quantum teleportation, and hence we expect that there would
also exist interesting algebraic structures in terms of the GHZ transform to
play important roles in quantum information and computation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1408.2390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1408.2390</id><created>2014-08-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Pandey</keyname><forenames>Ambrish</forenames></author><author><keyname>Verma</keyname><forenames>Mahendra K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chatterjee</keyname><forenames>Anando G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Biplab</forenames></author></authors><title>Similarities between 2D and 3D convection for large Prandtl number</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>9 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Pramana - J. Phys. (2016) 87: 13</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s12043-016-1204-z</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Using direct numerical simulations of Rayleigh-B\'{e}nard convection (RBC),
we perform a comparative study of the spectra and fluxes of energy and entropy,
and the scaling of large-scale quantities for large and infinite Prandtl
numbers in two (2D) and three (3D) dimensions. We observe close similarities
between the 2D and 3D RBC, in particular the kinetic energy spectrum $E_u(k)
\sim k^{-13/3}$, and the entropy spectrum exhibits a dual branch with a
dominant $k^{-2}$ spectrum. We showed that the dominant Fourier modes in the 2D
and 3D flows are very close. Consequently, the 3D RBC is quasi two-dimensional,
which is the reason for the similarities between the 2D and 3D RBC for large-
and infinite Prandtl numbers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.3049</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.3049</id><created>2014-09-10</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Beneke</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dighera</keyname><forenames>Francesco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hryczuk</keyname><forenames>Andrzej</forenames></author></authors><title>Relic density computations at NLO: infrared finiteness and thermal
  correction</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>36 pages, 6 figures, 6 tables; v2: erratum added, substantial change
  of the finite part of the thermal correction</comments><report-no>TUM-HEP 1052/16</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  There is an increasing interest in accurate dark matter relic density
predictions, which requires next-to-leading order (NLO) calculations. The
method applied up to now uses zero-temperature NLO calculations of annihilation
cross sections in the standard Boltzmann equation for freeze-out, and is
conceptually problematic, since it ignores the finite-temperature infrared (IR)
divergences from soft and collinear radiation and virtual effects. We address
this problem systematically by starting from non-equilibrium quantum field
theory, and demonstrate on a realistic model that soft and collinear
temperature-dependent divergences cancel in the collision term. Our analysis
provides justification for the use of the freeze-out equation in its
conventional form and determines the leading finite-temperature correction to
the annihilation cross section. This turns out to have a remarkably simple
structure.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.4360</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.4360</id><created>2014-09-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Seshadhri</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Andrew M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vorobeychik</keyname><forenames>Yevgeniy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mayo</keyname><forenames>Jackson</forenames></author><author><keyname>Armstrong</keyname><forenames>Robert C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Characterizing short-term stability for Boolean networks over any
  distribution of transfer functions</title><categories>nlin.CD cs.DM nlin.CG</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 94, 012301 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.94.012301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a characterization of short-term stability of random Boolean
networks under \emph{arbitrary} distributions of transfer functions. Given any
distribution of transfer functions for a random Boolean network, we present a
formula that decides whether short-term chaos (damage spreading) will happen.
We provide a formal proof for this formula, and empirically show that its
predictions are accurate. Previous work only works for special cases of
balanced families. It has been observed that these characterizations fail for
unbalanced families, yet such families are widespread in real biological
networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02348</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02348</id><created>2015-01-10</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Wen-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Shizhong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Law</keyname><forenames>K. T.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Realization and Dectection of Weyl Semimetals and Chiral Anomaly in
  Cold Atomic Systems</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>6 pages, 5 figures. Comments are welcome</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 013606 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.013606</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work, we describe a method to realize 3D Weyl semimetal by coupling
multilayers of honeycomb optical lattice in the presence of a pair of Raman
lasers. The Raman lasers render each isolated honeycomb layer a Chern
insulator. With finite interlayer coupling, the bulk gap of the system closes
at certain out-of-plane momenta due to Raman assisted tunnelling and result in
the Weyl semimetal phase. Using experimentally relevant parameters, we show
that both one and two pairs of Weyl points can be realized by tuning the
interlayer coupling strength. We suggest that Landau-Zener tunnelling can be
used to detect Weyl points and show that the transition probability increases
dramatically when Weyl point emerges. The realization of chiral anomaly by
using a magnetic field gradient is also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02285</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02285</id><created>2015-04-09</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mukherjee</keyname><forenames>Suvodip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Souradeep</keyname><forenames>Tarun</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified origin of hemispherical asymmetry in scalar and tensor
  perturbations</title><categories>astro-ph.CO gr-qc</categories><comments>15 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent measurements of temperature and polarization of Cosmic Microwave
Background (CMB) have improved our understanding of the Universe and are in
remarkable agreement with the $\Lambda$CDM cosmological model. However, scale
dependent features like power suppression in the angular power spectrum and
Cosmic Hemispherical Asymmetry (CHA) in the temperature field of CMB at large
angular scales, hinting at possible departure from the $\Lambda$CDM model
persist in the CMB data. In this paper we present a physical mechanism linked
to possible initial inhomogeneities in the inflationary scalar field that could
generate CHA in both scalar and tensor sector within the frame work of single
field inflationary model with an initial fast-roll phase. The modulation
amplitude of CHA in both scalar and tensor perturbations are related and depend
upon the initial shape of the inflaton potential. By using the observed value
of CHA and obeying the isotropy of the temperature field of CMB, we obtain the
theoretical upper bound on the amplitude of CHA for tensor perturbations within
the framework of single field initial fast roll inflation models. The bound
indicates that a maximum of $0.05\%$ modulation in tensor sector is possible
and hence within the measurability of future mission, tensor perturbations
should be statistically isotropic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.02606</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.02606</id><created>2015-04-10</created><updated>2015-12-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zi-qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>De-fu</forenames></author></authors><title>Melting temperature of heavy quarkonium with a holographic potential up
  to sub-leading order</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>4 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Physics C Vol. 40, No. 6 (2016) 064101</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1674-1137/40/6/064101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A calculation of the melting temperatures of heavy quarkonium states with the
holographic potential was introduced in a previous work. In this paper, we
consider the holographic potential at sub-leading order, which permits finite
coupling corrections to be taken into account. It is found that this correction
lowers the dissociation temperatures of heavy quarkonium.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.04173</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.04173</id><created>2015-04-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Pourhassan</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author></authors><title>Unified universe history through phantom extended Chaplygin gas</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>25 pages, 16 figures</comments><journal-ref>Canadian Journal of Physics 94 (2016) 659</journal-ref><doi>10.1139/cjp-2016-0154</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the universe evolution from inflation to late-time
acceleration in a unified way, using a two-component fluid constituted from
extended Chaplygin gas alongside a phantom scalar field. We extract solutions
for the various cosmological eras, focusing on the behavior of the scale
factor, the various density parameters and the equation-of-state parameter.
Furthermore, we extract and discuss bouncing solutions. Finally, we examine the
perturbations of the model, ensuring about their stability and extracting the
predictions for the tensor-to-scalar ratio.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1504.06814</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1504.06814</id><created>2015-04-26</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kranz</keyname><forenames>W. Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gelimson</keyname><forenames>Anatolij</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Kun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Gerard C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Golestanian</keyname><forenames>Ramin</forenames></author></authors><title>Effective dynamics of microorganisms that interact with their own trail</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>new figure with experimental results; expanded appendix</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 038101 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.038101</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Like ants, some microorganisms are known to leave trails on surfaces to
communicate. We explore how trail-mediated self-interaction could affect the
behavior of individual microorganisms when diffusive spreading of the trail is
negligible on the timescale of the microorganism using a simple
phenomenological model for an actively moving particle and a finite-width
trail. The effective dynamics of each microorganism takes on the form of a
stochastic integral equation with the trail interaction appearing in the form
of short-term memory. For moderate coupling strength below an emergent critical
value, the dynamics exhibits effective diffusion in both orientation and
position after a phase of superdiffusive reorientation. We report experimental
verification of a seemingly counterintuitive perpendicular alignment mechanism
that emerges from the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.01257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.01257</id><created>2015-06-03</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hellmann</keyname><forenames>Frank</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schultz</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grabow</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heitzig</keyname><forenames>Jobst</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kurths</keyname><forenames>J&#xfc;rgen</forenames></author></authors><title>Survivability of Deterministic Dynamical Systems</title><categories>nlin.AO nlin.CD</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 6, 29654 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29654</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The notion of a part of phase space containing desired (or allowed) states of
a dynamical system is important in a wide range of complex systems research. It
has been called the safe operating space, the viability kernel or the sunny
region. In this paper we define the notion of survivability: Given a random
initial condition, what is the likelihood that the transient behaviour of a
deterministic system does not leave a region of desirable states. We
demonstrate the utility of this novel stability measure by considering models
from climate science, neuronal networks and power grids. We also show that a
semi-analytic lower bound for the survivability of linear systems allows a
numerically very efficient survivability analysis in realistic models of power
grids. Our numerical and semi-analytic work underlines that the type of
stability measured by survivability is not captured by common asymptotic
stability measures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.08055</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.08055</id><created>2015-06-21</created><updated>2016-05-04</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>G. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bishi</keyname><forenames>Binaya K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sahoo</keyname><forenames>P. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scalar field and time varying Cosmological constant in $f(R,T)$ gravity
  for Bianchi type-I Universe</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>10 pages, 10 figures</comments><journal-ref>Chinese Journal of Physics, 54(2), 244-255, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.cjph.2016.04.010</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we have analysed the behaviour of scalar field and
cosmological constant in $f(R,T)$ theory of gravity. Here, we have considered
the simplest form of $f(R,T)$ i.e. $f(R,T)=R+2f(T)$, where $R$ is the Ricci
scalar and $T$ is the trace of the energy momentum tensor and explored the
spatially homogeneous and anisotropic Locally Rotationally Symmetric (LRS)
Bianchi type-I cosmological model. It is assumed that the Universe is filled
with two non-interacting matter sources namely scalar field (normal or phantom)
with scalar potential and matter contribution due to $f(R,T)$ action. We have
discussed two cosmological models according to power law and exponential law of
the volume expansion along with constant and exponential scalar potential as
sub models. Power law models are compatible with normal (quintessence) and
phantom scalar field whereas exponential volume expansion models are compatible
with only normal (quintessence) scalar field. The values of cosmological
constant in our models are in agreement with the observational results.
Finally, we have discussed some physical and kinematical properties of both the
models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.00768</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.00768</id><created>2015-07-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Friesecke</keyname><forenames>Gero</forenames></author><author><keyname>Henneke</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kunisch</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author></authors><title>Sparse Control of Quantum Systems</title><categories>math.OC math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><msc-class>81Q93, 49J20, 35Q41</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A new class of cost functionals for optimal control of quantum systems which
produces controls which are sparse in frequency and smooth in time is proposed.
This is achieved by penalizing a suitable time-frequency representation of the
control field, rather than the control field itself, and by employing norms
which are of $L^1$ or measure form with respect to frequency but smooth with
respect to time.
  We prove existence of optimal controls for the resulting nonsmooth
optimization problem, derive necessary optimality conditions, and rigorously
establish the frequency-sparsity of the optimizers. More precisely, we show
that the time-frequency representation of the control field, which a priori
admits a continuum of frequencies, is supported on only \textit{ finitely many}
frequencies.
  These results cover important systems of physical interest, including
(infinite-dimensional) Schr\&quot;odinger dynamics on multiple potential energy
surfaces as arising in laser control of chemical reactions. Numerical
simulations confirm that the optimal controls, unlike those obtained with the
usual $L^2$ costs, concentrate on just a few frequencies, even in the
infinite-dimensional case of laser-controlled chemical reactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.06385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.06385</id><created>2015-07-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>Theory of nuclear spin dephasing and relaxation by optically illuminated
  nitrogen-vancy center</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 17, 113041 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/17/11/113041</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dephasing and relaxation of the nuclear spins coupled to the nitrogen-vacancy
(NV) center during optical initialization and readout is an important issue for
various applications of this hybrid quantum register. Here we present both an
analytical description and a numerical simulation for this process, which agree
reasonably with the experimental measurements. For the NV center under cyclic
optical transition, our analytical formula not only provide a clear physics
picture, but also allows controlling the nuclear spin dissipation by tuning an
external magnetic field. For more general optical pumping, our analytical
formula reveals significant contribution to the nuclear spin dissipation due to
electron random hopping into/out of the $m=0$ (or $m=\pm1$) subspace. This
contribution is not suppressed even under saturated optical pumping and/or
vanishing magnetic field, thus providing a possible solution to the puzzling
observation of nuclear spin dephasing in zero perpendicular magnetic field [M.
V. G. Dutt \textit{et al}., Science \textbf{316}, 1312 (2007)]. It also implies
that enhancing the degree of spin polarization of the nitrogen-vacancy center
can reduce the effect of optical induced nuclear spin dissipation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.07265</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.07265</id><created>2015-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Mori</keyname><forenames>Shintaro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hino</keyname><forenames>Masafumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hisakado</keyname><forenames>Masato</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takahashi</keyname><forenames>Taiki</forenames></author></authors><title>Detection of non-self-correcting nature of information cascade</title><categories>physics.data-an</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Proceeding of ECCS 2014</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-29228-1_1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method of detecting non-self-correcting information cascades in
experiments in which subjects choose an option sequentially by observing the
choices of previous subjects. The method uses the correlation function $C(t)$
between the first and the $t+1$-th subject's choices. $C(t)$ measures the
strength of the domino effect, and the limit value $c\equiv \lim_{t\to
\infty}C(t)$ determines whether the domino effect lasts forever $(c&gt;0)$ or not
$(c=0)$. The condition $c&gt;0$ is an adequate condition for a non-self-correcting
system, and the probability that the majority's choice remains wrong in the
limit $t\to \infty$ is positive. We apply the method to data from two
experiments in which $T$ subjects answered two-choice questions: (i) general
knowledge questions ($T_{avg}=60$) and (ii) urn-choice questions ($T=63$). We
find $c&gt;0$ for difficult questions in (i) and all cases in (ii), and the
systems are not self-correcting.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1507.08775</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1507.08775</id><created>2015-07-31</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Bao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Wen</forenames></author></authors><title>Strongly polarizing weakly coupled $^{13}$C nuclear spins with optically
  pumped nitrogen-vacancy center</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Sci. Rep. 5, 15847 (2015)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep15847</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Enhancing the polarization of nuclear spins surrounding the nitrogen-vacancy
(NV) center in diamond has attracted widespread attention recently due to its
various applications. Here we present an analytical theory and comprehensive
understanding on how to optimize the dynamic nuclear polarization by an
optically pumped NV center near the ground state level anticrossing. Our
results not only provide a parameter-free explanation and a clearly physics
picture for the recently observed polarization dependence on the magnetic field
for strongly coupled $^{13}$C nuclei [H. J. Wang \textit{et al}., Nat. Commun.
4, 1 (2013)], but also demonstrate the possibility to strongly polarize weakly
coupled $^{13}$C nuclei under weak optical pumping and suitably chosen magnetic
field. This allows sensitive magnetic control of the $^{13}$C nuclear spin
polarization for NMR applications and significant suppression of the $^{13}$C
nuclear spin noise to prolong the NV spin coherence time.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.01198</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.01198</id><created>2015-10-05</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Schunk</keyname><forenames>Gerhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vogl</keyname><forenames>Ulrich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sedlmeir</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Strekalov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Otterpohl</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Averchenko</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schwefel</keyname><forenames>Harald G. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leuchs</keyname><forenames>Gerd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marquardt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Frequency tuning of a triply-resonant whispering-gallery mode resonator
  to MHz wide transitions for proposed quantum repeater schemes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>18 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Modern Optics, 1-16 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/09500340.2016.1148211</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum repeaters rely on an interfacing of flying qubits with quantum
memories. The most common implementations include a narrowband single photon
matched in bandwidth and central frequency to an atomic system. Previously, we
demonstrated the compatibility of our versatile source of heralded single
photons, which is based on parametric down-conversion in a triply-resonant
whispering-gallery mode resonator, with alkaline transitions [Schunk et al.,
Optica 2, 773 (2015)]. In this paper, we analyze our source in terms of phase
matching, available wavelength-tuning mechanisms, and applications to
narrow-band atomic systems. We resonantly address the D1 transitions of cesium
and rubidium with this optical parametric oscillator pumped above its
oscillation threshold. Below threshold, the efficient coupling of single
photons to atomic transitions heralded by single telecom-band photons is
demonstrated. Finally, we present an accurate analytical description of our
observations. Providing the demonstrated flexibility in connecting various
atomic transitions with telecom wavelengths, we show a promising approach to
realize an essential building block for quantum repeaters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1510.03312</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1510.03312</id><created>2015-10-12</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vagberg</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsson</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Teitel</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Critical Scaling of Bagnold Rheology at the Jamming Transition of
  Frictionless Two Dimensional Disks</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>20 pages, 21 figures; revised manuscript according to published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 93, 052902 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.93.052902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We carry out constant volume simulations of steady-state, shear driven,
rheology in a simple model of bidisperse, soft-core, frictionless disks in two
dimensions, using a dissipation law that gives rise to Bagnoldian rheology. We
carry out a detailed critical scaling analysis of our resulting data for
pressure $p$ and shear stress $\sigma$, in order to determine the critical
exponent $\beta$ that describes the algebraic divergence of the Bagnold
transport coefficients, as the jamming transition is approached from below. We
show that it is necessary, for the strain rates considered in this work, to
consider the leading correction-to-scaling term in order to achieve a
self-consistent analysis of our data. Our resulting value $\beta\approx 5.0\pm
0.4$ is clearly larger than the theoretical prediction by Otsuki and Hayakawa,
and is consistent with earlier numerical results by Peyneau and Roux, and
recent theoretical predictions by DeGiuli et al. We have also considered the
macroscopic friction $\mu\equiv \sigma/p$ and similarly find results consistent
with Peyneau and Roux, and with DeGiuli et al. Our results confirm that the
shear driven jamming transition in Bagnoldian systems is well described by a
critical scaling theory (as was found previously for Newtonian systems), and we
relate this scaling theory to the phenomenological constituent laws for
dilatancy and friction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.01952</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.01952</id><created>2015-11-05</created><updated>2016-05-18</updated><authors><author><keyname>Griesshammer</keyname><forenames>Harald W.</forenames><affiliation>George Washington U.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>McGovern</keyname><forenames>Judith A.</forenames><affiliation>U. of Manchester</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Phillips</keyname><forenames>Daniel R.</forenames><affiliation>Ohio U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Nucleon Polarisabilities at and Beyond Physical Pion Masses</title><categories>nucl-th hep-lat hep-ph</categories><comments>39 pages LaTeX2e (pdflatex) including 12 figures as 16 .pdf files
  using includegraphics. Version approved for publication in EPJA includes
  modifications, clarifications and removal of typographical errors in
  refereeing and publication process</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2016) 52: 139</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2016-16139-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We examine the results of Chiral Effective Field Theory ($\chi$EFT) for the
scalar- and spin-dipole polarisabilities of the proton and neutron, both for
the physical pion mass and as a function of $m_\pi$. This provides chiral
extrapolations for lattice-QCD polarisability computations. We include both the
leading and sub-leading effects of the nucleon's pion cloud, as well as the
leading ones of the $\Delta(1232)$ resonance and its pion cloud. The analytic
results are complete at N$^2$LO in the $\delta$-counting for pion masses close
to the physical value, and at leading order for pion masses similar to the
Delta-nucleon mass splitting. In order to quantify the truncation error of our
predictions and fits as $68$\% degree-of-belief intervals, we use a Bayesian
procedure recently adapted to EFT expansions. At the physical point, our
predictions for the spin polarisabilities are, within respective errors, in
good agreement with alternative extractions using experiments and
dispersion-relation theory. At larger pion masses we find that the chiral
expansion of all polarisabilities becomes intrinsically unreliable as $m_\pi$
approaches about $300\;$MeV---as has already been seen in other observables.
$\chi$EFT also predicts a substantial isospin splitting above the physical
point for both the electric and magnetic scalar polarisabilities; and we
speculate on the impact this has on the stability of nucleons. Our results
agree very well with emerging lattice computations in the realm where $\chi$EFT
converges. Curiously, for the central values of some of our predictions, this
agreement persists to much higher pion masses. We speculate on whether this
might be more than a fortuitous coincidence.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.05120</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.05120</id><created>2015-11-16</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Parsons</keyname><forenames>Kyle</forenames></author></authors><title>Loop-Erased Random Surfaces</title><categories>math.PR math-ph math.AT math.CO math.MP</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Loop-erased random walk and it's scaling limit, Schramm--Loewner evolution,
have found numerous applications in mathematics and physics. We present a 2
dimensional analogue of LERW, the loop erased random surface. We do this by
defining a 2 dimensional spanning tree and declaring that LERS should have the
same relation to these 2 trees as LERW has to ordinary spanning trees.
Furthermore we present numerical evidence that the growth rate for LERS on a
$\delta$ fine grid as $\delta \to 0$ is $2.5269 \pm 0.0017$ and we hypothesize
that it has an exact value of 48/19. This suggests the possibility of a fractal
limiting object for LERS analogous to SLE for LERW.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06684</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06684</id><created>2015-11-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Tschikawa</keyname><forenames>Ryuichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heligman</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahmadi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mucciolo</keyname><forenames>E. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hone</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishigami</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering strength of potassium on a carbon nanotube with known
  chirality</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045408 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045408</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have measured the scattering strength of charged impurities on a
semiconducting single-walled carbon nanotube with known chirality. The
resistivity of the nanotube is measured as a function of the density of
adsorbed potassium atoms, enabling the determination of the resistance added by
an individual potassium atom. Holes are scattered 37 times more efficiently
than electrons by an adsorbed potassium atom. The determined scattering
strength is used to reveal the spatial extent and depth of the scattering
potential for potassium, a model Coulomb adsorbate. Our result represents an
essential experimental input to understand adsorbate-induced scattering and
provides a crucial step for paving the way to rational design of nanotube-based
sensors.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.06737</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.06737</id><created>2015-11-20</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kovchegov</keyname><forenames>Yuri V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pitonyak</keyname><forenames>Daniel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sievert</keyname><forenames>Matthew D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Helicity Evolution at Small-x</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>33 pages, 20 figures; v2: typos corrected, a reference added; v3:
  more corrections included</comments><report-no>RBRC-1159, BNL-111624-2015-JA</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1601 (2016) 072</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP01(2016)072</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct small-x evolution equations which can be used to calculate quark
and anti-quark helicity TMDs and PDFs, along with the $g_1$ structure function.
These evolution equations resum powers of $\alpha_s \, \ln^2 (1/x)$ in the
polarization-dependent evolution along with the powers of $\alpha_s \, \ln
(1/x)$ in the unpolarized evolution which includes saturation effects. The
equations are written in an operator form in terms of polarization-dependent
Wilson line-like operators. While the equations do not close in general, they
become closed and self-contained systems of non-linear equations in the
large-$N_c$ and large-$N_c \, \&amp; \, N_f$ limits. As a cross-check, in the
ladder approximation, our equations map onto the same ladder limit of the
infrared evolution equations for $g_1$ structure function derived previously by
Bartels, Ermolaev and Ryskin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1511.09264</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1511.09264</id><created>2015-11-30</created><updated>2016-05-16</updated><authors><author><keyname>Figueroa-O'Farrill</keyname><forenames>Jos&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>Eleven-dimensional supergravity from filtered subdeformations of the
  Poincar\'e superalgebra</title><categories>hep-th math.DG math.RT</categories><comments>5 pages (v2: new title, added one reference, final version to appear
  in J. Phys A)</comments><report-no>EMPG-15-23</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016), 295204 (7pp)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/29/295204</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We summarise the results of our recent paper (arXiv:1511.08737) highlighting
what might be considered to be a Lie-algebraic derivation of eleven-dimensional
supergravity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.00784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.00784</id><created>2015-12-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodrigues</keyname><forenames>Davi R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sinova</keyname><forenames>Jairo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Abanov</keyname><forenames>Ar.</forenames></author></authors><title>Current driven domain wall creation in ferromagnetic nano-wires</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>this article is superseded by arXiv:1607.03336</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We predict the electrical generation and injection of domain walls into a
ferromagnetic nano-wire without the need of an assisting magnetic field. Our
theory shows that above a critical current $j_{c}$ domain walls are injected
into the nano-wire with a period $T\sim (j-j_{c})^{-1/2}$. In a uniaxial
anisotropy geometry this process does not require Dzyaloshinskii-Moria or
dipole-dipole interaction and can be done in a simple exchange ferromagnet. We
also show that this process and the period exponents are universal and do not
depend on the peculiarities of the microscopic Hamiltonian.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04199</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04199</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Doi</keyname><forenames>Takumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Aoki</keyname><forenames>Sinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gongyo</keyname><forenames>Shinya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsuda</keyname><forenames>Tetsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ikeda</keyname><forenames>Yoichi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Inoue</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Iritani</keyname><forenames>Takumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ishii</keyname><forenames>Noriyoshi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Miyamoto</keyname><forenames>Takaya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Murano</keyname><forenames>Keiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nemura</keyname><forenames>Hidekatsu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sasaki</keyname><forenames>Kenji</forenames></author></authors><title>Towards Lattice QCD Baryon Forces at the Physical Point: First Results</title><categories>hep-lat nucl-th</categories><comments>Talk given at the 12th International Conference on Hypernuclear and
  Strange Particle Physics (HYP2015), Sendai, Japan, 7-12 Sep 2015, 4 pages, 6
  figures</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-209, YITP-15-116, UTCCS-P-87</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Lattice QCD calculations of baryon forces are performed for the first time
with (almost) physical quark masses. $N_f = 2+1$ dynamical clover fermion gauge
configurations are generated at the lattice spacing of $a \simeq 0.085$ fm on a
$(96 a)^4 \simeq (8.2 {\rm fm})^4$ lattice with quark masses corresponding to
$(m_\pi, m_K) \simeq (146, 525)$ MeV. Baryon forces are calculated using the
time-dependent HAL QCD method. In this report, we study $\Xi\Xi$ and $NN$
systems both in $^1S_0$ and $^3S_1$-$^3D_1$ channels, and the results for the
central and tensor forces as well as phase shifts in the $\Xi\Xi$ $(^1S_0)$
channel are presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.05016</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.05016</id><created>2015-12-15</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Mervin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Yimo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Hanyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Yuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muller</keyname><forenames>David A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Xiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Chemical assembly of atomically thin transistors and circuits in a large
  scale</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><doi>10.1038/nnano.2016.115</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Next-generation electronics calls for new materials beyond silicon for
increased functionality, performance, and scaling in integrated circuits.
Carbon nanotubes and semiconductor nanowires are at the forefront of these
materials, but have challenges due to the complex fabrication techniques
required for large-scale applications. Two-dimensional (2D) gapless graphene
and semiconducting transition metal dichalcogenides (TMDCs) have emerged as
promising electronic materials due to their atomic thickness, chemical
stability and scalability. Difficulties in the assembly of 2D electronic
structures arise in the precise spatial control over the metallic and
semiconducting atomic thin films. Ultimately, this impedes the maturity of
integrating atomic elements in modern electronics. Here, we report the
large-scale spatially controlled synthesis of the single-layer semiconductor
molybdenum disulfide (MoS2) laterally in contact with conductive graphene.
Transition electron microscope (TEM) studies reveal that the single-layer MoS2
nucleates at the edge of the graphene, creating a lateral 2D heterostructure.
We demonstrate such chemically assembled 2D atomic transistors exhibit high
transconductance (10 uS), on-off ratios (10^6), and mobility (20 cm^2 V^-1
s^-1). We assemble 2D logic circuits, such as a heterostructure NMOS inverter
with a high voltage gain, up to 70, enabled by the precise site selectivity
from atomically thin conducting and semiconducting crystals. This scalable
chemical assembly of 2D heterostructures may usher in a new era in
two-dimensional electronic circuitry and computing.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.08796</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.08796</id><created>2015-12-29</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Arhrib</keyname><forenames>Abdesslam</forenames></author><author><keyname>B&#x153;hm</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;line</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Ernest</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Tzu-Chiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative Model of Neutrino Mass with Neutrino Interacting MeV Dark
  Matter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>34 pages, 4 figures, references added, journal version published in
  JCAP</comments><doi>10.1088/1475-7516/2016/04/049</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the radiative generation of neutrino mass through the
interactions of neutrinos with MeV dark matter. We construct a realistic
renormalizable model with one scalar doublet and one complex singlet together
with three light singlet Majorana fermions, all transforming under a dark U(1)
symmetry which breaks softly to Z_2. We study in detail the scalar sector which
supports this specific scenario and its rich phenomenology.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.09266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.09266</id><created>2015-12-31</created><updated>2016-03-31</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Zi-qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>De-fu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Yan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>R^2 corrections to the jet quenching parameter</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>5 pages,2 figures</comments><report-no>Volume 2016, Article ID 9503491</report-no><journal-ref>Advances in High Energy Physics, Volume 2016 (2016), Article
  ID9503491, 5 pages</journal-ref><doi>10.1155/2016/9503491</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A calculation of the $R^2$ corrections to the jet quenching parameter from
AdS/CFT correspondence is presented. These corrections are related to
curvature-squared corrections in the corresponding gravity dual. It is shown
that the corrections will increase or decrease the jet quenching parameter
depending on the coefficients of the high curvature terms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01978</id><created>2016-01-08</created><updated>2016-06-21</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rodriguez-Mendez</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eguiluz</keyname><forenames>Victor M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez-Garcia</keyname><forenames>Emilio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ramasco</keyname><forenames>Jose J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Percolation-based precursors of transitions in extended systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech physics.ao-ph physics.data-an</categories><comments>15 pages, 8 figures, to appear in Scientific Reports</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 29552 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29552</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Abrupt transitions are ubiquitous in the dynamics of complex systems. Finding
precursors, i.e. early indicators of their arrival, is fundamental in many
areas of science ranging from electrical engineering to climate. However,
obtaining warnings of an approaching transition well in advance remains an
elusive task. Here we show that a functional network, constructed from spatial
correlations of the system's time series, experiences a percolation transition
way before the actual system reaches a bifurcation point due to the collective
phenomena leading to the global change. Concepts from percolation theory are
then used to introduce early warning precursors that anticipate the system's
tipping point. We illustrate the generality and versatility of our
percolation-based framework with model systems experiencing different types of
bifurcations and with Sea Surface Temperature time series associated to El Nino
phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.03549</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.03549</id><created>2016-02-10</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lundow</keyname><forenames>P. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Campbell</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ising Spin Glasses and Renormalization Group Theory: the Binder cumulant</title><categories>cond-mat.dis-nn</categories><comments>7 pages, 11 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Numerical data on scaling of the normalized Binder cumulant and the
normalized correlation length are shown for the Thermodynamic limit regime,
first for canonical Ising ferromagnet models and then for a range of Ising spin
glass models. A fundamental Renormalization Group Theory rule linking the
critical exponents for the two observables is well obeyed in the Ising models,
but not for the Ising spin glasses in dimensions three and four. We conclude
that there is a violation of a standard Josephson hyperscaling rule in Ising
spin glasses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.04205</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.04205</id><created>2016-02-12</created><updated>2016-02-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Vella</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gregoire</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tuladhar</keyname><forenames>Sachetan M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vezie</keyname><forenames>Michelle S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Few</keyname><forenames>Sheridan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bazan</keyname><forenames>Claudia M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Jenny</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva-Acuna</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bittner</keyname><forenames>Eric R</forenames></author></authors><title>Do ultrafast exciton-polaron decoherence dynamics govern photocarrier
  generation efficiencies in polymer solar cells?</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, Article number: 29437 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29437</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  All-organic-based photovoltaic solar cells have attracted considerable
attention because of their low-cost processing and short energy payback time.
In such systems the primary dissociation of an optical excitation into a pair
of photocarriers has been recently shown to be extremely rapid and efficient,
but the physical reason for this remains unclear. Here, two-dimensional
photocurrent excitation spectroscopy, a novel non-linear optical spectroscopy,
is used to probe the ultrafast coherent decay of photoexcitations into
charge-producing states in a polymer:fullerene based solar cell. The
two-dimensional photocurrent spectra are interpreted by introducing a
theoretical model for the description of the coupling of the electronic states
of the system to an external environment and to the applied laser fields. The
experimental data show no cross-peaks in the two-dimensional photocurrent
spectra, as predicted by the model for coherence times between the exciton and
the photocurrent producing states of 20\,fs or less.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.07546</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.07546</id><created>2016-02-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Parattu</keyname><forenames>Krishnamohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Sumanta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Padmanabhan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational Principle for Gravity with Null and Non-null boundaries: A
  Unified Boundary Counter-term</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>6 pages, no figures, accepted in Eur. Phys. J. C</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C 76, 129 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-3979-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is common knowledge that the Einstein-Hilbert action does not furnish a
well-posed variational principle. The usual solution to this problem is to add
an extra boundary term to the action, called a counter-term, so that the
variational principle becomes well-posed. When the boundary is spacelike or
timelike, the Gibbons-Hawking-York counter-term is the most widely used. For
null boundaries, we had proposed a counter-term in a previous paper. In this
paper, we extend the previous analysis and propose a counter-term that can be
used to eliminate variations of the &quot;off-the-surface&quot; derivatives of the metric
on any boundary, regardless of its spacelike, timelike or null nature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.08586</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.08586</id><created>2016-02-27</created><updated>2016-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Hopui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Haixi</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum noise limit for force sensitivity of linear detectors</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We prove that the force sensitivity of the conventional optomechanical
detector associated with the optical quadrature measurement of the output beam
is lower bounded by the so-called ultimate quantum limit (UQL), i.e., the
absolute value of the imaginary part of the inverse mechanical susceptibility.
Through the linear response theory, we find that the force sensitivity of any
linear detector is lower bounded by a generalized UQL, which might beat the
usual UQL by properly tailoring the detector-oscillator interaction. We believe
that our results open a new direction for improving the performance of
high-sensitivity detection schemes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02272</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02272</id><created>2016-03-07</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Eckert</keyname><forenames>Dominique</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jauzac</keyname><forenames>Mathilde</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vazza</keyname><forenames>Franco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Owers</keyname><forenames>Matt</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kneib</keyname><forenames>Jean-Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tchernin</keyname><forenames>Celine</forenames></author><author><keyname>Intema</keyname><forenames>Huib</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knowles</keyname><forenames>Kenda</forenames></author></authors><title>A shock front at the radio relic of Abell 2744</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.CO</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, MNRAS in press</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1435</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Radio relics are Mpc-scale diffuse radio sources at the peripheries of galaxy
clusters which are thought to trace outgoing merger shocks. We present
XMM-Newton and Suzaku observations of the galaxy cluster Abell 2744 (z=0.306),
which reveal the presence of a shock front 1.5 Mpc East of the cluster core.
The surface-brightness jump coincides with the position of a known radio relic.
Although the surface-brightness jump indicates a weak shock with a Mach number
$\mathcal{M}=1.7_{-0.3}^{+0.5}$, the plasma in the post-shock region has been
heated to a very high temperature ($\sim13$ keV) by the passage of the shock
wave. The low acceleration efficiency expected from such a weak shock suggests
that mildly relativistic electrons have been re-accelerated by the passage of
the shock front.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.02602</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.02602</id><created>2016-03-08</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Campa</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Casetti</keyname><forenames>Lapo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latella</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Madrid</keyname><forenames>Agust&#xed;n</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruffo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions in Thirring's model</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>16 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 073205</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/073205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In his pioneering work on negative specific heat, Walter Thirring
in\-tro\-duced a model that is solvable in the microcanonical ensemble. Here,
we give a complete description of the phase-diagram of this model in both the
microcanonical and the canonical ensemble, highlighting the main features of
ensemble inequivalence. In both ensembles, we find a line of first-order phase
transitions which ends in a critical point. However, neither the line nor the
point have the same location in the phase-diagram of the two ensembles. We also
show that the microcanonical and canonical critical points can be analytically
related to each other using a Landau expansion of entropy and free energy,
respectively, in analogy with what has been done in [O. Cohen, D. Mukamel, J.
Stat. Mech., P12017 (2012)]. Examples of systems with certain symmetries
restricting the Landau expansion have been considered in this reference, while
no such restrictions are present in Thirring's model. This leads to a phase
diagram that can be seen as a prototype for what happens in systems of
particles with kinematic degrees of freedom dominated by long-range
interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04295</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04295</id><created>2016-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Arend</keyname><forenames>Carsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becker</keyname><forenames>Jonas Nils</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sternschulte</keyname><forenames>Hadwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinm&#xfc;ller-Nethl</keyname><forenames>Doris</forenames></author><author><keyname>Becher</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author></authors><title>Photoluminescence excitation and spectral hole burning spectroscopy of
  silicon vacancy centers in diamond</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>8 pages, 10 figures</comments><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.045203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Silicon-vacancy (SiV) centers in diamond are promising systems for quantum
information applications due to their bright single photon emission and
optically accessible spin states. Furthermore, SiV centers in low-strain
diamond are insensitive to pertubations of the dielectric environment, i.e.
they show very weak spectral diffusion. This property renders ensembles of SiV
centers interesting for sensing applications. We here report on
photoluminescence excitation (PLE) spectroscopy on an SiV ensemble in a low
strain, CVD-grown high quality diamond layer, where we measure the fine
structure with high resolution and obtain the linewidths and splittings of the
SiV centers. We investigate the temperature dependence of the width and
position of the fine structure peaks. Our measurements reveal linewidths of
about 10 GHz as compared to a lifetime limited width on the order of 0.1 GHz.
This difference arises from the inhomogeneous broadening of the transitions
caused by residual strain. To overcome inhomogeneous broadening we use spectral
hole burning spectroscopy which enables us to measure a nearly lifetime limited
homogeneous linewidth of 279 MHz. Furthermore, we demonstrate evidence of
coherent interaction in the system by driving a $\Lambda$-scheme. Additional
measurements on single emitters created by ion implantation confirm the
homogeneous linewidths seen in the spectral hole burning experiments and relate
the ground state splitting to the decoherence rate.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04398</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04398</id><created>2016-03-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lovey</keyname><forenames>D. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Usaj</keyname><forenames>Gonzalo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>L. E. F. Foa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Balseiro</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Floquet bound states around defects and adatoms in graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>16 pages, 14 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 93, 245434 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.93.245434</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent studies have focused on laser-induced gaps in graphene which have been
shown to have a topological origin, thereby hosting robust states at the sample
edges. While the focus has remained mainly on these topological chiral edge
states, the Floquet bound states around defects lack a detailed study. In this
paper we present such a study covering large defects of different shape and
also vacancy-like defects and adatoms at the dynamical gap at $\hbar\Omega/2$
($\hbar\Omega$ being the photon energy). Our results, based on analytical
calculations as well as numerics for full tight-binding models, show that the
bound states are chiral and appear in a number which grows with the defect
size. Furthermore, while the bound states exist regardless the type of the
defect's edge termination (zigzag, armchair, mixed), the spectrum is strongly
dependent on it. In the case of top adatoms, the bound states quasi-energies
depend on the adatoms energy. The appearance of such bound states might open
the door to the presence of topological effects on the bulk transport
properties of dirty graphene.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.04720</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.04720</id><created>2016-03-15</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Cardenas-Avendano</keyname><forenames>Alejandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>Jiachen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bambi</keyname><forenames>Cosimo</forenames></author></authors><title>Testing the Kerr black hole hypothesis: comparison between the
  gravitational wave and the iron line approaches</title><categories>gr-qc astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures. v2: updated some references as in the published
  version</comments><journal-ref>Phys.Lett.B760:254-258,2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.06.075</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The recent announcement of the detection of gravitational waves by the
LIGO/Virgo collaboration has opened a new window to test the nature of
astrophysical black holes. Konoplya &amp; Zhidenko have shown how the LIGO data of
GW 150914 can constrain possible deviations from the Kerr metric. In this
letter, we compare their constraints with those that can be obtained from
accreting black holes by fitting their reflected X-ray spectrum, the so-called
iron line method. We simulate observations with eXTP, a next generation X-ray
mission, finding constraints much stronger than those obtained by Konoplya &amp;
Zhidenko. Our results can at least show that, contrary to what is quite
commonly believed, it is not obvious that gravitational waves are the most
powerful approach to test strong gravity. In the presence of high quality data
and with the systematics under control, the iron line method may provide
competitive constraints.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.06194</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.06194</id><created>2016-03-20</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Nagendra</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA, Pune-411007, India</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Misra</keyname><forenames>Ranjeev</forenames><affiliation>IUCAA, Pune-411007, India</affiliation></author></authors><title>A Monte Carlo estimate for the fraction of thermal Comptonized photons
  that impinge back on the soft source in neutron star LMXBs</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>6 pages, 7 figures, 1 table, submitted to MNRAS</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In earlier works, it was shown that the energy dependent soft time lags
observed in kHz QPOs of neutron star low mass X-ray binaries (LMXBs) can be
explained as being due to Comptonization lags provided a significant fraction
($\eta \sim 0.2$ - $0.8$) of the Comptonized photons impinge back into the soft
photon source. Here we use a Monte Carlo scheme to verify if such a fraction is
viable or not. In particular we consider three different Comptonizing medium
geometries: (i) a spherical shell, (ii) a boundary layer like torus and (iii) a
corona on top of an accretion disk. Two set of spectral parameters
corresponding to the 'hot' and 'cold' seed photon models were explored. The
general result of the study is that for a wide range of sizes, the fraction
lies within $\eta \sim 0.3$ - $0.7$, and hence compatible with the range
required to explain the soft time lags. Since there is a large uncertainty in
the range, we cannot concretely rule out any of the geometries or spectral
models, but the analysis suggests that a boundary layer type geometry with a
'cold' seed spectral model is favoured over an accretion corona model. Better
quality data will allow one to constrain the geometry more rigorously. Our
results emphasise that there is significant heating of the soft photon source
by the Comptonized photons and hence this effect needs to be taken into account
for any detailed study of these sources.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1603.07166</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1603.07166</id><created>2016-03-22</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Stahl</keyname><forenames>Cl&#xe9;ment</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xue</keyname><forenames>She-Sheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Schwinger effect and backreaction in de Sitter spacetime</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>9 pages, 4 figures, matches published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Lett. B760 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physletb.2016.07.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider the particle-antiparticle pairs produced by both a strong
electric field and de Sitter curvature. We investigate in 1 + 1 D the
backreaction of the pairs on the electromagnetic field. To do so we describe
the canonical quantization of an electromagnetic field in de Sitter space and
add in the Einstein-Maxwell equation the fermionic current induced by the
pairs. After solving this equation, we find that the electric field gets either
damped or unaffected depending on the value of the pair mass and the gauge
coupling. No enhancement of the electromagnetic field to support a
magnetogenesis scenario is found. The physical picture is that the Schwinger
pairs locally created screen the production and amplification of the
electromagnetic field. However, if one considers light bosons created by the
Schwinger mechanism, we report a solution to the Einstein-Maxwell equation with
an enhancement of the electromagnetic field. This solution could be a new path
to primordial magnetogenesis.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00522</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00522</id><created>2016-04-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Moretti</keyname><forenames>Simone</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raposo</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martinez</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author></authors><title>Influence of Joule heating on current-induced domain wall depinning</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><journal-ref>J. Appl. Phys. 119, 213902 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1063/1.4953008</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The domain wall depinning from a notch in a Permalloy nanostrip on top of a
${\rm SiO_2/Si}$ substrate is studied theoretically under application of static
magnetic fields and the injection of short current pulses. The influence of
Joule heating on current-induced domain wall depinning is explored
self-consistently by coupling the magnetization dynamics in the ferromagnetic
strip to the heat transport throughout the system. Our results indicate that
Joule heating plays a remarkable role in these processes, resulting in a
reduction in the critical depinning field and/or in a temporary destruction of
the ferromagnetic order for typically injected current pulses. In agreement
with experimental observations, similar pinning-depinning phase diagrams can be
deduced for both current polarities when the Joule heating is taken into
account. These observations, which are incompatible with the sole contribution
of spin transfer torques, provide a deeper understanding of the physics
underlying these processes and establish the real scope of the spin transfer
torque. They are also relevant for technological applications based on
current-induced domain-wall motion along soft strips.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.00529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.00529</id><created>2016-04-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Poenaru</keyname><forenames>Dorin N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gherghescu</keyname><forenames>Radu A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spontaneous fission of superheavy nucleus $^{286}$Fl</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>18 pages, 9 figures, 3 tables, URL:
  http://link.aps.org/doi/10.1103/PhysRevC.94.014309</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 94 (1) (2016) 014309</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.014309</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The decimal logarithm of spontaneous fission half-life of the superheavy
nucleus $^{286}$Fl experimentally determined is $\log_{10} T_f^{exp} (s) =
-0.632$. We present a method to calculate the half-life based on the cranking
inertia and the deformation energy, functions of two independent surface
coordinates, using the best asymmetric two center shell model. In the first
stage we study the statics. At a given mass asymmetry up to about $\eta=0.5$
the potential barrier has a two hump shape, but for larger $\eta$ it has only
one hump. The touching point deformation energy versus mass asymmetry shows the
three minima, produced by shell effects, corresponding to three decay modes:
spontaneous fission, cluster decay and $\alpha$~decay. The least action
trajectory is determined in the plane $(R,\eta)$ where $R$ is the separation
distance of the fission fragments and $\eta$ is the mass asymmetry. We may find
a sequence of several trajectories one of which gives the least action. The
parametrization with two deformation coordinates $(R,\eta)$ and the radius of
the light fragment, $R_2$, exponentially decreasing with $R$ is compared with
the simpler one, in which $R_2$~=constant. The latter is closer to the reality
and reminds us about the alpha or cluster preformation at the nuclear surface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.01640</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.01640</id><created>2016-04-06</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Richard</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author></authors><title>Diphoton resonance at e+e- and photon colliders</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><report-no>LAL 16-029</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note, I will review the opportunities offered by the hint of a new
resonance observed at LHC for future e+e- TeV linear collider (LC) projects.
This discussion is mainly influenced by two specific scenarios of physics which
assume either a (pseudo-)scalar or a tensor resonance, but these estimates can
be used in most scenarios. I envisage either a photon collider, which has a
guaranteed signal with the LHC observation, or a standard e+e- collider, more
straightforward to implement. After a detailed study of the heavy graviton
scenario, I conclude that at a TeV LC, high accuracy measurements, including
rare modes, allow to unambiguously establish the origin of this resonance. Also
envisaged in some detail is a radion scenario which illustrates the production
of a scalar. The role of an LC for precision measurements on Higgs and top
couplings is recalled in the context of the Randall Sundrum model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.02834</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.02834</id><created>2016-04-11</created><updated>2016-05-05</updated><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Song</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhengwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Jun-Bao</forenames></author></authors><title>Scattering Equations, Twistor-string Formulas and Double-soft Limits in
  Four Dimensions</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>22 pages, 2 tables; v2: ref added, minor typos fixed</comments><report-no>CP3-16-35</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1607 (2016) 060</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP07(2016)060</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study scattering equations and formulas for tree amplitudes of various
theories in four dimensions, in terms of spinor helicity variables and on-shell
superspace for supersymmetric theories. As originally obtained in Witten's
twistor string theory and other twistor-string models, the equations can take
either polynomial or rational forms, and we clarify the simple relation between
them. We present new, four-dimensional formulas for all tree amplitudes in the
non-linear sigma model, a special Galileon theory and the maximally
supersymmetric completion of the Dirac-Born-Infeld theory. Furthermore, we
apply the formulas to study various double-soft theorems in these theories,
including the emissions of a pair of soft photons, fermions and scalars for
super-amplitudes in super-DBI theory.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.07114</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.07114</id><created>2016-04-24</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>D. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>N. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anisotropic transport and optical spectroscopy study on
  antiferromagentic triangular lattice EuCd_2As_2: an interplay between
  magnetism and charge transport properties</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 045112 (2016)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present anisotropic transport and optical spectroscopy studies on
EuCd_2As_2. The measurements reveal that EuCd_2As_2 is a low carrier density
semimetal with moderate anisotropic resistivity ratio. The charge carriers
experience very strong scattering from Eu magnetic moments, resulting in a
Kondo-like increase of resistivity at low temperature. Below the
antiferromagnetic transition temperature at $T_N$= 9.5 K, the resistivity drops
sharply due to the reduced scattering from the ordered Eu moments.
Nevertheless, the anisotropic ratio of $\rho_c/\rho_{ab}$ keeps increasing,
suggesting that the antiferromagnetic coupling is along the c-axis. The optical
spectroscopy measurement further reveals, besides an overdamped reflectance
plasma edge at low energy, a strong coupling between phonon and electronic
continuum. Our study suggests that EuCd_2As_2 is a promising candidate
displaying intriguing interplay among charge, magnetism and the underlying
crystal lattice.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.08094</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.08094</id><created>2016-04-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Cavina</keyname><forenames>Vasco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mari</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giovannetti</keyname><forenames>Vittorio</forenames></author></authors><title>Optimal processes for probabilistic work extraction beyond the second
  law</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><journal-ref>Scientific Reports 6, 29282 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/srep29282</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to the second law of thermodynamics, for every transformation
performed on a system which is in contact with an environment of fixed
temperature, the extracted work is bounded by the decrease of the free energy
of the system. However, in a single realization of a generic process, the
extracted work is subject to statistical fluctuations which may allow for
probabilistic violations of the previous bound. We are interested in enhancing
this effect, i.e. we look for thermodynamic processes that maximize the
probability of extracting work above a given arbitrary threshold. For any
process obeying the Jarzynski identity, we determine an upper bound for the
work extraction probability that depends also on the minimum amount of work
that we are willing to extract in case of failure, or on the average work we
wish to extract from the system. Then we show that this bound can be saturated
within the thermodynamic formalism of quantum discrete processes composed by
sequences of unitary quenches and complete thermalizations. We explicitly
determine the optimal protocol which is given by two quasi-static isothermal
transformations separated by a finite unitary quench.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00037</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00037</id><created>2016-04-29</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Davoudiasl</keyname><forenames>Hooman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giardino</keyname><forenames>Pier Paolo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Cen</forenames></author></authors><title>Exo-Higgs at 750 GeV and Genesis of Baryons</title><categories>hep-ph hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 015006 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.015006</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose that the diphoton excess at 750 GeV reported by ATLAS and CMS is
due to the decay of an ${\it exo-Higgs}$ scalar $\eta$ associated with the
breaking of a new $SU(2)_e$ symmetry, dubbed ${\it exo-spin}$. New fermions,
${\it exo-quarks}$ and ${\it exo-leptons}$, get TeV-scale masses through Yukawa
couplings with $\eta$ and generate its couplings to gluons and photons at
1-loop. The matter content of our model yields a $B-L$ anomaly under $SU(2)_e$,
whose breaking we assume entails a first order phase transition. A non-trivial
$B-L$ asymmetry may therefore be generated in the early universe, potentially
providing a baryogenesis mechanism through the Standard Model (SM) sphaleron
processes. The spontaneous breaking of $SU(2)_e$ can in principle directly lead
to electroweak symmetry breaking, thereby accounting for the proximity of the
mass scales of the SM Higgs and the exo-Higgs. Our model can be distinguished
from those comprising a singlet scalar and vector fermions by the discovery of
TeV scale exo-vector bosons, corresponding to the broken $SU(2)_e$ generators,
at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00068</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00068</id><created>2016-04-30</created><updated>2016-06-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ablikim</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Achasov</keyname><forenames>M. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ai</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albayrak</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Albrecht</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ambrose</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Amoroso</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>F. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>An</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bai</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ferroli</keyname><forenames>R. Baldini</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ban</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>D. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bennett</keyname><forenames>J. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertani</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bettoni</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bian</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bianchi</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Boyko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Briere</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cai</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cakir</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Calcaterra</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cetin</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chelkov</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>M. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chu</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cibinetto</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dbeyssi</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dedovich</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deng</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denig</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Denysenko</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Destefanis</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>DeMori</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ding</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>L. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>M. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dou</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Du</keyname><forenames>S. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Duan</keyname><forenames>P. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fan</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Farinelli</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fava</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fedorov</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feldbauer</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felici</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>C. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fioravanti</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fritsch</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>C. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Garzia</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goetzen</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>W. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gradl</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Greco</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>A. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>L. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guo</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Haddadi</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hafner</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hao</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harris</keyname><forenames>F. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>K. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Held</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heng</keyname><forenames>Y. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hou</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>X. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huang</keyname><forenames>Z. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hussain</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Q. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jiao</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>D. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Johansson</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Julin</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kalantar-Nayestanaki</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kavatsyuk</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ke</keyname><forenames>B. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kiese</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kliemt</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kloss</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kolcu</keyname><forenames>O. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kopf</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kornicer</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupsc</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>K&#xfc;hn</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lange</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lara</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Larin</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leng</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Cheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>D. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>F. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Jin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Q. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>W. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>X. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Z. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>G. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>D. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>F. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Fang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>H. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>K. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>L. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>S. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Zhiqing</forenames></author><author><keyname>Loehner</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lou</keyname><forenames>X. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Y. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>C. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>M. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Luo</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lyu</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>F. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>H. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>M. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Q. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ma</keyname><forenames>Y. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maas</keyname><forenames>F. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maggiora</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mao</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcello</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Messchendorp</keyname><forenames>J. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Min</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitchell</keyname><forenames>R. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mo</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morales</keyname><forenames>C. Morales</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muchnoi</keyname><forenames>N. Yu.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Muramatsu</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nefedov</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nerling</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nikolaev</keyname><forenames>I. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ning</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nisar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Niu</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Olsen</keyname><forenames>S. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ouyang</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pacetti</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Patteri</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelizaeus</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peng</keyname><forenames>H. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Peters</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pettersson</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ping</keyname><forenames>R. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poling</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prasad</keyname><forenames>V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>H. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qian</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiao</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>L. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>X. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qin</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Qiu</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rashid</keyname><forenames>K. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Redmer</keyname><forenames>C. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ripka</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rong</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rosner</keyname><forenames>Ch.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruan</keyname><forenames>X. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarantsev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savri&#xe9;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schoenning</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schumann</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shan</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shao</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>C. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>P. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shen</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>W. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sosio</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spataro</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>G. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>J. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>X. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Y. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Z. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tapan</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thorndike</keyname><forenames>E. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiemens</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ullrich</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uman</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Varner</keyname><forenames>G. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>B. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>D. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>L. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>P. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>W. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>X. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Y. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weber</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wei</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Weidenkaff</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wen</keyname><forenames>S. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wiedner</keyname><forenames>U.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolke</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>L. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>L. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>L. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xia</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiao</keyname><forenames>Z. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xie</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xiu</keyname><forenames>Q. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>G. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>Q. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Xu</keyname><forenames>X. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>W. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yan</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>H. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Y. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ye</keyname><forenames>M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>C. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>J. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>C. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>W. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yuncu</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zafar</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zallo</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>B. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>C. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>D. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>H. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>S. Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Y. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Z. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>J. Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Lei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Ling</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>M. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Q. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>T. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Y. B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Z. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhemchugov</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>J. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>W. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Y. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhong</keyname><forenames>B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhou</keyname><forenames>X. Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>K. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>S. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>X. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Y. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Z. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhuang</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zotti</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>B. S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zou</keyname><forenames>J. H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Improved measurement of the absolute branching fraction of
  $D^{+}\rightarrow \bar K^0 \mu^{+}\nu_{\mu}$</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>9 pages; 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. C (2016) 76:369</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjc/s10052-016-4198-2</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By analyzing 2.93 fb$^{-1}$ of data collected at $\sqrt s=3.773$ GeV with the
BESIII detector, we measure the absolute branching fraction ${\mathcal
B}(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar K^0\mu^{+}\nu_{\mu})=(8.72 \pm 0.07_{\rm stat.} \pm
0.18_{\rm sys.})\%$, which is consistent with previous measurements within
uncertainties but with significantly improved precision. Combining the Particle
Data Group values of ${\mathcal B}(D^0\to K^-\mu^+\nu_\mu)$, ${\mathcal
B}(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar K^0 e^{+}\nu_{e})$, and the lifetimes of the $D^0$ and
$D^+$ mesons with the value of ${\mathcal B}(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar K^0
\mu^{+}\nu_{\mu})$ measured in this work, we determine the following ratios of
partial widths: $\Gamma(D^0\to K^-\mu^+\nu_\mu)/\Gamma(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar
K^0\mu^{+}\nu_{\mu})=0.963\pm0.044$ and $\Gamma(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar K^0
\mu^{+}\nu_{\mu})/\Gamma(D^{+}\rightarrow\bar K^0 e^{+}\nu_{e})=0.988\pm0.033$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.00512</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.00512</id><created>2016-05-02</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lane</keyname><forenames>Charles D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Spacetime Variation of Lorentz-Violation Coefficients at Nonrelativistic
  Scale</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>8 pages; v2 has a paragraph added to subsection II.B.1</comments><report-no>Berry College HEP-004</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 94, 025016 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.94.025016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The notion of uniform and/or constant tensor fields of rank $&gt;0$ is
incompatible with general curved spacetimes. This work considers the
consequences of certain tensor-valued coefficients for Lorentz violation in the
Standard-Model Extension varying with spacetime position. We focus on two of
the coefficients, $a_\mu$ and $b_\mu$, that characterize Lorentz violation in
massive fermions, particularly in those fermions that constitute ordinary
matter. We calculate the nonrelativistic hamiltonian describing these effects,
and use it to extract the sensitivity of several precision experiments to
coefficient variation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.01529</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.01529</id><created>2016-05-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Garz&#xf3;</keyname><forenames>Vicente</forenames></author><author><keyname>Trizac</keyname><forenames>Emmanuel</forenames></author></authors><title>Tracer diffusion coefficients in a sheared inelastic Maxwell gas</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>19 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Stat. Mech. (2016) 073206</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-5468/2016/07/073206</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the transport properties of an impurity in a sheared granular gas,
in the framework of the Boltzmann equation for inelastic Maxwell models. We
investigate here the impact of a nonequilibrium phase transition found in such
systems, where the tracer species carries a finite fraction of the total
kinetic energy (ordered phase). To this end, the diffusion coefficients are
first obtained for a granular binary mixture in spatially inhomogeneous states
close to the simple shear flow. In this situation, the set of coupled Boltzmann
equations are solved by means of a Chapman-Enskog-like expansion around the
(local) shear flow distributions for each species, thereby retaining all the
hydrodynamic orders in the shear rate $a$. Due to the anisotropy induced by the
shear flow, three tensorial quantities $D_{ij}$, $D_{p,ij}$, and $D_{T,ij}$ are
required to describe the mass transport process instead of the conventional
scalar coefficients. These tensors are given in terms of the solutions of a set
of coupled algebraic equations, which can be \emph{exactly} solved as functions
of the shear rate $a$, the coefficients of restitution $\alpha_{sr}$ and the
parameters of the mixture (masses and composition). Once the forms of $D_{ij}$,
$D_{p,ij}$, and $D_{T,ij}$ are obtained for arbitrary mole fraction
$x_1=n_1/(n_1+n_2)$ (where $n_r$ is the number density of species $r$), the
tracer limit ($x_1\to 0$) is carefully considered for the above three diffusion
tensors. Explicit forms for these coefficients are derived showing that their
shear rate dependence is significantly affected by the order-disorder
transition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.03607</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.03607</id><created>2016-05-11</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Marshall</keyname><forenames>Jeffrey</forenames></author><author><keyname>Martin-Mayor</keyname><forenames>Victor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hen</keyname><forenames>Itay</forenames></author></authors><title>Practical engineering of hard spin-glass instances</title><categories>quant-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>8 pages plus appendix. 6+2 figures. Comments for v2: Fixed mistake in
  online title. Changed one sentence in abstract slightly, for better
  readability. Extended Sec. IIA, IV (final paragraph only), VI, based on
  referee comments. Updated References (removed duplicates, added footnote).
  Modified figure font sizing for readability</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 94, 012320 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.94.012320</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent technological developments in the field of experimental quantum
annealing have made prototypical annealing optimizers with hundreds of qubits
commercially available. The experimental demonstration of a quantum speedup for
optimization problems has since then become a coveted, albeit elusive goal.
Recent studies have shown that the so far inconclusive results, regarding a
quantum enhancement, may have been partly due to the benchmark problems used
being unsuitable. In particular, these problems had inherently too simple a
structure, allowing for both traditional resources and quantum annealers to
solve them with no special efforts. The need therefore has arisen for the
generation of harder benchmarks which would hopefully possess the
discriminative power to separate classical scaling of performance with size,
from quantum. We introduce here a practical technique for the engineering of
extremely hard spin glass Ising-type problem instances that does not require
`cherry picking' from large ensembles of randomly generated instances. We
accomplish this by treating the generation of hard optimization problems itself
as an optimization problem, for which we offer a heuristic algorithm that
solves it. We demonstrate the genuine thermal hardness of our generated
instances by examining them thermodynamically and analyzing their energy
landscapes, as well as by testing the performance of various state-of-the art
algorithms on them. We argue that a proper characterization of the generated
instances offers a practical, efficient way to properly benchmark experimental
quantum annealers, as well as any other optimization algorithm.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04906</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04906</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hamanowicz</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pietrukowicz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Udalski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Mroz</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Soszynski</keyname><forenames>I.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Szymanski</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Skowron</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Poleski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Wyrzykowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kozlowski</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Pawlak</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Ulaczyk</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames><affiliation>The OGLE Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>OGLE Study of the Sagittarius Dwarf Spheroidal Galaxy and its M54
  Globular Cluster</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>published version, changed IDs of detected variable stars in
  comparison to the first version</comments><journal-ref>Acta Astronomica, 2016, 66, 197</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use the fundamental-mode RR Lyr-type variable stars (RRab) from OGLE-IV
survey to draw a 3D picture of the central part of the tidally disrupted
Sagittarius Dwarf Spheroidal (Sgr dSph) galaxy. We estimate the line-of-sight
thickness of the Sgr dSph stream to be FWHM_cen=2.42 kpc. Based on OGLE-IV
observations collected in seasons 2011-2014 we conduct a comprehensive study of
stellar variability in the field of the globular cluster M54 (NGC 6715)
residing in the core of this dwarf galaxy. Among the total number of 268
detected variable stars we report the identification of 174 RR Lyr stars, four
Type II Cepheids, 51 semi-regular variable red giants, three SX Phe-type stars,
18 eclipsing binary systems. Eighty-three variable stars are new discoveries.
The distance to the cluster determined from RRab stars is d_M54 = 26.7
+/-0.03(stat) +/-1.3(sys) kpc. From the location of RRab stars in the
period-amplitude (Bailey) diagram we confirm the presence of two old
populations, both in the cluster and the Sgr dSph stream.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.04926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.04926</id><created>2016-05-16</created><updated>2016-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Brian C.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Engler</keyname><forenames>E. E.</forenames><affiliation>Washburn Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kachelrie&#xdf;</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames><affiliation>NTNU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Melott</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames><affiliation>Univ. Kansas</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Overholt</keyname><forenames>A. C.</forenames><affiliation>MidAmerica Univ.</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Semikoz</keyname><forenames>D. V.</forenames><affiliation>U. Paris Diderot, Nat. Res. Nuclear U.</affiliation></author></authors><title>Terrestrial Effects Of Nearby Supernovae In The Early Pleistocene</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.EP physics.ao-ph physics.geo-ph q-bio.PE</categories><comments>Revised version accepted at ApJL</comments><journal-ref>The Astrophysical Journal Letters, Volume 826, Number 1, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/2041-8205/826/1/L3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Recent results have strongly confirmed that multiple supernovae happened at
distances ~100 pc consisting of two main events: one at 1.7 to 3.2 million
years ago, and the other at 6.5 to 8.7 million years ago. These events are said
to be responsible for excavating the Local Bubble in the interstellar medium
and depositing 60Fe on Earth and the Moon. Other events are indicated by
effects in the local cosmic ray (CR) spectrum. Given this updated and refined
picture, we ask whether such supernovae are expected to have had substantial
effects on the terrestrial atmosphere and biota. In a first cut at the most
probable cases, combining photon and cosmic ray effects, we find that a
supernova at 100 pc can have only a small effect on terrestrial organisms from
visible light and that chemical changes such as ozone depletion are weak.
However, tropospheric ionization right down to the ground due to the
penetration of $\geq$TeV cosmic rays will increase by nearly an order of
magnitude for thousands of years, and irradiation by muons on the ground and in
the upper ocean will increase 20-fold, which will approximately triple the
overall radiation load on terrestrial organisms. Such irradiation has been
linked to possible changes in climate and increased cancer and mutation rates.
This may be related to a minor mass extinction around the Pliocene-Pleistocene
boundary, and further research on the effects is needed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08007</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08007</id><created>2016-05-25</created><authors><author><keyname>Chiloyan</keyname><forenames>Vazrik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zeng</keyname><forenames>Lingping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huberman</keyname><forenames>Samuel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maznev</keyname><forenames>Alexei A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelson</keyname><forenames>Keith A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Gang</forenames></author></authors><title>Variational Approach to Solving the Spectral Boltzmann Transport
  Equation in Transient Thermal Grating for Thin Films</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>19 pages, 4 figures</comments><doi>10.1063/1.4955164</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The phonon Boltzmann transport equation (BTE) is widely utilized to study
non-diffusive thermal transport. We find a solution of the BTE in the thin film
transient thermal grating (TTG) experimental geometry by using a recently
developed variational approach with a trial solution supplied by the Fourier
heat conduction equation. We obtain an analytical expression for the thermal
decay rate that shows excellent agreement with Monte Carlo simulations. We also
obtain a closed form expression for the effective thermal conductivity that
demonstrates the full material property and heat transfer geometry dependence,
and recovers the limits of the one-dimensional TTG expression for very thick
films and the Fuchs-Sondheimer expression for very large grating spacings. The
results demonstrate the utility of the variational technique for analyzing
non-diffusive phonon-mediated heat transport for nanostructures in
multi-dimensional transport geometries, and will assist the probing of the mean
free path (MFP) distribution of materials via transient grating experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08027</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08027</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Castro</keyname><forenames>Leonardo Andreta</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brasil</keyname><forenames>Carlos Alexandre</forenames></author><author><keyname>Napolitano</keyname><forenames>Reginaldo de Jesus</forenames></author></authors><title>Elliptical orbits in the phase-space quantization</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><doi>10.1590/1806-9126-RBEF-2016-0067</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The energy levels of hydrogen-like atoms are obtained from the phase-space
quantization, one of the pillars of the old quantum theory, by three different
methods - (i) direct integration, (ii) Sommerfeld's original method, and (iii)
complex integration. The difficulties come from the imposition of elliptical
orbits to the electron, resulting in a variable radial component of the linear
momentum. Details of the calculation, which constitute a recurrent gap in
textbooks that deal with phase-space quantization, are shown in depth in an
accessible fashion for students of introductory quantum mechanics courses.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1605.08137</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1605.08137</id><created>2016-05-25</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Changmin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Katmis</keyname><forenames>Ferhat</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jarillo-Herrero</keyname><forenames>Pablo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moodera</keyname><forenames>Jagadeesh S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gedik</keyname><forenames>Nuh</forenames></author></authors><title>Direct measurement of proximity-induced magnetism at the interface
  between a topological insulator and a ferromagnet</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>26 pages, 7 figures Journal reference added; title modified</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 7, 12014 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12014</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  When a topological insulator (TI) is in contact with a ferromagnet, both time
reversal and inversion symmetries are broken at the interface. An energy gap is
formed at the TI surface, and its electrons gain a net magnetic moment through
short-range exchange interactions. Magnetic TIs can host various exotic quantum
phenomena, such as massive Dirac fermions, Majorana fermions, the quantum
anomalous Hall effect and chiral edge currents along the domain boundaries.
However, selective measurement of induced magnetism at the buried interface has
remained a challenge. Using magnetic second harmonic generation, we directly
probe both the in-plane and out-of-plane magnetizations induced at the
interface between the ferromagnetic insulator (FMI) EuS and the
three-dimensional TI Bi2Se3. Our findings not only allow characterizing
magnetism at the TI-FMI interface but also lay the groundwork for imaging
magnetic domains and domain boundaries at the magnetic TI surfaces.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04846</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04846</id><created>2016-06-08</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Saha</keyname><forenames>Subhajit</forenames></author></authors><title>Cosmological thermodynamics with Hawking temperature on the apparent
  horizon and Unruh temperature of the fluid: Some interesting consequences</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>6 pages; v2: Typos corrected, Identical to published version</comments><journal-ref>Europhysics Letters 114, 59001 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/114/59001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Thermodynamics on the cosmological apparent horizon of a flat
Friedmann-Lemaitre-Robertson-Walker metric has been investigated with
Bekenstein entropy and Hawking temperature on the horizon, and Unruh
temperature for the fluid inside the horizon. This temperature is experienced
by a radial comoving observer infinitesimally close to the horizon due to the
pressure exerted by the fluid bounded by the horizon. An expression for the
entropy of the fluid has been obtained which is found to be proportional to the
volume of the thermodynamic system which implies that the Unruh temperature of
the fluid is inconsistent with the holographic principle. Further, we have been
able to find an expression for the effective entropy of the system. Finally,
assuming a barotropic equation of state $p=w\rho$ ($w$ constant) for the fluid,
it has been shown that the generalized second law holds good for a non-phantom
w, while thermodynamic equilibrium is never possible for such a scenario.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.04957</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.04957</id><created>2016-06-15</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hill</keyname><forenames>Christopher T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Theorem: A Static Magnetic N-pole Becomes an Oscillating Electric N-pole
  in a Cosmic Axion Field</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.CO hep-th</categories><comments>2 pages</comments><report-no>FERMILAB-PUB-16-222-T</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show for the classical Maxwell equations, including the axion
electromagnetic anomaly source term, that a cosmic axion field induces an
oscillating electric N-moment for any static magnetic N-moment. This is a
straightforward result, accessible to anyone who has taken a first year
graduate course in electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06815</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06815</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2016-07-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Yong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>Chung-Ming</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of Elliptical Galaxies with Planetary Nebulae in Modified
  Newtonian Dynamics</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><report-no>MN-16-1414-MJ.R2</report-no><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1697</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of an elliptical galaxy within a couple of effective radii can
be probed effectively by stars. However, at larger distances planetary nebulae
(PNe) replace stars as the tracer of the dynamics. Making use of the motion of
PNe, Romanowsky et al. (2003) measured the dynamics of three luminous
elliptical galaxies (NGC821, NGC3379, and NGC4494) at large distances from the
galactic center. They found that little dark matter is needed up to 6 effective
radii. Milgrom &amp; Sanders (2003) showed that this result can be understood in
the framework of MOdified Newtonian Dynamics (MOND). As more data are available
in the past decade, we revisit this problem. We combine PNe data (up to 6{8
effective radii) and stellar data from SAURON of 7 elliptical galaxies,
including those 3 galaxies in Romanowsky et al. (2003) with updated data and 4
other galaxies which have not been analyzed before. We conclude that the
dynamics of these galaxies can be well explained by MOND.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07203</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07203</id><created>2016-06-23</created><authors><author><keyname>Weng</keyname><forenames>Yakui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Lingfang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dagotto</keyname><forenames>Elbio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dong</keyname><forenames>Shuai</forenames></author></authors><title>Inversion of ferrimagnetic magnetization by ferroelectric switching via
  a novel magnetoelectric coupling</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 037601 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.037601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although several multiferroic materials/heterostructures have been
extensively studied, finding strong magnetoelectric couplings for the electric
field control of the magnetization remains challenging. Here, a novel
interfacial magnetoelectric coupling based on three components (ferroelectric
dipole, magnetic moment, and antiferromagnetic order) is analytically
formulated. As an extension of carrier-mediated magnetoelectricity, the new
coupling is shown to induce an electric-magnetic hysteresis loop. Realizations
employing BiFeO$_3$ bilayers grown along the [$111$] axis are proposed. Without
involving magnetic phase transitions, the magnetization orientation can be
switched by the carrier modulation driven by the field effect, as confirmed
using first-principles calculations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.07656</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.07656</id><created>2016-06-24</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Sarita</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jindal</keyname><forenames>V. K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermal expansion in 2D honeycomb structures: Role of transverse phonon
  modes</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>18 pages, 37 references and 11 figures. arXiv admin note: text
  overlap with arXiv:1107.2469, arXiv:cond-mat/0412643 by other authors. Some
  change in the language an 3 new references added</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Graphene and its derivatives including hexagonal BN are notorious for their
large negative thermal expansion over a wide range of temperature which is
quite unusual. We attempt to analyze this unusual behavior on the basis of
character of the phonon modes. The linear thermal expansion coefficients (LTEC)
of two-dimensional honeycomb structured pure graphene, h-BN and B/N doped
graphene are studied using density functional perturbation theory (DFPT) under
quasi harmonic approximation. The dynamical matrix and the phonon frequencies
were calculated using VASP code in interface with phonopy code. The approach is
first applied to pure graphene to calculate thermal expansion. The results
agree with earlier calculations using similar approach. Thereafter we have
studied the effect of B/N doping on LTEC and also compared it with LTEC of h-BN
sheet. The LTEC of graphene is negative in the whole temperature range under
study (0-1000K) with a room temperature (RT) value of -3.51X10-6K-1. The value
of LTEC at room temperature becomes more negative with B/N doping in graphene
as well as for h-BN sheet. In order to get an insight into the cause of
negative thermal expansion, we have computed the contribution of individual
phonon modes of vibration. We notice that it is principally the ZA (transverse
acoustic) mode which is responsible for negative thermal expansion. It has been
concluded that transverse mode in 2D hexagonal lattices have an important role
to play in many of the thermo dynamical properties of 2D structures.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.09381</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.09381</id><created>2016-06-30</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gvozdikova</keyname><forenames>M. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ziman</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhitomirsky</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Helicity, anisotropies and their competition in a multiferroic magnet:
  insight from the phase diagram</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, as accepted</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 94, 020406(R) (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.94.020406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Motivated by the complex phase diagram of MnWO4, we investigate competition
between anisotropy, magnetic field, and helicity for the anisotropic
next-nearest-neighbor Heisenberg model. Apart from two competing exchanges,
which favor a spiral magnetic structure, the model features the bi-axial
single-ion anisotropy. The model is treated in the real-space mean-field
approximation and the phase diagram containing various incommensurate and
commensurate states is obtained for different field orientations. We discuss
similarities and differences of the theoretical phase diagram and the
experimental diagram of MnWO4.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01061</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01061</id><created>2016-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Taufour</keyname><forenames>Valentin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaluarachchi</keyname><forenames>Udhara S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khasanov</keyname><forenames>Rustem</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Manh Cuong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guguchia</keyname><forenames>Zurab</forenames></author><author><keyname>Biswas</keyname><forenames>Pabitra Kumar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonf&#xe1;</keyname><forenames>Pietro</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Renzi</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Stella K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mun</keyname><forenames>Eun Deok</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Hyunsoo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Furukawa</keyname><forenames>Yuji</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Cai-Zhuang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>Kai-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bud'ko</keyname><forenames>Sergey L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Canfield</keyname><forenames>Paul C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Ferromagnetic Quantum Critical Point Avoided by the Appearance of
  Another Magnetic Phase in LaCrGe$_3$ under Pressure</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117 037207 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.037207</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The temperature-pressure phase diagram of the ferromagnet LaCrGe$_3$ is
determined for the first time from a combination of magnetization,
muon-spin-rotation and electrical resistivity measurements. The ferromagnetic
phase is suppressed near $2.1$~GPa, but quantum criticality is avoided by the
appearance of a magnetic phase, likely modulated, AFM$_Q$. Our density
functional theory total energy calculations suggest a near degeneracy of
antiferromagnetic states with small magnetic wave vectors $Q$ allowing for the
potential of an ordering wave vector evolving from $Q=0$ to finite $Q$, as
expected from the most recent theories on ferromagnetic quantum criticality.
Our findings show that LaCrGe$_3$ is a very simple example to study this
scenario of avoided ferromagnetic quantum criticality and will inspire further
study on this material and other itinerant ferromagnets.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.01353</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.01353</id><created>2016-07-05</created><authors><author><keyname>Need</keyname><forenames>R. F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Isaac</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kirby</keyname><forenames>B. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Borchers</keyname><forenames>J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Stemmer</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilson</keyname><forenames>Stephen D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Interface-driven ferromagnetism within the quantum wells of a rare earth
  titanate superlattice</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>Phys. Rev. Lett. 117, 037205</report-no><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.117.037205</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we present polarized neutron reflectometry measurements exploring thin
film heterostructures comprised of a strongly correlated Mott state, GdTiO$_3$,
embedded with SrTiO$_3$ quantum wells. Our results reveal that the net
ferromagnetism inherent to the Mott GdTiO$_3$ matrix propagates into the
nominally nonmagnetic SrTiO$_3$ quantum wells and tracks the magnetic order
parameter of the host Mott insulating matrix. Beyond a well thickness of 5 SrO
layers, the magnetic moment within the wells is dramatically suppressed,
suggesting that quenched well magnetism comprises the likely origin of quantum
critical magnetotransport in this thin film architecture. Our data demonstrate
that the interplay between proximate exchange fields and polarity induced
carrier densities can stabilize extended magnetic states within SrTiO$_3$
quantum wells.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03297</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03297</id><created>2016-07-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>D. J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistics of the zeros of $L$-functions and arithmetic correlations</title><categories>math.NT math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>PhD thesis defended at the University of Bristol</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This thesis determines some of the implications of non-universal and emergent
universal statistics on arithmetic correlations and fluctuations of arithmetic
functions, in particular correlations amongst prime numbers and the variance of
the expected number of prime numbers over short intervals are generalised by
associating these concepts to $L$-functions arising from number theoretic
objects.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03568</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03568</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2016-07-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Run-wu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Chang-wen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ji</keyname><forenames>Wei-xiao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Ping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Pei-ji</forenames></author></authors><title>Bismuthylene Monolayer: A Promising Quantum Spin Hall Insulator with
  Large Band Gaps</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>18 Pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of first-principles calculations, we predict a new 2D QSH insulator
in the porous allotrope of Bismuth monolayer, bismuthylene, its dynamics
stability being confirmed by phonon spectrum and molecular dynamics
simulations. The analyses of electronic structures reveal that it is a native
QSH state with a gap much as large as 0.29 eV at the {\Gamma} point, which is
larger than the buckled (0.2 eV) and flattened (0.2 eV) bismuth, Bi4Br4 (0.18
eV), as well as stanene (0.1 eV), also more stable energetically than these
systems. Interestingly, the bismuthylene has tunable band gaps and nontrivial
band topology under strains within -6 - 5 % and electric fields up to 0.8
eV/{\AA}. Furthermore, a tight-binding model is constructed to explain the
low-energy physics behind band topology induced by spin-orbit coupling. We also
propose a quantum well by sandwiching bismuthylene between two BN sheets and
reveals that this structure remains topologically nontrivial with a sizeable
band gap. This findings on QSH effect of bismuthylene provide a viable platform
in new generation of dissipationless electronics and spintronics devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03828</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03828</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sardanashvily</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author></authors><title>In memoriam: Dmitri Ivanenko</title><categories>physics.hist-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>9 pages in Science Newsletter, Issue 1 (2014) 16</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dmitri Ivanenko, professor of Moscow State University, was one of the great
theoreticians of XX century, an author of the proton-neutron model of atomic
nucleus. In honor of the 110th Year Anniversary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03895</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03895</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Fu</keyname><forenames>Liye</forenames></author><author><keyname>Danescu-Niculescu-Mizil</keyname><forenames>Cristian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Lillian</forenames></author></authors><title>Tie-breaker: Using language models to quantify gender bias in sports
  journalism</title><categories>cs.CL physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>Best paper award at the IJCAI workshop on NLP Meets Journalism; 5
  pages, 2 figures; data and other info available at
  http://www.cs.cornell.edu/~liye/tennis.html</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Gender bias is an increasingly important issue in sports journalism. In this
work, we propose a language-model-based approach to quantify differences in
questions posed to female vs. male athletes, and apply it to tennis post-match
interviews. We find that journalists ask male players questions that are
generally more focused on the game when compared with the questions they ask
their female counterparts. We also provide a fine-grained analysis of the
extent to which the salience of this bias depends on various factors, such as
question type, game outcome or player rank.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03898</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03898</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>Y. G.</forenames><affiliation>YNNU</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>C. Y.</forenames><affiliation>YNAO</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>S. J.</forenames><affiliation>LPSUN</affiliation></author></authors><title>Bethe-Heitler cascades as a plausible origin of hard spectra in distant
  TeV blazars</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>17 pages, 5 figures, published in A&amp;A (2016A&amp;A...585A...8Z)</comments><doi>10.1051/0004-6361/201526703</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Context. Very high-energy (VHE) $\gamma$-ray measurements of distant TeV
blazars can be nicely explained by TeV spectra induced by ultra high-energy
cosmic rays.
  Aims. We develop a model for a plausible origin of hard spectra in distant
TeV blazars. Methods. In the model, the TeV emission in distant TeV blazars is
dominated by two mixed components. The first is the internal component with the
photon energy around 1 TeV produced by inverse Compton scattering of the
relativistic electrons on the synchrotron photons (SSC) with a correction for
extragalactic background light absorbtion and the other is the external
component with the photon energy more than 1 TeV produced by the cascade
emission from high-energy protons propagating through intergalactic space.
  Results. Assuming suitable model parameters, we apply the model to observed
spectra of distant TeV blazars of 1ES 0229+200. Our results show that 1) the
observed spectrum properties of 1ES 0229+200, especially the TeV $\gamma$-ray
tail of the observed spectra, could be reproduced in our model and 2) an
expected TeV $\gamma$-ray spectrum with photon energy $&gt;$1 TeV of 1ES 0229+200
should be comparable with the 50-hour sensitivity goal of the Cherenkov
Telescope Array (CTA) and the differential sensitivity curve for the one-year
observation with the Large High Altitude Air Shower Observatory (LHAASO).
  Conclusions. We argue that strong evidence for the Bethe-Heitler cascades
along the line of sight as a plausible origin of hard spectra in distant TeV
blazars could be obtained from VHE observations with CTA, LHAASO, HAWC, and
HiSCORE.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03902</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03902</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldman</keyname><forenames>N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Budich</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zoller</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Topological Quantum Matter with Ultracold Gases in Optical Lattices</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas cond-mat.mes-hall quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures. Author-produced version of a Progress Article
  published in Nature Physics</comments><journal-ref>Nature Physics 12, 639-645 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/nphys3803</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the discovery of topological insulators, many topological phases have
been predicted and realized in a range of different systems, providing both
fascinating physics and exciting opportunities for devices. And although new
materials are being developed and explored all the time, the prospects for
probing exotic topological phases would be greatly enhanced if they could be
realized in systems that were easily tuned. The flexibility offered by
ultracold atoms could provide such a platform. Here, we review the tools
available for creating topological states using ultracold atoms in optical
lattices, give an overview of the theoretical and experimental advances and
provide an outlook towards realizing strongly correlated topological phases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03920</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03920</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Shapourian</keyname><forenames>Hassan</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical renormalization group approach to the spin-boson model</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5 pages, 4 figures, and 2 appendices</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 032119 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.032119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a semi-analytical approach beyond the Born-Markov approximation to
study the quench dynamics of the spin-boson model in the strong-coupling regime
($\alpha\leq1/2$) for the Ohmic bath. The basic idea in our approach is to
write an effective time-dependent model for the dynamics of the system coupled
to the bosonic bath after integrating out high-frequency bath modes. By
applying this procedure to the Heisenberg equations of motion, we derive a set
of flow equations for the system parameters as a function of time. The final
flow equations look similar to those of the equilibrium renormalization-group
theory; however, in our derivation the scaling parameter is set by the real
time. We solve the equations of motion with time-dependent renormalized
parameters and show that the resulting dynamics is in decent agreement with the
exact NRG calculations as well as the non-interacting blip approximation that
is a well-known good solution in this limit.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03921</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03921</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Ryan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roberts</keyname><forenames>Kris O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tiesinga</keyname><forenames>Eite</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wade</keyname><forenames>Andrew C. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blakie</keyname><forenames>P. Blair</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deb</keyname><forenames>Amita B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kj&#xe6;rgaard</keyname><forenames>Niels</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple scattering dynamics of fermions at an isolated p-wave resonance</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 4 figures, link to supplementary material</comments><journal-ref>Nature Communications 7, 12069 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/ncomms12069</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The wavefunction for indistinguishable fermions is anti-symmetric under
particle exchange, which directly leads to the Pauli exclusion principle, and
hence underlies the structure of atoms and the properties of almost all
materials. In the dynamics of collisions between two indistinguishable fermions
this requirement strictly prohibits scattering into 90 degree angles. Here we
experimentally investigate the collisions of ultracold clouds fermionic
$\rm^{40}K$ atoms by directly measuring scattering distributions. With
increasing collision energy we identify the Wigner threshold for p-wave
scattering with its tell-tale dumb-bell shape and no $90^\circ$ yield. Above
this threshold effects of multiple scattering become manifest as deviations
from the underlying binary p-wave shape, adding particles either isotropically
or axially. A shape resonance for $\rm^{40}K$ facilitates the separate
observation of these two processes. The isotropically enhanced multiple
scattering mode is a generic p-wave threshold phenomenon, while the axially
enhanced mode should occur in any colliding particle system with an elastic
scattering resonance.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03923</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03923</id><created>2016-04-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Kruglov</keyname><forenames>S. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonlinear Electromagnetic Fields As a Source of Universe Acceleration</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>20 pages, 4 figures, to appear in IJMPA</comments><doi>10.1142/S0217751X16500585</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A model of nonlinear electromagnetic fields with a dimensional parameter
$\beta$ is proposed. From PVLAS experiment the bound on the parameter $\beta$
was obtained. Electromagnetic fields are coupled with the gravitation field and
we show that the universe accelerates due to nonlinear electromagnetic fields.
The magnetic universe is considered and the stochastic magnetic field is a
background. After inflation the universe decelerates and approaches to the
radiation era. The range of the scale factor, when the causality of the model
and a classical stability take place, was obtained. The spectral index, the
tensor-to-scalar ratio, and the running of the spectral index were estimated
which are in approximate agreement with the PLANCK, WMAP, and BICEP2 data.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03926</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03926</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Alexander M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Alpha A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perkin</keyname><forenames>Susan</forenames></author></authors><title>The Electrostatic Screening Length in Concentrated Electrolytes
  Increases with Concentration</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>This document is the unedited authors' version of a Submitted Work
  that was subsequently accepted for publication in the Journal of Physical
  Chemistry Letters, copyright American Chemical Society, after peer review. To
  access the final edited and published work see
  http://pubsdc3.acs.org/articlesonrequest/AOR-EW6FuIC6wIh6D9qqEeHD</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 2016, 7, 2157-2163</journal-ref><doi>10.1021/acs.jpclett.6b00867</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  According to classical electrolyte theories interactions in dilute (low ion
density) electrolytes decay exponentially with distance, with the Debye
screening length the characteristic length-scale. This decay length decreases
monotonically with increasing ion concentration, due to effective screening of
charges over short distances. Thus within the Debye model no long-range forces
are expected in concentrated electrolytes. Here we reveal, using experimental
detection of the interaction between two planar charged surfaces across a wide
range of electrolytes, that beyond the dilute (Debye-Huuckel) regime the
screening length increases with increasing concentration. The screening lengths
for all electrolytes studied - including aqueous NaCl solutions, ionic liquids
diluted with propylene carbonate, and pure ionic liquids - collapse onto a
single curve when scaled by the dielectric constant. This non-monotonic
variation of the screening length with concentration, and its generality across
ionic liquids and aqueous salt solutions, demonstrates an important
characteristic of concentrated electrolytes of substantial relevance from
biology to energy storage.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03929</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03929</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Goldsmith</keyname><forenames>K. J. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pittard</keyname><forenames>J. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>The interaction of a magnetohydrodynamical shock with a filament</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>30 pages, 42 figures, accepted by MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS 461 (2016) 578</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1365</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present 3D magnetohydrodynamic numerical simulations of the adiabatic
interaction of a shock with a dense, filamentary cloud. We investigate the
effects of various filament lengths and orientations on the interaction using
different orientations of the magnetic field, and vary the Mach number of the
shock, the density contrast of the filament, and the plasma beta, in order to
determine their effect on the evolution and lifetime of the filament. We find
that in a parallel magnetic field filaments have longer lifetimes if they are
orientated more 'broadside' to the shock front, and that an increase in the
density contrast hastens the destruction of the cloud, in terms of the modified
cloud-crushing time-scale, tcs. The combination of a mild shock and a
perpendicular or oblique field provides the best condition for extending the
life of the filament, with some filaments able to survive almost indefinitely
since they are cocooned by the magnetic field. A high value for the density
contrast does not initiate large turbulent instabilities in either the
perpendicular or oblique field cases but rather draws the filament out into
long tendrils which may eventually fragment. In addition, flux ropes are only
formed in parallel magnetic fields. The length of the filament is, however, not
as important for the evolution and destruction of a filament.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03935</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03935</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Sunds&#xf8;y</keyname><forenames>P&#xe5;l</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fjeldberg</keyname><forenames>Egil</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Computing: Linear Optics Implementations</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>93 pages, 15 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  One of the main problems that optical quantum computing has to overcome is
the efficient construction of two-photon gates. Theoretically these gates can
be realized using Kerr-nonlinearities, but the techniques involved are
experimentally very difficult. We therefore employ linear optics with
projective measurements to generate these non-linearities. The downside is that
the measurement-induced nonlinearities achieved with linear optics are less
versatile and the success rate can be quite low. This project is mainly the
result of a literature study but also a theoretical work on the physics behind
quantum optical multiports which is essential for realizing two-photon gates.
By applying different postcorrection techniques we increase the probability of
success in a modifed non-linear sign shift gate which is foundational for the
two photon controlled-NOT gate. We prove that it's not possible to correct the
states by only using a single beam splitter. We show that it might be possible
to increase the probability of success using a more complex setup with at least
two error-correcting beam splitters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03947</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03947</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Kai</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Jing Ping</forenames></author></authors><title>Symbolic Representation and Classification of N=1 Supersymmetric
  Evolutionary Equations</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>24 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We extend the symbolic representation to the ring of N=1 supersymmetric
differential polynomials, and demonstrate that operations on the ring, such as
the super derivative, Frechet derivative and super commutator, can be carried
out in the symbolic way. Using the symbolic representation, we classify scalar
$\lambda$-homogeneous N=1 supersymmetric evolutionary equations with nonzero
linear term when $\lambda&gt;0$ for arbitrary order and give a comprehensive
description of all such integrable equations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03951</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03951</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>Hao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nguyen</keyname><forenames>Ariana E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alvillar</keyname><forenames>Sahar N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Empante</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bartels</keyname><forenames>Ludwig</forenames></author><author><keyname>Feng</keyname><forenames>Philip X. -L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Large-Scale Arrays of Single- and Few-Layer MoS2 Nanomechanical
  Resonators</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>14 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nanoscale 8, 10677-10685 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/c6nr01118g</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on fabrication of large-scale arrays of suspended molybdenum
disulfide (MoS2) atomic layers, as two-dimensional (2D) MoS2 nanomechanical
resonators. We employ a water-assisted lift-off process to release chemical
vapor deposited (CVD) MoS2 atomic layers from a donor substrate, followed by an
all-dry transfer onto microtrench arrays. The resultant large arrays of
suspended single- and few-layer MoS2 drumhead resonators (0.5 to 2um in
diameter) offer fundamental resonances (f_0) in the very high frequency (VHF)
band (up to ~120MHz) and excellent figures-of-merit up to f_0*Q ~ 3*10^10Hz. A
stretched circular diaphragm model allows us to estimate low pre-tension levels
of typically ~15mN/m in these devices. Compared to previous approaches, our
transfer process features high yield and uniformity with minimal liquid and
chemical exposure (only involving DI water), resulting in high-quality MoS2
crystals and exceptional device performance and homogeneity; and our process is
readily applicable to other 2D materials.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03964</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03964</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Arlee V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smith</keyname><forenames>Jesse J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Do</keyname><forenames>Binh T.</forenames></author></authors><title>Thermo-optic and thermal expansion coefficients of RTP and KTP crystals
  over 300-350 K</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>12 pages, 5 figures, 9 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report new measurements of the thermal expansion and thermo-optic
coefficients of RbTiOPO$_4$ (RTP) and KTiOPO$_4$ (KTP) crystals over the
temperature range 300-350 K. For RTP/KTP our coefficients of linear thermal
expansion at 305 K are: $\alpha_x=9.44/7.88\times 10^{-6}$/K,
$\alpha_y=12.49/9.48\times 10^{-6}$/K, $\alpha_z=-4.16/0.02\times 10^{-6}$/K.
Our normalized thermo-optic coefficients $\beta=(1/n)dn/dT$ at 632.8 nm and 305
K are: $\beta_x=5.39/3.78\times 10^{-6}$/K, $\beta_y=7.11/5.24\times
10^{-6}$/K, $\beta_z=12.35/9.34\times 10^{-6}$/K.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03978</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03978</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Klibanov</keyname><forenames>Michael V.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uniqueness of a phaseless inverse scattering problem for the generalized
  3-D Helmholtz equation</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An inverse scattering problems for the 3-D generalized Helmholtz equation is
considered. Only the modulus of the complex valued scattered wave field is
assumed to be measured and the phase is not measured. Uniqueness theorem is
proved.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03980</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03980</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Currie</keyname><forenames>Thayne</forenames><affiliation>NAOJ/Subaru Telescope</affiliation></author></authors><title>HR 8799: The Benchmark Directly-Imaged Planetary System</title><categories>astro-ph.EP astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>10 pages, 3 figures, one Star Trek reference; modified and
  reformatted version of short review article in the July 2016 Star Formation
  Newsletter</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  HR 8799 harbors arguably the first and best-studied directly-imaged planets.
In this brief article, I describe how the HR 8799 planetary system is a
benchmark system for studying the atmospheres, orbital properties, dynamical
stability, and formation of young superjovian planets. Multi-wavelength
photometry and spectroscopy show that HR 8799 bcde appear to have thicker
clouds than do field brown dwarfs of similar effective temperatures and exhibit
evidence for non-equilibrium carbon chemistry, features that are likely
connected to the planets' low surface gravities. Over 17 years of astrometric
data constrain the planets' orbits to not be face on but possibly in multiple
orbital resonances. At orbital separations of 15--70 au and with masses of
$\approx$ 5--7 $M_{\rm J}$, HR 8799 bcde probe the extremes of jovian planet
formation by core accretion: medium-resolution spectroscopy may provide clues
about these planets' formation conditions. Data from the next generation of 30
m-class telescopes should better constrain the planets' orbits, chemistry,
gravity, and formation history.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03983</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03983</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Tiantian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yi</keyname><forenames>Su</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Yunbo</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamics of a coupled spin vortex pair in dipolar spinor Bose-Einstein
  condensates</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>8 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 93, 053602 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.93.053602</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The collisional and magnetic field quench dynamics of a coupled spin-vortex
pair in dipolar spinor Bose-Einstein condensates in a double well potential are
numerically investigated in the mean field theory. Upon a sudden release of the
potential barrier the two layers of condensates collide with each other in the
trap center with the chirality of the vortex pair exchanged after each
collision, showing the typical signature of in-phase collision for the parallel
spin vortex phase, and out-of-phase collision for the antiparallel phase. When
quenching the transverse magnetic field, the vortex center in the
single-layered condensate starts to make a helical motion with oval-shaped
trajectories and the displacement of the center position is found to exhibit a
damped simple harmonic oscillation with an intrinsic frequency and damping
rate. The oscillation mode of the spin vortex pair may be tuned by the initial
magnetic field and the height of the Gaussian barrier, e.g. the gyrotropic
motions for parallel spin vortex pair are out of sync with each other in the
two layers, while those for the antiparallel pair exhibit a
double-helix-structure with the vortex centers moving opposite to each other
with the same amplitude.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03986</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03986</id><created>2016-07-13</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakraborty</keyname><forenames>Dipti</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dutta</keyname><forenames>Saumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gangopadhyay</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bhattacharyya</keyname><forenames>Abhijit</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative proton capture cross sections in the mass range $40-55$</title><categories>nucl-th astro-ph.HE astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures, accepted for publication in the journal Physical
  Review C</comments><journal-ref>Physical Review C 94, 015802 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.94.015802</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Proton capture cross sections in the energy range of astrophysical interest
for mass region 40-54 have been calculated in the Hauser-Feshbach formalism
with reaction code TALYS1.6. The density dependent M3Y effective
nucleon-nucleon interaction folded with target radial matter densities from
relativistic mean field approach is used to obtain the semi-microscopic optical
potential. A definite normalization of potential-well depths has been used over
the entire mass region. The $(p,\gamma)$ rates of some reactions, important in
the astrophysical scenario, are calculated using the potential in the relevant
mass region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04008</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04008</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Han</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Xingyu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author></authors><title>Multiple Staggered Mesh Ewald: Boosting the Accuracy of the Smooth
  Particle Mesh Ewald Method</title><categories>physics.comp-ph physics.chem-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The smooth particle mesh Ewald (SPME) method is the standard method for
computing the electrostatic interactions in the molecular simulations. In this
work, the multiple staggered mesh Ewald (MSME) method is proposed to boost the
accuracy of the SPME method. Unlike the SPME that achieves higher accuracy by
refining the mesh, the MSME improves the accuracy by averaging the standard
SPME forces computed on, e.g. $M$, staggered meshes. We prove, from theoretical
perspective, that the MSME is as accurate as the SPME, but uses $M^2$ times
less mesh points in a certain parameter range. In the complementary parameter
range, the MSME is as accurate as the SPME with twice of the interpolation
order. The theoretical conclusions are numerically validated both by a uniform
and uncorrelated charge system, and by a three-point-charge water system that
is widely used as solvent for the bio-macromolecules.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04019</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04019</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Feng-Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wenlin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Chui-Ping</forenames></author></authors><title>Strong coupling between two spin ensembles via a large Josephson
  junction</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We propose a method to achieve strong coupling between a spin ensemble and a
large Josephson junctions (LJJ). Then, the strong coupling between two spin
ensembles can be induced by a LJJ. A non-adiabatic holonomic single-qubit
quantum gates is realized. Moreover, with the dispersive interaction between
the spin ensembles and the LJJ, the high-fidelity two-qubit phase gate can be
implemented with two spin ensembles within an operation time 0.41 ns and $\pi$
phase-swap gate can be realized within an operation time 103.11 ns with a high
fidelity greater than 99%.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04022</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04022</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Zych</keyname><forenames>Magdalena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pikovski</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author><author><keyname>Costa</keyname><forenames>Fabio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brukner</keyname><forenames>&#x10c;aslav</forenames></author></authors><title>General relativistic effects in quantum interference of &quot;clocks&quot;</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages, 5 figures; proceeding of 8th Symposium on Frequency
  Standards and Metrology, Potsdam 2015; discussion address questions asked at
  the Symposium</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Physics: Conference Series 723 (2016) 012044</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1742-6596/723/1/012044</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Quantum mechanics and general relativity have been each successfully tested
in numerous experiments. However, the regime where both theories are jointly
required to explain physical phenomena remains untested by laboratory
experiments, and is also not fully understood by theory. This contribution
reviews recent ideas for a new type of experiments: quantum interference of
&quot;clocks&quot;, which aim to test novel quantum effects that arise from time
dilation. &quot;Clock&quot; interference experiments could be realised with atoms or
photons in near future laboratory experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04035</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04035</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ziegler</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Eldik</keyname><forenames>Christopher</forenames></author></authors><title>Simulation of diffusive particle propagation and related TeV gamma-ray
  emission at the Galactic Center</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>In Proceedings of the 34th International Cosmic Ray Conference
  (ICRC2015), The Hague, The Netherlands</comments><journal-ref>PoS(ICRC2015)914</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Observations of the Galactic Center (GC) region in very-high-energy (VHE,
&gt;100 GeV) gamma rays, conducted with the High Energy Stereoscopic System
(H.E.S.S.), led to the detection of an extended region of diffuse gamma-ray
emission in 2006. To date, the exact origin of this emission has remained
unclear, although a tight spatial correlation between the density distribution
of the molecular material of the Central Molecular Zone (CMZ) and the
morphology of the observed gamma-ray excess points towards a hadronic
production scenario. In this proceeding, we present a numerical study of the
propagation of high-energy cosmic rays (CRs) through a turbulent environment
such as the GC region. In our analysis, we derive an energy-dependent
parametrization for the diffusion coefficient which we use for our simulation
of the diffuse gamma-ray emission at the GC. Assuming that hadronic CRs have
been released by a single impulsive event at the center of our Galaxy, we probe
the question whether or not the interaction processes of the diffusing hadrons
with ambient matter can explain the observed diffuse gamma-ray excess. Our
results disfavor this scenario, as our analysis indicates that the diffusion
process is, on timescales compared to the typical proton lifetime at the GC
region, too slow to explain the extension of the observed emission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04057</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04057</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Liao</keyname><forenames>Longguang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhao</keyname><forenames>Yu-Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Zexian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Xiaobao</forenames></author></authors><title>Minimum Vertex-type Sequence Indexingfor Clusters on Square Lattice</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An effective indexing scheme for clusters that enables fast structure
comparison and congruence check is desperately desirable in the field of
mathematics, artificial intelligence, materials science, etc. Here we introduce
the concept of minimum vertex-type sequence for the indexing of clusters on
square lattice, which contains a series of integers each labeling the vertex
type of an atom. The minimum vertex-type sequence is orientation independent,
and it builds a one-to-one correspondence with the cluster. By using minimum
vertex-type sequence for structural comparison and congruence check, only one
type of data is involved, and the largest amount of data to be compared is n
pairs, n is the cluster size. In comparison with traditional coordinate-based
methods and distance-matrix methods, the minimum vertex-type sequence indexing
scheme has many other remarkable advantages. Furthermore, this indexing scheme
can be easily generalized to clusters on other high-symmetry lattices. Our work
can facilitate cluster indexing and searching in various situations, it may
inspire the search of other practical indexing schemes for handling clusters of
large sizes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04060</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04060</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Sa&#xdf;mannshausen</keyname><forenames>Heiner</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deiglmayr</keyname><forenames>Johannes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Merkt</keyname><forenames>Fr&#xe9;d&#xe9;ric</forenames></author></authors><title>Long-range Rydberg molecules, Rydberg macrodimers and Rydberg aggregates
  in an ultracold Cs gas</title><categories>physics.atom-ph quant-ph</categories><comments>28 pages, 11 figures, submitted to EPJ ST</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an overview of our recent investigations of long-range
interactions in an ultracold Cs Rydberg gas. These interactions are studied by
high-resolution photoassociation spectroscopy, using excitation close to
one-photon transitions into $n$p$_{3/2}$ Rydberg states with pulsed and
continuous-wave ultraviolet laser radiation, and lead to the formation of
long-range Cs$_2$ molecules. We observe two types of molecular resonances. The
first type originates from the correlated excitation of two atoms into
Rydberg-atom-pair states interacting at long range via multipole-multipole
interactions. The second type results from the interaction of one atom excited
to a Rydberg state with one atom in the electronic ground state. Which type of
resonances is observed in the experiments depends on the laser intensity and
frequency and on the pulse sequences used to prepare the Rydberg states. We
obtain insights into both types of molecular resonances by modelling the
interaction potentials, using a multipole expansion of the long-range
interaction for the first type of resonances and a Fermi-contact
pseudo-potential for the second type of resonances. We analyse the relation of
these long-range molecular resonances to molecular Rydberg states and ion-pair
states, and discuss their decay channels into atomic and molecular ions. In
experiments carried out with a two-colour two-photon excitation scheme, we
observe a large enhancement of Rydberg-excitation probability, which we
interpret as a saturable autocatalytic antiblockade phenomenon.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04084</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04084</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Yin</keyname><forenames>Mei</forenames></author></authors><title>Phase transitions in edge-weighted exponential random graphs</title><categories>math.PR cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>17 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The exponential family of random graphs represents an important and
challenging class of network models. Despite their flexibility, conventionally
used exponential random graphs have one shortcoming. They cannot directly model
weighted networks as the underlying probability space consists of simple graphs
only. Since many substantively important networks are weighted, this limitation
is especially problematic. We extend the existing exponential framework by
proposing a generic common distribution for the edge weights and rigorously
analyze the associated phase transitions and critical phenomena. We then apply
these general results to get concrete answers in exponential random graph
models where the edge weights are uniformly distributed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04087</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04087</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Manikandan</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Senthilvelan</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraenkel</keyname><forenames>R. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Amplification of matter rogue waves and breathers in
  quasi-two-dimensional Bose-Einstein condensates</title><categories>nlin.SI nlin.PS</categories><comments>16 pages, Published in Eur. Phys. J. B</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. B (2016) 89: 30</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjb/e2015-60936-0</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We construct rogue wave and breather solutions of a quasi-two-dimensional
Gross-Pitaevskii equation with a time-dependent interatomic interaction and
external trap. We show that the trapping potential and an arbitrary functional
parameter that present in the similarity transformation should satisfy a
constraint for the considered equation to be integrable and yield the desired
solutions. We consider two different forms of functional parameters and
investigate how the density of the rogue wave and breather profiles vary with
respect to these functional parameters. We also construct vector localized
solutions of a two coupled quasi-two-dimensional Bose-Einstein condensate
system. We then investigate how the vector localized density profiles modify in
the constant density background with respect to the functional parameters. Our
results may help to manipulate matter rogue waves experimentally in the
two-dimensional Bose-Einstein condensate systems.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04106</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04106</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Atemkeng</keyname><forenames>M. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>O. M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tasse</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Foster</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonas</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Using baseline-dependent window functions for data compression and
  field-of-interest shaping in radio interferometry</title><categories>astro-ph.IM</categories><doi>10.1093/mnras/stw1656</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In radio interferometry, observed visibilities are intrinsically sampled at
some interval in time and frequency. Modern interferometers are capable of
producing data at very high time and frequency resolution; practical limits on
storage and computation costs require that some form of data compression be
imposed. The traditional form of compression is a simple averaging of the
visibilities over coarser time and frequency bins. This has an undesired side
effect: the resulting averaged visibilities &quot;decorrelate&quot;, and do so
differently depending on the baseline length and averaging interval. This
translates into a non-trivial signature in the image domain known as
&quot;smearing&quot;, which manifests itself as an attenuation in amplitude towards
off-centre sources. With the increasing fields of view and/or longer baselines
employed in modern and future instruments, the trade-off between data rate and
smearing becomes increasingly unfavourable. In this work we investigate
alternative approaches to low-loss data compression. We show that averaging of
the visibility data can be treated as a form of convolution by a boxcar-like
window function, and that by employing alternative baseline-dependent window
functions a more optimal interferometer smearing response may be induced. In
particular, we show improved amplitude response over a chosen field of
interest, and better attenuation of sources outside the field of interest. The
main cost of this technique is a reduction in nominal sensitivity; we
investigate the smearing vs. sensitivity trade-off, and show that in certain
regimes a favourable compromise can be achieved. We show the application of
this technique to simulated data from the Karl G. Jansky Very Large Array (VLA)
and the European Very-long-baseline interferometry Network (EVN).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04116</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Heeg</keyname><forenames>K. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keitel</keyname><forenames>C. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Evers</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Inducing and detecting collective population inversions of M\&quot;ossbauer
  nuclei</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Up to now, experiments involving M\&quot;ossbauer nuclei driven by x-rays have
been restricted to the low-excitation regime. Here, a setup is proposed which
promises significant excitation, ideally exceeding full inversion of the
nuclear ensemble, at x-ray light sources under construction. We further
introduce a method to experimentally verify such inversions, in which
population inversions manifest themselves in symmetry flips of suitably
recorded spectra. It neither requires per-shot spectra of the incoming x-ray
pulses, nor absolute measurements of the scattered light intensity.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04123</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04123</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Dirkes</keyname><forenames>Alain</forenames></author></authors><title>Degravitation, Orbital Dynamics and the Effective Barycentre</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>34 pages, 4 figures. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1604.06016</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article we present a particular theory of gravity in which Einstein's
field equations are modified by promoting Newton's constant $G$ to a covariant
differential operator $G_\Lambda(\Box_g)$. The general idea was obviously
outlined for the first time in [13-16] and originates from the quest of finding
a mechanism that is able to degravitate the vacuum energy on cosmological
scales. We suggest in this manuscript a precise covariant coupling model which
acts like a high-pass filter with a macroscopic distance filter scale
$\sqrt{\Lambda}$. In the context of this specific theory of gravity we review
some cosmological aspects before we briefly recall the effective relaxed
Einstein equations outlined for the first time in [1]. We present a general
procedure to determine the gravitational potentials for a far away wave zone
field point. Moreover we work out the modified orbital dynamics of a
binary-system as well as the effective 1.5 post-Newtonian barycentre for a
generic $n$-body system. We notice that it is always possible to recover the
corresponding general relativistic results in the limit of vanishing nonlocal
modification parameters.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04129</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04129</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chiodaroli</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author></authors><title>Simplifying amplitudes in Maxwell-Einstein and Yang-Mills-Einstein
  supergravities</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>24 pages, PDFLaTex, a later version of this review is to appear as a
  contribution to an edited volume</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article reviews recent progress in formulating double-copy constructions
for scattering amplitudes in supergravity theories with N=2 supersymmetry in
five and four spacetime dimensions. Particular attention is devoted to infinite
families of Maxwell-Einstein theories with symmetric and homogeneous target
spaces and to Yang-Mills-Einstein theories with compact gauge groups. Extension
of the construction to theories with spontaneously-broken gauge symmetry is
also discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04139</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04139</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Benetazzo</keyname></author><author><keyname>A.</keyname></author><author><keyname>Gamba</keyname></author><author><keyname>M.</keyname></author><author><keyname>Barbariol</keyname></author><author><keyname>F</keyname></author></authors><title>Unseeded Large Scale PIV measurements accounting for capillary-gravity
  waves phase speed</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Large Scale Particle Image Velocimetry (LSPIV) is widely recognized as a
reliable method to measure water surface velocity field in open channels and
rivers. LSPIV technique is based on a camera view that frames the water surface
in a sequence, and image-processing methods to compute water surface
displacements between consecutive frames. Using LSPIV, high flow velocities, as
for example flood conditions, were accurately measured, whereas determinations
of low flow velocities is more challenging, especially in absence of floating
seeding transported by the flow velocity. In fact, in unseeded conditions,
typical surface features dynamics must be taken into account: besides surface
structures convected by the current, capillary-gravity waves travel in all
directions, with their own dynamics. Discrimination between all these phenomena
is here discussed, providing a new method to distinguish and to correct
unseeded LSPIV measurements associated with wavy structures, accounting for
their phase speed magnitude and direction. This has been done measuring
wavenumber vectors by using the same images exploited for PIV analysis. All
measurements are performed without any flow seeding and in total absence of
suspended materials, using the specular reflection of the water surface as a
key marker. Results obtained at low-flow regimes in a straight concrete-made
rectangular-section channel and in a river are satisfying, especially if
compared to those obtained from classic LSPIV application without
discrimination and correction. Moreover, a novel simple and safe procedure to
orthorectify images is here presented.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04154</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Ameri</keyname><forenames>Vahid</forenames></author></authors><title>Using quantum friction to synchronize rotating bodies</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Proposing a combined system of a nanoparticle and a plane surface in the
presence of electromagnetic vacuum fluctuations, the electromagnetic and medium
fields have been quantized. Quantum friction of nanoparticle due to the
presence of plane surface and also electromagnetic vacuum has been discussed.
The possibility of synchronizing rotating bodies through the quantum friction
between them are investigated. It has been shown that there is a significant
connection between the synchronization of the rotating bodies and their quantum
friction.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04185</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04185</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Atapin</keyname><forenames>Kirill</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fabrika</keyname><forenames>Sergei</forenames></author></authors><title>X-ray Variability of SS 433: Evidence for Supercritical Accretion</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>16 pages, 8 figures, published in Astronomy Letters</comments><journal-ref>Astron. Lett., 42, 517 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S106377371607001X</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the X-ray variability of SS433 based on data from the ASCA
observatory and the MAXI and RXTE/ASM monitoring missions. Based on the ASCA
data, we have constructed the power spectrum of SS433 in the frequency range
from $10^{-6}$ to 0.1 Hz, which confirms the presence of a flat portion
(flat-topped noise) in the spectrum at frequencies $3\times 10^{-5}$ -
$10^{-3}$ Hz. The periodic variability (precession, nutation, eclipses) begins
to dominate significantly over the stochastic variability at lower frequencies,
which does not allow the stochastic variability to be studied reliably. The
best agreement with the observations is reached by the model with the flat
portion extending to $9.5\times10^{-6}$ Hz and a power-law spectrum with index
of 2.6 below that frequency. The jet nutation with a period of about three days
suggests that the time for the passage of material through the disk is less
than this value. Therefore, at frequencies below $4\times10^{-6}$ Hz, the power
spectrum probably does not reflect the disk structure. It may depend on other
factors, for example, a variable mass accretion rate supplied by the donor. The
flat portion may arise from a rapid decrease in the viscous time in the
supercritical or radiative disk zones. It could be related to the variability
of the X-ray jets that are formed in the supercritical region.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04193</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04193</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Mahmoud</keyname><forenames>Eman</forenames></author><author><keyname>Takey</keyname><forenames>Ali</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shoukry</keyname><forenames>Amin</forenames></author></authors><title>Spectral Clustering for Optical Confirmation and Redshift Estimation of
  X-ray Selected Galaxy Cluster Candidates in the SDSS Stripe 82</title><categories>astro-ph.GA cs.OH</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures, 3 tables, 1 appendix, Accepted by Journal of
  &quot;Astronomy and Computing&quot;</comments><report-no>ASCOM163</report-no><doi>10.1016/j.ascom.2016.07.001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a galaxy cluster finding algorithm based on spectral clustering
technique to identify optical counterparts and estimate optical redshifts for
X-ray selected cluster candidates. As an application, we run our algorithm on a
sample of X-ray cluster candidates selected from the third XMM-Newton
serendipitous source catalog (3XMM-DR5) that are located in the Stripe 82 of
the Sloan Digital Sky Survey (SDSS). Our method works on galaxies described in
the color-magnitude feature space. We begin by examining 45 galaxy clusters
with published spectroscopic redshifts in the range of 0.1 to 0.8 with a median
of 0.36. As a result, we are able to identify their optical counterparts and
estimate their photometric redshifts, which have a typical accuracy of 0.025
and agree with the published ones. Then, we investigate another 40 X-ray
cluster candidates (from the same cluster survey) with no redshift information
in the literature and found that 12 candidates are considered as galaxy
clusters in the redshift range from 0.29 to 0.76 with a median of 0.57. These
systems are newly discovered clusters in X-rays and optical data. Among them 7
clusters have spectroscopic redshifts for at least one member galaxy.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04195</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04195</id><created>2016-07-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Zanzi</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>The cosmological constant problem in heterotic-M-theory and the orbifold
  of time</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>20 pages. Submitted to Mod. Phys. Lett. A</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Chameleon fields are quantum fields with an increasing mass as a function of
the matter density of the environment. Recently chameleon fields have been
exploited to solve the cosmological constant problem in the Modified Fujii's
Model - MFM [Phys Rev D82 (2010) 044006]. However, gravity has been treated
basically at a semiclassical level in that paper. In this article the stringy
origin of the MFM is further discussed: as we will see, the MFM can be obtained
from heterotic-M-theory. Consequently, a quantum description of gravity is
obtained and the theory is finite because we choose the string mass as our UV
cut-off. This stringy origin of the MFM creates stronger theoretical grounds
for our solution to the cosmological constant problem. In our analysis, time
will be compactified on a $S^1/Z_2$ orbifold and this peculiar compactification
of time has a number of consequences. For example, as we will see, quantum
gravity and a quantum gauge theory are actually the same theory in the sense
that gravity is the time-evolution of a gauge theory. This might be the key to
obtain a non-approximated stabilizing potential for the dilaton in the string
frame. In this paper we will further discuss the non-equivalence of different
conformal frames at the quantum level. As we will see, in our approach we use
basically a unique conformal frame: the frame where the masses of particles are
field dependent. A word of caution is necessary: we do not take into account
massive string states and IR divergences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04216</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Massri</keyname><forenames>Karim</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the NA48/2 collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Searches for Lepton Number Violation and resonances in the $K^{\pm} \to
  \pi\mu\mu$ decays at the NA48/2 experiment</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>8 pages. To be published in Rencontres de Moriond 2016 conference
  proceedings</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The NA48/2 experiment at CERN collected a large sample of charged kaon decays
into final states with multiple charged particles in 2003--2004. A new upper
limit on the rate of the lepton number violating decay $K^{\pm} \to \pi^{\mp}
\mu^{\pm} \mu^{\pm}$ obtained from this sample is reported:
$\mathcal{B}(K^{\pm} \to \pi^{\mp} \mu^{\pm} \mu^{\pm})&lt;8.6 \times 10^{-11}$ at
90\% CL. Searches for two-body resonances in the $K^{\pm} \to \pi\mu\mu$ decays
(including heavy neutral leptons~$N_4$ and inflatons~$\chi$) in the accessible
range of masses and lifetimes are also presented. In the absence of a signal,
upper limits are set on the products of branching ratios~$\mathcal{B}(K^{\pm}
\to \mu^{\pm} N_{4})\mathcal{B}(N_{4} \to \pi^{\mp}\mu^{\pm})$ and
$\mathcal{B}(K^{\pm} \to \pi^{\pm} \chi)\mathcal{B}(\chi \to \mu^{+}\mu^{-})$
as functions of the resonance mass and lifetime. These limits are in the
$10^{-10}-10^{-9}$ range for resonance lifetimes below 100~ps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04222</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04222</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Galakhov</keyname><forenames>Dmitry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moore</keyname><forenames>Gregory W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Comments On The Two-Dimensional Landau-Ginzburg Approach To Link
  Homology</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>77 pages, 12 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We describe rules for computing a homology theory of knots and links in
$\mathbb{R}^3$. It is derived from the theory of framed BPS states bound to
domain walls separating two-dimensional Landau-Ginzburg models with (2,2)
supersymmetry. We illustrate the rules with some sample computations, obtaining
results consistent with Khovanov homology. We show that of the two
Landau-Ginzburg models discussed in this context by Gaiotto and Witten one,
(the so-called Yang-Yang-Landau-Ginzburg model) does not lead to topological
invariants of links while the other, based on a model with target space equal
to the universal cover of the moduli space of $SU(2)$ magnetic monopoles, will
indeed produce a topologically invariant theory of knots and links.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04235</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Praszalowicz</keyname><forenames>Michal</forenames></author></authors><title>Saturation and geometrical scaling in small systems</title><categories>hep-ph nucl-th</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, talk presented at Excited QCD, Costa da Caparica,
  Portugal, March 6-12, 2016</comments><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Saturation and geometrical scaling (GS) of gluon distributions are a
consequence of the non-linear evolution equations of QCD. We argue that in pp
GS holds for the inelastic cross-section rather than for the multiplicity
distributions. We also discuss possible fluctuations of the proton saturation
scale in pA collisions at the LHC.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04238</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04238</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Xiang</keyname><forenames>Junsen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Cong</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sheng</keyname><forenames>Xianlei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Na</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cheng</keyname><forenames>Zhaohua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Qiang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Ziyu</forenames></author></authors><title>Criticality-Enhanced Magnetocaloric Effect in Quantum Spin Chain
  Material Copper Nitrate</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>14 pages, 9 + 4 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Low-dimensional quantum magnets, due to the existence of abundant exotic
quantum phases therein and experimental feasibilities in laboratories,
continues intriguing people in condensed matter physics. In this work, a
comprehensive study of Cu(NO$_3$)$_2$ $\cdot$ 2.5H$_2$O (copper nitrate
hemipentahydrate, CN), a spin chain material, is performed with multi-technique
approach including thermal tensor network (TTN) simulations, first-principles
calculations, as well as magnetization measurements in experiments. Employing a
cutting-edge TTN method developed in the present work, we determine the
couplings $J=5.13$ K, $\alpha=0.23(1)$ and Land\'e factors
$g_{\parallel}=2.31$, $g_{\perp}=2.14$ in an alternating Heisenberg
antiferromagnetic chain model, with which one can fit strikingly well the
magnetothermodynamic properties. Part of the fitted experimental data are
measured on the single-crystal CN specimens synthesized by us. Based on
first-principles calculations, we reveal explicitly the spin chain scenario in
CN by displaying the calculated electron density distributions, from which the
distinct superexchange paths are visualized. On top of that, we investigated
the magnetocaloric effect (MCE) in CN by calculating its isentropes and
magnetic Gr\&quot;ueisen parameter (GP). Prominent quantum-criticality-enhanced MCE
was uncovered, the TTN simulations are in good agreements with measured
isentropic lines in the sub-Kelvin region. We propose that CN is potentially a
very promising quantum critical coolant, due to the remarkably enhanced MCE
near both critical fields of moderate strengths as 2.87 and 4.08 T,
respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04249</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04249</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Joshi</keyname><forenames>Chaitanya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Irish</keyname><forenames>Elinor K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Spiller</keyname><forenames>Timothy P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generating strong squeezing in the dispersive regime of the quantum Rabi
  model</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 6 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a protocol to generate a large degree of squeezing of a boson
(light) field mode strongly coupled to a two-level system in the dispersive
regime. Our protocol exploits the strong dispersive coupling to introduce a
time dependent frequency change of the boson field. With an appropriately timed
sequence of sudden frequency changes, the quantum noise fluctuations in one
quadrature of the field can be reduced well below the standard quantum limit,
with a correspondingly increased uncertainty in the orthogonal quadrature. Even
in the presence of realistic noise and imperfections, the protocol should be
capable of generating substantial squeezing with present experimental
capabilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04250</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04250</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Cervantes-Cota</keyname><forenames>Jorge L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liebscher</keyname><forenames>D. -E.</forenames></author></authors><title>On constructing purely affine theories with matter</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>13 pages</comments><journal-ref>Gen. Relativ. Gravit. (2016) 48:108</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10714-016-2103-9</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore ways to obtain the very existence of a space-time metric from an
action principle that does not refer to it a priori. Although there are reasons
to believe that only a non-local theory can viably achieve this goal, we
investigate here local theories that start with Schroedinger's purely affine
theory [21], where he gave reasons to set the metric proportional to the Ricci
curvature aposteriori. When we leave the context of unified field theory, and
we couple the non-gravitational matter using some weak equivalence principle,
we can show that the propagation of shock waves does not define a lightcone
when the purely affine theory is local and avoids the explicit use of the Ricci
tensor in realizing the weak equivalence principle. When the Ricci tensor is
substituted for the metric, the equations seem to have only a very limited set
of solutions. This backs the conviction that viable purely affine theories have
to be non-local.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04252</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04252</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Levi</keyname><forenames>Michele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steinhoff</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Complete conservative dynamics for inspiralling compact binaries with
  spins at fourth post-Newtonian order</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>21 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this work we complete the spin dependent conservative dynamics of
inspiralling compact binaries at the fourth post-Newtonian order, and in
particular the recent derivation of the next-to-next-to-leading order
spin-squared interaction potential. We derive the physical equations of motion
of the position and the spin from a direct variation of the action. Further, we
derive the quadratic in spin Hamiltonians, as well as their expressions in the
center of mass frame. We construct the conserved integrals of motion, which
form the Poincare algebra. This construction provided a consistency check for
the validity of our result, which is crucial in particular in the current
absence of another independent derivation of the next-to-next-to-leading order
spin-squared interaction. Finally, we provide here the complete gauge invariant
relations among the binding energy, angular momentum, and orbital frequency of
an inspiralling binary with generic compact spinning components to the fourth
post-Newtonian order. These high post-Newtonian orders, in particular taking
into account the spins of the binary constituents, will enable to gain more
accurate information on the constituents from even more sensitive gravitational
wave detections to come.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04257</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04257</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Tabrizi</keyname><forenames>Amirhossein Molavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Knepley</keyname><forenames>Matthew G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bardhan</keyname><forenames>Jaydeep P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Generalizing The Mean Spherical Approximation as a Multiscale, Nonlinear
  Boundary Condition at the Solute--Solvent Interface</title><categories>math.NA physics.chem-ph q-bio.BM</categories><comments>14 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Molecular Physics, 2016</journal-ref><doi>10.1080/00268976.2016.1198503</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we extend the familiar continuum electrostatic model with a
perturbation to the usual macroscopic boundary condition. The perturbation is
based on the mean spherical approximation (MSA), to derive a multiscale
hydration-shell boundary condition (HSBC). We show that the HSBC/MSA model
reproduces MSA predictions for Born ions in a variety of polar solvents,
including both protic and aprotic solvents. Importantly, the HSBC/MSA model
predicts not only solvation free energies accurately but also solvation
entropies, which standard continuum electrostatic models fail to predict. The
HSBC/MSA model depends only on the normal electric field at the dielectric
boundary, similar to our recent development of an HSBC model for charge-sign
hydration asymmetry, and the reformulation of the MSA as a boundary condition
enables its straightforward application to complex molecules such as proteins.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04261</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04261</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Eunae</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kang</keyname><forenames>Jeong Won</forenames></author></authors><title>Molecular Dynamics Analysis of Graphene-Based Nanoelectromechanical
  Switch</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 3 figures, 229th ECS Meeting, accepted in ECS Transactions</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Here we present graphene-based nanoelectromechanical switch with the vertical
carbon nanotube electrode via classical molecular dynamics simulations. The
carbon nanotube is grown in the center of the square hole and the graphene
covers on the hole. The potential difference between the bottom of the hole and
the graphene is applied to deflect the graphene. By performing classical
molecular dynamic simulations, we investigate the electromechanical properties
of graphene-based nanoelectro- mechanical switch with carbon nanotube
electrode, which can be switched by the externally applied force. This
simulation work explicitly demonstrated that such devices are applicable to
nanoscale sensors and quantum computing, as well as ultra-fast-response
switching devices.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04262</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04262</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Wevers</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Torres</keyname><forenames>M. A. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jonker</keyname><forenames>P. G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wetuski</keyname><forenames>J. D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nelemans</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Steeghs</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maccarone</keyname><forenames>T. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heinke</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hynes</keyname><forenames>R. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Udalski</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kostrzewa-Rutkowska</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Groot</keyname><forenames>P. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gazer</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Szymanski</keyname><forenames>M. K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Britt</keyname><forenames>C. T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wyrzykowski</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Poleski</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of a high state AM CVn binary in the Galactic Bulge Survey</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in MNRAS Letters</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slw141</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report on the discovery of a hydrogen-deficient compact binary (CXOGBS
J175107.6-294037) belonging to the AM CVn class in the Galactic Bulge Survey.
Deep archival X-ray observations constrain the X-ray positional uncertainty of
the source to 0.57 arcsec, and allow us to uniquely identify the optical and UV
counterpart. Optical spectroscopic observations reveal the presence of broad,
shallow He i absorption lines while no sign of hydrogen is present, consistent
with a high state system. We present the optical lightcurve from Optical
Gravitational Lensing Experiment monitoring, spanning 15 years. It shows no
evidence for outbursts; variability is present at the 0.2 mag level on
timescales ranging from hours to weeks. A modulation on a timescale of years is
also observed. A Lomb-Scargle analysis of the optical lightcurves shows two
significant periodicities at 22.90 and 23.22 min. Although the physical
interpretation is uncertain, such timescales are in line with expectations for
the orbital and superhump periods. We estimate the distance to the source to be
between 0.5 - 1.1 kpc. Spectroscopic follow-up observations are required to
establish the orbital period, and to determine whether this source can serve as
a verification binary for the eLISA gravitational wave mission.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2016-07-15</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04263</id><created>2016-07-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Bressan</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Leucci</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panconesi</keyname><forenames>Alessandro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Raghavan</keyname><forenames>Prabhakar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Terolli</keyname><forenames>Erisa</forenames></author></authors><title>The Limits of Popularity-Based Recommendations, and the Role of Social
  Ties</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 9 figures, KDD 2016</comments><doi>10.1145/2939672.2939797</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we introduce a mathematical model that captures some of the
salient features of recommender systems that are based on popularity and that
try to exploit social ties among the users. We show that, under very general
conditions, the market always converges to a steady state, for which we are
able to give an explicit form. Thanks to this we can tell rather precisely how
much a market is altered by a recommendation system, and determine the power of
users to influence others. Our theoretical results are complemented by
experiments with real world social networks showing that social graphs prevent
large market distortions in spite of the presence of highly influential users.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
