<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<OAI-PMH xmlns="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/ http://www.openarchives.org/OAI/2.0/OAI-PMH.xsd">
<responseDate>2020-04-12T11:53:51Z</responseDate>
<request verb="ListRecords" until="2017-10-13" from="2017-10-13" metadataPrefix="arXiv" set="physics">http://export.arxiv.org/oai2</request>
<ListRecords>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:0711.0613</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>0711.0613</id><created>2007-11-05</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Birkandan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Newman-Penrose Calculator for Instanton Metrics</title><categories>gr-qc physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>13 pages. Matches the published version. The web page of the codes is
  changed as https://github.com/tbirkandan/NPInstanton</comments><journal-ref>Int.J.Mod.Phys.C19:1277,2008</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0129183108012807</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a Maple11+GRTensorII based symbolic calculator for instanton
metrics using Newman-Penrose formalism. Gravitational instantons are exact
solutions of Einstein's vacuum field equations with Euclidean signature. The
Newman-Penrose formalism, which supplies a toolbox for studying the exact
solutions of Einstein's field equations, was adopted to the instanton case and
our code translates it for the computational use.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1101.5507</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1101.5507</id><created>2011-01-28</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Nishant K.</forenames><affiliation>Nordita, KTH Royal Institute of Technology and Stockholm University, Sweden</affiliation><affiliation>Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research, G&#xf6;ttingen, Germany</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sridhar</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames><affiliation>Raman Research Institute, Bangalore, India</affiliation></author></authors><title>Plane shearing waves of arbitrary form: exact solutions of the
  Navier-Stokes equations</title><categories>astro-ph.GA physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures; version published in the European Physical
  Journal Plus</comments><report-no>NORDITA-2017-106</report-no><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132:403</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11659-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present exact solutions of the incompressible Navier-Stokes equations in a
background linear shear flow. The method of construction is based on Kelvin's
investigations into linearized disturbances in an unbounded Couette flow. We
obtain explicit formulae for all three components of a Kelvin mode in terms of
elementary functions. We then prove that Kelvin modes with parallel (though
time-dependent) wave vectors can be superposed to construct the most general
plane transverse shearing wave. An explicit solution is given, with any
specified initial orientation, profile and polarization structure, with either
unbounded or shear-periodic boundary conditions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1107.0619</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1107.0619</id><created>2011-07-04</created><authors><author><keyname>de Falco</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamascelli</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Dissipative dynamics of a spin system with three-body interaction</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theo. 44(32) 325303 (2011)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/44/32/325303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this note we explicitly solve the Lindblad equation for a system of three
spins with a three-body interaction, coupled to the environment by bath
operators that inject or absorb spin carriers. We exemplify the properties of
this solution in the context of a simple instance of Feynman's quantum computer
in which a two-qubit program line is executed, applying the $\sqrt{NOT}$
primitive to a one-qubit register.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.2565</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.2565</id><created>2012-12-11</created><authors><author><keyname>de Falco</keyname><forenames>Diego</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tamascelli</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author></authors><title>Noise-assisted quantum transport and computation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theo. 46(22) 225301 (2013)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/46/22/225301</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The transmission of an excitation along a spin chain can be hindered by the
presence of small fixed imperfections that create trapping regions where the
excitation may get caught (Anderson localization). A certain degree of noise,
ensuing from the interaction with a thermal bath, allows to overcome
localization (noise-assisted transport). In this paper we investigate the
relation between noise-assisted transport and (quantum) computation. In
particular we prove that noise does assist classical computation on a quantum
computing device but hinders the possibility of creating entanglement.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1212.6326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1212.6326</id><created>2012-12-27</created><updated>2013-04-26</updated><authors><author><keyname>Demidov</keyname><forenames>Denis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ahnert</keyname><forenames>Karsten</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupp</keyname><forenames>Karl</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gottschling</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Programming CUDA and OpenCL: A Case Study Using Modern C++ Libraries</title><categories>cs.MS cs.DC physics.comp-ph</categories><comments>21 pages, 4 figures, submitted to SIAM Journal of Scientific
  Computing and accepted</comments><doi>10.1137/120903683</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a comparison of several modern C++ libraries providing high-level
interfaces for programming multi- and many-core architectures on top of CUDA or
OpenCL. The comparison focuses on the solution of ordinary differential
equations and is based on odeint, a framework for the solution of systems of
ordinary differential equations. Odeint is designed in a very flexible way and
may be easily adapted for effective use of libraries such as Thrust, MTL4,
VexCL, or ViennaCL, using CUDA or OpenCL technologies. We found that CUDA and
OpenCL work equally well for problems of large sizes, while OpenCL has higher
overhead for smaller problems. Furthermore, we show that modern high-level
libraries allow to effectively use the computational resources of many-core
GPUs or multi-core CPUs without much knowledge of the underlying technologies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1304.4809</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1304.4809</id><created>2013-04-17</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gutfreund</keyname><forenames>Philipp</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maccarini</keyname><forenames>Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dennison</keyname><forenames>Andrew</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolff</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author></authors><title>The search for Nanobubbles by using specular and off-specular Neutron
  Reflectometry</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><doi>10.1021/acs.langmuir.6b02087</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We apply specular and off-specular neutron reflection at the hydrophobic
silicon/water interface to check for evidence of nanoscopic air bubbles whose
presence is claimed after an ad hoc procedure of solvent exchange. Nanobubbles
and/or a depletion layer at the hydrophobic/water interface have long been
discussed and generated a plethora of controversial scientific results. By
combining neutron reflectometry (NR), off-specular reflectometry (OSS) and
grazing incidence small angle neutron scattering (GISANS), we studied the
interface between hydrophobized silicon and heavy water before and after
saturation with nitrogen gas. Our specular reflectometry results can be
interpreted by assuming a sub-molecular sized depletion layer and the
off-specular measurements show no change with nitrogen super saturated water.
This picture is consistent with the assumption that, following the solvent
exchange, no additional nanobubbles are introduced at significant
concentrations (if present at all). Furthermore, we discuss the results, in
terms of the maximum surface coverage of nanobubbles that could be present on
the hydrophobic surface compatibly with the sensitivity limit of these
techniques.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1311.5100</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1311.5100</id><created>2013-11-20</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Waechtler</keyname><forenames>F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lima</keyname><forenames>A. R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pelster</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Low-Lying Excitation Modes of Trapped Dipolar Fermi Gases: From
  Collisionless to Hydrodynamic Regime</title><categories>cond-mat.quant-gas</categories><comments>Revised version including referee comments</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 043608 (2017)</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  By means of the Boltzmann-Vlasov kinetic equation we investigate dynamical
properties of a trapped, one-component Fermi gas at zero temperature, featuring
the anisotropic and long-range dipole-dipole interaction. To this end, we
determine an approximate solution by rescaling both space and momentum
variables of the equilibrium distribution, thereby obtaining coupled ordinary
differential equations for the corresponding scaling parameters. Based on
previous results on how the Fermi sphere is deformed in the hydrodynamic regime
of a dipolar Fermi gas, we are able to implement the relaxation-time
approximation for the collision integral. Then, we proceed by linearizing the
equations of motion around the equilibrium in order to study both the
frequencies and the damping of the low-lying excitation modes all the way from
the collisionless to the hydrodynamic regime. Our theoretical results are
expected to be relevant for understanding current experiments with trapped
dipolar Fermi gases.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1401.1278</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1401.1278</id><created>2014-01-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Tamascelli</keyname><forenames>Dario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zanetti</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author></authors><title>A quantum-walk-inspired adiabatic algorithm for graph isomorphism</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>10 pages, 5 figures</comments><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theo. 47(32) 325302 (2014)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/47/32/325302</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a 2-local quantum algorithm for graph isomorphism GI based on an
adiabatic protocol. By exploiting continuous-time quantum-walks, we are able to
avoid a mere diffusion over all possible configurations and to significantly
reduce the dimensionality of the visited space. Within this restricted space,
the graph isomorphism problem can be translated into the search of a satisfying
assignment to a 2-SAT formula without resorting to perturbation gadgets or
projective techniques. We present an analysis of the execution time of the
algorithm on small instances of the graph isomorphism problem and discuss the
issue of an implementation of the proposed adiabatic scheme on current quantum
computing hardware.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1409.2994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1409.2994</id><created>2014-09-10</created><updated>2014-12-19</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mintchev</keyname><forenames>Mihail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy transmutation in nonequilibrium quantum systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>Version to appear in Journal of Physics A: Mathematical and General</comments><report-no>IFUP-TH 9/2014, LAPTH-107/14</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48 (2015) 055003</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/5/055003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the particle and heat transport in quantum junctions with the
geometry of star graphs. The system is in a nonequilibrium steady state,
characterized by the different temperatures and chemical potentials of the heat
reservoirs connected to the edges of the graph. We explore the
Landauer-Buettiker state and its orbit under parity and time reversal
transformations. Both particle number and total energy are conserved in these
states. However the heat and chemical potential energy are in general not
separately conserved, which gives origin to a basic process of energy
transmutation among them. We study both directions of this process in detail,
introducing appropriate efficiency coefficients. For scale invariant
interactions in the junction our results are exact and explicit. They cover the
whole parameter space and take into account all nonlinear effects. The energy
transmutation depends on the particle statistics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1501.02390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1501.02390</id><created>2015-01-10</created><authors><author><keyname>Rowe</keyname><forenames>David J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Applications of the Capelli identities in physics and representation
  theory</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>19 pages</comments><journal-ref>D. J. Rowe, J. Physics.A; Math, Theo., 48 (2015) 055203</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/48/5/055203</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Capelli identities are shown to facilitate the construction of
representations of various Heisenberg algebras that arise in many-particle
quantum mechanics and the construction of holomorphic representations of many
Lie algebras by Vector Coherent State methods. We consider the original Capelli
identity and its generalizations by Turnbull and by Howe and Umeda.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.02154</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.02154</id><created>2015-02-07</created><authors><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>Bryn Ll.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Heins</keyname><forenames>Peter H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kerrigan</keyname><forenames>Eric C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Morrison</keyname><forenames>Jonathan F.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sharma</keyname><forenames>Ati S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Modelling for Robust Feedback Control of Fluid Flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><comments>Accepted for publication in the Journal of Fluid Mechanics</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics, Vol. 769, 2015, pp. 687-722</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2015.84</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This paper addresses the problem of obtaining low-order models of fluid flows
for the purpose of designing robust feedback controllers. This is challenging
since whilst many flows are governed by a set of nonlinear, partial
differential-algebraic equations (the Navier-Stokes equations), the majority of
established control theory assumes models of much greater simplicity, in that
they are firstly: linear, secondly: described by ordinary differential
equations, and thirdly: finite-dimensional. Linearisation, where appropriate,
overcomes the first disparity, but attempts to reconcile the remaining two have
proved difficult. This paper addresses these two problems as follows. Firstly,
a numerical approach is used to project the governing equations onto a
divergence-free basis, thus converting a system of differential-algebraic
equations into one of ordinary differential equations. This dispenses with the
need for analytical velocity-vorticity transformations, and thus simplifies the
modelling of boundary sensing and actuation. Secondly, this paper presents a
novel and straightforward approach for obtaining suitable low-order models of
fluid flows, from which robust feedback controllers can be synthesised that
provide a priori guarantees of robust performance when connected to the
(infinite-dimensional) linearised flow system. This approach overcomes many of
the problems inherent in approaches that rely upon model-reduction. To
illustrate these methods, a perturbation shear stress controller is designed
and applied to plane channel flow, assuming arrays of wall mounted shear-stress
sensors and transpiration actuators. DNS results demonstrate robust attenuation
of the perturbation shear-stresses across a wide range of Reynolds numbers with
a single, linear controller.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1502.05234</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1502.05234</id><created>2015-02-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Mintchev</keyname><forenames>Mihail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-linear quantum noise effects in scale invariant junctions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>LaTex, 1+20 pages, 10 figures</comments><report-no>IFUP-TH 2/2015, LAPTH-008/15</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 48 (2015) 285002</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study non-equilibrium steady state transport in scale invariant quantum
junctions with focus on the particle and heat fluctuations captured by the
two-point current correlation functions. We show that the non-linear behavior
of the particle current affects both the particle and heat noise. The existence
of domains of enhancement and reduction of the noise power with respect to the
linear regime are observed. The impact of the statistics is explored. We
demonstrate that in the scale invariant case the bosonic particle noise exceeds
the fermionic one in the common domain of heat bath parameters. Multi-lead
configurations are also investigated and the effect of probe terminals on the
noise is discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1503.07127</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1503.07127</id><created>2015-03-24</created><updated>2016-06-02</updated><authors><author><keyname>Friedman</keyname><forenames>Barry A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Levine</keyname><forenames>Gregory C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Scaling of Entanglement Entropy for the Heisenberg Model on Clusters
  Joined by Point Contacts</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Statistical Physics, November 2016, Volume 165, p
  727-739</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/s10955-016-1640-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The scaling of entanglement entropy for the nearest neighbor
antiferromagnetic Heisenberg spin model is studied computationally for clusters
joined by a single bond. Bisecting the balanced three legged Bethe Cluster,
gives a second Renyi entropy and the valence bond entropy which scales as the
number of sites in the cluster. For the analogous situation with square
clusters, i.e. two $L \times L$ clusters joined by a single bond, numerical
results suggest that the second Renyi entropy and the valence bond entropy
scales as $L$. For both systems, the environment and the system are connected
by the single bond and interaction is short range. The entropy is not constant
with system size as suggested by the area law.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1506.04425</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1506.04425</id><created>2015-06-14</created><updated>2017-08-09</updated><authors><author><keyname>Downing</keyname><forenames>C. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Portnoi</keyname><forenames>M. E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Bielectron vortices in two-dimensional Dirac semimetals</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP quant-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 2 figures</comments><journal-ref>Nat. Commun. 8, 897 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41467-017-00949-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Searching for new states of matter and unusual quasiparticles in emerging
materials and especially low-dimensional systems is one of the major trends in
contemporary condensed matter physics. Dirac materials, which host
quasiparticles which are described by ultrarelativistic Dirac-like equations,
are of a significant current interest from both a fundamental and applied
physics perspective. Here we show that a pair of two-dimensional massless
Dirac-Weyl fermions can form a bound state independently of the sign of the
inter-particle interaction potential, as long as this potential decays at large
distances faster than Kepler's inverse distance law. This leads to the
emergence of a new type of energetically-favourable quasiparticle: bielectron
vortices, which are double-charged and reside at zero-energy. Their bosonic
nature allows for condensation and may give rise to Majorana physics without
invoking a superconductor. These novel quasiparticles arguably explain a range
of poorly understood experiments in gated graphene structures at low doping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1512.04338</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1512.04338</id><created>2015-12-14</created><updated>2017-09-25</updated><authors><author><keyname>Demir</keyname><forenames>Durmus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guner</keyname><forenames>Tugrul</forenames></author></authors><title>Statistical Approach to Tunneling Time in Attosecond Experiments</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>28 pp, 4 embedded figs, 1 table; extended content; version to appear
  in Annals of Physics</comments><report-no>IZTECH-P06/2015</report-no><journal-ref>Annals of Physics 386 (2017) 291</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.09.009</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Tunneling, transport of particles through classically forbidden regions, is a
pure quantum phenomenon. It governs numerous phenomena ranging from
single-molecule electronics to donor-acceptor transition reactions. The main
problem is the absence of a universal method to compute tunneling time. This
problem has been attacked in various ways in the literature. Here, in the
present work, we show that a statistical approach to the problem, motivated by
the imaginary nature of time in the forbidden regions, lead to a novel
tunneling time formula which is real and subluminal (in contrast to various
known time definitions implying superluminal tunneling). This entropic
tunneling time, as we call it, shows good agreement with the tunneling time
measurements in laser-driven He ionization. Moreover, it sets an accurate range
for long-range electron transfer reactions. The entropic tunneling time is
general enough to extend to the photon and phonon tunneling phenomena.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01735</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01735</id><created>2016-01-07</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>D&#xfc;zta&#x15f;</keyname><forenames>Koray</forenames></author></authors><title>Coulomb fields as perturbations of type D vacuum space-times</title><categories>gr-qc math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>More detailed than the published version</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. Plus (2017) 132:406</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjp/i2017-11710-7</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We consider a test, non-null electromagnetic field special in the sense that
the principal null directions of the field lie along the two repeated principal
null directions of the type D vacuum background. We prove that the special
non-null field is a valid solution of the Maxwell equations on a type D
background. This field behaves as $1/r^2$ and the only non-vanishing Maxwell
scalar is $\phi_1$ so it can be called the Coulomb field. We show that the
contribution to the energy and angular momentum fluxes of the Coulomb field
vanishes at any surface of integration, on the type D vacuum backgrounds Kerr,
Kerr-Taub-NUT, Taub-NUT, and Schwarzschild. Therefore this field does not lead
to any perturbations of the mass and angular momentum parameters of these
space-times.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1601.01819</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1601.01819</id><created>2016-01-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Mintchev</keyname><forenames>Mihail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Non-equilibrium current cumulants and moments with a point-like defect</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.mes-hall math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>LaTex 1+20 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>IFUP-TH 1/2016</report-no><journal-ref>J. Phys. A: Math. Theor. 49 (2016) 265002</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1751-8113/49/26/265002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the exact n-point current expectation values in the
Landauer-Buttiker non-equilibrium steady state of a multi terminal system with
star graph geometry and a point-like defect localised in the vertex. The
current cumulants are extracted from the connected correlation functions and
the cumulant generating function is established. We determine the moments, show
that the associated moment problem has a unique solution and reconstruct
explicitly the corresponding probability distribution. The basic building
blocks of this distribution are the probabilities of particle emission and
absorption from the heat reservoirs, driving the system away from equilibrium.
We derive and analyse in detail these probabilities, showing that they fully
describe the quantum transport problem in the system.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1602.02858</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1602.02858</id><created>2016-02-08</created><authors><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Daiqin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ho</keyname><forenames>C. T. Marco</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mann</keyname><forenames>Robert B.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ralph</keyname><forenames>Timothy C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Circuit Model for a Uniformly Accelerated Mirror</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>New J. Phys. 19, 063017 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/1367-2630/aa71d1</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a quantum circuit model describing unitary interactions between
quantum fields and a uniformly accelerated object, and apply it to a
semi-transparent mirror which uniformly accelerates in the Minkowski vacuum.
The reflection coefficient $R_{\omega}$ of the mirror varies between 0 and 1,
representing a generalization of the perfect mirror ($R_{\omega}=1$) discussed
extensively in the literature. Our method is non-perturbative, not requiring
$R_{\omega} \sim 0$. We use the circuit model to calculate the radiation from
an eternally accelerated mirror and obtain a finite particle flux along the
past horizon provided an appropriate low frequency regularization is
introduced. More importantly, it is straightforward to see from our formalism
that the radiation is squeezed. The squeezing is closely related to cutting the
correlation across the horizon, which therefore may have important implications
to the formation of a black hole firewall.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1604.05965</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1604.05965</id><created>2016-04-16</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Smilga</keyname><forenames>Walter</forenames></author></authors><title>Noether's Theorem and its Complement: A Gateway to Particle Interaction</title><categories>physics.gen-ph</categories><comments>11 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Noether's theorem has gained outstanding importance in theoretical particle
physics, because it leads to basic conservation laws, such as the conservation
of momentum and of angular momentum. Closely related to this theorem, but
unnoticed so far, is a complementary law, which requires the (virtual) exchange
of momentum between the particles of a closed multi-particle system. This
exchange of momentum determines an interaction. For a two-particle system
defined by an irreducible representation of the Poincare group, this
interaction is identified as the electromagnetic interaction. This sheds new
light on the particle interactions described by the Standard Model. It resolves
long-standing questions about the value of the electromagnetic coupling
constant, and about divergent integrals in quantum electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00729</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00729</id><created>2016-06-02</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drivas</keyname><forenames>Theodore D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyink</keyname><forenames>Gregory L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Lagrangian fluctuation-dissipation relation for scalar turbulence, I.
  Flows with no bounding walls</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn math-ph math.MP math.PR</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics 829, 153-189 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.567</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  An exact relation is derived between scalar dissipation due to molecular
diffusivity and the randomness of stochastic Lagrangian trajectories for flows
without bounding walls. This &quot;Lagrangian fluctuation-dissipation relation&quot;
equates the scalar dissipation for either passive or active scalars to the
variance of scalar inputs associated to initial scalar values and internal
scalar sources, as those are sampled backward in time by the stochastic
Lagrangian trajectories. As an important application, we reconsider the
phenomenon of &quot;Lagrangian spontaneous stochasticity&quot; or persistent
non-determinism of Lagrangian particle trajectories in the limit of vanishing
viscosity and diffusivity. Previous work on the Kraichnan (1968) model of
turbulent scalar advection has shown that anomalous scalar dissipation is
associated in that model to Lagrangian spontaneous stochasticity. There has
been controversy, however, regarding the validity of this mechanism for scalars
advected by an actual turbulent flow. We here completely resolve this
controversy by exploiting the fluctuation-dissipation relation. For either a
passive or active scalar advected by any divergence-free velocity field,
including solutions of the incompressible Navier-Stokes equation, and away from
walls, we prove that anomalous scalar dissipation requires Lagrangian
spontaneous stochasticity. For passive scalars we prove furthermore that
spontaneous stochasticity yields anomalous dissipation for suitable initial
scalar distributions, so that the two phenomena are there completely
equivalent. These points are illustrated by numerical results from a database
of homogeneous, isotropic turbulence, which provide both additional support to
the results and physical insight into the representation of diffusive effects
by stochastic Lagrangian particle trajectories.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.00999</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.00999</id><created>2016-06-03</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koppenburg</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dolezal</keyname><forenames>Zdenek</forenames></author><author><keyname>Smizanska</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Rare decays of b hadrons</title><categories>hep-ex hep-ph</categories><comments>Contribution to Scholarpedia. This is the arXiv version with many
  more references. v5 updates to status at the end of summer 2017</comments><report-no>Nikhef-2016-024</report-no><journal-ref>Scholarpedia, 11(6): 32643 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.4249/scholarpedia.32643</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</license><abstract>  Rare decays of b hadrons provide a powerful way of identifying contributions
from physics beyond the Standard Model, in particular from new hypothetical
particles too heavy to be produced at colliders. The most relevant experimental
measurements are reviewed and possible interpretations are briefly discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1606.06884</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1606.06884</id><created>2016-06-22</created><updated>2017-06-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rajpoot</keyname><forenames>Subhash</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vacaru</keyname><forenames>Sergiu I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On Supersymmetric Geometric Flows and $\mathcal{R}^2$ Inflation From
  Scale Invariant Supergravity</title><categories>hep-th math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>v3 is accepted to AP NY, updated affiliation, and new references;
  Authors comments on &quot;text overlap with arXiv:1409.7076 ...&quot;: together with
  [T. Gheorghiu et al. AP NY 369 (2016) 1], we present further developments of
  the published version of arXiv: 1409.7076 - cited several times, with
  repeating text and results by A. Kehagias, et al</comments><journal-ref>Annals of Physics NY 384 (2017) 20-60</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.aop.2017.06.016</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Models of geometric flows pertaining to $\mathcal{R}^2$ scale invariant
(super) gravity theories coupled to conformally invariant matter fields are
investigated. Related to this work are supersymmetric scalar manifolds that are
isomorphic to the K\&quot;{a}hlerian spaces $\mathcal{M}_n=SU(1,1+k)/U(1)\times
SU(1+k)$ as generalizations of the non-supersymmetric analogs with
$SO(1,1+k)/SO(1+k)$ manifolds. For curved superspaces with geometric evolution
of physical objects, a complete supersymmetric theory has to be elaborated on
nonholonomic (super) manifolds and bundles determined by non-integrable
superdistributions with additional constraints on (super) field dynamics and
geometric evolution equations. We also consider generalizations of Perelman's
functionals using such nonholonomic variables which result in the decoupling of
geometric flow equations and Ricci soliton equations with supergravity
modifications of the $R^2$ gravity theory. As such, it is possible to construct
exact non-homogeneous and locally anisotropic cosmological solutions for
various types of (super) gravity theories modelled as modified Ricci soliton
configurations. Such solutions are defined by employing the general ansatz
encompassing coefficients of generic off-diagonal metrics and generalized
connections that depend generically on all spacetime coordinates. We consider
nonholonomic constraints resulting in diagonal homogeneous configurations
encoding contributions from possible nonlinear parametric geometric evolution
scenarios, off-diagonal interactions and anisotropic polarization/ modification
of physical constants. We also analyze the conditions under which such modified
mimetic type theories and solutions reproduce the Starobinsky inflationary
models in the double scalar approach.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.03397</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.03397</id><created>2016-07-12</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>L&#xe4;hnemann</keyname><forenames>Jonas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flissikowski</keyname><forenames>Timur</forenames></author><author><keyname>W&#xf6;lz</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Geelhaar</keyname><forenames>Lutz</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grahn</keyname><forenames>Holger T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>Oliver</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jahn</keyname><forenames>Uwe</forenames></author></authors><title>Quenching of the luminescence intensity of GaN nanowires under electron
  beam exposure: Impact of C adsorption on the exciton lifetime</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>This is an author-created, un-copyedited version of an article
  accepted for publication/published in Nanotechnology. IOP Publishing Ltd is
  not responsible for any errors or omissions in this version of the manuscript
  or any version derived from it. The Version of Record is available online at
  http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/0957-4484/27/45/455706</comments><journal-ref>Nanotechnology 27, 455706 (2016)</journal-ref><doi>10.1088/0957-4484/27/45/455706</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron irradiation of GaN nanowires in a scanning electron microscope
strongly reduces their luminous efficiency as shown by cathodoluminescence
imaging and spectroscopy. We demonstrate that this luminescence quenching
originates from a combination of charge trapping at already existing surface
states and the formation of new surface states induced by the adsorption of C
on the nanowire sidewalls. The interplay of these effects leads to a complex
temporal evolution of the quenching, which strongly depends on the incident
electron dose per area. Time-resolved photoluminescence measurements on
electron-irradiated samples reveal that the carbonaceous adlayer affects both
the nonradiative and the radiative recombination dynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1607.04224</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1607.04224</id><created>2016-07-14</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Carneiro</keyname><forenames>Pedro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grismayer</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fonseca</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>Lu&#xed;s</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Electrodynamics vacuum polarization solver</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph hep-th physics.comp-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The self-consistent modeling of vacuum polarization due to virtual
electron-positron fluctuations is of relevance for many near term experiments
associated with high intensity radiation sources and represents a milestone in
describing scenarios of extreme energy density. We present a generalized
finite-difference time-domain solver that can incorporate the modifications to
Maxwell's equations due to vacuum polarization. Our multidimensional solver
reproduced in one dimensional configurations the results for which an analytic
treatment is possible, yielding vacuum harmonic generation and birefringence.
The solver has also been tested for two-dimensional scenarios where finite
laser beam spot sizes must be taken into account. We employ this solver to
explore different types of counter-propagating configurations that can be
relevant for future planned experiments aiming to detect quantum vacuum
dynamics at ultra-high electromagnetic field intensities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1608.02404</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1608.02404</id><created>2016-08-08</created><updated>2016-08-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Graft</keyname><forenames>Donald A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Anomalous Postselection in the Hensen et al. Bell Test</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><journal-ref>Incorporated into Section 4 of: Open Physics, Volume 15, Issue 1
  (Sep 2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1515/phys-2017-0068</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown that the data of the Hensen et al. Bell test experiment exhibits
anomalous postselection that can fully account for the apparent violation of
the CHSH inequality. A simulation of a local realist model implementing similar
postselection is presented. The model produces an apparent violation of CHSH
indistinguishable from that of the experiment. The experimental data also
appears to violate no-signaling, and it is shown how postselection can produce
an artifactual violation of no-signaling. The Hensen et al. experiment does not
succeed in rejecting classical locality and therefore does not confirm quantum
nonlocality.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.05427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.05427</id><created>2016-09-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Mintchev</keyname><forenames>Mihail</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santoni</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sorba</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum Transport in Presence of Bound States -- Noise Power</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>LaTex 1+11 pages, 4 figures</comments><report-no>IFUP-TH 06/2016</report-no><journal-ref>Annalen der Physik 259 (2017) 1600274</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/andp.201600274</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The impact of bound states in Landauer-Buttiker scattering approach to
non-equilibrium quantum transport is investigated. We show that the noise power
at frequency $\nu$ is sensitive to all bound states with energies $\omega_b$
satisfying $|\omega_b| &lt; \nu$. We derive the exact expression of the bound
state contribution and compare it to the one produced by the scattering states
alone. It turns out that the bound states lead to specific modifications of
both space and frequency dependence of the total noise power. The theoretical
and experimental consequences of this result are discussed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.06745</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.06745</id><created>2016-09-21</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bhat</keyname><forenames>Pallavi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebrahimi</keyname><forenames>Fatima</forenames></author><author><keyname>Blackman</keyname><forenames>Eric G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Subramanian</keyname><forenames>Kandaswamy</forenames></author></authors><title>Evolution of the magnetorotational instability on initially tangled
  magnetic fields</title><categories>astro-ph.HE physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Published in MNRAS, 6 pages, 5 figures</comments><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1989</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The initial magnetic field of previous magnetorotational instability (MRI)
simulations has always included a significant system-scale component, even if
stochastic. However, it is of conceptual and practical interest to assess
whether the MRI can grow when the initial field is turbulent. The ubiquitous
presence of turbulent or random flows in astrophysical plasmas generically
leads to a small-scale dynamo (SSD), which would provide initial seed turbulent
velocity and magnetic fields in the plasma that becomes an accretion disc. Can
the MRI grow from these more realistic initial conditions? To address this we
supply a standard shearing box with isotropically forced SSD generated magnetic
and velocity fields as initial conditions, and remove the forcing. We find that
if the initially supplied fields are too weak or too incoherent, they decay
from the initial turbulent cascade faster than they can grow via the MRI. When
the initially supplied fields are sufficient to allow MRI growth and
sustenance, the saturated stresses, large-scale fields, and power spectra match
those of the standard zero net flux MRI simulation with an initial large scale
vertical field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1609.07119</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1609.07119</id><created>2016-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Bakker</keyname><forenames>Alexander M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Tony E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ruckert</keyname><forenames>Kelsey L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Sea-level projections representing deeply uncertain ice-sheet
  contributions</title><categories>physics.ao-ph</categories><comments>13 pages, 4 figures, 1 supplementary file</comments><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-04134-5</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Future sea-level rise poses nontrivial risks for many coastal communities.
Managing these risks often relies on consensus projections like those provided
by the IPCC. Yet, there is a growing awareness that the surrounding
uncertainties may be much larger than typically perceived. Recently published
sea-level projections appear widely divergent and highly sensitive to
non-trivial model choices and the West Antarctic Ice Sheet (WAIS) may be much
less stable than previously believed, enabling a rapid disintegration. In
response, some agencies have already announced to update their projections
accordingly. Here, we present a set of probabilistic sea-level projections that
approximate deeply uncertain WAIS contributions. The projections aim to inform
robust decisions by clarifying the sensitivity to non-trivial or controversial
assumptions. We show that the deeply uncertain WAIS contribution can dominate
other uncertainties within decades. These deep uncertainties call for the
development of robust adaptive strategies. These decision-making needs, in
turn, require mission-oriented basic science, for example about potential
signposts and the maximum rate of WAIS induced sea-level changes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1610.03596</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1610.03596</id><created>2016-10-12</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Ogawa</keyname><forenames>Noriaki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatsuda</keyname><forenames>Tetsuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mochizuki</keyname><forenames>Atsushi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tachikawa</keyname><forenames>Masashi</forenames></author></authors><title>Dynamical Pattern Selection of Growing Cellular Mosaic in Fish Retina</title><categories>q-bio.CB cond-mat.soft cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>REVTeX, 12 pages, 7 figures, published in Phys.Rev.E (v2)</comments><report-no>RIKEN-QHP-248, RIKEN-STAMP-29</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 032416 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.032416</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A Markovian lattice model for photoreceptor cells is introduced to describe
the growth of mosaic patterns on fish retina. The radial stripe pattern
observed in wild-type zebrafish is shown to be selected naturally during the
retina growth, against the geometrically equivalent, circular stripe pattern.
The mechanism of such dynamical pattern selection is clarified on the basis of
both numerical simulations and theoretical analyses, which find that the
successive emergence of local defects plays a critical role in the realization
of the wild-type pattern.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1611.01074</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1611.01074</id><created>2016-11-03</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Rupp</keyname><forenames>Daniela</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fl&#xfc;ckiger</keyname><forenames>Leonie</forenames></author><author><keyname>Adolph</keyname><forenames>Marcus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorkhover</keyname><forenames>Tais</forenames></author><author><keyname>Krikunova</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Jan Phillipe</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xfc;ller</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author><author><keyname>Oelze</keyname><forenames>Tim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ovcharenko</keyname><forenames>Yevheniy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sauppe</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schorb</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wolter</keyname><forenames>David</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harmand</keyname><forenames>Marion</forenames></author><author><keyname>Treusch</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bostedt</keyname><forenames>Christoph</forenames></author><author><keyname>M&#xf6;ller</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Diffractive imaging of transient electronic core-shell structures in a
  nanoplasma</title><categories>physics.atm-clus</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have recorded the coherent diffraction images of individual xenon clusters
with intense extreme ultraviolet pulses to elucidate the influence of
light-induced electronic changes on the diffraction pattern. Using the FLASH
free-electron laser we tuned the wavelength to specific xenon atomic and ionic
resonances. The data show the emergence of a transient core-shell structure
within the otherwise homogeneous sample. Simulations indicate that ionization
and nanoplasma formation result in a cluster shell with strongly altered
refraction. The presented resonant scattering approach enables imaging of
ultrafast electron dynamics on their natural time scale.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1612.04870</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1612.04870</id><created>2016-12-14</created><authors><author><keyname>Chakravarty</keyname><forenames>Sudip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Zhiqiang</forenames></author></authors><title>Comment on &quot;Magnetotransport signatures of a single nodal electron
  pocket constructed from Fermi arcs&quot;</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 146501 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.146501</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We comment on the recent work [N. Harrison, \textit{et al.} Phys. Rev. B {\bf
92}, 224505 (2015)] which attempts to explain the sign reversal and quantum
oscillations of the Hall coefficient observed in cuprates from a single nodal
diamond-shaped electron pocket with concave arc segments. Given the importance
of this work, it calls for a closer scrutiny. Their conclusion of sign reversal
of the Hall coefficient depends on a non-generic rounding of the sharp
vertices. Moreover, their demonstration of quantum oscillation in the Hall
coefficient from a single pocket is unconvincing. We maintain that at least two
pockets with different scattering rates is necessary to explain the observed
quantum oscillations of the Hall coefficient.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.00998</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.00998</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hofer</keyname><forenames>Patrick P.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quasi-probability distributions for observables in dynamic systems</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Accepted in Quantum</comments><journal-ref>Quantum 1, 32 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.22331/q-2017-10-12-32</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  We develop a general framework to investigate fluctuations of non-commuting
observables. To this end, we consider the Keldysh quasi-probability
distribution (KQPD). This distribution provides a measurement-independent
description of the observables of interest and their time-evolution.
Nevertheless, positive probability distributions for measurement outcomes can
be obtained from the KQPD by taking into account the effect of measurement
back-action and imprecision. Negativity in the KQPD can be linked to an
interference effect and acts as an indicator for non-classical behavior.
Notable examples of the KQPD are the Wigner function and the full counting
statistics, both of which have been used extensively to describe systems in the
absence as well as in the presence of a measurement apparatus. Here we discuss
the KQPD and its moments in detail and connect it to various time-dependent
problems including weak values, fluctuating work, and Leggett-Garg
inequalities. Our results are illustrated using the simple example of two
subsequent, non-commuting spin measurements.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.01186</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.01186</id><created>2017-02-03</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Anisimova</keyname><forenames>Elena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Higgins</keyname><forenames>Brendon L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourgoin</keyname><forenames>Jean-Philippe</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cranmer</keyname><forenames>Miles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Choi</keyname><forenames>Eric</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hudson</keyname><forenames>Danya</forenames></author><author><keyname>Piche</keyname><forenames>Louis P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Scott</keyname><forenames>Alan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Makarov</keyname><forenames>Vadim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jennewein</keyname><forenames>Thomas</forenames></author></authors><title>Mitigating radiation damage of single photon detectors for space
  applications</title><categories>physics.ins-det astro-ph.IM quant-ph</categories><comments>The license has been corrected. Note that the license of v2 was
  incorrect and not valid. No other changes since v2</comments><msc-class>81-05</msc-class><journal-ref>EPJ Quantum Technol. 4, 10 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epjqt/s40507-017-0062-z</doi><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  Single-photon detectors in space must retain useful performance
characteristics despite being bombarded with sub-atomic particles. Mitigating
the effects of this space radiation is vital to enabling new space applications
which require high-fidelity single-photon detection. To this end, we conducted
proton radiation tests of various models of avalanche photodiodes (APDs) and
one model of photomultiplier tube potentially suitable for satellite-based
quantum communications. The samples were irradiated with 106 MeV protons at
doses approximately equivalent to lifetimes of 0.6 , 6, 12 and 24 months in a
low-Earth polar orbit. Although most detection properties were preserved,
including efficiency, timing jitter and afterpulsing probability, all APD
samples demonstrated significant increases in dark count rate (DCR) due to
radiation-induced damage, many orders of magnitude higher than the 200 counts
per second (cps) required for ground-to-satellite quantum communications. We
then successfully demonstrated the mitigation of this DCR degradation through
the use of deep cooling, to as low as -86 degrees C. This achieved DCR below
the required 200 cps over the 24 months orbit duration. DCR was further reduced
by thermal annealing at temperatures of +50 to +100 degrees C.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1702.03116</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1702.03116</id><created>2017-02-10</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Joonho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lee</keyname><forenames>Kimyeong</forenames></author></authors><title>Little strings on $D_n$ orbifolds</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>29 pages, 9 figures; v2: minor changes, published version</comments><report-no>KIAS-P17011</report-no><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2017)045</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore two classes of 6d $\mathcal{N}=(1,0)$ little string theories
obtained from type IIA/IIB NS5-branes probing $D_n$ singularities. Their tensor
branches are described by effective gauge theories whose instanton solitons are
macroscopic little strings. We specifically study two families of 2d
$\mathcal{N}=(0,4)$ gauge theories which describe at low energy the worldsheet
dynamics of the type IIA/IIB little strings. These gauge theories are useful to
calculate the supersymmetric partition functions of the little string theories
on $\mathbf{R}^4 \times T^2$. We establish the T-duality of the little string
theories by utilizing their BPS spectra as a probe.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.02971</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.02971</id><created>2017-03-08</created><updated>2017-09-14</updated><authors><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zhenyue</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maksimov</keyname><forenames>P. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>White</keyname><forenames>Steven R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chernyshev</keyname><forenames>A. L.</forenames></author></authors><title>Disorder-Induced Mimicry of a Spin Liquid in YbMgGaO$_4$</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>5+ main text, 7+ supplemental, text asymptotically close to PRL</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 157201 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.157201</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We suggest that a randomization of the pseudo-dipolar interaction in the
spin-orbit-generated low-energy Hamiltonian of YbMgGaO$_4$ due to an
inhomogeneous charge environment from a natural mixing of Mg$^{2+}$ and
Ga$^{3+}$ can give rise to orientational spin disorder and mimic a
spin-liquid-like state. In the absence of such quenched disorder, $1/S$ and
density matrix renormalization group calculations both show robust ordered
states for the physically relevant phases of the model. Our scenario is
consistent with the available experimental data and further experiments are
proposed to support it.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.08133</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.08133</id><created>2017-03-07</created><updated>2017-07-13</updated><authors><author><keyname>Drivas</keyname><forenames>Theodore D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eyink</keyname><forenames>Gregory L.</forenames></author></authors><title>A Lagrangian fluctuation-dissipation relation for scalar turbulence, II.
  Wall-bounded flows</title><categories>physics.flu-dyn</categories><journal-ref>Journal of Fluid Mechanics 829, 236-279 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1017/jfm.2017.571</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive here Lagrangian fluctuation-dissipation relations for advected
scalars in wall-bounded flows. The relations equate the dissipation rate for
either passive or active scalars to the variance of scalar inputs from the
initial values, boundary values, and internal sources, as those are sampled
backward in time by stochastic Lagrangian trajectories. New probabilistic
concepts are required to represent scalar boundary conditions at the walls: the
boundary local-time density at points on the wall where scalar fluxes are
imposed and the boundary first hitting-time at points where scalar values are
imposed. These concepts are illustrated both by analytical results for the
problem of pure heat conduction and by numerical results from a database of
channel-flow flow turbulence, which also demonstrate the scalar mixing
properties of near-wall turbulence. As an application of the
fluctuation-dissipation relation, we examine for wall-bounded flows the
relation between anomalous scalar dissipation and Lagrangian spontaneous
stochasticity, i.e. the persistent non-determinism of Lagrangian particle
trajectories in the limit of vanishing viscosity and diffusivity. In the first
paper of this series, we showed that spontaneous stochasticity is the only
possible mechanism for anomalous dissipation of passive or active scalars, away
from walls. Here it is shown that this remains true when there are no scalar
fluxes through walls. Simple examples show, on the other hand, that a distinct
mechanism of non-vanishing scalar dissipation can be thin scalar boundary
layers near the walls. Nevertheless, we prove for general wall-bounded flows
that spontaneous stochasticity is another possible mechanism of anomalous
scalar dissipation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1703.09162</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1703.09162</id><created>2017-03-27</created><updated>2017-08-20</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fernandes</keyname><forenames>Karan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mitra</keyname><forenames>Arpita</forenames></author></authors><title>Gravitational anomalies on the Newton-Cartan background</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th</categories><comments>37 pages, no figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 085003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.085003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We derive the trace and diffeomorphism anomalies of the Schr\&quot;odinger field
minimally coupled to the Newton-Cartan background using Fujikawa's path
integral approach. This approach in particular enables us to calculate the
one-loop contributions due to all the fields of the Newton-Cartan structure. We
determine the coefficients and demonstrate that gravitational anomalies for
this theory always arise in odd dimensions. Due to the gauge field contribution
of the background we find that in $2+1$ dimensions the trace anomaly contains
terms which have a form similar to that of the $1+1$ and $3+1$ dimensional
relativistic trace anomalies. This result reveals that the Newton-Cartan
background which satisfies the Frobenius condition possesses a Type A trace
anomaly in contrast with the result of Lishitz spacetimes. As an application we
demonstrate that the coefficient of the term similar to the $1+1$ dimensional
relativistic trace anomaly satisfies a c-theorem condition.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00294</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00294</id><created>2017-04-02</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Birkandan</keyname><forenames>T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Horta&#xe7;su</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Heun-type solutions for Schwarzschild metric with electromagnetic fields</title><categories>math-ph gr-qc math.MP</categories><comments>8 pages, 2 figures. Matches the published version</comments><journal-ref>Europhys.Lett. 119 (2017) no.2, 20002</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/119/20002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We find confluent Heun solutions to the radial equations of two
Halilsoy-Badawi metrics. For the first metric, we studied the radial part of
the massless Dirac equation and for the second case, we studied the radial part
of the massless Klein-Gordon equation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00747</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00747</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-05-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Singh</keyname><forenames>Tejinder P.</forenames></author></authors><title>A new length scale for quantum gravity</title><categories>gr-qc hep-th quant-ph</categories><comments>7 pages, 1 figure; v2 - minor typo corrected, Honorable Mention in
  the Gravity Research Foundation 2017 Awards for Essays on Gravitation</comments><journal-ref>Int. J. Mod. Phys 26 (2017) 1743015</journal-ref><doi>10.1142/S0218271817170155</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show why and how Compton wavelength and Schwarzschild radius should be
combined into one single new length scale, which we call the
Compton-Schwarzschild length. Doing so offers a resolution of the black hole
information loss paradox, and suggests Planck mass remnant black holes as
candidates for dark matter. It also compels us to introduce torsion, and
identify the Dirac field with a complex torsion field. Dirac equation, and
Einstein equations, are shown to be mutually dual limiting cases of an
underlying gravitation theory which involves the Compton-Schwarzschild length
scale, and includes a complex torsion field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.00790</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.00790</id><created>2017-04-03</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Han</keyname><forenames>Tao</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Xing</forenames></author></authors><title>Radiative Decays of the Higgs Boson to a Pair of Fermions</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 6 figures, 6 tables; Minor corrections, references updated,
  version published in JHEP</comments><report-no>PITT-PACC-1703</report-no><journal-ref>JHEP 1710 (2017) 036</journal-ref><doi>10.1007/JHEP10(2017)036</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We revisit the radiative decays of the Higgs boson to a fermion pair
$h\rightarrow f\bar{f}\gamma$ where $f$ denotes a fermion in the Standard Model
(SM). We include the chirality-flipping diagrams via the Yukawa couplings at
the order $\mathcal{O}(y_f^2 \alpha)$, the chirality-conserving contributions
via the top-quark loops of the order $\mathcal{O}(y_t^2 \alpha^3)$, and the
electroweak loops at the order $\mathcal{O}(\alpha^4)$. The QED correction is
about $Q_f^2\times {\cal O}(1\%)$ and contributes to the running of fermion
masses at a similar level, which should be taken into account for future
precision Higgs physics. The chirality-conserving electroweak-loop processes
are interesting from the observational point of view. First, the branching
fraction of the radiative decay $h \to \mu^+\mu^- \gamma$ is about a half of
that of $h \to \mu^+\mu^-$, and that of $h \to e^+ e^- \gamma$ is more than
four orders of magnitude larger than that of $h \to e^+ e^-$, both of which
reach about $10^{-4}$. The branching fraction of $h \to \tau^+\tau^- \gamma$ is
of the order $10^{-3}$. All the leptonic radiative decays are potentially
observable at the LHC Run 2 or the HL-LHC. The kinematic distributions for the
photon energy or the fermion pair invariant mass provide non-ambiguous
discrimination for the underlying mechanisms of the Higgs radiative decay. We
also study the process $h \to c\bar c \gamma$ and evaluate the observability at
the LHC. We find it comparable to the other related studies and better than the
$h \to J/\psi\ \gamma$ channel in constraining the charm-Yukawa coupling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.02444</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.02444</id><created>2017-04-08</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Volk</keyname><forenames>Kathryn</forenames></author><author><keyname>Malhotra</keyname><forenames>Renu</forenames></author></authors><title>The curiously warped mean plane of the Kuiper belt</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>This version corrects an error in Figure 7 and typographical errors
  in some equations in Appendix D (changes accepted as an erratum in AJ)</comments><doi>10.3847/1538-3881/aa79ff</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We measured the mean plane of the Kuiper belt as a function of semi-major
axis. For the classical Kuiper belt as a whole (the non-resonant objects in the
semi-major axis range 42--48~au), we find a mean plane of inclination
$i_m=1.8^{\circ}$$^{+0.7^{\circ}}_{-0.4^{\circ}}$ and longitude of ascending
node $\Omega_m=77^{\circ}$$^{+18^{\circ}}_{-14^{\circ}}$ (in the J2000
ecliptic-equinox coordinate system), in accord with theoretical expectations of
the secular effects of the known planets. With finer semi-major axis bins, we
detect a statistically significant warp in the mean plane near semi-major axes
40--42~au. Linear secular theory predicts a warp near this location due to the
$\nu_{18}$ nodal secular resonance, however the measured mean plane for the
40.3-42~au semi-major axis bin (just outside the $\nu_{18}$) is inclined
$\sim13^{\circ}$ to the predicted plane, a nearly 3-$\sigma$ discrepancy. For
the more distant Kuiper belt objects of semi-major axes in the range 50--80~au,
the expected mean plane is close to the invariable plane of the solar system,
but the measured mean plane deviates greatly from this: it has inclination
$i_m=9.1^{\circ}$$^{+6.6^{\circ}}_{-3.8^{\circ}}$ and longitude of ascending
node $\Omega_m=227^{\circ}$$^{+18^{\circ}}_{-44^{\circ}}$. We estimate this
deviation from the expected mean plane to be statistically significant at the
$\sim97-99\%$ confidence level. We discuss several possible explanations for
this deviation, including the possibility that a relatively close-in
($a\lesssim100$~au), unseen small planetary-mass object in the outer solar
system is responsible for the warping.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.05689</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.05689</id><created>2017-04-19</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Araki</keyname><forenames>Yasufumi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nomura</keyname><forenames>Kentaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Skyrmion-induced anomalous Hall conductivity on topological insulator
  surfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>10 pages, 4 figures; published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 165303 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.165303</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electron spin-momentum locking together with background magnetic textures can
significantly alter the electron transport properties. We theoretically
investigate the electron transport at the interface between a topological
insulator and a magnetic insulator with magnetic skyrmions on the top. In
contrast to the conventional topological Hall effect in normal metals, the
skyrmions yield an additional contribution to the anomalous Hall conductivity
even in the absence of in-plane magnetic texture, arising from the phase factor
characteristic to Dirac electrons acquired at skyrmion boundary.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1704.08907</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1704.08907</id><created>2017-04-28</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Robinson</keyname><forenames>Martin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bruna</keyname><forenames>Maria</forenames></author></authors><title>Particle-based and Meshless Methods with Aboria</title><categories>cs.MS cond-mat.soft q-bio.QM</categories><journal-ref>SoftwareX 6 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.softx.2017.07.002</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Aboria is a powerful and flexible C++ library for the implementation of
particle-based numerical methods. The particles in such methods can represent
actual particles (e.g. Molecular Dynamics) or abstract particles used to
discretise a continuous function over a domain (e.g. Radial Basis Functions).
Aboria provides a particle container, compatible with the Standard Template
Library, spatial search data structures, and a Domain Specific Language to
specify non-linear operators on the particle set. This paper gives an overview
of Aboria's design, an example of use, and a performance benchmark.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.01355</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.01355</id><created>2017-05-03</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hajiali</keyname><forenames>M. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hamdi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roozmeh</keyname><forenames>S. E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mohseni</keyname><forenames>S. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Current driven second harmonic domain wall resonance in ferromagnetic
  metal/ nonmagnetic metal bilayer: a field-free method for spin Hall angle
  measurements</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall physics.app-ph</categories><comments>M. R. Hajiali and M. Hamdi contributed equally to this work</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 144406 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.144406</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the ac current-driven domain wall motion in bilayer ferromagnetic
metal (FM)/nonmagnetic metal (NM) nanowire. The solution of the modified
Landau-Lifshitz-Gilbert equation including all the spin transfer torques is
used to describe motion of the domain wall in presence of the spin Hall effect.
We show that the domain wall center has second harmonic frequency response in
addition to the known first harmonic excitation. In contrast to the
experimentally observed second harmonic response in harmonic Hall measurements
of spin-orbit torque in magnetic thin films, this second harmonic response
directly originates from spin-orbit torque driven domain wall dynamics. Based
on the spin current generated by domain wall dynamics, the longitudinal spin
motive force generated voltage across the length of the nanowire is determined.
The second harmonic response introduces additionally a new practical field-free
and all-electrical method to probe the effective spin Hall angle for FM/NM
bilayer structures that could be applied in experiments. Our results also
demonstrate the capability of utilizing FM/NM bilayer structure in domain wall
based spin torque signal generators and resonators.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.03961</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.03961</id><created>2017-05-10</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>G&#xf3;mez-Le&#xf3;n</keyname><forenames>&#xc1;lvaro</forenames></author></authors><title>Hierarchy of correlations for the Ising model in the Majorana
  representation</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>10 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 064426 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.064426</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum Ising model in D dimensions with the equation of motion
technique, in combination with the Majorana representation for spins. The
decoupling scheme used for the Green's functions is based on the hierarchy of
correlations in position space. To lowest order this method reproduces the well
known mean field phase diagram and critical exponents. When correlations
between spins are included, we show how the appearance of thermal fluctuations
and magnons strongly affect the physical properties. We demonstrate that in 1D
and for B=0, thermal fluctuations completely destroy the ordered phase, and
that near the quantum critical point, the quantum model displays different
behavior than its classical counterpart. We discuss the connection with the
Dyson's equation formalism and the explicit form of the self-energies.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.06994</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.06994</id><created>2017-05-19</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>P&#xe9;rez-Espigares</keyname><forenames>Carlos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Marcuzzi</keyname><forenames>Matteo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Guti&#xe9;rrez</keyname><forenames>Ricardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lesanovsky</keyname><forenames>Igor</forenames></author></authors><title>Epidemic dynamics in open quantum spin systems</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.quant-gas physics.atom-ph</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Lett. 119, 140401 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevLett.119.140401</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We explore the non-equilibrium evolution and stationary states of an open
many-body system which displays epidemic spreading dynamics in a classical and
a quantum regime. Our study is motivated by recent experiments conducted in
strongly interacting gases of highly excited Rydberg atoms where the
facilitated excitation of Rydberg states competes with radiative decay. These
systems approximately implement open quantum versions of models for population
dynamics or disease spreading where species can be in a healthy, infected or
immune state. We show that in a two-dimensional lattice, depending on the
dominance of either classical or quantum effects, the system may display a
different kind of non-equilibrium phase transition. We moreover discuss the
observability of our findings in laser driven Rydberg gases with particular
focus on the role of long-range interactions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1705.07722</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1705.07722</id><created>2017-05-22</created><updated>2017-08-07</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wong</keyname><forenames>Tony E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Keller</keyname><forenames>Klaus</forenames></author></authors><title>Deep Uncertainty Surrounding Coastal Flood Risk Projections: A Case
  Study for New Orleans</title><categories>physics.geo-ph</categories><doi>10.1002/2017EF000607</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Future sea-level rise drives severe risks for many coastal communities.
Strategies to manage these risks hinge on a sound characterization of the
uncertainties. For example, recent studies suggest that large fractions of the
Antarctic ice sheet (AIS) may rapidly disintegrate in response to rising global
temperatures, leading to potentially several meters of sea-level rise during
the next few centuries. It is deeply uncertain, for example, whether such an
AIS disintegration will be triggered, how much this would increase sea-level
rise, whether extreme storm surges intensify in a warming climate, or which
emissions pathway future societies will choose. Here, we assess the impacts of
these deep uncertainties on projected flooding probabilities for a levee ring
in New Orleans, Louisiana. We use 18 scenarios, presenting probabilistic
projections within each one, to sample key deeply uncertain future projections
of sea-level rise, radiative forcing pathways, storm surge characterization,
and contributions from rapid AIS mass loss. The implications of these deep
uncertainties for projected flood risk are thus characterized by a set of 18
probability distribution functions. We use a global sensitivity analysis to
assess which mechanisms contribute to uncertainty in projected flood risk over
the course of a 50-year design life. In line with previous work, we find that
the uncertain storm surge drives the most substantial risk, followed by general
AIS dynamics, in our simple model for future flood risk for New Orleans.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00209</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00209</id><created>2017-06-01</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>McAllister</keyname><forenames>Ben T.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Flower</keyname><forenames>Graeme</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kruger</keyname><forenames>Justin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ivanov</keyname><forenames>Eugene N.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Goryachev</keyname><forenames>Maxim</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bourhill</keyname><forenames>Jeremy</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tobar</keyname><forenames>Michael E.</forenames></author></authors><title>The ORGAN Experiment: An axion haloscope above 15 GHz</title><categories>physics.ins-det hep-ex</categories><comments>15 pages, 5 figures. V2: As published in Physics of Dark Universe</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present first results and future plans for the Oscillating Resonant Group
AxioN (ORGAN) experiment, a microwave cavity axion haloscope situated in Perth,
Western Australia designed to probe for high mass axions motivated by several
theoretical models. The first stage focuses around 26.6 GHz in order to
directly test a claimed result, which suggests axions exist at the
corresponding mass of $110~\mu$eV. Later stages will move to a wider scan range
of 15-50 GHz ($60-210~\mu $eV). We present the results of the pathfinding run,
which sets a limit on $g_{a\gamma\gamma}$ of $2.02\times 10^{-12} $eV$^{-1}$ at
26.531 GHz, or 110~$\mu$eV, in a span of 2.5 neV (shaped by the Lorentzian
resonance) with $90 \%$ confidence. Furthermore, we outline the current design
and future strategies to eventually attain the sensitivity to search for well
known axion models over the wider mass range.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.00784</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.00784</id><created>2017-06-02</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Aurell</keyname><forenames>Erik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bo</keyname><forenames>Stefano</forenames></author></authors><title>Steady diffusion in a drift field: a comparison of large deviation
  techniques and multiple-scale analysis</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.soft q-bio.QM</categories><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E 96, 032140 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.032140</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A particle with internal unobserved states diffusing in a force field will
generally display effective advection-diffusion. The drift velocity is
proportional to the mobility averaged over the internal states, or effective
mobility, while the effective diffusion has two terms. One is of the
equilibrium type and satisfies an Einstein relation with the effective mobility
while the other is quadratic in the applied force. In this contribution we
present two new methods to obtain these results, on the one hand using large
deviation techniques, and on the other by a multiple-scale analysis, and
compare the two. We consider both systems with discrete internal states and
continuous internal states. We show that the auxiliary equations in the
multiple-scale analysis can also be derived in second-order perturbation theory
in a large deviation theory of a generating function (discrete internal states)
or generating functional (continuous internal states). We discuss that
measuring the two components of the effective diffusion give a way to determine
kinetic rates from only first and second moments of the displacement in steady
state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.01401</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.01401</id><created>2017-06-05</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Strano</keyname><forenames>Emanuele</forenames></author><author><keyname>Giometto</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shai</keyname><forenames>Saray</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bertuzzo</keyname><forenames>Enrico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mucha</keyname><forenames>Peter J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rinaldo</keyname><forenames>Andrea</forenames></author></authors><title>The scaling structure of the global road network</title><categories>physics.soc-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Because of increasing global urbanization and its immediate consequences,
including changes in patterns of food demand, circulation and land use, the
next century will witness a major increase in the extent of paved roads built
worldwide. To model the effects of this increase, it is crucial to understand
whether possible self-organized patterns are inherent in the global road
network structure. Here, we use the largest updated database comprising all
major roads on Earth, together with global urban and cropland inventories, to
suggest that road length distributions within croplands are indistinguishable
from urban ones, once rescaled to account for the difference in mean road
length. Such similarity extends to road length distributions within urban or
agricultural domains of given area. We find two distinct regimes for the
scaling of the mean road length with the associated area, holding in general at
small and at large values of the latter. In suitably large urban and cropland
domains, we find that mean and total road lengths increase linearly with their
domain area, differently from earlier suggestions. Scaling regimes suggest that
simple and universal mechanisms regulate urban and cropland road expansion at
the global scale. As such, our findings bear implications for global road
infrastructure growth based on land-use change and for planning policies
sustaining urban expansions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02302</id><created>2017-06-07</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gandhi</keyname><forenames>Siddharth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madhusudhan</keyname><forenames>Nikku</forenames></author></authors><title>GENESIS: New Self-Consistent Models of Exoplanetary Spectra</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><comments>24 pages, 16 figures, Published in MNRAS</comments><journal-ref>2017, MNRAS, 472, pp. 2334-2355</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx1601</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We are entering the era of high-precision and high-resolution spectroscopy of
exoplanets. Such observations herald the need for robust self-consistent
spectral models of exoplanetary atmospheres to investigate intricate
atmospheric processes and to make observable predictions. Spectral models of
plane-parallel exoplanetary atmospheres exist, mostly adapted from other
astrophysical applications, with different levels of sophistication and
accuracy. There is a growing need for a new generation of models custom-built
for exoplanets and incorporating state-of-the-art numerical methods and
opacities. The present work is a step in this direction. Here we introduce
GENESIS, a plane-parallel, self-consistent, line-by-line exoplanetary
atmospheric modelling code which includes (a) formal solution of radiative
transfer using the Feautrier method, (b) radiative-convective equilibrium with
temperature correction based on the Rybicki linearisation scheme, (c) latest
absorption cross sections, and (d) internal flux and external irradiation,
under the assumptions of hydrostatic equilibrium, local thermodynamic
equilibrium and thermochemical equilibrium. We demonstrate the code here with
cloud-free models of giant exoplanetary atmospheres over a range of equilibrium
temperatures, metallicities, C/O ratios and spanning non-irradiated and
irradiated planets, with and without thermal inversions. We provide the
community with theoretical emergent spectra and pressure-temperature profiles
over this range, along with those for several known hot Jupiters. The code can
generate self-consistent spectra at high resolution and has the potential to be
integrated into general circulation and non-equilibrium chemistry models as it
is optimised for efficiency and convergence. GENESIS paves the way for
high-fidelity remote sensing of exoplanetary atmospheres at high resolution
with current and upcoming observations.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02517</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02517</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Isakov</keyname><forenames>V. I.</forenames></author></authors><title>On the properties of the $^{229}$Th isotope</title><categories>nucl-th</categories><comments>10 pages, one figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Electromagnetic properties of the deformed neutron-odd nucleus $^{229}$Th are
investigated in the framework of the unified model, with primary emphasis upon
the properties of the low-lying isomeric state.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.02567</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.02567</id><created>2017-06-08</created><updated>2017-08-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Heiba</keyname><forenames>Bassel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Sheng</forenames></author><author><keyname>T&#xe4;uber</keyname><forenames>Uwe C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Boundary Effects on Population Dynamics in Stochastic Lattice
  Lotka-Volterra Models</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.PE</categories><comments>20 pages, 8 figures. to appear in Physica A</comments><journal-ref>Physica A 491 (2018) 582</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physa.2017.09.039</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate spatially inhomogeneous versions of the stochastic
Lotka-Volterra model for predator-prey competition and coexistence by means of
Monte Carlo simulations on a two-dimensional lattice with periodic boundary
conditions. To study boundary effects for this paradigmatic population dynamics
system, we employ a simulation domain split into two patches: Upon setting the
predation rates at two distinct values, one half of the system resides in an
absorbing state where only the prey survives, while the other half attains a
stable coexistence state wherein both species remain active. At the domain
boundary, we observe a marked enhancement of the predator population density.
The predator correlation length displays a minimum at the boundary, before
reaching its asymptotic constant value deep in the active region. The frequency
of the population oscillations appears only very weakly affected by the
existence of two distinct domains, in contrast to their attenuation rate, which
assumes its largest value there. We also observe that boundary effects become
less prominent as the system is successively divided into subdomains in a
checkerboard pattern, with two different reaction rates assigned to neighboring
patches. When the domain size becomes reduced to the scale of the correlation
length, the mean population densities attain values that are very similar to
those in a disordered system with randomly assigned reaction rates drawn from a
bimodal distribution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03229</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03229</id><created>2017-06-10</created><updated>2017-06-15</updated><authors><author><keyname>Athanasopoulos</keyname><forenames>Nikolaos</forenames></author><author><keyname>Siakavellas</keyname><forenames>Nicolaos J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Smart patterned surfaces with programmable thermal emissivity and their
  design through combinatorial strategies</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>30 pages, 6 Figures, 6 Supplementary Figures, 7 Supplementary Tables</comments><journal-ref>Scientific Reports, 7, Article number: 12908, 10 October 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1038/s41598-017-13132-6</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The emissivity of common materials remains constant with temperature
variations, and cannot drastically change. However, it is possible to design
its entire behaviour as a function of temperature, and to significantly modify
the thermal emissivity of a surface through the combination of different
materials and patterns. Here, we show that smart patterned surfaces consisting
of smaller structures (motifs) may be designed to respond uniquely through
combinatorial design strategies by transforming themselves from 2D to 3D
complex structures with a two-way shape memory effect. The smart surfaces can
passively manipulate thermal radiation without-the use of controllers and power
supplies-because their modus operandi has already been programmed and
integrated into their intrinsic characteristics; the environment provides the
energy required for their activation. Each motif emits thermal radiation in a
certain manner, as it changes its geometry; however, the spatial distribution
of these motifs causes them to interact with each other. Therefore, their
combination and interaction determine the global behaviour of the surfaces,
thus enabling their a priori design. The emissivity behaviour is not random; it
is determined by two fundamental parameters, namely the combination of
orientations in which the motifs open (n-fold rotational symmetry (rn)) and the
combination of materials (colours) on the motifs; these generate functions
which fully determine the dependency of the emissivity on the temperature.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.03693</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.03693</id><created>2017-06-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Gao</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zheng</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>L. L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonasera</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Description of Charged Particle Pseudorapidity Distributions in Pb+Pb
  Collisions with Tsallis Thermodynamics</title><categories>nucl-th hep-ph</categories><comments>9 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Eur. Phys. J. A (2017) 53: 197</journal-ref><doi>10.1140/epja/i2017-12397-y</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The centrality dependence of pseudorapidity distributions for charged
particles produced in Au+Au collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}=130$ GeV and 200 GeV
at RHIC, and in Pb+Pb collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}=2.76$ TeV at LHC are
investigated in the fireball model, assuming that the rapidity axis is
populated with fireballs following one distribution function. We assume that
the particles in the fireball fulfill the Tsallis distribution. The theoretical
results are compared with the experimental measurements and a good agreement is
found. Using these results, the pseudorapidity distributions of charged
particles produced in Pb+Pb central collisions at $\sqrt{s_{NN}}=5.02$ TeV and
10 TeV are predicted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08692</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08692</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Guan</keyname><forenames>Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Liu</keyname><forenames>Ying</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yu</keyname><forenames>Zhi-Ming</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Shan-Shan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yao</keyname><forenames>Yugui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Shengyuan A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Two-dimensional Spin-Orbit Dirac Point in Monolayer HfGeTe</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>9 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. Materials 1, 054003 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevMaterials.1.054003</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dirac points in two-dimensional (2D) materials have been a fascinating
subject of research, with graphene as the most prominent example. However, the
Dirac points in existing 2D materials, including graphene, are vulnerable
against spin-orbit coupling (SOC). Here, based on first-principles calculations
and theoretical analysis, we propose a new family of stable 2D materials, the
HfGeTe-family monolayers, which represent the first example to host so-called
spin-orbit Dirac points (SDPs) close to the Fermi level. These Dirac points are
special in that they are formed only under significant SOC, hence they are
intrinsically robust against SOC. We show that the existence of a pair of SDPs
are dictated by the nonsymmorphic space group symmetry of the system, which are
very robust under various types of lattice strains. The energy, the dispersion,
and the valley occupation around the Dirac points can be effectively tuned by
strain. We construct a low-energy effective model to characterize the Dirac
fermions around the SDPs. Furthermore, we find that the material is
simultaneously a 2D $\mathbb{Z}_2$ topological metal, which possesses
nontrivial $\mathbb{Z}_2$ invariant in the bulk and spin-helical edge states on
the boundary. From the calculated exfoliation energies and mechanical
properties, we show that these materials can be readily obtained in experiment
from the existing bulk materials. Our result reveals HfGeTe-family monolayers
as a promising platform for exploring spin-orbit Dirac fermions and novel
topological phases in two-dimensions.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1706.08993</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1706.08993</id><created>2017-06-27</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Quan</keyname><forenames>Xinfeng</forenames></author><author><keyname>Madura</keyname><forenames>Jeffry D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hutchison</keyname><forenames>Geoffrey R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Self-Assembled Monolayer Piezoelectrics: Electric-Field Driven
  Conformational Changes</title><categories>physics.app-ph cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>22 pages, 3 figures Keywords: Molecular springs, piezoelectrics,
  self-assembled monolayers, electromechanical materials</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We demonstrate that an applied electric field causes piezoelectric distortion
across single molecular monolayers of oligopeptides. We deposited
self-assembled monolayers ~1.5 nm high onto smooth gold surfaces. These
monolayers exhibit strong piezoelectric response that varies linearly with
applied bias (1-3V), measured using piezoresponse force microscopy (PFM). The
response is markedly greater than control experiments with rigid alkanethiols
and correlates with surface spectroscopy and theoretical predictions of
conformational change from applied electric fields. Unlike existing
piezoelectric oxides, our peptide monolayers are intrinsically flexible, easily
fabricated, aligned and patterned without poling.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.00025</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.00025</id><created>2017-06-30</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Armata</keyname><forenames>Federico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Latmiral</keyname><forenames>Ludovico</forenames></author><author><keyname>Plato</keyname><forenames>A. D. K</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>M. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum limits to gravity estimation with optomechanics</title><categories>quant-ph cond-mat.mes-hall physics.optics</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. A 96, 043824 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevA.96.043824</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a table-top quantum estimation protocol to measure the
gravitational acceleration $g$ by using an optomechanical cavity. In
particular, we exploit the non-linear quantum light-matter interaction between
an optical field and a massive mirror acting as mechanical oscillator. The
gravitational field influences the system dynamics affecting the phase of the
cavity field during the interaction. Reading out such phase carried by the
radiation leaking from the cavity, we provide an estimate of the gravitational
acceleration through interference measurements. Contrary to previous studies,
having adopted a fully quantum description, we are able to propose a quantum
analysis proving the ultimate bound to the estimability of the gravitational
acceleration and verifying optimality of homodyne detection. Noticeably, thanks
to the light-matter decoupling at the measurement time, no initial cooling of
the mechanical oscillator is in principle demanded.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.05755</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.05755</id><created>2017-07-18</created><authors><author><keyname>Smirnov</keyname><forenames>Ivan</forenames></author></authors><title>The Digital Flynn Effect: Complexity of Posts on Social Media Increases
  over Time</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.SI</categories><doi>10.1007/978-3-319-67256-4_3</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Parents and teachers often express concern about the extensive use of social
media by youngsters. Some of them see emoticons, undecipherable initialisms and
loose grammar typical for social media as evidence of language degradation. In
this paper, we use a simple measure of text complexity to investigate how the
complexity of public posts on a popular social networking site changes over
time. We analyze a unique dataset that contains texts posted by 942, 336 users
from a large European city across nine years. We show that the chosen
complexity measure is correlated with the academic performance of users: users
from high-performing schools produce more complex texts than users from
low-performing schools. We also find that complexity of posts increases with
age. Finally, we demonstrate that overall language complexity of posts on the
social networking site is constantly increasing. We call this phenomenon the
digital Flynn effect. Our results may suggest that the worries about language
degradation are not warranted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.07392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.07392</id><created>2017-07-23</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Iorsh</keyname><forenames>I. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dini</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kibis</keyname><forenames>O. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Shelykh</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Optically induced Lifshitz transition in bilayer graphene</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>Published version</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 155432 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.155432</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  It is shown theoretically that the renormalization of the electron energy
spectrum of bilayer graphene with a strong high-frequency electromagnetic field
(dressing field) results in the Lifshitz transition - the abrupt change in the
topology of the Fermi surface near the band edge. This effect substantially
depends on the polarization of the field: The linearly polarized dressing field
induces the Lifshitz transition from the quadruply-connected Fermi surface to
the doubly-connected one, whereas the circularly polarized field induces the
multicritical point, where the four different Fermi topologies may coexist. As
a consequence, the discussed phenomenon creates physical basis to control the
electronic properties of bilayer graphene with light.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08416</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08416</id><created>2017-07-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Abdullah</keyname><forenames>Nzar Rauf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tang</keyname><forenames>Chi-Shung</forenames></author><author><keyname>Manolescu</keyname><forenames>Andrei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gudmundsson</keyname><forenames>Vidar</forenames></author></authors><title>Spin-dependent heat and thermoelectric currents in a Rashba ring coupled
  to a photon cavity</title><categories>cond-mat.mes-hall</categories><comments>RevTeX, 16 pages with 14 eps-figures included</comments><journal-ref>Physica E 95, 102 (2018)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physe.2017.09.011</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Spin-dependent heat and thermoelectric currents in a quantum ring with Rashba
spin-orbit interaction placed in a photon cavity are theoretically calculated.
The quantum ring is coupled to two external leads with different temperatures.
In a resonant regime, with the ring structure in resonance with the photon
field, the heat and the thermoelectric currents can be controlled by the Rashba
spin-orbit interaction. The heat current is suppressed in the presence of the
photon field due to contribution of the two-electron and photon replica states
to the transport while the thermoelectric current is not sensitive to changes
in parameters of the photon field. Our study opens a possibility to use the
proposed interferometric device as a tunable heat current generator in the
cavity photon field.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.08466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.08466</id><created>2017-07-26</created><updated>2017-09-28</updated><authors><author><keyname>Monnai</keyname><forenames>Akihiko</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ollitrault</keyname><forenames>Jean-Yves</forenames></author></authors><title>Constraining the equation of state with identified particle spectra</title><categories>nucl-th hep-lat hep-ph nucl-ex</categories><comments>12 pages, 8 figures; minor revision</comments><report-no>Saclay t17/132</report-no><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. C 96, 044902 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevC.96.044902</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that in a central nucleus-nucleus collision, the variation of the
mean transverse mass with the multiplicity is determined, up to a rescaling, by
the variation of the energy over entropy ratio as a function of the entropy
density, thus providing a direct link between experimental data and the
equation of state. Each colliding energy thus probes the equation of state at
an effective entropy density, whose approximate value is $19$ fm$^{-3}$ for
Au+Au collisions at 200 GeV and $41$ fm$^{-3}$ for Pb+Pb collisions at 2.76
TeV, corresponding to temperatures of $227$ MeV and $279$ MeV if the equation
of state is taken from lattice calculations. The relative change of the mean
transverse mass as a function of the colliding energy gives a direct measure of
the pressure over energy density ratio $P/\epsilon$, at the corresponding
effective density. Using RHIC and LHC data, we obtain $P/\epsilon=0.21\pm
0.10$, in agreement with the lattice value $P/\epsilon=0.23$ in the
corresponding temperature range. Measurements over a wide range of colliding
energies using a single detector with good particle identification would help
reducing the error.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09170</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09170</id><created>2017-07-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Sabli&#x107;</keyname><forenames>Jurij</forenames></author><author><keyname>Delgado-Buscalioni</keyname><forenames>Rafael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Praprotnik</keyname><forenames>Matej</forenames></author></authors><title>Application of the Eckart frame to soft matter: rotation of star
  polymers under shear flow</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>29 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Soft Matter {\bf 13}, 6988-7000, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1039/C7SM00616K</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The Eckart co-rotating frame is used to analyze the dynamics of star polymers
under shear flow, either in melt or solution and with different types of bonds.
This formalism is compared with the standard approach used in many previous
studies on polymer dynamics, where an apparent angular velocity $\omega$ is
obtained from relation between the tensor of inertia and angular momentum. A
common mistake is to interpret $\omega$ as the molecular rotation frequency,
which is only valid for rigid-body rotation. The Eckart frame, originally
formulated to analyze the infrared spectra of small molecules, dissects
different kinds of displacements: vibrations without angular momentum, pure
rotation, and vibrational angular momentum (leading to a Coriolis cross-term).
The Eckart frame co-rotates with the molecule with an angular frequency
$\Omega$ obtained from the Eckart condition for minimal coupling between
rotation and vibration. The standard and Eckart approaches are compared with a
straight description of the star's dynamics taken from the time autocorrelation
of the monomers positions moving around the molecule's center of mass. This is
an underdamped oscillatory signal, which can be described by a rotation
frequency $\omega_R$ and a decorrelation rate $\Gamma$. We consistently find
that $\Omega$ coincides with $\omega_R$, which determines the characteristic
tank-treading rotation of the star. By contrast, the apparent angular velocity
$\omega &lt; \Omega$ does not discern between pure rotation and molecular
vibrations. We believe that the Eckart frame will be useful to unveil the
dynamics of semiflexible molecules where rotation and deformations are
entangled, including tumbling, tank-treading motions and breathing modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1707.09288</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1707.09288</id><created>2017-07-26</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Athanasiadis</keyname><forenames>Ignatios</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wheeler</keyname><forenames>Simon J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grassl</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Hydro-mechanical network modelling of particulate composites</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Differential shrinkage in particulate quasi-brittle materials causes
microcracking which reduces durability in these materials by increasing their
mass transport properties. A hydro-mechanical three-dimensional periodic
network approach was used to investigate the influence of particle and specimen
size on the specimen permeability. The particulate quasi-brittle materials
studied here consist of stiff elastic particles, and a softer matrix and
interfacial transition zones between matrix and particles exhibiting nonlinear
material responses. An incrementally applied uniform eigenstrain, along with a
damage-plasticity constitutive model, are used to describe the shrinkage and
cracking processes of the matrix and interfacial transition zones. The results
showed that increasing particle diameter at constant volume fraction increases
the crack widths and, therefore, permeability, which confirms previously
obtained 2D modelling results. Furthermore, it was demonstrated that specimen
thickness has, in comparison to the influence of particle size, a small
influence on permeability increase due to microcracking.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1708.01255</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1708.01255</id><created>2017-08-03</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>de Oliveira</keyname><forenames>E. Capelas</forenames></author><author><keyname>Menon</keyname><forenames>M. J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Silva</keyname><forenames>P. V. R. G.</forenames></author></authors><title>Analytic components for the hadronic total cross-section: Fractional
  calculus and Mellin transform</title><categories>hep-ph math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 pages, 2 figures, 1 table, text revised (including title and
  abstract), references and discussion on Mellin transform added, some
  statements corrected. Analytic and fit results are the same as v1</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In high-energy hadron-hadron collisions, the dependence of the total
cross-section ($\sigma_{tot}$) with the energy still constitutes an open
problem for QCD. Phenomenological analyses usually relies on analytic
parameterizations provided by the Regge-Gribov formalism and fits to the
experimental data. In this framework, the singularities of the scattering
amplitude in the complex angular momentum plane determine the asymptotic
behavior of $\sigma_{tot}$ in terms of the energy. Usual applications connect
simple and triple pole singularities with asymptotic power and
logarithmic-squared functions of the energy, respectively. More restrict
applications have considered as a leading component for $\sigma_{tot}$ an
empirical function consisting of a logarithmic raised to a real exponent, which
is treated as a free fit parameter. With this function, data reductions lead to
good descriptions of the experimental data and real (not integer) values of the
exponent. In this paper, making use of two independent formalisms (fractional
calculus and Mellin transform), we first show that the singularity associated
with this empirical function is a branch point and then we explore the
mathematical consequences of the result and possible physical interpretations.
After reviewing the determination of the singularities from asymptotic forms of
interest through the Mellin transform, we demonstrate that the same analytic
results can be obtained by means of the Caputo fractional derivative, leading,
therefore, to fractional calculus interpretations. Besides correlating Mellin
transform, non-local fractional derivatives and exploring the generalization
from integer to real exponents and derivative orders, this fractional calculus
result may provide insights for physical interpretations on the asymptotic rise
of $\sigma_{tot}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.00070</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.00070</id><created>2017-08-31</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Jafarzade</keyname><forenames>Shahriyar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nazari</keyname><forenames>Zainab</forenames></author></authors><title>A New Integrable Ising-type Model from 2d $\mathcal{N}$=(2,2) Dualities</title><categories>hep-th cond-mat.stat-mech math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>21 pages, 6 figures</comments><msc-class>81T60, 16T25, 14K25</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We show that the equality of 2d $\mathcal{N}$=(2,2) supersymmetric indices in
Seiberg-type duality leads to a new integrable Ising-type model. The emergence
of the new model is the result of correspondence between the supersymmetric
$SU(2)$ quiver gauge theories and the Yang-Baxter equation. Using this
correspondence, we solve the star-triangle relation and obtain the
two-dimensional exactly solvable spin model. The model corresponding to our
solution possesses continuous spin variables on the circle and the Boltzmann
weights are demonstrated in terms of Jacobi theta function. Using the solution
of the star-triangle relation, we also construct interaction-round-a-face and
vertex models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.04171</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.04171</id><created>2017-09-13</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Collion</keyname><forenames>Stephane</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vaugon</keyname><forenames>Michel</forenames></author></authors><title>Multi-Fibers Bundles as a new model for high-dimensional Spacetimes</title><categories>math.DG gr-qc</categories><comments>16 pages. Extract of another work emphasizing a mathematical aspect.
  Added :details on notations, correction in the last theorem. arXiv admin
  note: text overlap with arXiv:1010.1516; substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1709.04172</comments><msc-class>83C22, 83E05, 83E15</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Around 1920, Kaluza and Klein had the idea to add a fifth dimension to the
classical 4-dimensional spacetime of general relativity to create a geometric
theory of gravitation and electromagnetism. Today, theoretical evidences, like
string theory, suggest the need for a spacetime with more than five dimensions.
  We want to present in this paper a mathematical structure generalizing the
fiber bundle structure to the case of a product fiber of the form $F=S \times
W$, that enable the possible definition of multiple naturally defined fibers at
each point of the manifold, on which therefore one can define objects that
depend only on one of the components of the global fiber.
  Although we do not pretend here to model precisely other known physical
interactions, we present this geometric structure as a possible way to model or
encode deviations from standard 4-dimensional General Relativity, or &quot;dark&quot;
effects such as dark matter or energy ; (we refer to the authors' article [3]
). Also this geometry was a starting point for the second author's new approach
to a geometric unification of General Relativity and Quantum Physics ( see
[23]).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.05081</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.05081</id><created>2017-09-15</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Fairoos</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ghosh</keyname><forenames>Avirup</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sarkar</keyname><forenames>Sudipta</forenames></author></authors><title>Massless charged particles: Cosmic censorship, and Third law of Black
  Hole Mechanics</title><categories>gr-qc</categories><comments>12 pages, 9 figures, Minor changes in the reference section</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. D 96, 084013 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevD.96.084013</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The formulation of the laws of black hole mechanics assumes the stability of
black holes under perturbations in accordance with the &quot;cosmic censorship
hypothesis&quot;(CCH). CCH prohibits the formation of a naked singularity by a
physical process from a regular black hole solution with an event horizon.
Earlier studies show that naked singularities can indeed be formed leading to
the violation of CCH if a near-extremal black hole is injected with massive
charged particles and the back reaction effects are neglected. We investigate
the validity of CCH by considering the infall of charged massless particles as
well as a charged null shell. We also discuss the issue of third law of black
hole mechanics in the presence of null charged particles by considering various
possibilities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.07724</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.07724</id><created>2017-09-22</created><authors><author><keyname>Cr&#xe9;pin</keyname><forenames>P. -P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kupriyanova</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gu&#xe9;rout</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lambrecht</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nesvizhevsky</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Reynaud</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Voronin</keyname><forenames>A. Yu.</forenames></author></authors><title>Quantum reflection of antihydrogen from a liquid helium film</title><categories>physics.atom-ph</categories><journal-ref>EPL, 119 (2017) 33001</journal-ref><doi>10.1209/0295-5075/119/33001</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the quantum reflection of ultracold antihydrogen atoms bouncing on
the surface of a liquid helium film. The Casimir-Polder potential and quantum
reflection are calculated for different thicknesses of the film supported by
different substrates. Antihydrogen can be protected from anni- hilation for as
long as 1.3s on a bulk of liquid 4He, and 1.7s for liquid 3He. These large
lifetimes open interesting perspectives for spectroscopic measurements of the
free fall acceleration of antihydrogen. Variation of the scattering length with
the thickness of a film of helium shows interferences which we interpret
through a Liouville transformation of the quantum reflection problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.08948</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.08948</id><created>2017-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Smilgys</keyname><forenames>R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonnell</keyname><forenames>I. A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Formation of stellar clusters</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>10 pages; 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>MNRAS; Volume 472; Pages 4982,4991; 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1093/mnras/stx2396</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate the triggering of star formation and the formation of stellar
clusters in molecular clouds that form as the ISM passes through spiral shocks.
The spiral shock compresses gas into $\sim$100 pc long main star formation
ridge, where clusters forming every 5-10 pc along the merger ridge. We use a
gravitational potential based cluster finding algorithm, which extracts
individual clusters, calculates their physical properties and traces cluster
evolution over multiple time steps. Final cluster masses at the end of
simulation range between 1000 and 30000 M$_{\odot}$ with their characteristic
half-mass radii between 0.1 pc and 2 pc. These clusters form by gathering
material from 10-20 pc size scales. Clusters also show a mass - specific
angular momentum relation, where more massive clusters have larger specific
angular momentum due to the larger size scales, and hence angular momentum from
which they gather their mass. The evolution shows that more massive clusters
experiences hierarchical merging process, which increases stellar age spreads
up to 2-3 Myr. Less massive clusters appear to grow by gathering nearby
recently formed sinks, while more massive clusters with their large global
gravitational potentials are increasing their mass growth from gas accretion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.09201</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.09201</id><created>2017-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Weiyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Song</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hu</keyname><forenames>Ding</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Rui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Harriger</keyname><forenames>L. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tian</keyname><forenames>Wei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Cao</keyname><forenames>Huibo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dai</keyname><forenames>Pengcheng</forenames></author></authors><title>Local breaking of four-fold rotational symmetry by short-range magnetic
  order in heavily overdoped Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Cu$_{x}$)$_{2}$As$_{2}$</title><categories>cond-mat.supr-con cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>accepted by Physical Review B Rapid Communications</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. B 96, 161106(R), (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevB.96.161106</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We investigate Cu-doped Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$)$_2$As$_2$ with transport,
magnetic susceptibility, and elastic neutron scattering measurements. In the
heavily Cu-doped regime where long-range stripe-type antiferromagnetic order in
BaFe$_2$As$_2$ is suppressed, Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$)$_2$As$_2$ (0.145 $\leq x
\leq$ 0.553) samples exhibit spin-glass-like behavior in magnetic
susceptibility and insulating-like temperature dependence in electrical
transport. Using elastic neutron scattering, we find stripe-type short-range
magnetic order in the spin-glass region identified by susceptibility
measurements. The persistence of short-range magnetic order over a large doping
range in Ba(Fe$_{1-x}$Cu$_x$)$_2$As$_2$ likely arises from local arrangements
of Fe and Cu that favor magnetic order, with Cu acting as vacancies relieving
magnetic frustration and degeneracy. These results indicate locally broken
four-fold rotational symmetry, suggesting that stripe-type magnetism is
ubiquitous in iron pnictides.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.09863</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.09863</id><created>2017-09-28</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Hirano</keyname><forenames>Shingo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hosokawa</keyname><forenames>Takashi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yoshida</keyname><forenames>Naoki</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuiper</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author></authors><title>Supersonic Gas Streams Enhance the Formation of Massive Black Holes in
  the Early Universe</title><categories>astro-ph.CO astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>Published in Science, combined with updated SOM, additional images
  and movies are available at
  http://www-utap.phys.s.u-tokyo.ac.jp/naoki.yoshida/Blackhole/0929e.html</comments><doi>10.1126/science.aai9119</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The origin of super-massive black holes in the early universe remains poorly
understood.Gravitational collapse of a massive primordial gas cloud is a
promising initial process,but theoretical studies have difficulty growing the
black hole fast enough.We report numerical simulations of early black hole
formation starting from realistic cosmological conditions.Supersonic gas
motions left over from the Big Bang prevent early gas cloud formation until
rapid gas condensation is triggered in a proto-galactic halo. A protostar is
formed in the dense, turbulent gas cloud, and it grows by sporadic mass
accretion until it acquires 34,000 solar masses.The massive star ends its life
with a catastrophic collapse to leave a black hole -- a promising seed for the
formation of a monstrous black hole.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.09871</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.09871</id><created>2017-09-28</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Riegler</keyname><forenames>Max</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zwikel</keyname><forenames>C&#xe9;line</forenames></author></authors><title>Canonical Charges in Flatland</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>37 pages; v2: added references</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this series of lectures we give an introduction to the concept of
asymptotic symmetry analysis with a focus on asymptotically flat spacetimes in
2+1 dimensions. We explain general ideas of quantizing gauge theories and then
apply these ideas to gravity both in the metric as well as the Chern-Simons
formulations. This enables one to compute the asymptotic symmetries of given
gravitational configurations that in turn act as the basic underlying
symmetries of a possible dual quantum field theory in the context of
holography. We also briefly elaborate on the concept of &quot;soft hair&quot; excitations
of black holes in this context.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.10136</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.10136</id><created>2017-09-28</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Koro&#x161;ak</keyname><forenames>Dean</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rupnik</keyname><forenames>Marjan Slak</forenames></author></authors><title>Collective sensing of $\beta$-cells generates the metabolic code at
  optimal islet size</title><categories>physics.bio-ph cond-mat.stat-mech q-bio.CB q-bio.QM</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Major part of a pancreatic islet is composed of beta cells that secrete
insulin, a key hormone regulating influx of nutrients into all cells in a
vertebrate organism to support nutrition, housekeeping or energy storage. Beta
cells constantly communicate with each other using both direct, short-range
interactions through gap junctions, and paracrine long-range signaling.
However, how these cell interactions shape collective sensing and cell behavior
in islets that leads to insulin release is unknown. When stimulated by specific
ligands, primarily glucose, beta cells collectively respond with expression of
a series of transient Ca$^{2+}$ changes on several temporal scales. Here we
analyze a set of Ca$^{2+}$ spike trains recorded in acute rodent pancreatic
tissue slice under physiological conditions. We found strongly correlated
states of co-spiking cells coexisting with mostly weak pairwise correlations
widespread across the islet. Furthermore, the collective Ca$^{2+}$ spiking
activity in islet shows on-off intermittency with scaling of spiking
amplitudes, and stimulus dependent autoassociative memory features. We use a
simple spin glass-like model for the functional network of a beta cell
collective to describe these findings and argue that Ca$^{2+}$ spike trains
produced by collective sensing of beta cells constitute part of the islet
metabolic code that regulates insulin release and limits the islet size.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1709.10493</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1709.10493</id><created>2017-09-29</created><authors><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Mohan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ko</keyname><forenames>Hsin-Yu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Remsing</keyname><forenames>Richard C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Andrade</keyname><forenames>Marcos F. Calegari</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santra</keyname><forenames>Biswajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Zhaoru</forenames></author><author><keyname>Selloni</keyname><forenames>Annabella</forenames></author><author><keyname>Car</keyname><forenames>Roberto</forenames></author><author><keyname>Klein</keyname><forenames>Michael L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perdew</keyname><forenames>John P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wu</keyname><forenames>Xifan</forenames></author></authors><title>Ab initio theory and modeling of water</title><categories>cond-mat.soft cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.chem-ph physics.comp-ph</categories><journal-ref>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci., 114, 10846 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1073/pnas.1712499114</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Water is of the utmost importance for life and technology. However, a
genuinely predictive ab initio model of water has eluded scientists. We
demonstrate that a fully ab initio approach, relying on the strongly
constrained and appropriately normed (SCAN) density functional, provides such a
description of water. SCAN accurately describes the balance among covalent
bonds, hydrogen bonds, and van der Waals interactions that dictates the
structure and dynamics of liquid water. Notably, SCAN captures the density
difference between water and ice I{\it h} at ambient conditions, as well as
many important structural, electronic, and dynamic properties of liquid water.
These successful predictions of the versatile SCAN functional open the gates to
study complex processes in aqueous phase chemistry and the interactions of
water with other materials in an efficient, accurate, and predictive, ab initio
manner.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.00651</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.00651</id><created>2017-09-24</created><authors><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Yiwen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lin</keyname><forenames>Charles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chang</keyname><forenames>PoHan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helmy</keyname><forenames>Amr S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Highly Sensitive Wavelength-scale Amorphous Hybrid Plasmonic Detectors</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>4 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Optica Vol. 4, Issue 10, pp. 1259-1262 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1364/OPTICA.4.001259</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Hybrid integration of plasmonics and Si photonics is a promising architecture
for global microprocessor interconnects. To this end, practical plasmonic
devices not only should provide athermal, broadband operation over
wavelength-scale footprint, but also support non-intrusive integration with
low-loss Si waveguides as well as CMOS back-end-of-line processes. Here, we
demonstrate a hybrid plasmonic photodetector with a single active junction
fabricated via back-end deposited amorphous materials coupled to Si nanowires
with only 1.5dB loss. Utilizing internal photoemission, our detectors measured
sensitivity of -35dBm in a 620nm by 5{\mu}m footprint at 7V bias. Moreover,
responsivity up to 0.4mA/W and dark current down to 0.2nA were obtained. The
high process tolerance is demonstrated between {\lambda}=1.2-1.8{\mu}m and up
to 100{\deg}C. The results suggest the potential towards plasmonic-photonic
optoelectronic integration on top of Si chips without costly process
modifications.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.02263</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.02263</id><created>2017-10-05</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Bagchi</keyname><forenames>Debarshee</forenames></author></authors><title>Energy transport in the presence of long-range interactions</title><categories>cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><comments>7 pages, 6 figures</comments><journal-ref>Phys. Rev. E, 96, 042121 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1103/PhysRevE.96.042121</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study energy transport in the paradigmatic Hamiltonian mean-field (HMF)
model and other related long-range interacting models using molecular dynamics
simulations. We show that energy diffusion in the HMF model is subdiffusive in
nature, which confirms a recently obtained intriguing result that, despite
being globally interacting, this model is a thermal insulator in the thermo-
dynamic limit. Surprisingly, when additional nearest neighbor interactions are
introduced to the HMF model, an energy superdiffusion is observed. We show that
these results can be consistently explained by studying energy localization due
to thermally generated intrinsic localized excitation modes (discrete
breathers) in nonlinear discrete systems. Our analysis for the HMF model can
also be readily extended to more generic long-range interacting models where
the interaction strength decays algebraically with the (shortest) distance
between two lattice sites. This reconciles many of the apparently
counter-intuitive results presented recently [C. Olivares and C. Anteneodo,
Phys. Rev. E 94, 042117 (2016); D. Bagchi, Phys. Rev. E 95, 032102 (2017)]
concerning energy transport in two such long-range interacting models.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03326</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03326</id><created>2017-10-09</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Gildersleve</keyname><forenames>Patrick</forenames></author><author><keyname>Yasseri</keyname><forenames>Taha</forenames></author></authors><title>Inspiration, Captivation, and Misdirection: Emergent Properties in
  Networks of Online Navigation</title><categories>physics.soc-ph cs.CY cs.SI physics.data-an</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The World Wide Web (WWW) has fundamentally changed the ways billions of
people are able to access information. Thus, understanding how people seek
information online is an important issue of study. Wikipedia is a hugely
important part of information provision on the web, with hundreds of millions
of users browsing and contributing to its network of knowledge. The study of
navigational behaviour on Wikipedia, due to the site's popularity and breadth
of content, can reveal more general information seeking patterns that may be
applied beyond Wikipedia and the Web. Our work addresses the relative
shortcomings of existing literature in relating how information structure
influences patterns of navigation online. We study aggregated clickstream data
for articles on the English Wikipedia in the form of a weighted, directed
navigational network. We introduce two parameters that describe how articles
act to source and spread traffic through the network, based on their in/out
strength and entropy. From these, we construct a navigational phase space where
different article types occupy different, distinct regions, indicating how the
structure of information online has differential effects on patterns of
navigation. Finally, we go on to suggest applications for this analysis in
identifying and correcting deficiencies in the Wikipedia page network that may
also be adapted to more general information networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.03584</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.03584</id><created>2017-10-10</created><updated>2017-10-11</updated><authors><author><keyname>Wang</keyname><forenames>Mengjia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Hongyi</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kovalevitch</keyname><forenames>Tatiana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salut</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kim</keyname><forenames>Myun-Sik</forenames></author><author><keyname>Suarez</keyname><forenames>Miguel Angel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bernal</keyname><forenames>Maria-Pilar</forenames></author><author><keyname>Herzig</keyname><forenames>Hans-Peter</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lu</keyname><forenames>Huihui</forenames></author><author><keyname>Grosjean</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author></authors><title>Magnetic spin-orbit interaction directs Bloch surface waves</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study the directional excitation of optical surface waves controlled by
the magnetic field of light. We theoretically predict that a spinning magnetic
dipole develops a tunable unidirectional coupling of light to TE-polarized
Bloch surface waves (BSWs). Experimentally, we show that the helicity of light
projected onto a subwavelength groove milled in the top layer of a 1D photonic
crystal (PC) controls the power distribution between two TE-polarized BSWs
excited on both sides of the groove. Such a phenomenon is shown to be mediated
solely by the helicity of the magnetic field of light, thus revealing a
magnetic spin-orbit interaction. Remarkably, this magnetic optical effect is
clearly observed with a near-field coupler governed by an electric dipole
moment: it is of the same order of magnitude as the electric optical effects
involved in the coupling. The magnetic spin-orbit interaction opens new degrees
of freedom in the manipulation of light and offers appealing novel
opportunities in the development of integrated optical functionalities.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04066</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04066</id><created>2017-10-11</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Yang</keyname><forenames>Jun</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhu</keyname><forenames>Zuo-Nong</forenames></author></authors><title>A coupled focusing-defocusing complex short pulse equation:
  multisoliton, breather, and rogue wave</title><categories>nlin.SI</categories><comments>26 pages, 16 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Nonlinear Schr\&quot;odinger equation, short pulse equation and complex short
pulse equation have important application in nonlinear optics. They can be
derived from the Maxwell equation. In this paper, we investigate a coupled
focusing-defocusing complex short pulse equation.
  The bright-bright, bright-dark and dark-dark soliton solutions of the coupled
focusing-defocusing complex short pulse equation are given.
  Then the breathers are derived from the dark soliton solution. The rogue wave
solutions are also constructed.
  The dynamics and the asymptotic behavior of the soliton solutions are
analyzed, which reveals that there exist the elastic or inelastic collision in
bright-bright soliton solution. But the interactions of bright-dark and
dark-dark soliton solutions are both elastic.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04177</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04177</id><created>2017-10-11</created><updated>2017-10-12</updated><authors><author><keyname>Mattie</keyname><forenames>Heather</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eng&#xf8;-Monsen</keyname><forenames>Kenth</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ling</keyname><forenames>Rich</forenames></author><author><keyname>Onnela</keyname><forenames>Jukka-Pekka</forenames></author></authors><title>The Social Bow Tie</title><categories>cs.SI physics.soc-ph stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Understanding tie strength in social networks, and the factors that influence
it, have received much attention in a myriad of disciplines for decades.
Several models incorporating indicators of tie strength have been proposed and
used to quantify relationships in social networks, and a standard set of
structural network metrics have been applied to predominantly online social
media sites to predict tie strength. Here, we introduce the concept of the
&quot;social bow tie&quot; framework, a small subgraph of the network that consists of a
collection of nodes and ties that surround a tie of interest, forming a
topological structure that resembles a bow tie. We also define several
intuitive and interpretable metrics that quantify properties of the bow tie. We
use random forests and regression models to predict categorical and continuous
measures of tie strength from different properties of the bow tie, including
nodal attributes. We also investigate what aspects of the bow tie are most
predictive of tie strength in two distinct social networks: a collection of 75
rural villages in India and a nationwide call network of European mobile phone
users. Our results indicate several of the bow tie metrics are highly
predictive of tie strength, and we find the more the social circles of two
individuals overlap, the stronger their tie, consistent with previous findings.
However, we also find that the more tightly-knit their non-overlapping social
circles, the weaker the tie. This new finding complements our current
understanding of what drives the strength of ties in social networks.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04206</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04206</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Srivastava</keyname><forenames>Deepa</forenames></author><author><keyname>Das</keyname><forenames>Bhargab</forenames></author></authors><title>Pico-strain-level dynamic perturbation measurement using {\pi}FBG sensor</title><categories>physics.ins-det physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Interferometric interrogation technique realized for conventional fiber Bragg
grating (FBG) sensors is historically known to offer the highest sensitivity
measurements, however, it has not been yet explored for {\pi}-phase-shifted FBG
({\pi}FBG) sensors. This, we believe, is due to the complex nature of the
reflection/transmission spectrum of a {\pi}FBG, which cannot be directly used
for interferometric interrogation purpose. Therefore, we propose here an
innovative as well as simple concept towards this direction, wherein, the
transmission spectrum of a {\pi}FBG sensor is optically filtered using a
specially designed fiber grating. The resulting filtered spectrum retains the
entire characteristics of a {\pi}FBG sensor and hence the filtered spectrum can
be interrogated with interferometric principles. Furthermore, due to the
extremely narrow transmission notch of a {\pi}FBG sensor, a fiber
interferometer can be realized with significantly longer path difference. This
leads to substantially enhanced detection limit as compared to sensors based on
a regular FBG of similar length. Theoretical analysis demonstrate that high
resolution weak dynamic strain measurement down to 4 p{\epsilon}/sqrt(Hz) is
easily achievable.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04216</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04216</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Ron</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hevroni</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maniv</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mograbi</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jin</keyname><forenames>L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jia</keyname><forenames>C. -L.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Urban</keyname><forenames>K. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Markovich</keyname><forenames>G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dagan</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author></authors><title>Solution Monolayer Epitaxy for Tunable Atomically Sharp Oxide Interfaces</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el cond-mat.mes-hall cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 figures 5 pages</comments><journal-ref>Adv. Mater. Interfaces 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/admi.201700688</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Epitaxial growth of atomically-sharp interfaces serves as one of the main
building blocks of nanofabrication. Such interfaces are crucial for the
operation of various devices including transistors, photo-voltaic cells, and
memory components. In order to avoid charge traps that may hamper the operation
of such devices, it is critical for the layers to be atomically-sharp.
Fabrication of atomically sharp interfaces normally requires ultra-high vacuum
techniques and high substrate temperatures. We present here a new self-limiting
wet chemical process for deposition of epitaxial layers from alkoxide
precursors. This method is fast, cheap, and yields perfect interfaces as we
validate by various analysis techniques. It allows the design of
heterostructures with half-unit cell resolution. We demonstrate our method by
designing hole-type oxide interfaces SrTiO3/BaO/LaAlO3. We show that transport
through this interface exhibits properties of mixed electron-hole contributions
with hole mobility exceeding that of electrons. Our method and results are an
important step forward towards a controllable design of a p-type oxide
interface.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04235</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04235</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Gendron-Marsolais</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kraft</keyname><forenames>R. P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bogdan</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hlavacek-Larrondo</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Forman</keyname><forenames>W. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Jones</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Su</keyname><forenames>Y.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nulsen</keyname><forenames>P.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Randall</keyname><forenames>S. W.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Roediger</keyname><forenames>E.</forenames></author></authors><title>Uplift, feedback and buoyancy: radio lobe dynamics in NGC 4472</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>12 pages, 7 figures, accepted for publication in ApJ</comments><journal-ref>ApJ, 848:26, 2017</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/aa8a6f</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present results from deep (380 ks) \textit{Chandra} observations of the
AGN outburst in the massive early-type galaxy NGC 4472. We detect cavities in
the gas coincident with the radio lobes and estimate the eastern and western
lobe enthalpy to be $(1.1 \pm 0.5 )\times 10^{56}$ erg and $(3 \pm 1 )\times
10^{56}$ erg, and the average power required to inflate the lobes to be $(1.8
\pm 0.9)\times 10^{41}$ erg s$^{-1}$ and $(6 \pm 3)\times 10^{41}$ erg
s$^{-1}$, respectively. We also detect enhanced X-ray rims around the radio
lobes with sharp surface brightness discontinuities between the shells and the
ambient gas. The temperature of the gas in the shells is less than that of the
ambient medium, suggesting that they are not AGN-driven shocks but rather gas
uplifted from the core by the buoyant rise of the radio bubbles. We estimate
the energy required to lift the gas to be up to $(1.1 \pm 0.3 )\times 10^{56}$
erg and $(3 \pm 1 )\times 10^{56}$ erg for the eastern and western rim
respectively, constituting a significant fraction of the total outburst energy.
A more conservative estimate suggests that the gas in the rim was uplifted a
smaller distance, requiring only $20-25\%$ of this energy. In either case, if a
significant fraction of this uplift energy is thermalized via hydrodynamic
instabilities or thermal conduction, our results suggest that it could be an
important source of heating in cool core clusters and groups. We also find
evidence for a central abundance drop in NGC 4472. The iron abundance profile
shows that the region along the cavity system has a lower metallicity than the
surrounding, undisturbed gas, similar to the central region. This also shows
that bubbles have lifted low-metallicity gas from the center.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04239</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04239</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Bouville</keyname><forenames>Florian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author></authors><title>Dispersion of Boron Nitride Powders in Aqueous Suspensions with
  Cellulose</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>15 pages, 7 figures</comments><journal-ref>Bouville, F., &amp; Deville, S. (2014). Dispersion of boron nitride
  powders in aqueous suspensions with cellulose. Journal of the American
  Ceramic Society, 97(2), 394-398</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/jace.12653</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The dispersion of nitride and carbide ceramic particles in water is
difficult, due to the absence of hydroxyl groups on their surface. Boron
nitride is not an exception and despite its numerous applications, no effective
dispersant has been identified so far. We demonstrate here the dispersion
properties of two cellulose derivatives for hexagonal boron nitride powders,
hydroxyl ethyl cellulose and methyl cellulose. The effect of particle sizes and
cellulose concentration was investigated. The adsorption of cellulose onto the
surface of the BN particles was confirmed by isotherm adsorption. Zeta
potential measurements shows a charge screening effect of the cellulose The
suspensions obtained were highly loaded and stable versus pH, and thus could
lead to homogeneous codispersion of BN particles and sintering additives.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04243</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04243</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Pavlov</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vuoristo</keyname><forenames>Petri</forenames></author><author><keyname>Savin</keyname><forenames>Alexander</forenames></author><author><keyname>Koivuluoto</keyname><forenames>Heli</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gorchakov</keyname><forenames>Konstantin</forenames></author></authors><title>Functional Zr, {\alpha}-Ta, and ({\alpha}-\b{eta}) Ta thick coatings
  obtained by original arc-evaporator</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>13 pages, 14 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Novel plasma-clustered deposition technique, called PVD Droplets, as well as
its main principles of operation were described. New types of obtained thick,
over 20 {\mu}m, functional coatings basing on Ta and Zr have been presented.
Results of research in physic-chemical properties of the coating materials are
listed including preliminary studies of superconductive properties. Comparative
evaluation between of obtained coatings and sample CVD coating was made.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04245</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04245</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Hern&#xe1;n-Caballero</keyname><forenames>Antonio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hatziminaoglou</keyname><forenames>Evanthia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Alonso-Herrero</keyname><forenames>Almudena</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mateos</keyname><forenames>Silvia</forenames></author></authors><title>Disentangling accretion disk and dust emissions in the infrared spectrum
  of type 1 AGN</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>8 pages, 4 figures; accepted for publication in Frontiers in
  Astronomy and Space Sciences, Research Topic &quot;Quasars at all cosmic epochs&quot;;
  proceedings of the conference &quot;Quasars at all cosmic epochs&quot;, held in Padova,
  April 2-7, 2017</comments><doi>10.3389/fspas.2017.00030</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We use a semi-empirical model to reproduce the 0.1-10um spectral energy
distribution (SED) of a sample of 85 luminous quasars. In the model, the
continuum emission from the accretion disk as well as the nebular lines are
represented by a single empirical template (disk), where differences in the
optical spectral index are reproduced by varying the amount of extinction. The
near- and mid-infrared emission of the AGN-heated dust is modelled as the
combination of two black-bodies (dust). The model fitting shows that the disk
and dust components are remarkably uniform among individual quasars, with
differences in the observed SED largely accounted for by varying levels of
obscuration in the disk as well as differences in the relative luminosity of
the disk and dust components. By combining the disk-subtracted SEDs of the 85
quasars, we generate a template for the 1-10um emission of the AGN-heated dust.
Additionally, we use a sample of local Seyfert 1 galaxies with full
spectroscopic coverage in the 0.37um to 39um range to demonstrate a method for
stitching together spectral segments obtained with different PSF and extraction
apertures. We show that the disk and dust templates obtained from luminous
quasars also reproduce the optical-to-mid-infrared spectra of local Seyfert 1s
when the contribution from the host galaxy is properly subtracted.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04253</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04253</id><created>2017-10-09</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Guanhua</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Huiyuan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gong</keyname><forenames>Rumei</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tan</keyname><forenames>Yang</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sun</keyname><forenames>Javier Rodraiguez Vazquez de Aldana Yuping</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chen</keyname><forenames>Feng</forenames></author></authors><title>Ultrasensitive biosensor based on Nd:YAG waveguide laser: Tumor cell and
  Dextrose solution</title><categories>physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work demonstrates the Nd:YAG waveguide laser as an efficient platform
for the bio-sensing. The waveguide was fabricated in the Nd:YAG crystal by the
cooperation of the ultrafast laser writing and ion irradiation. As the laser
oscillation in the Nd:YAG waveguide is ultra-sensitivity to the external
environment of the waveguide. Even a weak disturbance would induce a large
variation of the output power of the laser. According to this feature, the
Nd:YAG waveguide coated with Graphene and WSe2 layers is used as substrate for
the microfluidic channel. When the microflow crosses the Nd:YAG waveguide, the
laser oscillation in the waveguide is disturbed, and induces the fluctuation of
the output laser. Through the analysis of the fluctuation, the concentration of
the dextrose solution and the size of the tumor cell are distinguished
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04260</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04260</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Stupar</keyname><forenames>Sandra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vedral</keyname><forenames>Vlatko</forenames></author></authors><title>Was inflation necessary for the existence of time?</title><categories>quant-ph gr-qc</categories><comments>5 pages; comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Modern physics has unlocked a number of mysteries regarding the early
Universe, such as the baryogenesis, the unification of the strong and
electroweak forces and the nucleosynthesis. However, understanding the very
early Universe, close to the Planck epoch, still presents a major challenge.
The theory of inflation, which is assumed to have taken place towards the end
of the very early Universe, has been introduced in order to solve a number of
cosmological problems. However, concrete observational evidence for inflation
is still outstanding and the physical mechanisms behind inflation remain mostly
unknown. In this paper we argue for inflation from a different standpoint. In
order for time to have any concrete physical meaning in the very early and the
early Universe, the capacity of the Universe to measure time - its size or,
equivalently, memory - must be at least as large as the number of clock &quot;ticks&quot;
that need to be recorded somewhere within the Universe. Using this simple
criterion, we provide a sketch proof showing that in the absence of inflation
the subsystems of the Universe might not have been able to undertake the
synchronised evolution described by the time we use today.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04266</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04266</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Brandt</keyname><forenames>Oleg</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the DZero Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Direct measurement of the top quark mass in $p\bar p$ collisions at D0</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>5 pages, presented at EPS-HEP 2017 in Venice</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The mass of the top quark is a fundamental parameter of the Standard Model
and has to be determined experimentally. In these proceedings, I review recent
direct measurements of the top quark mass in $p\bar p$ collisions at $\sqrt
s=1.96$ TeV recorded by the D0 experiment at the Tevatron. The measurements are
performed in final states containing one and two charged leptons. I will
present the legacy combination of all top quark mass measurements from the D0
experiment and their combination with results from the CDF experiment. A
relative precision of down to 0.3\% is attained.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04271</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04271</id><created>2017-10-04</created><authors><author><keyname>Syubaev</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhizhchenko</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vitrik</keyname><forenames>O.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kudryashov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Porfirev</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fomchenkov</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Khonina</keyname><forenames>S.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kuchmizhak</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author></authors><title>Zero-OAM laser printing of chiral nanoneedles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci physics.app-ph physics.optics</categories><comments>5 pages, 3 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Laser irradiation of various materials including metals, polymers and
semiconductors with vortex beams was previously shown to twist transiently
molten matter providing the direct easy-to-implement way to obtain chiral
surface relief. Specifically for metals, this effect was attributed to transfer
of an optical angular momentum (OAM) carrying by the vortex beam. In this
Letter, we report the formation of twisted metal nanoneedles on the surface of
silver and gold metal films under their irradiation with zero-OAM laser beam
having spiral-shape lateral intensity distribution. Our comparative experiments
clearly demonstrate, for the first time, that the formation process of chiral
nanoneedles on the surface of plasmonic-active metals is mainly governed by the
temperature-gradient induced chiral thermocapillary mass transfer rather that
the OAM driven rotation of the transiently molten matter.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04277</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04277</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Mal</keyname><forenames>Prolay Kumar</forenames><affiliation>for ATLAS and CMS Collaborations</affiliation></author></authors><title>Top Quark Decay Properties</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>conference proceedings for LHCP2017</comments><report-no>CMS CR-2017/322</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Due to the large production cross-section, many of the top quark properties
can be measured very precisely at the LHC. A very few recent results, probed
only through the top quark decay vertices are presented here. These results are
based on proton-proton collision datasets recorded by the ATLAS and CMS
experiments at sqrt(s)=7, 8 and 13 TeV. All the measurements and observed
limits are consistent with the Standard Model (SM) predictions, while strong
bounds on anomalous Wtb couplings are established.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04282</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04282</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Keitch</keyname><forenames>Ben</forenames></author><author><keyname>Negnevitsky</keyname><forenames>Vlad</forenames></author><author><keyname>Zhang</keyname><forenames>Weida</forenames></author></authors><title>Programmable and scalable radio-frequency pulse sequence generator for
  multi-qubit quantum information experiments</title><categories>quant-ph physics.atom-ph physics.ins-det</categories><comments>11 pages, 11 figures. Comments welcome</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present a versatile rf pulse control system that has been designed for
multi-qubit quantum experiments. One instrument can be scaled to provide 32
channels of rf between 10 - 450 MHz. Synchronization can be achieved across
multiple instruments. By using direct digital synthesis and custom control
circuitry contained within a field-programmable gate array, sequences of
transform-limited pulses can be produced. These have been used to carry out
quantum gates that are able to meet fault-tolerant thresholds for single- and
two-qubit gate fidelities, as published elsewhere. We have also extended the
frequency to the gigahertz regime using additional mixers to address hyperfine
transitions in atomic systems. The system uses an efficient memory management
scheme and a low-latency communications protocol that allows pulse sequences to
be updated in real-time. Together these can enable outcome-based algorithms
such as quantum error correction to be executed. The system is fully
programmable in C++, and other languages such as Python can be supported by the
on-board CPU, offering a highly flexible platform for a wide variety of
experimental systems, and has been proven in trapped-ion quantum information
experiments.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04290</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04290</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Barber</keyname><forenames>Ahron S.</forenames><affiliation>for the HAWC Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Kieda</keyname><forenames>David B.</forenames><affiliation>for the HAWC Collaboration</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Springer</keyname><forenames>R. Wayne</forenames><affiliation>for the HAWC Collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Detection of Near Horizontal Muons with the HAWC Observatory</title><categories>astro-ph.HE astro-ph.IM physics.ins-det</categories><comments>Presented at the 35th International Cosmic Ray Conference (ICRC2017),
  Bexco, Busan, Korea. See arXiv:1708.02572 for all HAWC contributions</comments><report-no>HAWC-ICRC/2017/31</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The HAWC (High Altitude Water Cherenkov) gamma ray observatory is able to
observe muons with nearly horizontal trajectories. HAWC is located at an
altitude of 4100 meters a.s.l. on the Sierra Negra volcano in Mexico. The HAWC
detector is composed of 300 water tanks, each 7.3 m in diameter and 4.5 m tall,
densely packed over a physical area of 22,000 m$^{2}$. Previous and current
experiments have observed high zenith angle (near horizontal) muons at or near
sea level. HAWC operates as a hodoscope able to observe multi-TeV muons at
zenith angles greater than 75 degrees. This is the first experiment to measure
near horizontal muons at high altitude and with large ($\geq$ 10 m) separations
for multiple muons. These muons are distinguishable from extensive air showers
by observing near horizontal particles propagating with the speed of light. The
proximity of Sierra Negra and Pico de Orizaba volcanoes provides an additional
measurement of muons with rock overburdens of several km water equivalent. We
will present the angular distribution and rate at which HAWC observes these
muon events
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04299</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04299</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Beck</keyname><forenames>Christian</forenames></author></authors><title>Possible resonance effect of dark matter axions in SNS Josephson
  junctions</title><categories>hep-ph astro-ph.IM</categories><comments>Based on talk given at the EPS Conference on High Energy Physics,
  5-12 July 2017 Venice. 6 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Dark matter axions can generate peculiar effects in special types of
Josephson junctions, so-called SNS junctions. One can show that the axion field
equations in a Josephson environment allow for very small oscillating
supercurrents, which manifest themselves as a tiny wiggle in the I-V curve, a
so-called Shapiro step, which occurs at a frequency given by the axion mass.
The effect is very small but perfectly measurable in modern nanotechnological
devices. In this paper I will summarize the theory and then present evidence
that candidate Shapiro steps of this type have indeed been seen in several
independent condensed matter experiments. Assuming the observed tiny Shapiro
steps are due to axion flow then these data point to an axion mass of $(106 \pm
6)\mu$eV, consistent with what is expected for the QCD axion. In addition to
the above small Shapiro resonance effects at frequencies in the GHz region one
also expects to see broad-band noise effects at much lower frequencies. Overall
this approach provides a novel pathway for the future design of new types of
axionic dark matter detectors. The resonant Josephson data summarized in this
paper are consistent with a 'vanilla' axion with a coupling constant
$f_a=\sqrt{v_{EW}m_{Pl}}=5.48 \cdot 10^{10}$GeV given by the geometric average
of the electroweak symmetry breaking scale $v_{EW}$ and the Planck mass
$m_{Pl}$.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04302</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04302</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Lam</keyname><forenames>C. S.</forenames></author></authors><title>Holographic Scattering Amplitudes</title><categories>hep-th</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Inspired by ancient astronomy, we propose a holographic description of
perturbative scattering amplitudes, as integrals over a `celestial sphere'.
Since Lorentz invariance, local interactions, and particle propagations all
take place in a four-dimensional space-time, it is not trivial to accommodate
them in a lower-dimensional `celestial sphere'. The details of this task will
be discussed step by step, resulting in the Cachazo-He-Yuan (CHY) and similar
scattering amplitudes, thereby providing them with a holographic non-string
interpretation.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04305</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04305</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Alizadeh</keyname><forenames>Z.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Panahi</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author></authors><title>Integrable and superintegrable systems with higher order integrals of
  motion: master function formalism</title><categories>math-ph math.MP</categories><comments>18 Pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this article, we construct two-dimensional integrable and superintegrable
sys- tems in terms of the master function formalism and relate them to
Mielnik;s and Marquette;s construction in supersymmetric quantum mechanics. For
two diferent cases of the master functions, we obtain two diferent
two-dimensional superintegrable systems with higher order integrals of motion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04365</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04365</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Chiaki</keyname><forenames>Gen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tominaga</keyname><forenames>Nozomu</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nozawa</keyname><forenames>Takaya</forenames></author></authors><title>Classification of extremely metal-poor stars: absent region in
  A(C)-[Fe/H] plane and the role of dust cooling</title><categories>astro-ph.GA</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures, accepted as a Letter to Monthly Notices of the
  Royal Astronomical Society (MNRASL)</comments><doi>10.1093/mnrasl/slx163</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Extremely metal-poor (EMP) stars are the living fossils with records of
chemical enrichment history at the early epoch of galaxy formation. By the
recent large observation campaigns, statistical samples of EMP stars have been
obtained. This motivates us to reconsider their classification and formation
conditions. From the observed lower-limits of carbon and iron abundances of
Acr(C) ~ 6 and [Fe/H]cr ~ -5 for C-enhanced EMP (CE-EMP) and C-normal EMP
(CN-EMP) stars, we confirm that gas cooling by dust thermal emission is
indispensable for the fragmentation of their parent clouds to form such
low-mass, i.e., long-lived stars, and that the dominant grain species are
carbon and silicate, respectively. We constrain the grain radius r_i^{cool} of
a species i and condensation efficiency f_{ij} of a key element j as
r_C^{cool}/f_{C, C} = 10 um and r_Sil^{cool}/f_{Sil, Mg} = 0.1 um to reproduce
Acr(C) and [Fe/H]cr, which give a universal condition 10^{[C/H]-2.30} +
10^[Fe/H] &gt; 10^{-5.07} for the formation of every EMP star. Instead of the
conventional boundary [C/Fe] = 0.7 between CE- and CN-EMP stars, this condition
suggests a physically meaningful boundary [C/Fe]_{b} = 2.30 above and below
which carbon and silicate grains are dominant coolants, respectively.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04368</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04368</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kamath</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Van Winckel</keyname><forenames>H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wood</keyname><forenames>P. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Asplund</keyname><forenames>M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>M.</keyname></author><author><keyname>Karakas</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Lattanzio</keyname><forenames>J. C.</forenames></author></authors><title>Discovery of a Metal-poor, Luminous Post-AGB Star that Failed the Third
  Dredge-up</title><categories>astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>15 pages, 13 figures, 6 tables</comments><journal-ref>2017ApJ...836...15K</journal-ref><doi>10.3847/1538-4357/836/1/15</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Post-asymptotic giant branch (post-AGB) stars are known to be chemically
diverse. In this paper we present the first observational evidence of a star
that has failed the third dredge-up (TDU). J005252.87-722842.9 is a A-type
($T_{\rm eff}$ = 8250 $\pm$ 250K) luminous (8200 $\pm$ 700 $\rm L_{\odot}$),
metal-poor ($\textrm{[Fe/H]}$ = $- 1.18 \pm$ 0.10), low-mass (M$_{\rm initial}$
$\approx$ 1.5 $-$ 2.0 $\rm M_{\odot}$) post-AGB star in the Small Magellanic
Cloud. Through a systematic abundance study, using high-resolution optical
spectra from UVES, we found that this likely post-AGB object shows an
intriguing photospheric composition with no confirmed carbon-enhancement (upper
limit of [C/Fe] $&lt;$ 0.50) nor enrichment of $s$-process elements. We derived an
oxygen abundance of [O/Fe] = 0.29 $\pm$ 0.1. For Fe and O, we took into account
the effects of non-local thermodynamic equilibrium (NLTE). We could not derive
an upper limit for the nitrogen abundance as there are no useful nitrogen lines
within our spectral coverage. The chemical pattern displayed by this object has
not been observed in single or binary post-AGBs. Based on its derived stellar
parameters and inferred evolutionary state, single star nucleosynthesis models
predict that this star should have undergone TDU episodes while on the AGB and
be carbon-enriched. However, our observations are in contrast with these
predictions. We identify two possible Galactic analogues which are likely to be
post-AGB stars, but the lack of accurate distances (hence luminosities) to
these objects does not allow us to confirm their post-AGB status. If they have
low luminosities then they are likely to be dusty post-RGB stars. The discovery
of J005252.87-722842.9 reveals a new stellar evolutionary channel whereby a
star evolves without any third dredge-up episodes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04382</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04382</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Everitt</keyname><forenames>Richard G.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Prangle</keyname><forenames>Dennis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Maybank</keyname><forenames>Philip</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bell</keyname><forenames>Mark</forenames></author></authors><title>Marginal sequential Monte Carlo for doubly intractable models</title><categories>stat.CO cs.AI physics.data-an stat.ME stat.ML</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Bayesian inference for models that have an intractable partition function is
known as a doubly intractable problem, where standard Monte Carlo methods are
not applicable. The past decade has seen the development of auxiliary variable
Monte Carlo techniques (M{\o}ller et al., 2006; Murray et al., 2006) for
tackling this problem; these approaches being members of the more general class
of pseudo-marginal, or exact-approximate, Monte Carlo algorithms (Andrieu and
Roberts, 2009), which make use of unbiased estimates of intractable posteriors.
Everitt et al. (2017) investigated the use of exact-approximate importance
sampling (IS) and sequential Monte Carlo (SMC) in doubly intractable problems,
but focussed only on SMC algorithms that used data-point tempering. This paper
describes SMC samplers that may use alternative sequences of distributions, and
describes ways in which likelihood estimates may be improved adaptively as the
algorithm progresses, building on ideas from Moores et al. (2015). This
approach is compared with a number of alternative algorithms for doubly
intractable problems, including approximate Bayesian computation (ABC), which
we show is closely related to the method of M{\o}ller et al. (2006).
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04385</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04385</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Katsura</keyname><forenames>Hosho</forenames></author><author><keyname>Moriya</keyname><forenames>Hajime</forenames></author><author><keyname>Nakayama</keyname><forenames>Yu</forenames></author></authors><title>On highly degenerate supersymmetric ground states of the fermion lattice
  model by Nicolai</title><categories>math-ph cond-mat.stat-mech cond-mat.str-el hep-th math.MP</categories><comments>30pages</comments><msc-class>82B20, 81Q60</msc-class><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a spinless fermion lattice model that has ${\cal{N}}=2$
supersymmetry given by Hermann Nicolai. We show that high degeneracy of
supersymmetric ground states of the Nicolai model is associated to breakdown of
local fermion symmetries hidden in the model.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04390</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04390</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Zhuo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Li</keyname><forenames>Bin</forenames></author></authors><title>Develop a perfect spectrometer in water window</title><categories>physics.optics</categories><comments>9 pages, 9 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We report a novelly universal scheme for design of a grazing incidence
spectrometer, which creates an excellent meridional flat field in its detector
domain to deliver the desired spectral resolution throughout the full
designated spectral range, while eliminates the sagittal astigmatism to enhance
the spectral intensity simultaneously. The intrinsic optical properties of the
system are thoroughly investigated and optimized, especially how the detector
plane approaches to the actual meridional or sagittal focal curves is well
quantified. We demonstrated within the &quot;water window&quot;, i.e. 2-5nm wavelength
range, the resolving power of 6000-18000 could be achieved for the effective
meridional source size of 200um r.m.s.; and it would be further improved to
20000-40000 if the source size is confined down to 50um r.m.s.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04392</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04392</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Saiz</keyname><forenames>Eduardo</forenames></author><author><keyname>Tomsia</keyname><forenames>Antoni</forenames></author></authors><title>Freeze casting of hydroxyapatite scaffolds for bone tissue engineering</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>23 pages, 12 figures</comments><journal-ref>Biomaterials, 27(32), 5480-5489 (2006)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.biomaterials.2006.06.028</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Although extensive efforts have been put into the development of porous
scaffolds for bone regeneration, with encouraging results, all porous materials
have a common limitation: the inherent lack of strength associated with
porosity. Hence, the development of porous hydroxyapatite scaffolds has been
hindered to non-load bearing applications. We report here how freeze-casting
can be applied to synthesize porous hydroxyapatite scaffolds exhibiting
unusually high compressive strength, e.g. up to 145 MPa for 47% porosity and 65
MPa for 56% porosity. The materials are characterized by well-defined pore
connectivity along with directional and completely open porosity. Various
parameters affecting the porosity and compressive strength have been
investigated, including initial slurry concentration, freezing rate, and
sintering conditions. The implications and potential application as bone
substitute are discussed. These results might open the way for
hydroxyapatite-based materials designed for load-bearing applications. The
biological response of these materials is yet to be tested.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04399</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04399</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Schmidt</keyname><forenames>Burkhard</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thalmeier</keyname><forenames>Peter</forenames></author></authors><title>Frustrated two dimensional quantum magnets</title><categories>cond-mat.str-el</categories><comments>78 pages, 54 figures</comments><journal-ref>Physics Reports 703 (2017) 1-59</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.physrep.2017.06.004</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We overview physical effects of exchange frustration and quantum spin
fluctuations in (quasi-) two dimensional (2D) quantum magnets ($S=1/2$) with
square, rectangular and triangular structure. Our discussion is based on the
$J_1$-$J_2$ type frustrated exchange model and its generalizations. These
models are closely related and allow to tune between different phases,
magnetically ordered as well as more exotic nonmagnetic quantum phases by
changing only one or two control parameters. We survey ground state properties
like magnetization, saturation fields, ordered moment and structure factor in
the full phase diagram as obtained from numerical exact diagonalization
computations and analytical linear spin wave theory. We also review finite
temperature properties like susceptibility, specific heat and magnetocaloric
effect using the finite temperature Lanczos method. This method is powerful to
determine the exchange parameters and g-factors from experimental results. We
focus mostly on the observable physical frustration effects in magnetic phases
where plenty of quasi-2D material examples exist to identify the influence of
quantum fluctuations on magnetism.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04408</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04408</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Diehl</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gaunt</keyname><forenames>Jonathan R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Double parton scattering theory overview</title><categories>hep-ph</categories><comments>25 pages, 7 figures. Prepared for: Multiple Parton Interactions at
  the LHC, Eds. P. Bartalini and J. R. Gaunt, World Scientific, Singapore</comments><report-no>CERN-TH-2017-204, DESY 17-161</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The dynamics of double hard scattering in proton-proton collisions is quite
involved compared with the familiar case of single hard scattering. In this
contribution, we review our theoretical understanding of double hard scattering
and of its interplay with other reaction mechanisms.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04424</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04424</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kumar</keyname><forenames>Arun</forenames><affiliation>on behalf of the CMS collaboration</affiliation></author></authors><title>Higgs boson measurements in $WW$, $\tau\tau$ and $\mu\mu$ channels with
  CMS</title><categories>hep-ex</categories><comments>6 pages, Presented in Large Hadron Collider Physics conference (LHCP)
  2017, in Shanghai, China</comments><report-no>CMS CR2017_238</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This note presents search for the Standard Model Higgs boson in $WW$,
$\tau\tau$ and $\mu\mu$ decay channels with the proton-proton collision data
collected by the CMS experiment at the LHC. The results have been derived using
different amounts of luminosities for different channels.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04427</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04427</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kool</keyname><forenames>Th. W.</forenames></author></authors><title>Description of a specialized stress equipment for EPR X-band
  measurements</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 1 figure</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A specialized stress equipment has been developed for EPR X-band experiments.
Uniaxial stress experiments in EPR of different impurity ions in SrTiO3 and
BaTiO3 will be reviewed.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04438</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04438</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Hollands</keyname><forenames>Lotte</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kidwai</keyname><forenames>Omar</forenames></author></authors><title>Higher length-twist coordinates, generalized Heun's opers, and twisted
  superpotentials</title><categories>hep-th math.AG math.CA math.GT</categories><comments>91 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this paper we study a proposal of Nekrasov, Rosly and Shatashvili that
describes the effective twisted superpotential obtained from a class S theory
geometrically as a generating function in terms of certain complexified
length-twist coordinates, and extend it to higher rank. First, we introduce a
higher rank analogue of Fenchel-Nielsen type spectral networks in terms of a
generalized Strebel condition. We find new systems of spectral coordinates
through the abelianization method and argue that they are higher rank analogues
of the Nekrasov-Rosly-Shatashvili Darboux coordinates. Second, we give an
explicit parametrization of the locus of opers and determine the generating
functions of this Lagrangian subvariety in terms of the higher rank Darboux
coordinates in some specific examples. We find that the generating functions
indeed agree with the known effective twisted superpotentials. Last, we relate
the approach of Nekrasov, Rosly and Shatashvili to the approach using quantum
periods via the exact WKB method.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04442</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04442</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevalier</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author></authors><title>Martensitic relief observation by atomic force microscopy in yttria
  stabilized zirconia</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>6 pages, 4 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the American Ceramic Society, 86(12), 2225-2227 (2003)</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1151-2916.2003.tb03639.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The tetragonal to monoclinic (t-m) phase transformation of zirconia has been
the object of extensive investigations of the last twenty years, and is now
recognised as being of martensitic nature. However, martensitic transformation
has only been observed by transmission electron microscopy or indirect methods.
Though the benefit on the fracture toughness and crack resistance was the main
interest, the transformation is now considered for its consequences on the
degradation of the material. The use of AFM reported here allowed the
observation of the first stages of martensite relief growth and of new
martensitic features.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04443</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04443</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevalier</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Attaoui</keyname><forenames>Hassan El</forenames></author></authors><title>Atomic force microscopy study and qualitative analysis of martensite
  relief in zirconia</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>14 pages, 13 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the American Ceramic Society, 88(5), 1261-1267</journal-ref><doi>10.1111/j.1551-2916.2005.00174.x</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A recent report [S. Deville et al., J. Am. Ceram. Soc., 86(12), 2225 (2003)]
has shown the new possibilities offered by atomic force microscopy (AFM) to
investigate martensitic transformation induced relief in zirconia. In this
paper, we studied qualitatively the surface relief resulting from martensitic
tetragonal to monoclinic phase transformation in yttria and ceria-doped
zirconia by AFM. AFM appears as a very powerful tool to investigate martensite
relief with a great precision. The phenomenological theory of martensitic
crystallography could be succesfully applied to explain all the observed
features. The formation conditions of the martensite are discussed, as well as
ways of accommodating locally the transformation strain, i.e.
self-accommodating variant pairs and microcracking. Variants growth sequences
are observed. These observations bring new insights and explanations on the
transformation initiation and propagation sequences.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04448</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04448</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Ali</keyname><forenames>Mohamed Kamal Ahmed</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ezzat</keyname><forenames>Fawzy M. H.</forenames></author><author><keyname>El-Gawwad</keyname><forenames>K. A. Abd</forenames></author><author><keyname>Salem</keyname><forenames>M. M. M.</forenames></author></authors><title>Effect of Lubricant Contaminants on Tribological Characteristics During
  Boundary Lubrication Reciprocating Sliding</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This article presents the effect of the presence of solid contaminants, in
engine lubricating oil, on the tribological parameters, which impact negatively
on the performance of the engine and increase fuel consumption. This study
revealed that the lubricant was contaminated by Fe, Cu, Al, Pb and SiO2
particles. The tribological tests were performed using 0.63, 0.85 and 1.1 m s-1
average sliding speeds and 120 N contact load to mimic the boundary lubrication
regime of the sliding reciprocating motion of the piston ring/liner interface
in an engine. The presence of the solid contaminants in engine oils leads to an
increase in friction coefficient, wear and frictional power losses, increasing
the surfaces roughness as a consequence. The results showed that grain size and
concentrations strongly affected the tribological parameters. In order to
minimize the effect of solid contaminants, it is necessary to improve the
filtration accuracy for lubricating oils.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04449</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04449</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Gremillard</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevalier</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fantozzi</keyname><forenames>Gilbert</forenames></author></authors><title>A critical comparison of methods for the determination of the ageing
  sensitivity in biomedical grade yttria stabilized zirconia</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>11 pages, 8 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of Biomedical Materials Research 72(2), 239-245 (2005)</journal-ref><doi>10.1002/jbm.b.30123</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Since the recent failure events of two particular series of zirconia femoral
heads for total hip replacement prosthesis, a large decrease in the use of
zirconia ceramics for orthopaedic implants has been observed. In spite of the
biomedical success of this material during the last ten years, this was
required for safety reasons, until the cause of the failures is known. It has
been shown that these failures were related to the low temperature hydrothermal
degradation (also known as ageing). Thus it is crucial to better understand the
ageing behaviour, in order to be able to assess its importance and then control
it if required. In this paper, various techniques relevant to assess the
hydrothermal degradation sensitivity of biomedical grade yttria stabilized
zirconia are discussed and compared. The expected outputs of conventional
methods, i.e. X-Ray diffraction and scanning electron microscopy are examined.
More recent methods like optical interferometry and atomic force microscopy are
presented, with their respective benefits and drawbacks. An up to date
comparison of these different techniques is provided, and their use for
ensuring the long term reliability of a particular batch of zirconia in terms
of ageing degradation is demonstrated.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04453</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04453</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Stinshoff</keyname><forenames>Rolf</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wimmer</keyname><forenames>Sebastian</forenames></author><author><keyname>Ebert</keyname><forenames>Hubert</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fecher</keyname><forenames>Gerhard H</forenames></author><author><keyname>Felser</keyname><forenames>Claudia</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chadov</keyname><forenames>Stanislav</forenames></author></authors><title>Temperature-dependent charge transport in the compensated ferrimagnet
  Mn$_{1.5}$V$_{0.5}$FeAl from first principles</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>5 pages, 5 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present an ab-initio study of the temperature-dependent longitudinal and
anomalous Hall resistivities in the compensated collinear ferrimagnet
Mn$_{1.5}$V$_{0.5}$FeAl. Its transport properties are calculated using the
general fully relativistic Kubo--Bastin formalism and their temperature
dependency is accounted for magnetic and structural disorder. Both scattering
sources, together with the residual chemical disorder, were treated equally
provided by the CPA (Coherent Potential Approximation) SPR-KKR (Spin-Polarized
Relativistic Korringa-Kohn-Rostoker) method. All calculated properties showed
good agreement with a recent experimental results, providing useful specific
information on the chemical and magnetic arrangement as well as on the
influence of disorder. Finally, we demonstrated that the anomalous Hall effect
in such compensated systems occurs regardless of the vanishing net spin moment.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04454</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04454</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gremillard</keyname><forenames>Laurent</forenames></author><author><keyname>Chevalier</keyname><forenames>J&#xe9;r&#xf4;me</forenames></author><author><keyname>Deville</keyname><forenames>Sylvain</forenames></author><author><keyname>Epicier</keyname><forenames>Thierry</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fantozzi</keyname><forenames>Gilbert</forenames></author></authors><title>Modeling the aging kinetics of zirconia ceramics</title><categories>cond-mat.mtrl-sci</categories><comments>20 pages, 9 figures</comments><journal-ref>Journal of the European Ceramic Society, 24(13), 3483-3489 (2004)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.jeurceramsoc.2003.11.025</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Yttria-stabilized tetragonal zirconia polycrystals (3Y-TZP) with different
microstructures were elaborated. The isothermal tetragonal to monoclinic
transformation was investigated at 134 {\deg}C in steam by X-ray diffraction,
Atomic Force Microscopy (AFM) and optical interferometry. The aging kinetics
were analyzed in terms of nucleation and growth, using the Mehl-Avrami-Johnson
(MAJ) formalism. Numerical simulation of the aging of zirconia surfaces was
also conducted, and the results were used to better fit the aging kinetics. The
simulation shows that the exponent of the MAJ laws is controlled not only by
the nucleation and growth mechanisms, but also - and mainly - by their
respective kinetic parameters. Measurements of nucleation and growth rates at
the surface, at the beginning of aging, and the use of numerical simulation
allow the accurate prediction of aging kinetics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04456</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04456</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Thapliyal</keyname><forenames>Kishore</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pathak</keyname><forenames>Anirban</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sen</keyname><forenames>Biswajit</forenames></author><author><keyname>Perina</keyname><forenames>Jan</forenames></author></authors><title>Nonclassicality in non-degenerate hyper-Raman processes</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>Nonclassicality of non-degenerate hyper-Raman processes is
  investigated using a completely quantum mechanical treatment</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A perturbative analytic operator solution of a completely quantum mechanical
Hamiltonian of multi-photon pump non-degenerate hyper-Raman process is
obtained. It is shown that the obtained solution is general in nature as the
solutions of non-degenerate hyper-Raman and stimulated Raman processes can be
obtained as special cases of the present solution. The analytic solutions
obtained here are used to investigate the nonclassical properties of the
different modes in the stimulated, spontaneous and partially spontaneous
multi-photon pump non-degenerate hyper-Raman processes. The nonclassical nature
of these processes is witnessed by means of single mode and intermodal
quadrature squeezing, intermodal entanglement of different orders, lower order
and higher order photon antibunching. Interestingly, manifesting the
multiphoton nature of the pump modes, a bunch of nonclassicality involving them
are observed due to self-interaction of various pump modes.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04466</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04466</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bikmaev</keyname><forenames>I. F.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Nikolaeva</keyname><forenames>E. A.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Shimansky</keyname><forenames>V. V.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Galeev</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Zhuchkov</keyname><forenames>R. Ya.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Irtuganov</keyname><forenames>E. N.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Melnikov</keyname><forenames>S. S.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sakhibullin</keyname><forenames>N. A.</forenames><affiliation>Kazan Federal University</affiliation><affiliation>Academy of Sciences of Tatarstan</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Grebenev</keyname><forenames>S. A.</forenames><affiliation>Space Research Institute, Moscow</affiliation></author><author><keyname>Sharipova</keyname><forenames>L. M.</forenames><affiliation>Crimean Astrophysical Observatory</affiliation></author></authors><title>Spectroscopic study of the optical counterpart to the Fast X-ray
  Transient IGR J17544-2619 based on observations at the 1.5-m RTT-150
  telescope</title><categories>astro-ph.HE</categories><comments>13 pages, 11 figures, 4 tables</comments><journal-ref>Astronomy Letters, v. 43, no. 10, pp. 664-676 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1134/S1063773717100012</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We present the results of our long-term photometric and spectroscopic
observations at the Russian-Turkish RTT-150 telescope for the optical
counterpart to one of the best-known sources, representatives of the class of
fast X-ray transients, IGR J17544-2619. Based on our optical data, we have
determined for the first time the orbital and physical parameters of the binary
system by the methods of Doppler spectroscopy. We have computed theoretical
spectra of the optical counterpart by applying non-LTE corrections for selected
lines and obtained the parameters of the stellar atmosphere and the optical
star ($T_{\rm eff}=33\,000$ K, $\log\,g=3.85$, $R=9.5\ R_{\odot},$ and $M=23\
M_{\odot}$). The latter suggest that the optical star is not a supergiant as
has been thought previously.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04480</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04480</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Kranz</keyname><forenames>W. Till</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sperl</keyname><forenames>Matthias</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic theory for strong uniform shear flow of granular media at high
  density</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>Powders &amp; Grains 2017</comments><journal-ref>EPJ Web of Conferences 140, 03064 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1051/epjconf/201714003064</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We discuss the uniform shear flow of a fluidized granular bed composed of
monodisperse Hertzian spheres. Considering high densities around the glass
transition density of inelastic Hertzian spheres, we report kinetic theory
expressions for the Newtonian viscosity as well as the Bagnold coefficient. We
discuss the dependence of the transport coefficients on density and coefficient
of restitution.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04482</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04482</id><created>2017-08-28</created><authors><author><keyname>Nielbock</keyname><forenames>Markus</forenames></author></authors><title>Navigating with the Kamal</title><categories>physics.ed-ph physics.pop-ph</categories><comments>8 pages, 12 figures. Accepted for publication at AstroEDU. This
  resource was developed in the framework of Space Awareness. Space Awareness
  is funded by the European Commission's Horizon 2020 Programme under grant
  agreement no. 638653. arXiv admin note: substantial text overlap with
  arXiv:1708.07700, arXif:1708.08777, arXiv:1708.08332</comments><report-no>astroedu1647</report-no><license>http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</license><abstract>  The students build and use an old navigational tool from the Arab world of
the 9th century, the kamal. After an introduction to historic seafaring and
navigation, they build this simple tool and understand how it can be used to
measure angles. After learning that the elevation of Polaris is (almost)
identical to the latitude of the observer, they apply this knowledge while
using the kamal. During a field trip, they actually measure the elevation of
Polaris. The result is compared with modern methods.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04489</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04489</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Artemyev</keyname><forenames>A. V.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Neishtadt</keyname><forenames>A. I.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Vasiliev</keyname><forenames>A. A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Mourenas</keyname><forenames>D.</forenames></author></authors><title>Kinetic equation for systems with resonant captures and scatterings</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>11 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We study a Hamiltonian system of type describing a charged particle resonant
interaction with an electromagnetic wave. We consider an ensemble of particles
that repeatedly pass through the resonance with the wave, and study evolution
of the distribution function due to multiple scatterings on the resonance and
trappings (captures) into the resonance. We derive the corresponding kinetic
equation. Particular cases of this problem has been studied in our recent
papers [1, 2].
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04491</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04491</id><created>2017-09-26</created><authors><author><keyname>He</keyname><forenames>Angela</forenames></author></authors><title>Overcoming Barriers to Engagement with Educational Video Games for
  Self-Directed Learning: A Mixed-Methods Case Study</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>67 pages, 3 figures, 2 tables</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Research has established increased engagement and positive behavioral,
attitudinal, and learning outcomes from educational games. Although engagement
begets these benefits, there is a lack of research on how students engage with
educational games, especially when self-directed. Additionally, research on the
effects of engagement on performance is conflicting. This study aimed to
identify barriers to students' self-directed engagement with two anatomy
educational games, methods to overcome identified barriers, and the impact of
engagement on learning performance. Employing the within-case and cross-case
approach and triangulation of data, four educational-game specific barriers
emerged (from most common to least common): 1) negative perceptions of
educational games, 2) incompatible audience, 3) incompatible difficulty, and 4)
price. Path analysis found that engagement may have insignificant, positive
effects on performance. These findings indicate that students' self-directed
engagement with educational games is impeded by unique barriers and engagement
may not be vital for performance. Suggestions for game design and marketing
emerged to help developers, teachers, and researchers overcome identified
barriers.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04492</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04492</id><created>2017-09-27</created><authors><author><keyname>Percy</keyname><forenames>John R.</forenames></author></authors><title>Forty Years of Linking Variable Star Research with Education</title><categories>physics.ed-ph astro-ph.IM astro-ph.SR</categories><comments>Submitted to the proceedings of the conference &quot;Remote Telescopes,
  Student Research, and Education&quot;</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  In this review, I reflect on four decades of my experience in linking
astronomy research and education by supervising variable-star research projects
by undergraduates, and by outstanding senior high school students. I describe
the evolution of my experience, the students I have supervised, the nature of
their projects, the educational contexts of the projects, the need for &quot;best
practices&quot;, the journals in which we publish, and the special role of the
American Association of Variable Star Observers (AAVSO). I then describe our
recent research on pulsating red giants and related objects, including three
astrophysical mysteries that we have uncovered. Finally, I suggest how my
projects might be scaled up or extended by others who supervise student
research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04498</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04498</id><created>2017-10-11</created><authors><author><keyname>Castagnoli</keyname><forenames>Giuseppe</forenames></author></authors><title>Back to the seminal Deutsch algorithm</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages. A bare description of the seminal Deutsch algorithm is
  followed by a short discussion of the fundamenal questions raised by its
  quantum speedup. This means to be an invitation to physicists of the
  foundations to address the foundations of the speedup</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  A bare description of the seminal quantum algorithm devised by Deutsch could
mean more than an introduction to quantum computing. It could contribute to
opening the field to interdisciplinary research.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04500</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04500</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bl&#xfc;mlein</keyname><forenames>J.</forenames></author><author><keyname>De Freitas</keyname><forenames>A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schneider</keyname><forenames>C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sch&#xf6;nwald</keyname><forenames>K.</forenames></author></authors><title>The Three Loop Two-Mass Contribution to the Gluon Vacuum Polarization</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>5 pages Latex</comments><report-no>DESY 17--157,DO--TH 17/26</report-no><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We calculate the two-mass contribution to the 3-loop vacuum polarization of
the gluon in Quantum Chromodynamics at virtuality $p^2 = 0$ for general masses
and also present the analogous result for the photon in Quantum
Electrodynamics.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04506</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04506</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Gueroult</keyname><forenames>Renaud</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rax</keyname><forenames>Jean-Marcel</forenames></author><author><keyname>Fisch</keyname><forenames>Nathaniel J.</forenames></author></authors><title>Opportunities for plasma separation techniques in rare earth elements
  recycling</title><categories>physics.plasm-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to Journal of Cleaner Production</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Rare earth elements recycling has been proposed to alleviate supply risks and
market volatility. In this context, the potential of a new recycling pathway,
namely plasma mass separation, is uncovered through the example of nedodymium -
iron - boron magnets recycling. Plasma mass separation is shown to address some
of the shortcomings of existing rare earth elements recycling pathways, in
particular detrimental environmental effects. A simplified mass separation
model suggests that plasma separation performances could compare favourably
with existing recycling options. In addition, simple energetic considerations
of plasma processing suggest that the cost of these techniques may not be
prohibitive, particularly considering that energy costs from solar may become
significantly cheaper. Further investigation and experimental demonstration of
plasma separation techniques should permit asserting the potential of these
techniques against other recycling techniques currently under development.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04516</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04516</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Sborlini</keyname><forenames>German F. R.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Driencourt-Mangin</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hernandez-Pinto</keyname><forenames>Roger</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rodrigo</keyname><forenames>German</forenames></author></authors><title>Four-dimensional regularization of higher-order computations: FDU
  approach</title><categories>hep-ph hep-th</categories><comments>7 pages, 3 figures. Contribution to the Proceedings of the EPS-HEP
  2017 Conference</comments><journal-ref>PoS(EPS-HEP2017)547</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We have recently proposed a new regularization framework based on the
loop-tree duality theorem. This theorem allows to rewrite loop level amplitudes
in terms of tree-level structures and phase-space integrations. In consequence,
it is possible to combine naturally real and virtual contributions at integrand
level. Moreover, through the introduction of a proper momentum-mapping, a
complete local cancellation of infrared singularities is achieved, by-passing
the necessity of counter-terms. In this article, we briefly explain the
implementation of this novel approach to compute some physical processes, and
we show how to deal with both infrared and ultraviolet divergences without
using DREG.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04525</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04525</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Mathis</keyname><forenames>H&#xe9;l&#xe8;ne</forenames><affiliation>LMJL</affiliation></author></authors><title>A thermodynamically consistent model of a liquid-vapor fluid with a gas</title><categories>math.AP cond-mat.stat-mech</categories><proxy>ccsd</proxy><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This work is devoted to the consistent modeling of a three-phase mixture of a
gas, a liquid and its vapor. Since the gas and the vapor are mis-cible, the
mixture is subjected to a non-symmetric constraint on the volume. Adopting the
Gibbs formalism, the study of the extensive equilibrium entropy of the system
allows to recover the Dalton's law between the two gaseous phases. In addition,
we distinguish whether phase transition occurs or not between the liquid and
its vapor. The thermodynamical equilibria are described both in extensive and
intensive variables. In the latter case, we focus on the geometrical properties
of equilibrium entropy. The consistent characterization of the thermodynamics
of the three-phase mixture is used to introduce two Homogeneous Equilibrium
Models (HEM) depending on mass transfer is taking into account or not.
Hyperbolicity is investigated while analyzing the entropy structure of the
systems. Finally we propose two Homogeneous Relaxation Models (HRM) for the
three-phase mixtures with and without phase transition. Supplementary equations
on mass, volume and energy fractions are considered with appropriate source
terms which model the relaxation towards the thermodynamical equilibrium, in
agreement with entropy growth criterion.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04534</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04534</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Dias</keyname><forenames>Geovani Lopes</forenames></author><author><keyname>Santos</keyname><forenames>Renato P. dos</forenames></author></authors><title>Big Data as a Technology-to-think-with for Scientific Literacy</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>23 pages, 2 figures, 8 tables</comments><acm-class>K.3.1; J.2; H.2.8</acm-class><journal-ref>Acta Scientiae 19(2017):350-372</journal-ref><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  This research aimed to identify indications of scientific literacy resulting
from a didactic and investigative interaction with Google Trends Big Data
software by first-year students from a high-school in Novo Hamburgo, Southern
Brazil. Both teaching strategies and research interpretations lie on four
theoretical backgrounds. Firstly, Bunge's epistemology, which provides a
thorough characterization of Science that was central to our study. Secondly,
the conceptual framework of scientific literacy of Fives et al. that makes our
teaching focus precise and concise, as well as supports one of our
methodological tool: the SLA (scientific literacy assessment). Thirdly, the
&quot;crowdledge&quot; construct from dos Santos, which gives meaning to our study when
as it makes the development of scientific literacy itself versatile for paying
attention on sociotechnological and epistemological contemporary phenomena.
Finally, the learning principles from Papert's Constructionism inspired our
educational activities. Our educational actions consisted of students, divided
into two classes, investigating phenomena chose by them. A triangulation
process to integrate quantitative and qualitative methods on the assessments
results was done. The experimental design consisted in post-tests only and the
experimental variable was the way of access to the world. The experimental
group interacted with the world using analyses of temporal and regional plots
of interest of terms or topics searched on Google. The control class did
'placebo' interactions with the world through on-site observations of
bryophytes, fungus or whatever in the schoolyard. As general results of our
research, a constructionist environment based on Big Data analysis showed
itself as a richer strategy to develop scientific literacy, compared to a free
schoolyard exploration.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04548</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04548</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Maqueira-Albo</keyname><forenames>Isis</forenames></author><author><keyname>Bonacchini</keyname><forenames>Giorgio Ernesto</forenames></author><author><keyname>DellErba</keyname><forenames>Giorgio</forenames></author><author><keyname>Pace</keyname><forenames>Giuseppina</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sassi</keyname><forenames>Mauro</forenames></author><author><keyname>Rooney</keyname><forenames>Myles</forenames></author><author><keyname>Resel</keyname><forenames>Roland</forenames></author><author><keyname>Beverina</keyname><forenames>Luca</forenames></author><author><keyname>Caironi</keyname><forenames>Mario</forenames></author></authors><title>Latent Pigments Strategy for Robust Active Layers in Solution-Processed,
  Complementary Organic Field-Effect Transistors</title><categories>physics.app-ph</categories><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Solution-processed organic semiconductors enable the fabrication of
large-area and flexible electronics by means of cost-effective, solution-based
mass manufacturing techniques. However, for many applications an insoluble
active layer can offer technological advantages in terms of robustness to
processing solvents. This is particularly relevant in field-effect transistors
(FET), where processing of dielectrics or barriers from solution on top of the
semiconductor layer typically imposes the use of orthogonal solvents in order
not to interfere with the nanometer thick accumulation channel. To this end,
the use of latent pigments, highly soluble molecules which can produce
insoluble films after a post-deposition thermal cleavage of solubilizing
groups, is a very promising strategy. In this contribution, we demonstrate the
use of tert-Butyloxycarbonyl (t-Boc) functionalized diketopyrrolopyrrole and
perylene-diimide small molecules for good hole and electron transporting films.
t-Boc thermal cleavage produces a densification of the films, along with a
strong structural rearrangement of the deprotected molecules, strongly
improving charge mobility in both p- and n-type FET. We also highlight the
robustness of these highly insoluble semiconducting layers to typical and
aggressive processing solvents. These results can greatly enhance the degree of
freedom in the manufacturing of multi-layered organic electronic devices,
offering enhanced stability to harsh processing steps.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04558</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04558</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Cachazo</keyname><forenames>Freddy</forenames></author></authors><title>Combinatorial Factorization</title><categories>hep-th</categories><comments>14 pages</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  The simplest integrands in the CHY formulation of scattering amplitudes are
constructed using the so-called Parke-Taylor functions. Parke-Taylor functions
also turn out to belong to a large class of rational functions known as MHV
leading singularities. In fact, Parke-Taylor functions correspond to planar MHV
leading singularities. In this note we study the behavior of CHY integrands
constructed using non-planar MHV leading singularities under collinear and
multi-particle factorization limits. General $n$-particle MHV leading
singularities are completely characterized by a set of $(n-2)$ triples of
particle labels. We give a simple operation on this combinatorial data which
&quot;factors&quot; the list into two sets of triples defining two lower point MHV
leading singularities. The fact that general MHV leading singularities form a
closed set under &quot;multi-particle factorizations&quot; is surprising from their gauge
theoretic origin.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04561</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04561</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Bet</keyname><forenames>Bram</forenames></author><author><keyname>Georgiev</keyname><forenames>Rumen</forenames></author><author><keyname>Uspal</keyname><forenames>William</forenames></author><author><keyname>Eral</keyname><forenames>Huyesin Burak</forenames></author><author><keyname>van Roij</keyname><forenames>Ren&#xe9;</forenames></author><author><keyname>Samin</keyname><forenames>Sela</forenames></author></authors><title>Calculating the motion of highly confined, arbitrary-shaped particles in
  Hele-Shaw channels</title><categories>cond-mat.soft</categories><comments>18 pages, 5 figures, 4 supplemental movies</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  We combine theory, numerical calculations, and experiments to accurately
predict the motion of anisotropic particles in shallow microfluidic channels,
in which the particles are strongly confined in the vertical direction. We
formulate an effective quasi-two-dimensional description of the Stokes flow
around the particle via the Brinkman equation, which can be solved in a time
that is two orders of magnitude faster than the three-dimensional problem. The
computational speedup enables us to calculate the full trajectories of
particles in the channel. To test our scheme, we study the motion of
dumbbell-shaped particles that are produced in a microfluidic channel using
`continuous flow lithography'. Contrary to what was reported in earlier work
(Uspal et al., Nature communications 4 (2013)), we find that the reorientation
time of a dumbbell particle in an external flow exhibits a minimum as a
function of its disk size ratio. This finding is in excellent agreement with
new experiments, thus confirming the predictive power of our scheme.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04563</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04563</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Chasseur</keyname><forenames>Tobias</forenames></author><author><keyname>Motzoi</keyname><forenames>Felix</forenames></author><author><keyname>Kaicher</keyname><forenames>Michael</forenames></author><author><keyname>Dallaire-Demers</keyname><forenames>Pierre-Luc</forenames></author><author><keyname>Wilhelm</keyname><forenames>Frank K.</forenames></author></authors><title>Benchmarking non-simulable quantum processes via symmetry conservation</title><categories>quant-ph</categories><comments>6 pages, 2 figures</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  As quantum devices scale up, many-body quantum gates and algorithms begin to
surpass what is possible to simulate classically. Validation methods which rely
on such classical simulation, such as process tomography and randomized
benchmarking, cannot efficiently check correctness of most of the processes
involved. In particular non-Clifford gates are a requirement for not only
universal quantum computation but for any algorithm or quantum simulation that
yields fundamental speedup in comparison with its classical counterpart. We
show that it is in fact still possible to validate such non-simulable processes
by taking advantage of expected or engineered conservations laws in the system,
combined with a unitary one-design strategy to randomize errors over the
computational Hilbert space. We show that in the context of (fault-tolerant)
quantum error correction, we can construct a one-design using the logically
encoded Clifford group over the engineered error-free stabilizer subspace to
obtain average error for arbitrary logically-encoded gates and algorithms. In
the case of benchmarking simulation of physical systems, these can have various
exotic symmetries over which one-design strategies can nonetheless be
constructed. We give examples for fermionic systems which conserve particle
number, as well as for the Fermi-Hubbard model. The symmetry benchmarking
method preserves robustness to state preparation and measurement imperfections.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04594</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04594</id><created>2017-09-06</created><authors><author><keyname>Tajeddine</keyname><forenames>Radwan</forenames></author><author><keyname>Soderlund</keyname><forenames>Krista M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Thomas</keyname><forenames>Peter C.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Helfenstein</keyname><forenames>Paul</forenames></author><author><keyname>Hedman</keyname><forenames>Matthew M.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Burns</keyname><forenames>Joseph A.</forenames></author><author><keyname>Schenk</keyname><forenames>Paul M.</forenames></author></authors><title>True Polar Wander of Enceladus From Topographic Data</title><categories>astro-ph.EP</categories><journal-ref>Icarus, Volume 295, p. 46-60 (2017)</journal-ref><doi>10.1016/j.icarus.2017.04.019</doi><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Many obsects in the solar system are suspected to have experience
reorientation of their spin axes. As their rotation rates are slow and their
shapes are nearly spherical, the formation of mass anomalies, by either
endogenic of exogenic processes, can change objects' moments of inertia.
Therefore, the objects reorient to align their largest moment of inertia with
their spin axis. Such phenomenon is called True Polar Wander (TPW).
  Here we report the discovery of a global series of topographic lows on
Saturn's satellite Enceladus that we interpret to show that this synchronously
locked moon has undergone TPW by ~55{\deg} about the tidal axis. We use
improved topographic data from the spherical harmonic expansion of Cassini limb
and stereogrammetric measurements to characterize regional topography over the
surface of Enceladus. We identify a group of nearly antipodal basins orthogonal
to a topographic basin chain tracing a non-equatorial circumglobal belt across
Enceladus' surface. We argue that the belt and the antipodal regions are fossil
remnants of an earlier equator and poles, respectively. We argue that these
lows arise from isostasic compensation and that their pattern reflects spatial
variations in internal dynamics of the ice shell. Our hypothesis is consistent
with a variety of geological features visible in Cassini images.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
<record>
<header>
 <identifier>oai:arXiv.org:1710.04624</identifier>
 <datestamp>2017-10-13</datestamp>
 <setSpec>physics</setSpec>
</header>
<metadata>
 <arXiv xmlns="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv/ http://arxiv.org/OAI/arXiv.xsd">
 <id>1710.04624</id><created>2017-10-12</created><authors><author><keyname>Weliweriya</keyname><forenames>Nandana</forenames></author><author><keyname>Huynh</keyname><forenames>Tra</forenames></author><author><keyname>Sayre</keyname><forenames>Eleanor C</forenames></author></authors><title>Standing fast: Translation among durable representations using
  evanescent representations in upper-division problem solving</title><categories>physics.ed-ph</categories><comments>Submitted to PERC 2017</comments><license>http://arxiv.org/licenses/nonexclusive-distrib/1.0/</license><abstract>  Mastering problem solving requires students to not only understand and apply
physics concepts but also employ mathematics and mathematical representations
(sketches, diagrams, graphs, gestures, equations and spoken language)
skillfully. As part of a larger project to investigate problem solving
processes among upper division physics students, we investigate how students
coordinate among multiple representations while solving problems. Data for this
study is drawn from an upper-division Electromagnetism I course, where students
engage in individual oral exams. We do moment-by-moment analysis of students'
problem solving to see how they translate between durable representations
(diagrams, written mathematical equations) with the help of evanescent
representations (gestures, words); and how they build up durable
representations where they can &quot;stand fast&quot; later. In this paper, we present
the case of Larry as an exemplary case for problem solving. Larry starts from a
durable representation (diagram) and builds up from there using evanescent
representations (gestures and words), standing fast on the diagram. He later
translates to a different kind of durable representation (mathematics), where
he reasons and answers the original problem.
</abstract></arXiv>
</metadata>
</record>
</ListRecords>
</OAI-PMH>
